<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edmund Husserl on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/edmund-husserl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edmund Husserl on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2003 01:01:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/edmund-husserl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Epistemology: Paper on Husserl and Logical Investigations</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Epistemology-Paper-on-Husserl-and-Logical-Investigations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2003 01:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Epistemology-Paper-on-Husserl-and-Logical-Investigations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, I will be trying to discuss Edmund Husserl&amp;rsquo;s theory of impossible objects and meanings in the &lt;em&gt;Logical Investigations&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; His theories of experience, knowledge, truth, and fact, will also be discussed in an attempt to determine their relation to these impossible things.&amp;nbsp; By looking at the &lt;em&gt;Logical Investigations&lt;/em&gt; Investigation by Investigation, I hope to see where he speaks of his ideas of experience, knowledge, truth and fact.&amp;nbsp; After looking at these ideas, I should be able to end by speaking of impossible things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first mention that we get of knowledge is in the Prolegomena, where he is talking about logic, and how it can be the foundation for the sciences.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Science is concerned, as its name indicates, with knowing &amp;hellip; it represents a set of external arrangements, which, just as they arose out of the knowledge-acts of many individuals, can again pass over into just such acts of countless individuals, in a readily understandable manner&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 16-7).&amp;nbsp; Logic, therefore, would be the way that we come upon, and find, or list, these external arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl clarifies what knowledge is when he states that &amp;ldquo;in the narrowest, strictest sense, it requires to be evident, to have the luminous certainty that what we have acknowledged &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;, that what we have rejected &lt;em&gt;is not&lt;/em&gt;, a certainty distinguished in familiar fashion from blind belief, from vague opining, however firm and decided&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 17).&amp;nbsp; To distinguish it from blind belief, &amp;ldquo;we need grounded validations in order to pass beyond what, in knowledge, is immediately and therefore trivially evident&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 19).&amp;nbsp; In other words, we need a set of rules, a logic, to guide us.&amp;nbsp; Following these rules of logic, we will eventually come to the truth.&amp;nbsp; Truths then come from knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are other things of importance in the Prolegomena, near the end, he sets up what he will be discussing in the actual investigations.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Since the essential aim of scientific knowledge can only be achieved through theory, in the strict sense of the nomological sciences, we replace our question by a question as to the &lt;em&gt;conditions of the possibility of theory in general&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; A theory as such consists of truths, and its form of connection is a deductive one.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 149)&amp;nbsp; In other words, logic should be able to come up with those necessary laws, or truths, that will apply to theories in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little later, Husserl goes on to state the three tasks of pure logic.&amp;nbsp; The first such task is to &amp;ldquo;lay down the more important concepts, in particular all the &lt;em&gt;primitive&lt;/em&gt; concepts which &amp;lsquo;make possible&amp;rsquo; the interconnected web of knowledge as seen objectively, and particularly the web of theory&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 153).&amp;nbsp; Objects and their meaning will then be discussed, and this then will become the foundation that will be used to build upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second task is then to look at the laws that are built up from the first task.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;On the one hand, the truth or falsity of &lt;em&gt;meanings&lt;/em&gt; as such, purely on the basis of their categorial formal structure, on the other hand (in relation to their &lt;em&gt;objective&lt;/em&gt; correlates), the being and not being of objects as such, of states of affairs as such, again on the basis of their pure, categorial form.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 154)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third task will be to come up with a theory of manifolds.&amp;nbsp; That is, to create &amp;ldquo;a science which definitely works out the form of the essential types of possible theories or fields of theory, and investigates their legal relations with one another&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 157).&amp;nbsp; Those investigations that come after this Prolegomena will deal with those first and second tasks, so that those who attempt the third task will have some foundation to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Introduction before Investigation I, Husserl once again notes what it is that will be discussed in the following investigations.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;The pure phenomenology of the experiences of thinking and knowing &amp;hellip; has, as its exclusive concern, experiences intuitively seizable and analyzable in the pure generality of their essence&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 165).&amp;nbsp; Here then he states that we will not deal with the specifics of the experiences, but rather with the &amp;lsquo;essence&amp;rsquo; that which is common.&amp;nbsp; He will not be dealing with that which is at first &amp;lsquo;visible&amp;rsquo;, but rather with that which comes about after analysis; an attempt to find their foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the introduction out of the way, Husserl can begin the first task.&amp;nbsp; &amp;lsquo;Expression&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;sign&amp;rsquo; are first looked at, and proven to be not equivalent.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Every sign is a sign for something, but not every sign has &amp;lsquo;meaning&amp;rsquo;, a &amp;lsquo;sense&amp;rsquo; that the sign &amp;lsquo;expresses&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 183)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl next looks at &amp;lsquo;demonstration&amp;rsquo; as having two meanings; &amp;lsquo;indication&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;proof&amp;rsquo;.&amp;nbsp; Demonstration in the sense of &amp;lsquo;proof&amp;rsquo;, means to show that something is true.&amp;nbsp; For example, the premises demonstrate the conclusion in a logical proof.&amp;nbsp; On the other hand, something is demonstrated in the sense of &amp;lsquo;indication&amp;rsquo; when past demonstrations have proven something to be true, and we therefore rely on that previous knowledge.&amp;nbsp; In Husserl&amp;rsquo;s words: &amp;ldquo;in such situations, where certain states of affairs readily serve to indicate others which are, in themselves, their consequences, they do not function in thought as logical grounds of the latter, but work through connections which previous actual demonstration, or blind learning from authority, has established among our convictions, whether as actual mental states or as dispositions for such&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 185).&amp;nbsp; Belief in what was proven before serves as the basis of indication in such a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl would next like to separate indicative signs from meaningful signs, the latter of which he calls expressions.&amp;nbsp; Indicative signs are relative to those who in interpret them, as such, their meaning can change, and hence the expression meant can be lost.&amp;nbsp; All talk then of expressions in the &lt;em&gt;Logical Investigations&lt;/em&gt;, will deal with meaningful signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In section nine, Husserl discusses acts, meanings, and fulfillment.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A name&lt;/em&gt;, e.g., names its object whatever the circumstances, in so far as it &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; that object.&amp;nbsp; But if the object is not intuitively before one, and so not before one as a named or meant object, mere meaning is all there is to it.&amp;nbsp; If the originally &lt;em&gt;empty&lt;/em&gt; meaning-intention is now fulfilled, the relation to an object is realized, the naming becomes an actual, conscious relation between name and object named.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 192)&amp;nbsp; I see this as the following; if someone refers to something, but you at first have no idea what it is that they are referring to, then there is a meaning, but it means the object that you do not know of.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Each expression not merely says something, but says it &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; something: it not only has a meaning, but refers to certain &lt;em&gt;objects&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 197)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl seems to believe that the &amp;lsquo;something&amp;rsquo; of above (the latter) is intuited; &amp;ldquo;in order to be quite clear as to the sense of an expression (or as to the content of a concept) one must construct a corresponding intuition: in this intuition one sees what the expression &amp;lsquo;really means&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 211).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we see mention of essences in a context in which we are better able to get a grasp on what he means.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;The knowledge meant is one whose self-evidence calls only for pure representation of the &amp;lsquo;conceptual essences&amp;rsquo;, in which the general word-meanings find their perfect fulfillments: all question as to the existence of objects corresponding to such concepts, or falling under such conceptual essences, is ruled out.&amp;nbsp; &amp;hellip;&amp;nbsp; Conceptual essences are rather the fulfilling sense which is &amp;lsquo;given&amp;rsquo; when the word-meanings (i.e. the meaning-intentions of the words) terminate in corresponding, directly intuitive presentations, and in certain cogitative elaborations and formations of the same.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 212)&amp;nbsp; That is, it is possible for an intention of a species to be fulfilled by intuition of the species, and without any real, experienced, object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, Husserl notes the difference between &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;essentially subjective and occasional&lt;/em&gt; expressions, on the one hand, and &lt;em&gt;objective&lt;/em&gt; expressions, on the other&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 218).&amp;nbsp; By subjective, or occasional, expressions, he means expressions that have meanings that are functions of the occasion of utterance.&amp;nbsp; By objective expressions, he means expressions that have the same meaning regardless of the occasion of their utterance.&amp;nbsp; Any expression with an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo;, or time and place, would be an example of a subjective expression, while mathematical expressions would be an example of an objective expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;States of affairs&amp;rsquo; deals directly with these concepts.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Where the sciences unfold systematic theories &amp;hellip; there is absolutely no talk of judgements, ideas and other mental acts.&amp;nbsp; The objective researcher or course &lt;em&gt;clarifies&lt;/em&gt; his expressions &amp;hellip; but he only points thereby to the &lt;em&gt;objective meaning&lt;/em&gt; of his expressions, he indicates what &amp;lsquo;contents&amp;rsquo; he has in mind, which play their part as constitutive moments in the truths of his field.&amp;nbsp; He is not interested in understanding, but in the concepts, which are for him ideal unities of meaning, and also in the truths, which themselves are made up out of such concepts.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 225)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who wishes to speak of the true &amp;lsquo;state of affairs&amp;rsquo; in a specific context, should not speak subjectively, from their own perspective, but rather try to be as objective as possible.&amp;nbsp; Looking at things objectively, and not trying to bring in one&amp;rsquo;s own ideas, or judgements, will allow one meaning that all researchers can share, as opposed to a subjective meaning from each researcher.&amp;nbsp; As is stated still later, &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Use words with an absolutely selfsame meaning: exclude all meaning-variations.&amp;nbsp; Distinguish meanings and keep them distinct in declarative thought, and employ sharply distinct sensible signs.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 231)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigation II gives us better understanding of what he means by species, as well as moments, which was briefly mentioned before.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;The relation between the meaning and the significant expression (or its &amp;lsquo;meaning-tincture&amp;rsquo;) is the same as the relation, e.g., between the Species Red and a red object of intuitive experience (or the &amp;lsquo;moment&amp;rsquo; of red which appears in this object).&amp;nbsp; When we mean red &lt;em&gt;in specie&lt;/em&gt;, a red object appears before us, and in this sense we look towards the red object to which we are nevertheless not referring.&amp;nbsp; The moment of red is at the same time emphasized in this object, and to that extent we can again say that we are looking towards this moment of red.&amp;nbsp; But we are not referring to this individually definite trait in the object, as we are referring to it when, e.g., we make the phenomenological observation that the moments of red in the separate portions of the apparent object&amp;rsquo;s surface are themselves separate.&amp;nbsp; While the red object and its emphasized moment of red appear before us, we are rather &amp;lsquo;meaning&amp;rsquo; the single identical Red, and are meaning it in a novel conscious &lt;em&gt;manner&lt;/em&gt;, thought which precisely the Species, and not the individual becomes our object.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 237)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigation II also gives us a look at what it is that we mean when we talk of reality.&amp;nbsp; It is the particulars that are real, and not the universals.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;We may simply define &amp;lsquo;reality&amp;rsquo; in terms of temporality.&amp;nbsp; For the only point of importance is to oppose it to the timeless &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; of the ideal.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 1, 249)&amp;nbsp; Therefore, he seems to say that the cat, sitting on the mat, is really real, while the idea of &amp;lsquo;cat&amp;rsquo;, or the ideal &amp;lsquo;cat&amp;rsquo;, is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving onto Investigation III, here he talks of wholes and parts, as well as independence and dependence.&amp;nbsp; Objects, according to Husserl, can either be parts, or they are parts &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Every object is either actually or possibly a part.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 4)&amp;nbsp; Wholes, for example, have parts, but they can also be a part of something else.&amp;nbsp; For another example, A can be a part of B (which is composed of A, C, E, G, I) and B could be a part of L (which is composed of B, D, F, H, J).&amp;nbsp; Therefore, in relation to A, B is a whole, while in relation to L, B is a part.&amp;nbsp; Also, parts are either dependent, or independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, my head is a part of my whole body.&amp;nbsp; One can have the idea of my head, hold my head&amp;rsquo;s image in their mind, without the idea of my whole body.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, my head is independent of my whole body.&amp;nbsp; However, the colour of an object is dependent upon the object.&amp;nbsp; While one could have the idea of my head without the context of my whole body, it is impossible to think of the colour of my skin, eyes, or hair, without something that is that colour.&amp;nbsp; In order to see colour, we must have extension.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, one might say that colour is founded on, or dependent on, extension.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;A part &lt;em&gt;as such&lt;/em&gt; cannot exist at all without a whole whose part it is.&amp;nbsp; On the other hand we say, with an eye to &lt;em&gt;independent&lt;/em&gt; parts: A part often &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; exist without a whole whose part it is.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 20)&amp;nbsp; The second chapter of this Investigation gives specific rules that dependent parts of wholes follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigation IV uses this discussion of parts and wholes to speak of simple and complex meanings.&amp;nbsp; If we read the expression &amp;lsquo;a man of iron&amp;rsquo;, there are parts of this expression &amp;ndash; man and iron &amp;ndash; that have meanings, which, when taken together, give the expression meaning.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, the expression &amp;lsquo;a man of iron&amp;rsquo; expresses, or means, &amp;lsquo;a human being who is as strong as a bar of iron&amp;rsquo;, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as most people realize, meanings can only be combined in a certain order.&amp;nbsp; That is, there are &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; laws that direct how words can be combined in an expression.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;The expression &amp;lsquo;This tree is green&amp;rsquo; has unified meaning.&amp;nbsp; If we formalize this meaning &amp;hellip; we obtain &amp;lsquo;This S is P&amp;rsquo;, an ideal form whose range of values consist solely of independent (propositional) meanings.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 62)&amp;nbsp; We could not switch the words around and get &amp;lsquo;This green is tree&amp;rsquo;, without a loss of the unified meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, while we can substitute &amp;lsquo;ball&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;sign&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;hat&amp;rsquo;, etc. for S, we could not substitute something like &amp;lsquo;gold&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;red&amp;rsquo;, etc. for S.&amp;nbsp; By inserting a word, or words, that are not in the same category as the original word, we have only a &amp;lsquo;word-series&amp;rsquo;, an expression which expresses no meaning because it does not follow the &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; laws, and is therefore nonsense.&amp;nbsp; This is different then an absurd expression.&amp;nbsp; An absurd statement &amp;ndash; such as &amp;lsquo;a round square&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; has meaning, but it means an impossible object.&amp;nbsp; That is, one can never have a round square, even though it is grammatically correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final example, following the structure &amp;lsquo;This S is P&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; for instance &amp;lsquo;This tree is green&amp;rsquo;.&amp;nbsp; An expression such as &amp;lsquo;This red dog is blue&amp;rsquo; would be an expression of nonsense, while &amp;lsquo;This square is round&amp;rsquo; would be an expression of absurdity.&amp;nbsp; Husserl asks the reader to keep these two concepts separate, as they do not belong together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl claims that there are laws that should be used in order to prevent nonsense from occurring in a valid expression.&amp;nbsp; Absurdity, however, is slightly difficult, but there still must be ways of preventing such expressions from occurring.&amp;nbsp; This then is his idea of our modern logical rules, which, if the starting expressions are valid and true, then we can be guaranteed that the expressions that follow are valid and true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigation V discusses experience, and the part that it plays in all this.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Experiences of meaning are classifiable as &amp;lsquo;acts&amp;rsquo;, and the meaningful element in each such single act must be sought in the act-experience, and not in its object; it must lie in that element which makes the act an &amp;lsquo;intentional&amp;rsquo; experience, one &amp;lsquo;directed&amp;rsquo; to objects.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 79)&amp;nbsp; Husserl later states that, &amp;ldquo;The experienced content, generally speaking, is not the perceived object.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 104)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this, he seems to mean that it is the senses that we experience.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Sensations&lt;/em&gt;, and the acts &amp;lsquo;interpreting&amp;rsquo; them or apperceiving them, are alike experienced, &lt;em&gt;but they do not appear as objects&lt;/em&gt;: they are not seen, heard or &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; by any sense.&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Objects&lt;/em&gt; on the other hand, appear and are perceived, but they are not &lt;em&gt;experienced&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 105)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, together with his discussion of intention, seems to point to the following ideas.&amp;nbsp; When one looks at a cat, which is sitting on a mat, then they have an experience of the cat on the mat.&amp;nbsp; In this case, there is an ego (which is what Husserl calls the perceiver) as well as objects that are perceived.&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;The ego is intentionally directed to some object&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 101), in this case the cat, which is on the mat.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, Husserl says that we are &amp;lsquo;intending&amp;rsquo; the cat on the mat, in that we are &amp;ldquo;specially noticing, or attending to something.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 101)&amp;nbsp; Husserl also clarifies that acts are mental in nature, not as is commonly held, activities, and &amp;ldquo;is either a presentation or is founded upon presentations&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 80).&amp;nbsp; He also states that an &amp;lsquo;intentional experience&amp;rsquo; is any &amp;ldquo;concrete experience that &amp;lsquo;refers&amp;rsquo; intentionally to an object&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 144)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;States of affairs&amp;rsquo; are also discussed in this investigation.&amp;nbsp; States of affairs is that which we direct our intention to, or, in other words, that which we perceive.&amp;nbsp; It is this state of affairs then, which we then make a judgement about.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, for example, the cat on the mat would be the state of affairs of reality, which we then perceive, and then make a judgement about, such as &amp;lsquo;that cat is indeed on the mat&amp;rsquo;.&amp;nbsp; The state of affairs is the matter that we make a judgement about.&amp;nbsp; As Husserl stated earlier, it is necessary to keep our eye on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving onto Investigation VI, Husserl points out that all the material that has been discussed has barely touched upon the task of giving an explanation of knowledge.&amp;nbsp; Expressions and meaning, leading up to knowledge, will be the topics, the goals, of this final Investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Undeniably and importantly, the meaning of expressions must lie in the intentional essence of the relevant acts&amp;rdquo; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 184).&amp;nbsp; That is, Husserl states that while we start with meaning-intention and we work our way up to meaning-fulfillment or from a &amp;lsquo;concept&amp;rsquo; to a &amp;lsquo;corresponding intuition&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning-fulfillment is what we seek to achieve in order to obtain true knowledge of reality.&amp;nbsp; For example, if my friend looks out his window and says &amp;lsquo;There is a dog running around in my field&amp;rsquo;, then I have an idea of what he means.&amp;nbsp; Perhaps I imagine what his field looks like, from seeing it before, and have a mental picture of a dog, also from experience, and place the two together.&amp;nbsp; However, there are various things that can occur that will prevent my meaning from being fulfilled.&amp;nbsp; For example, it could not be a dog that is in the field, but rather a cat, that due to the distance, my friend mistakenly took to be a dog.&amp;nbsp; This is what Husserl calls conflict, or frustration, as the meaning cannot be fulfilled and speak of the true state of affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in this example, what he says has a meaning for me.&amp;nbsp; However, if he had said something such as &amp;lsquo;There is a wolk in my new rafledum&amp;rsquo;, then I would only understand that something was in his new something.&amp;nbsp; If he explains to me that a wolk is a type of insect, and a rafledum is a type of flower, then I would have a better understanding of his statement.&amp;nbsp; Here is where Husserl distinguishes between the intuitive contents of a presentation and the signitive contents.&amp;nbsp; The intuitive contents are those things that are, or become, apparent.&amp;nbsp; On the other hand, the signitive contents are those things that do not become apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, a purely intuitive presentation would be one with the dog, in which all of the contents of the presentation, or statement, have readily apparent meaning.&amp;nbsp; A purely signitive presentation, on the other hand, would be one in which there was nothing in the statement which was apparent.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, a purely signitive presentation, or if any signitive contents were in a presentation, then the meaning could not be fulfilled.&amp;nbsp; Husserl also makes a distinction that purely signitive intentions are empty in that they do not contain meaning and therefore cannot be fulfilled, while intuitive intentions are fulfilling in that they can be fulfilled and contain meaning within them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go back to our previous, intuitive, example, it is also possible that what my friend saw was a dog, and in fact was a germen shepherd.&amp;nbsp; However, when I imagined the scene, I saw a poodle.&amp;nbsp; It is only by my looking at the scene, or by my friend thoroughly explaining the scene, that my friends meaning could be completely fulfilled.&amp;nbsp; This is clarified later when he states that &amp;ldquo;If then, in each pure intuition we take &lt;em&gt;Pp&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ip&lt;/em&gt; to be the weights of its &lt;em&gt;purely&lt;/em&gt; perceptual and &lt;em&gt;purely&lt;/em&gt; imaginative components, we can write down the symbolic equation &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Pp&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;Ip&lt;/em&gt; = 1&amp;rsquo; where 1 symbolizes the weight of the total intuitive content of the pure intuition, and thus the total content of its object.&amp;nbsp; If &lt;em&gt;Ip&lt;/em&gt; = 0, i.e. if the pure intuition is free from all imaginal content, it should be called a &lt;em&gt;pure perception&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;nbsp; But if &lt;em&gt;Pp&lt;/em&gt; = 0, the intuition is called &lt;em&gt;pure imagination&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; (Husserl, Vol. 2, 237)&amp;nbsp; In other cases, the intuition has some perceptual contents, and some imaginative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that in the example above, the presentation is purely intuitive, as all of the words have meaning, as well as a perception of &amp;lsquo;pure imagination&amp;rsquo;, but if I had a glimpse of the field, but not the dog, then it would not be a pure imagination or a pure perception, and instead would lie between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, of a dog in a field, it is entirely possible that the statement will have meaning.&amp;nbsp; That is, that the statement is not an empty intention, it is internally consistent, and points to a specific state of affairs in reality.&amp;nbsp; However, it was entirely possible that the statement was impossible, had there been inconsistencies.&amp;nbsp; This is one of the things that the laws of a logic should be able to prevent against, as was stated earlier in the &lt;em&gt;Logical Investigations&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second third of Investigation VI deals with sensuous and categorial intuitions.&amp;nbsp; While I have some understanding of what he is talking about here, like the rest of it, I have a hard time putting it down in words.&amp;nbsp; So, I will try to make some sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have a red ball in my hand, it is a simple object in the respect that it is a whole thing &amp;ndash; a &amp;lsquo;red ball&amp;rsquo;.&amp;nbsp; However, it is made up of parts.&amp;nbsp; It is red, squishy, bouncy, smooth, etc.&amp;nbsp; We can say various things about this ball, in the structure of &amp;lsquo;this ball is x&amp;rsquo;, where x is a moment of the ball.&amp;nbsp; For example, &amp;lsquo;this ball is red&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;this ball is squishy&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;this ball is bouncy&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;this ball is smooth&amp;rsquo;.&amp;nbsp; Each of these properties is a part of the whole, the ball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we look at this ball, the whole ball is explicate, while the various parts are implicate.&amp;nbsp; That is, we clearly see the whole, and through it, the parts.&amp;nbsp; The same is true of the various parts of the whole.&amp;nbsp; For example, when we see red, we know that extension is a part of it, as extension is necessary for color to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we see an object then, we first have a sensuous intuition, followed by a categorial intuition.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, I believe that he means something like the following:&amp;nbsp; If we represent the ball as &amp;lsquo;b&amp;rsquo;, then our simple intuition would give us &amp;lsquo;b&amp;rsquo;.&amp;nbsp; On the other hand, a categorial intuition would give us something like &amp;lsquo;b = r &amp;middot; s &amp;middot; y &amp;middot; m &amp;middot; &amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; where &amp;lsquo;r&amp;rsquo; stands for red, &amp;lsquo;s&amp;rsquo; for squishy, &amp;lsquo;y&amp;rsquo; for bouncy, and &amp;lsquo;m&amp;rsquo; for smooth.&amp;nbsp; Using any of the modern logical connectives, as was explained in class, is what distinguishes a categorial, from a simple intuition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it seems that Husserl talks more about possibility in the &lt;em&gt;Logical Investigations&lt;/em&gt; then he does of impossibility.&amp;nbsp; However, if you do not do what Husserl speaks of in relation to possible objects and meaning, then you are almost guaranteed to have an impossible one.&amp;nbsp; While I believe I have a grasp of what it is that Husserl is trying to get across, from the reading, as well as looking at modern logic, many of his ideas are still a little sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl, Edmund, &lt;em&gt;Logical Investigations Volume 1 and 2&lt;/em&gt;, New York, Routledge, 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Created:&lt;/strong&gt; April 27th 2003&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modified:&lt;/strong&gt; June 4th 2003; October 30th 2003; February 13th 2004&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt; See also my paper titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Husserls-Phenomenological-Epoche-and-Theory-of-Intentionality.aspx&#34;&gt;Husserl&amp;rsquo;s Phenomenological Epoch&amp;eacute; and the Theory of Intentionality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Husserl&#39;s Phenomenological Epoché and Theory of Intentionality</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Husserls-Phenomenological-Epoche-and-Theory-of-Intentionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2002 01:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Husserls-Phenomenological-Epoche-and-Theory-of-Intentionality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edmund Husserl, in his &lt;em&gt;Ideas Pertaining to a Pure Phenomenology and to a Phenomenological Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;, begins by discussing natural cognition and experience. Husserl explores experience, believing that experience is how we view the world around us. However, it is not enough to know that experience gives us insight. According to Husserl, we must, primarily, know how we are conscious of the world around us, before we can talk about the actuality of what we see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl, in this book, hopes to explain his phenomenological epoch&amp;eacute;, or reduction, as well as show just how important the epoch&amp;eacute;, and his theory of intentionality, are to experience and knowledge. For this paper, I will discuss the epoch&amp;eacute;, both how it works as well as its purpose in Husserl&#39;s theory. Also, I&#39;ll be using Husserl&#39;s theory of intentionality to show how it works into this. Hopefully, the importance of what Husserl is doing will be shown by the end of this paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of Husserl&#39;s theory necessitates that examples are used to explain particular points. Therefore, it will be necessary to use examples in this paper. For our first example we will take these pieces of paper that this paper is printed on. Now, when you look at these papers, when you physically turn your eyes to them, you are paying attention to the pieces of paper, you are conscious of them. Husserl also uses the words &#39;intending&#39;, and &#39;grasping&#39; in place of &#39;paying attention&#39; to mean the same general idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when Husserl states that &#34;physical things are intended to not only in perception but also in memories&#34; (71), he is telling us that not only can you look upon the pieces of paper with your eyes, and perceive them that way, but you can also intend them in your mind. For example, you can look at these pieces of paper, and say some statement about them, such as &#39;these papers are white with black writing&#39;. However, you can also put these papers into a folder, and, using your memory, recall what they look like, and say that &#39;those papers were white with black writing&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both examples above you are stating some perceived fact about an object. That is, in the first example you are making a statement about objects that are sitting in front of you, while in the next example you are making a statement about objects that you are recollecting. Later, Husserl will use particular words to describe each of the features of the act of perceiving something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, Husserl brings the Ego into perception and consciousness. The Ego is that which either a) grasps, b) maintains in grasp, or c) releases from grasp that which is being paid attention to, or that which you are intending. For example, using the example above, the Ego grasps, or pays attention, to the sheets of paper. Now, if you&#39;re paying attention to both the table that the papers are laying on in addition to the papers themselves, you maintain your consciousness of the papers, but also pay attention to the table. Therefore, your Ego is grasping the table, and maintaining the papers in its grasp. Now, if you no longer want to pay attention to the sheets of paper lying on the table, but would rather pay attention to the table itself, by itself, then your Ego releases the papers from its grasp, and maintains its grasp on the table. To continue further, perhaps a few moments after you begin to study the table, a door is slammed shut, or opened, and you turn to look in the general direction. Whatever it is that you are now paying attention to, perhaps the closest door, is now your primary concern. Perhaps you no longer even remember what you were doing before, and therefore, the table is no longer in the grasp of the Ego - it is no longer maintained in the Ego&#39;s grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this basically amounts to is a general theory of how individuals pay attention to that which they are studying. In the example above, first the papers were looked at, then the papers in relation to the table, then, the focus was moved solely to the table, and finally the door was looked at because of an abrupt noise. So, first one thing was the focus of the attention, and then two objects were, then just one, and finally another, different object. However, there is a constant movement from one object to another. Therefore, any individual always has at least one object that they are paying attention to at any time. Also, the object does not necessarily need to be a physical thing, as, as stated above, memories can also be objects of regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, before I turn to the next topic, I will introduce a new example. For this example, we will take an individual sitting at his desk, on which lies a soda can. Now, using the example above with the sheets of paper on the table as our guide, let&#39;s take a look at what this individual may be thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, let us imagine that the individual is looking at the soda can. Now, the individual might be thinking about its properties or characteristics. For example, perhaps the soda can is red with white writing on it. The individual can also see that it is slightly shiny and that it is open. Now, while the individual is thinking this, they are probably holding the belief that the object that they see, that they perceive, is what they are describing. That is, they would probably be pretty surprised if someone were to say that the can is really blue, because they see a red can. However, let us put that aside for a moment. Now, let us say the individual, who we will designate as P, has been sitting in the same position while looking at this can before him. Now, each of his experiences of the soda can have been from the same general side of the can. That is, P hasn&#39;t rotated the can, but has merely focused on the one original view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, perhaps there is writing on the can that starts on the side of the can that he presently viewing, but that continues onto a side that he cannot see from his current position. Now, based upon previous cans that P has seen, or based upon his previous experiences with words and writing, P may believe that the writing continues onto the sides that he cannot see. Also, P may believe that the red color continues onto the other sides, and that the can will be shiny on the other sides, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, P cannot be sure that his intentions, namely that the can is going to be red and shiny on the sides that he cannot see and that the words will continue until they make a full word, or complete sentence, are correct until he looks at the other sides. So, P decides to turn the can ninety degrees to look at another side of the can. After P has turned the can ninety degrees, he finds that indeed he was correct. The writing continues on, and as does the red color and the shiny look of the can. Now, Husserl calls each new look at an object of consciousness, in this case the can, an adumbration. With each new adumbration, or look, at an object, our knowledge of the object becomes more and more clear or adequate in that we know more about the object that we are examining, and we are less likely to be missing some essential information about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, after looking at this side of the can, P can still not be sure that his idea of the can, as being red and shiny all over and whatever else he perceives the can to have as characteristics, is true on the other sides that he has not yet experienced. So, P turns the can ninety degrees yet again. However, after rotating the can P finds that this side has an ashy residue, and is more yellow then red. Therefore, P has now learned that the can is not as he first believed it to be - red and shiny all over - but instead has a characteristic that he would have missed had he not rotated it enough. This goes along with what Husserl tells us about experience and objects. Only by continually looking at something with new and different perspectives can the perceiver ever know whether their intention of the thing is adequate or not. So, while P&#39;s intention of the can was red and shiny all over, his intention of the can was inadequate, in that the can is not red and shiny all over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, P continues to look at the can even further, now knowing that his original intention of the can was incorrect, and wishing to find out more. Perhaps, after another ninety degree rotation, the can flickers and disappears, leaving a circular device. P may now realize that the can was merely an illusion created by some kind of projector. However, the realization of illusion need not even be realized right away. Possibly after that last mentioned rotation, the can is how P believes it will continue - that is, it is like the first two sides of the can. However, a few years later, the can is shown to be merely a projection when the battery runs out in the circular projector device. Therefore, this shows but one example of how we cannot be sure that what we intend an object as is really is how it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also take another example, which most people have probably experienced at one time or another. While walking down the street, or sitting down somewhere and watching people go by, you see someone that you know. You call out to them, and find that they look towards you. However, while they get closer, and perhaps after halving the original distance, you realize that it is not who you thought it was. However, after they are within a few feet of the individual, you find that it is indeed the person that you originally thought it was, and you were indeed correct in your original intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at these examples, Husserl would say that they show that we can never really know whether something really exists, nor whether something is actually what we intend it to be. Indeed, this brings up the exact point that Husserl wants to make. Husserl does not really want to work with whether what we see as real is real, but rather Husserl wants to be able to understand intentionality. That is, while we may find out eventually, after further adumbrations of the &#39;matter&#39; that we are conscious of, that the thing does not actually exist, we have still perceived it at some point in time as real. That is, in the example above, P still perceived the soda can, even though it wasn&#39;t actually there. He had an intention of the soda can as really existing, even though P found that it didn&#39;t really exist after he had experienced it further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl, in this book, wishes to understand how it is that we perceive anything and how we can learn to know that what we perceive is as we believe it to be or not. For example, Husserl, in his reduction, asks us to bracket, or put off to the side, questions and determinations of the reality of the object that we perceive. Husserl tell us that &#34;we [phenomenologists] put out of action the general positing which belongs to the essence of the natural attitude; we parenthesize everything which that positing encompasses with respect to being: &lt;em&gt;thus the whole natural world&lt;/em&gt; which is continually &#39;there for us&#39;, &#39;on hand,&#39; and which will always remain there according to consciousness as an &#39;actuality&#39; even if we choose to parenthesize it.&#34; (61)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the epoch&amp;eacute; is that which allows us to exclude, for the most part, predetermined judgements (as those from science and past experiences) so that we can be free from previously placed restrictions. When we are free from past experiences, we no longer just give newly seen objects characteristics that we have seen in similar objects, but rather, we search for what the object really is. For example, when we see something, then we usually believe that it is real. However, that may not be the case, as it may in fact be an illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the question is: &#39;How does psychology fit into this?&#39; After all, psychology deals with mental processes and behavior, much like phenomenology. For example, psychology is used to show why P, in the example above, feels the way that he does about the soda can. In other words, psychology uses knowledge of the subject to learn why they feel the way about the object that they perceive and why and they perceive it as they do. Psychology makes a judgement about the object, however. That is, psychology does not bracket, or parenthesize, whether any of the things perceived are real or not. Psychology instead deals with why characteristics are given to the object by the subject, with what mental events lead to the characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phenomenology, on the other hand, has more of a relation to any and all mental events, for any and every consciousness, or Ego. So, to take the example of P and the soda can above, and to add on to it, let us imagine that another individual, R, comes in to P&#39;s area, after leaving his area, and looks at the same soda can that P was looking at. There would be some events that occurred for P that R would also experience. For example, both would have an experience of some object, O, which is a soda can in our example. However, O would not necessarily appear to be the same to both of them. P could have some experiences, such as the experiences from his previous adumbrations, which R would not necessarily have. However, R could always perform the same steps as P, and possibly, come upon approximately the same experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it is important to point out that while they both perceive the same object, O, they may not have the same intention of the object. Even if they both have the intention that the soda can before them is red and shiny, what they mean by that is not the same thing. However, they can both do similar things with their experiences. For example, they can both have reflections upon their experiences. After they turn their attention to something else, they can still call up a memory, a reflection, of the object that they had just seen. Of course, the object of their individual reflections will probably not be the same as well, because of their different original experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, we have an object before us. We experience the object, and have some data that we experience from the object. These experiences, these senses or meanings, which the Ego grasps, are what Husserl calls noemata. From each experience, or each adumbration, the Ego grasps a noema. These noemata are then organized and put together by what Husserl calls the Ego. The organized and interpreted information is what Husserl calls noeses. Husserl believes that there is an internal and external world, as well as a world that is neither internal nor external. The external world is where the soda can, in our example, is, while the internal world is where the different noeses are. This shows that noeses are based up the individual, and therefore more personal, than objects themselves are. Noemata, on the other hand, are somewhere else. Noemata are the meanings or sense bestowed upon the object, and, according to Husserl, can be experienced by more then one individual, more then once. Because noemata can be repeated, P has the ability to speak of the soda can that he is experiencing with R as the same soda can that he was experiencing before R came into the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, phenomenology is more of a way of determining the nature of reality, as well as how the mind can know things, whether the things are physical or mental. In this way, as well as in other ways, phenomenology is more like metaphysics. Phenomenology requires that phenomenologists, as well as other individuals, realize a few things. The first thing that must be realized is that the objects we perceive may or may not have the properties that are attributed to them. The only way to know whether they do is to examine them and get more and more experience with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it must be realized that value is not inherent in the object, but rather that the value is a direct result of the personal view of the individual. Objects may have value in that they are more or less like the ideal object, however, this can only really be found by experience and examination, and can only be &#39;given&#39; to the object by the individual who is experiencing the object. Of course, one of the things that Husserl makes clear is that an object can never really be adequately known, whether it be physical or mental. The reason for this is the fact that any object can always have something else known about it, and in fact, can always be but a mere illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the main purpose of phenomenology appears to be a way of finding out not so much about the truth, but how we perceive and experience physical and mental things. It is through phenomenology that we can realize that we have a determined way of perceiving things, whether they are real or not, and it is through phenomenology that we can determine the way we perceive things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The epoch&amp;eacute; plays an important part in phenomenology. The epoch&amp;eacute; sets predetermined ideals to the side, so that they do not cloud our judgement. It does something which is similar to that which an individual must do when he wants to learn about a different culture. If anyone wishes to truly understand another culture, all of the individual&#39;s previously determined feelings and values must be aside. The culture must be looked at neutrally as it is, not in comparison to any another culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While psychology is similar, in many ways, to phenomenology, they are not the same. Psychology lacks the epoch&amp;eacute;, and it is this that is the major difference between the two. Psychology looks at the world as real, while phenomenology makes no assertions either way. It is phenomenology, with the aide of the epoch&amp;eacute;, the transcendental reduction, that helps lead phenomenologists to pure metaphysics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bibliography:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husserl, Edmund, &lt;em&gt;Ideas Pertaining to a Pure Phenomenology and to a Phenomenological Philosophy: First Book&lt;/em&gt; (1913), tr. F Kersten, Martinues Nijhoff, The Hague, 1982.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Created:&lt;/strong&gt; December 9th &amp;ndash; 16th 2002&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modified:&lt;/strong&gt; February 13th 2004; February 5th 2005&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt; See also my paper titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Epistemology-Paper-on-Husserl-and-Logical-Investigations.aspx&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epistemology: Paper on Husserl and Logical Investigations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
