<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mysql on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/mysql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mysql on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 12:40:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing WordPress 2.9.2 on Windows Server 2003 using Microsoft&#39;s Web Platform Installer</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Installing-WordPress-292-on-Windows-Server-2003-using-Microsofts-Web-Platform-Installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 12:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Installing-WordPress-292-on-Windows-Server-2003-using-Microsofts-Web-Platform-Installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had need to install and test WordPress for some possible work. While I was tempted to go the Linux route, shortly after the OS was setup I decided to skip that and stick with Windows. Since Microsoft has released a platform that supposedly makes it easy to install Web-related applications, I decided to give it a try to determine just how simple it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is an overview of the setup process to install WordPress 2.9.2 on Windows Server 2003, using Microsoft&#39;s Web Platform Installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Web Platform Installer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/web/platform/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Microsoft Web Platform Installer&lt;/a&gt; can be downloaded from Microsoft.com and acts as middle-ground between all of the various applications that it covers, which is fairly robust (a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/web/gallery/&#34;&gt;full listing&lt;/a&gt; is available).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_01.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;, WordPress is available along with a handful of other blogging applications. Upon selecting this and pressing Install, you&#39;re presented with the listing of dependencies and other applications that may be required (Figures &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_02.jpg&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_03.jpg&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_04.jpg&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was going to install MySQL on a dedicated virtual machine, and was able to deselect that, for ease I&#39;ve kept in selected here. At this time I&#39;m not sure (yet)&amp;nbsp;of how that would impact the installation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since MySQL was being installed, I was prompted, right away before anything was downloaded, for an administrator password, as seen in &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_05.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 5&lt;/a&gt;. Even though I thought&amp;nbsp;I had everything installed for IIS, I was also prompted, as shown in &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_06.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 6&lt;/a&gt;, for a Windows Server 2003 disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_07.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 7&lt;/a&gt; alludes to the fact that the individual requirements are downloaded and installed, moving right into the setup of any Web sites as required, as seen in &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_08.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 8&lt;/a&gt;. In this case I kept the defaults. Additional WordPress setups are shown in Figures &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_09.jpg&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_10.jpg&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_11.jpg&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_12.jpg&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;, where the database is setup. It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-MySQL-and-phpMyAdmin-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;installed MySQL&lt;/a&gt;, so how this relates to that installation is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all components have been installed, you&#39;re presented with a nice little screen, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_13.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 13&lt;/a&gt;. You can then launch WordPress and go through the setups necessary (Figures &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_14.jpg&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_15.jpg&#34;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;), log in (&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_16.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 16&lt;/a&gt;) and view the administrative interface (&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_17.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 17&lt;/a&gt;) and home page (&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/webPlatformInstaller_WordPress_18.jpg&#34;&gt;Figure 18&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thoughts on the Platform Installer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I initially didn&#39;t think much of the installer, having actually used it, I&#39;m pleasantly surprised. It&#39;s an extremely simple process, similar to how one might install applications through, say, Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes a lot of the guess-work out of the process, which is rather nice. On the other hand, while I can get going with WordPress at this point (and I was able to do my testing fairly quickly), the disadvantage of this is that I don&#39;t know any of the complexities of the setup process. I haven&#39;t installed WordPress (or PHP, or MySQL), but rather an installer has. But, I like the challenge of figuring things out on my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is why while I like the Installer, and will definitely use it when I need to quickly test something, for the most part I&#39;ll probably stick with old-fashioned methods of installation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Quickie: MySQL and PostgreSQL passwords</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another Ubuntu Quickie, this time on the default passwords for MySQL and PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MySQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;mysql -u root
UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&amp;rsquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;password&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;) WHERE User = &amp;lsquo;root&amp;rsquo;;
FLUSH PRIVILEGES;
\q&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;
sudo -u postgres psql template1
ALTER USER postgres WITH PASSWORD &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;password&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;;
\q&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Quickie: Installing MySQL and PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-Installing-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 21:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-Installing-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For SQL on Ubuntu Linux, I decided it was easiest to just use the repositories to just install MySQL and PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a couple of reasons for this. First, MySQL docs recommend it.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, there&#39;s not that much that I really want to configure in SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MySQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install mysql-server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, this will install;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libdbd-mysql-perl&lt;br /&gt;libdbi-perl&lt;br /&gt;libnet-daemon-perl&lt;br /&gt;libplrpc-perl&lt;br /&gt;mysql-client-5.0&lt;br /&gt;mysql-server&lt;br /&gt;mysql-server-5.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggested packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dbishell&lt;br /&gt;libcompress-zlib-perl&lt;br /&gt;tinyca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mailx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s some official GUIs that you can also install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install mysql-admin mysql-query-browser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, this will install;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libcairomm-1.0-1&lt;br /&gt;libglibmm-2.4-1c2a&lt;br /&gt;libgtkhtml3.8-15&lt;br /&gt;libgtkmm-2.4-1c2a&lt;br /&gt;mysql-admin&lt;br /&gt;mysql-admin-common&lt;br /&gt;mysql-query-browser&lt;br /&gt;mysql-query-browser-common&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggested packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libgtkhtml3.8-dbg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For PostgreSQL, it&#39;s a bit longer of a string, since there&#39;s four packages, but it&#39;s still easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install postgresql-8.2 postgresql-client-8.2 postgresql-client-common postgresql-common&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may as well also go from pgAdmin III, which &#34;is the most popular and feature rich Open Source administration and development platform for PostgreSQL.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install pgadmin3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, this will install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libpq4&lt;br /&gt;libwxbase2.6-0&lt;br /&gt;libwxgtk2.6-0&lt;br /&gt;pgadmin3&lt;br /&gt;pgadmin3-data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pgagent (adds functionality to schedule PostgreSQL jobs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next time ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time we&#39;ll &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL-passwords.aspx&#34;&gt;configure databases&lt;/a&gt; for both MySQL and PostgreSQL on Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The major failing of Akismet ...</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-major-failing-of-Akismet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 08:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-major-failing-of-Akismet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The major failing of the Akismet plug-in is that you can&#39;t determine which IPs, if any, are spamming your site the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akismet needs to have the ability to group by IP, as well as show counts for each IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In place of that, you can run the following query to get this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;select comment_author_ip, count(comment_author_ip) count from wp_comments where comment_approved = &#39;spam&#39; group by comment_author_ip order by count desc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This query will display the IP of the user who posted a message flagged as spam, and will also display the number of times a user with that IP posted a spam message. Of course, since Akismet deletes comments marked as spam after a certain amount of time, you&#39;ll need to run this on a semi-regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have this list, check out where the IP address points to, and if you don&#39;t see your users coming from that IP, block it through htaccess. I recommend you also add the date you did this in the comments, so you&#39;re aware of why you added the IP. In three months, you may also want to unblock the IP and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can also use another plug-in to automate this, but after hearing bad stories about the plug-in - Bad Behaviour - I&#39;m not quite willing to go that route yet. Maybe in a couple of months I&#39;ll give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 6: phpBB</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-6-phpBB/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2006 18:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-6-phpBB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s that time again. This time, we&#39;ll be looking at &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.phpbb.com/&#34;&gt;phpBB&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;phpBB is a high powered, fully scalable, and highly customizable Open Source bulletin board package. phpBB has a user-friendly interface, simple and straightforward administration panel, and helpful FAQ. Based on the powerful PHP server language and your choice of MySQL, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL or Access/ODBC database servers, phpBB is the ideal free community solution for all web sites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot&#39;s of features, so let&#39;s get to it. In this article, we&#39;ll be installing phpBB version 2.0.21, which is the latest version, as of June 9, 2006. A beta version of 3.0 came out a very short period before this article was written, otherwise I don&#39;t know that phpBB would have made it. Anywho, on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The zip file for phpBB weighs in at around 650 KB. Unzipped, we&#39;re looking at almost 2 MB. The zip file contains a single phpBB2 folder, so extract away. phpBB is also available in gzip and bz2 formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out these requirements. PHP 4.0.3+ and one of these database systems; MySQL 3.22+ or PostgreSQL 7.0.3+ or MS SQL Server 7+ or MS Access 2000+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&#39;re installing it locally as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you&#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run ... and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;mysql -h localhost -u root -p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;re installing phpBB, we&#39;ll create a database called phpBB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;create database phpBB;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we&#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &#39;&lt;strong&gt;phpbb&lt;/strong&gt;&#39; to something different (as this is the user&#39;s password).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop
ON &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt;.*
TO &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;&lt;strong&gt;phpbb&lt;/strong&gt;&#39;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt;.*&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;&lt;strong&gt;phpbb&lt;/strong&gt;&#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&#39;t exist yet, we&#39;re also giving a password to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the query is OK, enter the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&#39;phpbb&#39;) WHERE User = &#39;phpBB&#39;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the phpBB user. Once you&#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;show databases;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&#39;s a database of phpbb. Yippee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s install phpBB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing phpBB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, unzip the downloaded zip file. I&#39;ll be using one called phpBB2.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;re installing locally, we don&#39;t have to worry about permissions. So, once phpBB has been decompressed, navigate to the phpBB root folder in your browser. You&#39;ll be automatically be redirected to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/phpbb2/install/install.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/phpbb2/install/install.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a form to fill-out, so let&#39;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database Type: MySQL 4.x/5.x&lt;br /&gt;Choose your installation method: Install&lt;br /&gt;Database Server Hostname/DSN: localhost&lt;br /&gt;Your Database Name: phpBB&lt;br /&gt;Database Username: phpBB&lt;br /&gt;Database Password: phpbb&lt;br /&gt;Prefix for tables in database: phpbb_&lt;br /&gt;Admin Email Address: strivinglife@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;Domain Name: localhost&lt;br /&gt;Server Port: 80&lt;br /&gt;Script path: /projects/phpbb2/&lt;br /&gt;Administrator Username: admin&lt;br /&gt;Administrator Password: cbe15b&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it. Woot. You&#39;ll have to delete or rename the install and contrib folders (I put an underscore before both). At this point, you can start bouncing around the forum. Woot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How&#39;s the code look?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most other forums, phpBB uses tables, and doesn&#39;t care to declare a summary. There&#39;s also an issue with an &#39;invalid&#39; target for the footer link.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internally, code is commented pretty darn well. However, the main comment header is the same copyright notice over and over. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed, phpBB setups up one category, one forum, and one post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the look is very boxy, and reminds me of the look of a number of other forums. There&#39;s really not that much, graphically, that separates it from the others. Very similar look to MyBB and PunBB. Where&#39;s the admin interface? Oh, there&#39;s a link way down at the bottom of the page. Eh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking for updates, amongst other things, is quite easy from the interface, and the install even had an option regarding upgrading. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do have archived files with the changed and patched files only available for download, which is quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;phpBB is pretty much like the others that we&#39;ve reviewed. But, now that we&#39;ve gone over all of them, as far as installation and first impressions, it&#39;s time to dig into them deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review article, where we start busting heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 5: PunBB</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-5-PunBB/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2006 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-5-PunBB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Almost there. This time, we&amp;#39;ll be looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.punbb.org/&#34;&gt;PunBB&lt;/a&gt;. First, I did donate to PunBB development some time ago. At the time, I liked PunBB, and received some great support. It&amp;#39;s been sometime since that time, so I don&amp;#39;t know how things stand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anywho, &amp;ldquo;PunBB is a fast and lightweight PHP-powered discussion board. It is released under the GNU General Public License. Its primary goals are to be faster, smaller and less graphically intensive as compared to other discussion boards. PunBB has fewer features than many other discussion boards, but is generally faster and outputs smaller, semantically correct XHTML-compliant pages.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In this article, we&amp;#39;ll be installing PunBB version 1.2.14, which is the latest version, as of October 15, 2006.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The zip file for MyBB weighs in at around 250 KB. Unzipped, we&amp;#39;re looking at a bit over 800 KB. The zip file does not contain a single folder, but rather three, so you&amp;#39;ll want to unzip to a single PunBB folder. PunBB is also available in gzip and bz2 formats.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Best requirements thus far. PHP 4.1.0+ and MySQL 3.23.17+, or PHP 4.3.0+ and PostgreSQL 7.0+, or SQLite. Not to shabby, as this is the first we&amp;#39;ve reviewed that supports something other than just MySQL for the database.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&amp;#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&amp;#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&amp;#39;re installing it locally as well).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run &amp;hellip; and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&amp;#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     mysql -h localhost -u root -p
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&amp;#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing PunBB, we&amp;#39;ll create a database called PunBB.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     create database PunBB;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, we&amp;#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;punbb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39; to something different (as this is the user&amp;#39;s password).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&lt;br /&gt;
    ON &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    TO &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;punbb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;punbb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, we&amp;#39;re also giving a password to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the query is OK, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD&lt;em&gt;PASSWORD(&amp;#39;punbb&amp;#39;) WHERE User = &amp;#39;PunBB&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the PunBB user. Once you&amp;#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     show databases;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&amp;#39;s a database of punbb. Yippee.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, let&amp;#39;s install PunBB.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing PunBB&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, unzip the downloaded zip file. The files are within three folders in the zip file, so make sure you create a folder to dump these into. I&amp;#39;ll be using one called punbb.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing locally, we don&amp;#39;t have to worry about permissions. So, once PunBB has been decompressed, navigate to the PunBB root folder in your browser. You&amp;#39;ll be told that config.php doesn&amp;#39;t exist, and be given a link to the install file. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/punbb/install.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/punbb/install.php&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s a form to fill-out, so let&amp;#39;s get to it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can select your database type, which we&amp;#39;ll leave at MySQL Standard. Database server hostname can be left at localhost.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Database name: PunBB&lt;br /&gt;
Database username: PunBB&lt;br /&gt;
Database password: punbb&lt;br /&gt;
Table prefix: punbb&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Administrator username: admin&lt;br /&gt;
Password: cbe15b&lt;br /&gt;
Administrator&amp;#39;s e-mail: strivinglife@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
Base URL: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/punbb&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/punbb&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, start the installation. Once that&amp;#39;s done, you&amp;#39;ll need to copy some text into a new config.php file, and then you can hit the main forum page at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/punbb/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/punbb/&lt;/a&gt; (for example).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How&amp;#39;s the code look?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Like most other forums, PunBB uses a table, and doesn&amp;#39;t care to declare a summary. However, that looks like the only issue.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Internally, code is commented pretty darn well. Not too shabby at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once installed, PunBB setups up one category, one forum, and one post.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, the look is very boxy, and reminds me of the look of a number of other forums. There&amp;#39;s really not that much, graphically, that separates it from the others. The look is very similar to MyBB, but much flatter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Checking for updates, amongst other things, is quite easy from the interface. Unfortunately, when I attempted to check for updates, Apache started choking on me, specifically with problems in the php4ts.dll (as it did with MyBB).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
They do have archived files with the changed files only available for download, which is quite nice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
PunBB is pretty much like the others that we&amp;#39;ve reviewed. Until we get into the last forum, and start comparing all six, we&amp;#39;ll leave it at that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 4: MyBB</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-4-MyBB/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2006 21:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-4-MyBB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This time, we&amp;#39;ll be looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mybboard.com/&#34;&gt;MyBB&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;MyBB is a powerful, efficient and free forum package developed in PHP and MySQL. MyBB has been designed with the end users in mind, you and your subscribers. Full control over your discussion system is presented right at the tip of your fingers, from multiple styles and themes to the ultimate customisation of your forums using the template system.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In this article, we&amp;#39;ll be installing MyBB version 1.2.1, which is the latest version, as of September 27, 2006.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The zip file for MyBB weighs in at just over 1 MB. Unzipped, we&amp;#39;re looking at almost 3 MB. The zip file does not contain a single folder, but rather two, so you&amp;#39;ll want to unzip to a single MyBB folder. MyBB is also available in gzip and bzip formats.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
MyBB requirements were dang hard to find. That said, MyBB requires PHP 4.3.11+ and MySQL 4.0+. The PHP requirement actually seems a little high.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&amp;#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&amp;#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&amp;#39;re installing it locally as well).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run &amp;hellip; and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&amp;#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     mysql -h localhost -u root -p
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&amp;#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing MyBB, we&amp;#39;ll create a database called MyBB.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     create database MyBB;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, we&amp;#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;mybb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39; to something different (as this is the user&amp;#39;s password).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&lt;br /&gt;
    ON &lt;strong&gt;MyBB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    TO &lt;strong&gt;MyBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;mybb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;MyBB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;MyBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;mybb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, we&amp;#39;re also giving a password to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the query is OK, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD&lt;em&gt;PASSWORD(&amp;#39;mybb&amp;#39;) WHERE User = &amp;#39;MyBB&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the MyBB user. Once you&amp;#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     show databases;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&amp;#39;s a database of mybb. Yippee.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, let&amp;#39;s install MyBB.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing MyBB&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, unzip the downloaded zip file. The files are within two folders in the zip file, so make sure you create a folder to dump these into. I&amp;#39;ll be using one called mybb.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing locally, we don&amp;#39;t have to worry about permissions. So, once MyBB has been decompressed, navigate to the MyBB root folder in your browser and then the upload/install folder. On my install, this is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/mybb/upload/install/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/mybb/install/&lt;/a&gt;. I simply moved the upload folder&amp;#39;s contents into the mybb folder.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;re in for it now. There&amp;#39;s ten pages, from the initial look, that you&amp;#39;ll have to go through. Here goes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Read and Next along. There&amp;#39;s a Requirements Check page which will tell you if you&amp;#39;re set for requirements. If you&amp;#39;ve followed along with my other tutorials, you will be set.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In Database Configuration, leave Host as is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Database Host: localhost&lt;br /&gt;
    Database Username: MyBB&lt;br /&gt;
    Database Password: mybb&lt;br /&gt;
    Database Name: MyBB&lt;br /&gt;
    Table Prefix: mybb&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once this has been entered, and you&amp;#39;ve pressed Next, the necessary tables (all fifty of them) will be created. Okay, so I was kidding about the fifty, but there&amp;#39;s a whole lot. Yeesh. Next will populate these tables with some data, then setup the default theme.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Board Configuration is next, which will have some default settings. These will be fine, except the cookie path will have to be updated (why they couldn&amp;#39;t do this, since they populated the others, we&amp;#39;ll never know), followed by an email setting. Based on the URL of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/mybb/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/mybb/&lt;/a&gt;, my settings were as follows. Note that the domain is blank.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Cookie Domain:&lt;br /&gt;
    Cookie Path: /projects/mybb/
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Next you&amp;#39;ll create an Administrator Account. I used the same settings as I&amp;#39;ve used for the previous forums.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Username: admin&lt;br /&gt;
    Password: cbe15b
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, MyBB will be setup. Yay. The installer will also be locked by the creation of a &amp;#39;lock&amp;#39; file. That is nice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How&amp;#39;s the code look?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Like most other forums, MyBB uses tables, and doesn&amp;#39;t care to declare a summary. However, that looks like the only issue. Some of the admin pages are especially table-heavy.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Internally, some code is commented, while some is not. That&amp;#39;s unfortunate, but from the MyBB site, it sounds like this will change.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once installed, MyBB setups up one category and no topics.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, the look is very boxy, and reminds me of the look of a number of other forums. There&amp;#39;s really not that much, graphically, that separates it from the others.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Checking for updates, amongst other things, is quite easy from the interface. Unfortunately, when I attempted to check for updates, Apache started choking on me, specifically with problems in the php4ts.dll.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s one download file, but it looks like they do state what files have been changed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
MyBB has a nice administrative interface, but the default layout doesn&amp;#39;t really get me excited. That&amp;#39;s all I&amp;#39;ll say, until we&amp;#39;ve got the last two forums installed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 3: Simple Machines</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-3-Simple-Machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-3-Simple-Machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Curiously, in late-September 2006, &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplemachines.org/&#34;&gt;Simple Machines Forum&lt;/a&gt; turned three (it had been three years since 1.0 beta 1). That&amp;#39;s curious because the current stable version of Simple Machines is 1.0.9, and there&amp;#39;s a 1.1 RC3 out as well (as of late-October 2006).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In this article, we&amp;#39;ll be installing Simple Machines version 1.0.9, so we can compare it to the other PHP forums that we&amp;#39;ve installed, or will be installing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The zip file for Vanilla 1.0.1 weighs in at just over 1.1 MB. Wow. Of the six forums we review, this is the largest. However, this is for the full install. There&amp;#39;s also update and upgrade versions, as well as two other compressed formats (tar.gz and tar.bz2). Unzipped, we&amp;#39;re looking at just over 3 MB of file.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Simple Machines requires PHP 4.1.0+ and MySQL 3.23.28+. Compared to the other forums we&amp;#39;ll be going over, these requirements are pretty low (especially the MySQL requirement). There are a number of PHP settings that must be turned on or off, for Simple Machines to function. Bossy, aren&amp;#39;t they? If you&amp;#39;ve followed along, our server will have all of these options set as they require.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&amp;#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&amp;#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&amp;#39;re installing it locally as well).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run &amp;hellip; and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&amp;#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     mysql -h localhost -u root -p
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&amp;#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing Simple Machines, we&amp;#39;ll create a database called SimpleMachines.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     create database SimpleMachines;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, we&amp;#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;simplemachines&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39; to something different (as this is the user&amp;#39;s password).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&lt;br /&gt;
    ON &lt;strong&gt;SimpleMachines&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    TO &lt;strong&gt;SimpleMachines&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;simplemachines&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;SimpleMachines&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;SimpleMachines&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;simplemachines&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, we&amp;#39;re also giving a password to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the query is OK, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD&lt;em&gt;PASSWORD(&amp;#39;simplemachines&amp;#39;) WHERE User = &amp;#39;SimpleMachines&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the SimpleMachines user. Once you&amp;#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     show databases;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&amp;#39;s a database of simplemachines. Yippee.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, let&amp;#39;s install Simple Machines.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing Simple Machines&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, unzip the downloaded zip file. The files are not within a directory in the zip file, so make sure you create a folder to dump these into. I&amp;#39;ll be using one called SimpleMachines.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing locally, we don&amp;#39;t have to worry about permissions. So, once Simple Machines has been decompressed, navigate to the Simple Machines root folder in your browser. Since you haven&amp;#39;t setup Simple Machines yet, it will redirect you to the installer, which is located at, in my install, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/simplemachines/install.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/simplemachines/install.php&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;ll be prompted for Basic and MySQL Server settings. I left the Basic Settings as they were. MySQL Server Settings have been started, we just need to confirm and finish them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    MySQL server name: localhost&lt;br /&gt;
    MySQL username: SimpleMachines&lt;br /&gt;
    MySQL password: simplemachines&lt;br /&gt;
    MySQL database name: SimpleMachines&lt;br /&gt;
    MySQL table prefix: smf&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once you proceed, you should now be able to create your account. As before, I used the same username and password as I used in the previous forum installs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Your username: admin&lt;br /&gt;
    Password: cbe15b&lt;br /&gt;
    Password: cbe15b&lt;br /&gt;
    Email Address: strivinglife@gmail.com
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;ll also need to enter in the MySQL database password, which is the same as you used before (simplemachines in my case). With that, finish up. You should be told that the installation process is complete, and you can now delete the install file (possibly using the installer). You&amp;#39;ll be automatically logged in. If install.php still exists, you&amp;#39;ll be told so.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How&amp;#39;s the code look?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, Simple Machines is very table heavy. Combined with the fact that they don&amp;#39;t have summaries, the code isn&amp;#39;t the cleanest. In addition, links use ids that start with numbers, which is not that good of a thing.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Inside, the code looks pretty darn good.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once installed, Simple Machines setups up one category and one topic (with one post). That&amp;#39;s nice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, the look is very, very, boxy. Some people like this, but I like things that flow a little more. There is another theme installed by default, which looks much better.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Checking for updates is quite easy from the interface. From the looks of it, upgrading is just as easy, since there&amp;#39;s a separate file. Wow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve used Simple Machines before on Fractovia. I don&amp;#39;t really care for it, since it feels and looks clunky. On the bright side, no configuration files to manually update. Thus far, three reviews down, I&amp;#39;m siding heavily with Vanilla.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, before we dig any further, we&amp;#39;ll need to install some more forums.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 2: Vanilla</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-2-Vanilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2006 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-2-Vanilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
While the &lt;a href=&#34;http://getvanilla.com/&#34;&gt;Vanilla&lt;/a&gt; forum&amp;#39;s are fairly unknown, it&amp;#39;s been around for a little over a year. &amp;ldquo;Vanilla is an open-source, standards-compliant, multi-lingual, fully extensible discussion forum for the web.&amp;rdquo; The version we&amp;#39;ll be installing, 1.0.1, was released in late-August 2006.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The zip file for Vanilla 1.0.1 (which is the only download type) weighs in at just under 400 KB. Unzipped, it&amp;#39;s almost 1.2 MB in size. Overall, that&amp;#39;s pretty small.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Vanilla requires PHP 4.1+ and MySQL 3.23+. Compared to the other forums we&amp;#39;ll be going over, these requirements are pretty low (especially the MySQL requirement).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&amp;#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&amp;#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&amp;#39;re installing it locally as well).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run &amp;hellip; and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&amp;#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    mysql -h localhost -u root -p
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&amp;#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing Vanilla, we&amp;#39;ll create a database called Vanilla.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     create database Vanilla;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, we&amp;#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;vanilla&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39; to something different (as this is the user&amp;#39;s password).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&lt;br /&gt;
    ON &lt;strong&gt;Vanilla&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    TO &lt;strong&gt;Vanilla&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;vanilla&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;Vanilla&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;Vanilla&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;vanilla&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, we&amp;#39;re also giving a password to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the query is OK, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&amp;#39;vanilla&amp;#39;) WHERE User = &amp;#39;Vanilla&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the Vanilla user. Once you&amp;#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     show databases;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&amp;#39;s a database of vanilla. Yippee.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, let&amp;#39;s install Vanilla.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing Vanilla&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, unzip the downloaded zip file. The files are all included in a Vanilla.1.0.1 folder. For this guide, we&amp;#39;ll be keeping it in that folder, since we&amp;#39;ll be installing a number of forums, but changing the name to remove the version information.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once Vanilla has been decompressed, navigate to the Vanilla root folder in your browser. Since you haven&amp;#39;t setup Vanilla yet, it will redirect you to the installer, which is located at, in my install, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/vanilla/setup/index.html&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/vanilla/setup/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here, there&amp;#39;s a couple of options. You can either install fresh (which is what we&amp;#39;ll be doing) or find out how to upgrade from a previous version. For now, let&amp;#39;s click on the link to &amp;ldquo;install a completely brand new version of Vanilla&amp;rdquo;. These steps will walk you through the setup almost completely.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to assure that permissions have been setup correctly on files and folders. We&amp;#39;re okay in this respect, so check the permissions and continue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Next, you&amp;#39;ll need to enter in information regarding MySQL. If you&amp;#39;ve been following along, these are as follows.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
MySQL Server: localhost&lt;br /&gt;
MySQL Database Name: Vanilla&lt;br /&gt;
MySQL User: Vanilla&lt;br /&gt;
MySQL Password: vanilla
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Click on the link to continue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, you&amp;#39;ll need to create an administrative account, setup a contact email, and confirm cookie options. What follows are my options, but customize as needed. Note that for password, I simply used the password I was given for bbPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Username: admin&lt;br /&gt;
Password: cbe15b&lt;br /&gt;
Support Contact Name: James Skemp&lt;br /&gt;
Support Email Address: strivinglife@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
Forum Name: Vanilla&lt;br /&gt;
Cookie Domain: localhost&lt;br /&gt;
Cookie Path: /projects/vanilla/
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One final click, and you&amp;#39;re ready to go. You can either login, as they direct, or just take a look at the main page. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/vanilla/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/vanilla/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How&amp;#39;s the code look?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All-in-all, the code validates beautifully, and is a pleasure to read. The random code files I pulled up were extremely well documented. I&amp;#39;ve rarely seen code such as this.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Like the code, the default layout is beautiful. Simple, simple, simple. The administrative interface uses the same wrapper as the main site, so ditto for it. And, what&amp;#39;s this, no tables?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, entering into some options, you lose your left-side navigation, and there&amp;#39;s no way to go back via a link. Fortunately, this isn&amp;#39;t the case for all of the options.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No forums or topics are already setup, for better or worse. On the one hand, it makes clean-up easy, but it also means you have to do this yourself just to get a look.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Checking for updates is quite easy from the interface. Unfortunately, upgrading basically involves reinstalling Vanilla. If you&amp;#39;ve made modifications, you&amp;#39;ll need to re-add them. However, they do say that you can see what files have changed, which means you can do a compare to add in the new changes. Not too shabby.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I like Vanilla based on my first impression. Editing configuration files is no fun, especially for people who can&amp;#39;t code. Vanilla makes all of this really easy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, on the other hand, it&amp;#39;s MySQL connection step doesn&amp;#39;t provide much help to the person who doesn&amp;#39;t know any of this. Default to localhost, since that will usually be what the user needs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before we dig any further, we&amp;#39;ll need to install some more forums.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 1: bbPress</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-1-bbPress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-1-bbPress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A relative new-comer, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bbpress.org/&#34;&gt;bbPress&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;is forum software with a twist from the creators of WordPress&amp;rdquo;. The first public version, 0.72, was released in mid-October 2006, and the version we&amp;#39;ll be installing, 0.73, was released a couple of weeks later. Downloading bbPress is fairly easy, since there&amp;#39;s only two options &amp;ndash; one for the installer in .zip, and one in .tar.gz.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At 170 KB, the zip file is extremely small, and is less than 500 KB unzipped. Of the six pieces of forum software that I&amp;#39;ll be reviewing, bbPress is the smallest, but we&amp;#39;ll see what that translates into as far as functionality.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
bbPress requires PHP 4.2+ and MySQL 4.0+, as well as MultiViews or mod_rewrite. All-in-all, pretty standard.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&amp;#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&amp;#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&amp;#39;re installing it locally as well).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run &amp;hellip; and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&amp;#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     mysql -h localhost -u root -p
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&amp;#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing bbPress, we&amp;#39;ll create a database called bbPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     create database bbPress;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, we&amp;#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;bbpress&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39; to something different (as this is the user&amp;#39;s password).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&lt;br /&gt;
    ON &lt;strong&gt;bbPress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    TO &lt;strong&gt;bbPress&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;bbpress&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;bbPress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;bbPress&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;bbpress&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, we&amp;#39;re also giving a password to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the query is ok, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&amp;rsquo;bbpress&amp;rsquo;) WHERE User = &amp;lsquo;bbPress&amp;rsquo;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the bbPress user. Once you&amp;#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     show databases;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&amp;#39;s a database of bbpress. Yippee.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, let&amp;#39;s install bbPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing bbPress&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, unzip the downloaded zip file. The files are all included in a bbpress folder. For this guide, we&amp;#39;ll be keeping it in that folder, since we&amp;#39;ll be installing a number of forums. However, if you decide to go with bbPress, you may not want to keep the files in the bbPress folder.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once bbPress has been decompressed, go into the bbpress folder and make a copy of the config-sample.php file. Rename the copy to simply config.php. Next, open the file. There&amp;#39;s a lot of things to change, so get ready.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, change lines 4 to 7 (begin with &amp;#39;define&amp;#39;). Per the above, it&amp;#39;ll be something like the following.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     define(&amp;#39;BBDB_NAME&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;bbPress&amp;#39;); // The name of the database&lt;br /&gt;
    define(&amp;#39;BBDB_USER&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;bbPress&amp;#39;); // Your MySQL username&lt;br /&gt;
    define(&amp;#39;BBDB_PASSWORD&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;bbpress&amp;#39;); // &amp;hellip;and password&lt;br /&gt;
    define(&amp;#39;BBDB_HOST&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;localhost&amp;#39;); // 99% chance you won&amp;#39;t need to change this value
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Line 15 will need to be changed as well. For my installation, it was as follows.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     $bb-&amp;gt;domain = &amp;#39;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost&amp;amp;#39;&#34;&gt;http://localhost&amp;amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt;; // Example: &amp;#39;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbpress.example.com&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://bbpress.example.com&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Line 17 was changed as well. This may vary for your installation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     $bb-&amp;gt;path = &amp;#39;/projects/bbpress/&amp;#39;;                // Example: &amp;#39;/forums/&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;m going to leave the name (line 20) as is, but change line 23, the email. Make sure you change your&amp;#39;s accordingly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     $bb-&amp;gt;admin_email = &amp;#39;strivinglife@gmail.com&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Line 35 should also be changed, per your timezone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     $bb-&amp;gt;gmt_offset = 0;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We&amp;#39;ll leave everything else as is, for now. Let&amp;#39;s make sure Apache is up and running, and we&amp;#39;ll see what else we have to do. Head over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/bbpress/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/bbpress/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Click the First Step link. Enter in a couple options for the Administrator. These include Login name, Website, Location, and Interests.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;ll also need to define your First Forum by giving it a Name and a Description.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Only Login name and Forum Name are required, so I entered &amp;#39;admin&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;Test&amp;#39;, respectively. Continue to the next step.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The Second Step creates the tables (8) and gives you a password. It&amp;#39;s random, so hold on to it. In my case, it was &lt;strong&gt;cbe15b&lt;/strong&gt;. You can click on either link to go to the bbPress page, which is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/bbpress/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/bbpress/&lt;/a&gt;, in my case.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can now login to check out the Administrative interface, or you check out the topic that was created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How&amp;#39;s the code look?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Overall, the code validates pretty dang well. There&amp;#39;s a minor issue with an opening and closing small tag, with nothing between, on the main interface view, and some tables missing summaries, but other than that &amp;hellip; code looks good.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As far as the internal PHP code, like WordPress, it&amp;#39;s full. You&amp;#39;ll need to reference files and documentation, back and forth, but that&amp;#39;s to be expected, I suppose.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Upgrading and default layout&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike some of the other forums we&amp;#39;ll be looking at, there&amp;#39;s no upgrade-only installation file. Yuck. Upgrading WordPress is a beast, and it looks like that&amp;#39;s going to be an issue with bbPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Where it gets really bad is when you look at the layout. The default layout, especially for the admin interface, could absolutely be better. Unfortunately, it looks like the styles are buried in multiple files, in multiple folders.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As with WordPress, it looks like upgrading is going to be a beast (with functions dropping and being added), but even more so because there doesn&amp;#39;t appear to be a way to easily create your own styles, outside of the core files.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Administrative interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The administrative interface, other than being rather ugly, is pretty simple. Unfortunately, there&amp;#39;s no way, via the interface alone, to modify the styles or code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, I&amp;#39;m going to stop, since we&amp;#39;ll want other forums to compare before we go any further. However, you should have a bbPress, version 0.73, forum setup.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Apache 2.0.59 to a Windows-based computer, locally: Part 3</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2006 16:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 1 of this Apache 2.0.59 guide&lt;/a&gt;, we setup Apache 2.0.59 on a Windows XP SP2 machine. We also setup Perl and mod_perl, attempting to mimic our Apache 1.3.34 install. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 2 of this Apache 2.0.59 guide&lt;/a&gt;, we setup ColdFusion MX 6.1 and 7.0. This time, we&#39;ll be continuing in our quest by adding support for both PHP 4 and PHP 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous guides, we &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-PHP-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;installed PHP 4&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Dual-installing-PHP-Running-PHP-5-and-4-on-the-same-local2c-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP 5&lt;/a&gt;, so if you need to install either one, do so with the above directions. If you&#39;ll be installing PHP 4 and PHP 5 for the first time, and have not installed on Apache 1.3.x already, then you may be able to pick and choose from these guides to get the information you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we do this, however, we need to think about just what we&#39;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until this point, you may have installed any (or none) of the below. (Keep in mind that you can generalize these if you have slightly newer versions. So, PHP 5.1.4 = PHP 5.x.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache 1.3.34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache 2.0.59&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 4.4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 5.1.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ColdFusion MX 6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ColdFusion MX 7.0.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us a number of options on what our local Web server could be running at one time. For example, we could be running PHP 4, ColdFusion MX 6.1, and Apache 1.3.x or Apache 2.0.x. Likewise, we could use PHP 4 or PHP 5, or ColdFusion MX 6.1 or ColdFusion MX 7.0. Writing out a list of all of our possible combinations, we&#39;ve got something like the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF6.1_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF7.0_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF6.1_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF7.0_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF6.1_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF7.0_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF6.1_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF7.0_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we could also run our local server without the ColdFusion MX component, or PHP component at all. For ease, however, we&#39;ll just stick with one of the above possibilities. What this means is that for each of the above that you want to run, you&#39;ll need to have an httpd.conf file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed my above guides, than you should already have the Apache 1.3.x configuration files (although with slightly different names). Once we have all eight configurations, we can write batch files to automate most of the process. For getting these up and running. With one click (and maybe just a little renaming), we can have the Web server that we want up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you may have for Apache 1.3.x, I recommend you create a &#39;configuration&#39; folder in your DocumentRoot directory (so, c:\home\configuration\ if you&#39;ve been following along) where you can begin compiling httpd.conf files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I&#39;ve obviously followed by own guides, so I have four files thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should also have either one or two php.ini files &amp;ndash; one for PHP 4 and one for PHP 5 &amp;ndash; that we&#39;ll also want to put copies of in this folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP4.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP5.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache 1.3.x and Apache 2.0.x use the same php.ini files. So, it&#39;s not necessary to make one copy each for Apache 1.3.x and one each for 2.0.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This done, we can begin connecting to PHP 4 and PHP 5 on Apache 2.0.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hooking up PHP 4.4.2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous guide, we &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-PHP-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;installed PHP 4.4.2&lt;/a&gt; and in yet &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Moving-the-location-of-PHP-on-your-hard-drive.aspx&#34;&gt;a later guide moved our installation&lt;/a&gt; to the c:\php4\ folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;ve already got PHP 4 working on Apache 1.3.x, most of our setup is already complete. Now it&#39;s just a matter of hooking up Apache 2.0.x to recognize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we&#39;ll need to make sure we&#39;ve got a backup of the httpd.conf file in the C:\Program Files\Apache Group\Apache2\conf folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now open the Apache 2 httpd.conf file. Do a search for LoadModule, and at the end of this section, add the following line. Keep in mind that if you installed PHP 4 to a different folder, you should make that change here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LoadModule php4_module &#34;c:/php4/php4apache2.dll&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, do a search for AddType. After the first uncommented line (AddType application/x-gzip .gz .tgz), place the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AddType application/x-httpd-php .php&lt;br /&gt;AddType application/x-httpd-php-source .phps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, add &#39;index.php&#39; to the DirectoryIndex line, where ever you&#39;d like it be called in the order of things. Depending upon preference, you may also want to add index.htm, since Apache 2.0.x doesn&#39;t seem to want to include these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save httpd.conf. Now go to the c:\php4\ directory (or where you installed PHP 4) and copy the php4apache2.dll from the sapi folder into the root PHP folder. So, from c:\php4\sapi\ to c:\php4\.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For php.ini, everything should be setup correctly. However, you&#39;ll want to verify that the right php.ini file is in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now start Apache2 from the Services panel (or the Apache Services Monitor) and you should find that the description lists PHP 4. If you go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/phpinfo.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/phpinfo.php&lt;/a&gt; (if you created this file), you should also find that PHP is up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure both your ColdFusion MX 6.1 and ColdFusion MX 7.0 httpd.conf files have the httpd.conf changes made, and you can switch between either version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Connecting to PHP 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you&#39;ve already setup PHP 4 for Apache 2.0.x, using the instructions above, moving to PHP 5 is extremely easy. So easy, in fact, that it&#39;s scary. Make a copy of any httpd.conf files you may have for PHP 4. For example, the two I have in C:\Program Files\Apache Group\Apache2\conf\ are called httpd_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf and httpd_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll copy both of these and rename them to httpd_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf and httpd_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf. That done open both up and do a search for php4, one file at a time. You&#39;ll find php4 three times, in the following line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LoadModule php4_module &#34;c:/php4/php4apache2.dll&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which you&#39;ll simply change to three &#39;5&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LoadModule php5_module &#34;c:/php5/php5apache2.dll&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now save the httpd.conf files. The php5apache2.dll file will already be in this location, so you should be set to go. Make a copy of either one of these, make sure that you&#39;re using the right php.ini file, restart Apache2, and verify that phpinfo() gives the correct information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&#39;t that easy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Now that PHP 4 and/or PHP 5 are installed ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&#39;ve setup PHP 4 and/or PHP 5 with Apache 2.0.x, it&#39;s time to backup the necessary .conf files into our &#39;configuration&#39; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll have up to ten files in this folder (c:\home\configuration\). Up to eight .conf files and up to two .ini files. I&#39;ve listed all ten possibilities below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP4.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP5.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s create a blank text file called zblank.txt. Next, we should determine whether we want to have a version that does not run ColdFusion MX. If you want to, read the next section. Otherwise, skip the next section and read the following one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Removing ColdFusion MX from our configurations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove ColdFusion MX, you&#39;ll need four more httpd.conf files. Two for Apache 1.3.x and two for Apache 2.0.x, as each has two versions of PHP. Since it doesn&#39;t matter which one we take from, just copy the four httpd.conf files that reference CFMX6.1 in their file names.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, simply remove the &#39;Copy of &#39; and &#39;CFMX&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;&#39; from the four file names. You&#39;ll end up with the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_PHP4.conf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_PHP5.conf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_PHP4.conf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s just a couple of things to remove from each of these conf files. The following block will need to be removed from the Apache 1.3.x files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# JRun Settings&lt;br /&gt;LoadModule jrun_module &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/1/mod_jrun.so&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;IfModule mod_jrun.c&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Verbose false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Apialloc false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ssl false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ignoresuffixmap false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Serverstore &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/1/jrunserver.store&#34;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Bootstrap 127.0.0.1:51010&lt;br /&gt;#JRunConfig Errorurl &amp;lt;optionally redirect to this URL on errors&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;AddHandler jrun-handler .jsp .jws .cfm .cfml .cfc&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this block will need to be removed from the Apache 2.0.x files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# JRun Settings&lt;br /&gt;LoadModule jrun_module &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/2/mod_jrun20.so&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;IfModule mod_jrun20.c&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Verbose false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Apialloc false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ssl false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ignoresuffixmap false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Serverstore &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/2/jrunserver.store&#34;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Bootstrap 127.0.0.1:51010&lt;br /&gt;#JRunConfig Errorurl &amp;lt;optionally redirect to this URL on errors&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;AddHandler jrun-handler .jsp .jws .cfm .cfml .cfc&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure &#39;index.cfm index.cfml&#39; is removed from the DirectoryIndex lines in each file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By allowing our Apache 2.0.x server, and Apache 1.3.x server, to run without checking for ColdFusion MX, we can keep it running quick, even if we decide not to start any versions of ColdFusion MX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we have left is hooking up MySQL and PostgreSQL and creating batch files to use these httpd.conf and php.ini files to get the server we want up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let the hardest part begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Connecting to MySQL and PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazingly enough, as long as you already setup MySQL and PostgreSQL for Apache 1.3.x, you&#39;re all set to begin using MySQL and PostgreSQL for both ColdFusion MX 6.1, ColdFusion MX 7.0, PHP 4, and PHP 5. This is because ColdFusion MX is handling the SQL requests via the datasources, and PHP is likewise handling it&#39;s own requests (via the php.ini file).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to test this using the PHP files I detailed before (&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-MySQL-and-phpMyAdmin-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;check MySQL connection in PHP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-PostgreSQL-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;check PostgreSQL connection in PHP&lt;/a&gt;) or just using the ColdFusion MX Administrator to check all datasources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coming in Part 4 ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Part 4, I&#39;ll be going over how to create the batch files that we&#39;ll need to work with the httpd.conf and php.ini files that we&#39;ve created. While I could detail it here, better to just put it in it&#39;s own article/post, as that makes things much easier (if not for you, then at least for me ;)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing MySQL Query Browser 1.1.20 on a local Windows-based, Apache, server</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Installing-MySQL-Query-Browser-1120-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 20:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Installing-MySQL-Query-Browser-1120-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In a previous guide, we installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/?p=53&#34;&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/?p=55&#34;&gt;MySQL Administrator&lt;/a&gt;. In this guide, we&amp;#39;ll be installing the MySQL Query Browser, version 1.1.20.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
First, we&amp;#39;ll need to download a copy of the latest version from &lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/query-browser/&#34;&gt;http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/query-browser/&lt;/a&gt; At the time of this writing, that is version 1.1.20. The Windows, x86, version is just over 5 MB, for a MSI file. Once the file has downloaded, open it.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When you&amp;#39;re presented with the license agreement, read through it and accept to continue. You may as well keep the installation path as the default of C:\Program Files\MySQL\MySQL Query Browser 1.1\, unless you&amp;#39;ve installed the Administrator tool to a different location.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For Setup Type, select either Complete or Custom. There&amp;#39;s only one option, so there&amp;#39;s not a real big difference. I&amp;#39;ll select Custom. The Browser will take a little over 10 MB of space, once installed; certainly not a big deal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, press Install, followed by Finish, once the installation is done; it won&amp;#39;t take long.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you may want to create a shortcut to the Browser, in your /home/ directory, as you may have done for the Administrator tool. Another alternative is to create a shortcut to the MySQL System Tray Monitor, which will allow you to launch either of the two tools from the tray.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve done this, or not, start MySQL Query Browser. You can find it either in the installation directory, or in the Start menu, under MySQL. When you start Query Browser up, you&amp;rsquo;ll be asked to supply some information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Server Host: localhost&lt;br /&gt;
Username: root&lt;br /&gt;
Password: (your password)&lt;br /&gt;
Default Schema: (leave blank)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;ll be warned that you should choose a default schema, but let&amp;#39;s just Ignore that for the moment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since you haven&amp;#39;t selected a default schema, you&amp;#39;ll have to select a schema from the schemata area. Double click on any of the available schemata. Once you do this, the schema will be bold.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now that you&amp;#39;ve selected a schema, you can run a query on the tables to produce some results. If you haven&amp;#39;t already used tables, we can quickly create, and then delete, a table to show how this works.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The following query will create a test table.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS TestDatabase (&lt;br /&gt;
    TestColumn1 varchar(100) default &amp;#39;&amp;#39;,&lt;br /&gt;
    TestColumn2 int(10) NOT NULL auto_increment,&lt;br /&gt;
    PRIMARY KEY (TestColumn2)&lt;br /&gt;
    )
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Enter this code, and press Execute. In the bottom left corner, you&amp;#39;ll see that your query returned no results. In addition, it doesn&amp;#39;t look like the database had a table added to it. Right click on the database you&amp;#39;ve selected, and select Refresh. Your test table will now display.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can now run a select on the table, which won&amp;#39;t display any rows, but will display the column names.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, we&amp;#39;ll remove the table by running the following query.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    DROP TABLE TestDatabase
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While no results will be returned, the query will run, and a refresh on the database will show that the table no longer exists.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And with that, you&amp;#39;ve got a new way to run queries on your tables, without creating an application file in PHP or ColdFusion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/a-local-apache-web-server-on-a-windows-xp-computer/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading phpMyAdmin (2.7.0-pl2 to 2.8.1) on a local, Windows-based, Apache server</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Upgrading-phpMyAdmin-%28270-pl2-to-281%29-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2006 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Upgrading-phpMyAdmin-%28270-pl2-to-281%29-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In a &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/?p=53&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we installed phpMyAdmin 2.7.0-pl2 to our local Web server. We did this so that we would have an easy way to administer our MySQL databases, from a PHP-based interface. This time, we&amp;#39;ll be upgrading phpMyAdmin to version 2.8.1.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Downloading and unzipping&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, we&amp;#39;ll need to grab the download for phpMyAdmin, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phpmyadmin.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.phpmyadmin.net/&lt;/a&gt;. As of this writing, the current version is 2.8.1. The zip file runs about 3.5 MB.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once the download has finished, we can unzip the file into our main Web directory (C:\home). Depending upon how you installed the previous version of phpMyAdmin, you can either keep this new version in a folder containing the version number, or not. For example: c:\home\phpMyAdmin-2.8.1\ or c:\home\phpMyAdmin\ If you&amp;#39;ll be doing things the latter way, make sure you make a backup of your previously installed phpMyAdmin directory - just in case. If you&amp;#39;ll be saving to a directory containing the version information, then there&amp;#39;s no real reason to remove the old directory (unless you&amp;#39;re concerned with space).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Configuring phpMyAdmin&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point you can go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/phpmyadmin-2.8.1/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/phpmyadmin-2.8.1/&lt;/a&gt; However, if you do so, you&amp;#39;ll notice that you&amp;#39;re unable to view the interface due to an error. As with our initial install, we need to configure phpMyAdmin before we can start using it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Browse to the directory containing your previous installation of phpMyAdmin (for example, C:\home\phpMyAdmin-2.7.0-pl2) and copy the file config.inc.php. Now, make a copy of this file in your upgraded phpMyAdmin&amp;#39;s directory - C:\home\phpMyAdmin-2.8.1\config.inc.php, for example.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Open this file and verify that $cfg&lt;a href=&#34;on line 31&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;PmaAbsoluteUri&amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt; is correct. If you&amp;#39;ve switched from one directory scheme to another (with version number to without, or vice versa), then this may not be correct.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should now be able to refresh, or visit, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/phpmyadmin-2.8.1/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/phpmyadmin-2.8.1/&lt;/a&gt; and log in, using one of the MySQL user names and passwords you&amp;#39;ve setup.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, if you setup a subdomain in your httpd.conf file (C:\Program Files\Apache Group\Apache\conf), you can modify the subdomain so that it points to the correct path. If you make this change, make sure you restart Apache afterwards.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And with that, you&amp;#39;ve successfully updated phpMyAdmin. Really, a pretty easy upgrade.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/a-local-apache-web-server-on-a-windows-xp-computer/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WP-ShortStat SQL queries</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/WP-ShortStat-SQL-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 20:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/WP-ShortStat-SQL-queries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.happyarts.de/wp-shortstat/&#34;&gt;wp-shortstat plugin&lt;/a&gt;, modified for WordPress 2.x use by Markus Kaemmerer, is a great little plugin.  I&amp;#39;ve been using it since March 17, and since Markus has been doing a deal of updating (additional functionality, as well as bug fixes), I&amp;#39;ve been checking it on a regular basis (and have looked through the code more than once).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, since I started out by using 1.3, I&amp;#39;ve got a problem with old records skewing my stats.  To remedy that, I&amp;#39;ve written a couple of SQL queries, for use in phpMyAdmin, for example.  Before I release them to the wild, I wanted to see if I can get a smaller audience to try them out.  I&amp;#39;ve tried them out on my own stats, but &amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If someone wants to create a PHP page that does these, certainly go for it - just share the souce code.  There&amp;#39;s also a way to update more than one row at a time, but, I&amp;#39;d much rather do things one row at a time, just in case.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you run these queries, please backup your database, or this table, before you run these queries.  Note that the &amp;#39;standard&amp;#39; table name is wp_ss_stats.  If your&amp;#39;s is named differently, you may have to change these queries accordingly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET version = &amp;#39;2.1&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;Googlebot/2.1 (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/bot.html)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/bot.html)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND version = &amp;#39;Indeterminable&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET version = &amp;#39;2.1&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;Mozilla/5.0 (compatible; Googlebot/2.1; +&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/bot.html)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/bot.html)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND version = &amp;#39;Indeterminable&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET version = &amp;#39;0.9&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;msnbot/0.9 (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND version = &amp;#39;Indeterminable&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET browser = &amp;#39;msnbot&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;msnbot/0.9 (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND browser = &amp;#39;Crawler/Search Engine&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET version = &amp;#39;1.0&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;msnbot/1.0 (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND version = &amp;#39;Indeterminable&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET browser = &amp;#39;msnbot&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;msnbot/1.0 (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://search.msn.com/msnbot.htm)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND browser = &amp;#39;Crawler/Search Engine&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET version = &amp;#39;2.1&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;Mediapartners-Google/2.1&amp;#39; AND version = &amp;#39;Indeterminable&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET browser = &amp;#39;Feedfetcher-Google&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;Feedfetcher-Google; (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/feedfetcher.html)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/feedfetcher.html)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND browser = &amp;#39;Indeterminable&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE &amp;#39;wp_ss_stats&amp;#39; SET browser = &amp;#39;Feedfetcher-Google&amp;#39; WHERE user_agent = &amp;#39;Feedfetcher-Google; (+&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/feedfetcher.html)&amp;amp;#39&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/feedfetcher.html)&amp;amp;#39&lt;/a&gt;; AND browser = &amp;#39;Crawler/Search Engine&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE wp_ss_stats SET browser = &amp;#39;Yahoo-Blogs&amp;#39; WHERE version = &amp;#39;5.5&amp;#39; AND user_agent = &amp;#39;Yahoo-Blogs/v3.9 (compatible; Mozilla 4.0; MSIE 5.5; &lt;a href=&#34;http://help.yahoo.com/help/us/ysearch/crawling/crawling-02.html&#34;&gt;http://help.yahoo.com/help/us/ysearch/crawling/crawling-02.html&lt;/a&gt; )&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    UPDATE wp_ss_stats SET version = &amp;#39;3.9&amp;#39; WHERE version = &amp;#39;5.5&amp;#39; AND user_agent = &amp;#39;Yahoo-Blogs/v3.9 (compatible; Mozilla 4.0; MSIE 5.5; &lt;a href=&#34;http://help.yahoo.com/help/us/ysearch/crawling/crawling-02.html&#34;&gt;http://help.yahoo.com/help/us/ysearch/crawling/crawling-02.html&lt;/a&gt; )&amp;#39;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;downloads&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Download these queries in txt format: &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/files/2006/04/mysql%20sql%20queries%20for%20wp_ss_stats.txt&#34;&gt;WP-ShortStat SQL queries&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Want more added?  Let me know.  I&amp;#39;d like to do Googlebot and Yahoo! Slurp, among others, but I&amp;#39;m waiting for Markus to support them in his plugin.  I figure once he thinks I&amp;#39;m done pestering him, I&amp;#39;ll send him the code and a request ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Remember, running a SELECT query first is your best bet if you&amp;#39;re unsure of what you may be updating.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    SELECT * FROM wp_ss_stats WHERE version = &amp;#39;2.1&amp;#39; AND browser = &amp;#39;Crawler/Search Engine&amp;#39;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding MySQL connectivity to ColdFusion MX on a local Windows-based, Apache, server</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Adding-MySQL-connectivity-to-ColdFusion-MX-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2006 08:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Adding-MySQL-connectivity-to-ColdFusion-MX-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Until now, we&#39;ve yet to setup a connection to MySQL from ColdFusion MX. This has meant that while we can do cool database things in PHP (like WordPress), we can&#39;t in ColdFusion. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, we&#39;ll be setting up MySQL 4.1.18 and ColdFusion MX 6.1 on our local server. Because of some of the choices that we&#39;ve made before, this installation is going to be fairly quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting up MySQL database and user&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we&#39;ll need to setup a MySQL database and user for ColdFusion. So, start MySQL Administrator and create a new catalog called COLDFUSIONMX. While MySQL Administrator will down-cap the name, we&#39;ll enter it in all-caps, just because.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup a new MySQL User ColdFusionMX, and add the localhost domain, and assign all privileges to the COLDFUSIONMX schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, close out of MySQL Administrator, and go to the command line (Window + R, and cmd) and type the following, as we&#39;ve done before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;mysql -u root -p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press enter, and type in the root password. Finally, we&#39;ll change the password for ColdFusionMX for all hosts. Password should be 16 characters or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&#39;your_password&#39;) WHERE User = &#39;ColdFusionMX&#39;;&lt;br /&gt;FLUSH PRIVILEGES;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exit out of this and the command line (&#34;exit&#34;, enter, &#34;exit&#34;, enter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting up in ColdFusion MX Administrator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&#39;ve setup our database and user in MySQL, we&#39;ll need to setup the datasource in ColdFusion MX. If ColdFusion isn&#39;t already started, start ColdFusion via Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log in to ColdFusion MX Administrator (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/CFIDE/administrator/index.cfm&#34;&gt;http://localhost/CFIDE/administrator/index.cfm&lt;/a&gt; if you&#39;ve been following along), and select Data Sources under DATA &amp;amp; SERVICES on the left side navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the Data Source name of MySQLDatabase, and select MySQL under Driver. Hit Add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the resulting screen, enter the following information. Make sure you enter in your_password the password you used above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database: COLDFUSIONMX&lt;br /&gt;Server: localhost, leave Port to 3306&lt;br /&gt;Username: ColdFusionMX&lt;br /&gt;Password: your_password&lt;br /&gt;Description: MySQL database for ColdFusion MX 6.1. (or whatever you want to type)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hit Submit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Verify All Connections. This will test the three Access databases (if you set up the samples for ColdFusionMX) as well as your new MySQL database. You should get a Status of OK after doing this (and you may get an OK after initially setting up the database).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we continue, note that we can only connect to MySQL this easily because of the OLD_PASSWORD function we do on our password. Since we&#39;ve been doing this all along, it&#39;s the easiest solution. The other solution is to update some files, which we won&#39;t go into since we don&#39;t have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a test table in MySQL with ColdFusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we&#39;ll be creating a ColdFusion file to test our connection to MySQL via ColdFusion. Copy and paste the following text into a new file in Notepad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;coldfusion&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;cfquery name=&#34;CreateNewDatabase&#34; datasource=&#34;MySQLDatabase&#34;&amp;gt;
    CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS TestDatabase (
        TestColumn1 varchar(100) default &#39;&#39;,
        TestColumn2 int(10) NOT NULL auto_increment,
        PRIMARY KEY (TestColumn2)
    )
&amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;cfoutput&amp;gt;If you see this, the table has been created&amp;lt;/cfoutput&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this to c:\home\coldfusionmx6_1\CreateMySQLTable.cfm. Hit this page (&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/coldfusionmx6_1/CreateMySQLTable.cfm&#34;&gt;http://localhost/coldfusionmx6_1/CreateMySQLTable.cfm&lt;/a&gt;), and you should see a message saying &#34;If you see this, the table has been created&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now log in to MySQL Adminstrator, click on Catalogs, and then on coldfusionmx schemata and you should see your table, with 0 rows and about 16 kB of data length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit this page again (refresh), you&#39;ll notice that you still get the same message, and the table doesn&#39;t increase in size, and you don&#39;t get another table called TestDatabase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dropping (removing) our test table in MySQL with ColdFusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we&#39;ll quickly go over deleting, or dropping, TestDatabase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new CFM file, or add the following to the bottom of the existing CFM file, and save the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;coldfusion&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;cfquery name=&#34;DropNewDatabase&#34; datasource=&#34;MySQLDatabase&#34;&amp;gt;
    DROP TABLE IF EXISTS TestDatabase
&amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;cfoutput&amp;gt;If you see this, the table has been dropped&amp;lt;/cfoutput&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you now run the new file, or the old file with this addition, you&#39;ll see a run-on sentence saying that the table has been created, and has been dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you move into MySQL Administrator, you&#39;ll notice that the table has now disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations &amp;ndash; you&#39;ve now setup ColdFusion MX 6.1 to work with MySQL. In a future tutorial, we&#39;ll go over setting up PostgreSQL to connect with ColdFusion MX 6.1, and in another tutorial, how to create a form in ColdFusion that will use MySQL data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we leave, note that the table we&#39;ve setup could also be used by PHP, if we wanted. Additionally, any of the previous tables we&#39;ve setup in PHP could be accessed by ColdFusion, if we enter them as a data source in ColdFusion Administrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/a-local-apache-web-server-on-a-windows-xp-computer/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>