<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blade Runner on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/blade-runner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blade Runner on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 20:26:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/blade-runner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Brian J. Robb&#39;s Counterfeit Worlds</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-Brian-J-Robbs-Counterfeit-Worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 20:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-Brian-J-Robbs-Counterfeit-Worlds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is the review that I wrote for Amazon.com for the book &lt;cite&gt;Counterfeit Worlds&lt;/cite&gt; by Brian J. Robb.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The book can be purchased online at Amazon.com: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1840239689?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=strivinglifen-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1840239689&#34;&gt;Counterfeit Worlds: Philip K. Dick on Film&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First off, I haven&amp;#39;t read too many books on films based upon the works of PKD. I bought this book because I&amp;#39;m a fan of Dick&amp;#39;s works, and the films that are closely linked to it (A Scanner Darkly primarily, but before that film came out, Blade Runner - the rest, to me, are like Vanilla Sky, and the Matrix; movies &amp;#39;using&amp;#39; Dick&amp;#39;s ideas).&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Secondly, I found this to be a very good overview of not only the films that were based on PKD&amp;#39;s works (Blade Runner, Total Recall, Screamers, Confessions d&amp;#39;un Barjo, Impostor, Minority Report, Paycheck, and A Scanner Darkly), but also his life (~32 pages), radio and TV adaptations, and upcoming/unmade projects (film and otherwise).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should read this book if;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
a) You&amp;#39;re interested in reading about PKD&amp;#39;s life,&lt;br /&gt;
b) You&amp;#39;re interested in reading about how some of his films ended up being made (those listed above),&lt;br /&gt;
c) You&amp;#39;re interested in reading about the influence that PKD&amp;#39;s works had on the realm of film in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You shouldn&amp;#39;t read this book if you want to find out more about the radio/tv programs based upon his works, since you won&amp;#39;t get too much from this book on these (not that you necessarily should).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you&amp;#39;re just interested in finding out more about Blade Runner, you&amp;#39;d probably be safe purchasing this book for that reason alone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s lots of pictures, the type is rather normal (small-ish, in a good way), and there&amp;#39;s some new content in this book - not just the author&amp;#39;s perspectives, but also new interviews, albeit only snippets from these - so you&amp;#39;ll certainly get your money&amp;#39;s worth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
4 stars because I didn&amp;#39;t &amp;#39;love it&amp;#39; - I thought it was very good, and I may end up looking at particular parts over again (and it got me to dust off my copy of Impostor for another viewing), but there&amp;#39;s no real reason to re-read the book, in my opinion.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>