<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/categories/political/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 21:08:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/categories/political/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve never understood about Conservatives</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-Ive-never-understood-about-Conservatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 21:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-Ive-never-understood-about-Conservatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never understood how conservatives can be anti-government, but also be for government intervention in regards to abortion, prostitution, gay/lesbian marriage/civil unions, video and movie ratings, marijuana, and etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course liberals aren&#39;t necessarily pushing hard for some of these, but see a benefit to government that doesn&#39;t include making the above illegal (and enforcing those laws) and building up the miltary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&#39;s the fact that some people are for legalizing and then taxing some of those items, and they&#39;re anti-new taxes?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countries that come to mind ...</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Countries-that-come-to-mind-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 23:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Countries-that-come-to-mind-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
When I think of Europe I think of the U.K., France, then Germany. What about Spain though?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Moving east, Japan and China, followed by North Korea. I realize that India should be on the list, but it&amp;#39;s not one that immediately comes to mind.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Africa, as a whole, is not on the list; only bad things come to mind (AIDs and spammers/scammers).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Same with Israel; isn&amp;#39;t it bad that&amp;nbsp;I think not of religiousness, but rather of constant war?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Is the above because of the media?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Obama have a personal blog?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Should-Obama-have-a-personal-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2009 08:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Should-Obama-have-a-personal-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I work at the State Bar of Wisconsin, the membership of which elects a president every year. (Technically they elect a president-elect, but that&amp;#39;s moot.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One of the things my co-workers and I (&lt;a href=&#34;http://rmlumley.com/&#34;&gt;Rob&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrrofl.com/&#34;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt;) bounced off each other was a blog for the president-elect, for the three years they serve (president-elect, president, and outgoing (?)).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With the Obama administration, I wonder if the time of weekly addresses is out, and the time of a more timely blog is in. (Obviously, had Palin been elected, this wouldn&amp;#39;t even be an issue, which is pretty scary.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not only could this serve as a more personal look into the White House, but also into our President.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Granted, he has a number of other &amp;#39;Web 2.0&amp;#39;/social networking outlets, but these aren&amp;#39;t directly run by Obama. And of course, a blog probably wouldn&amp;#39;t be him directly filling it in either, but ... he may at least generate the ideas and feelings behind it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Could it be possible? Looking ahead, when would we see another who actually stands a chance of being the first?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you assume I&#39;m a liberal because I wear Grateful Dead shirts?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Do-you-assume-Im-a-liberal-because-I-wear-Grateful-Dead-shirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 08:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Do-you-assume-Im-a-liberal-because-I-wear-Grateful-Dead-shirts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I ran into a co-worker who suggested that&amp;nbsp;I probably held a certain environmental view,&amp;nbsp;because I was wearing a Grateful Dead shirt. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I knew it to be true, I&amp;#39;d never really thought that my political views too may be out there based upon the band t-shirt that I was wearing. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wearing Grateful Dead? Liberal. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wearing Bruce Springsteen? Liberal. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wearing Fleetwood Mac? Liberal. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Billy Joel? That&amp;#39;s probably liberal as well. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My co-worker Rob (looks like his domain expired)&amp;nbsp;was wearing a OS X shirt. Liberal? Conservative? I know it&amp;#39;s the former, but it raised the question (in my mind), would a conservative ever wear that shirt? Would they ever wear one of my shirts? 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Do I like the Grateful Dead because I&amp;#39;m a liberal, or am I a liberal because I like the Grateful Dead? How about technology? 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hmm ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Obama</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/President-Obama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 23:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/President-Obama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
About 10 minutes ago Fox, CNN, NBC, and ABC showed Obama winning the election.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After 2 disappointments ... it&amp;#39;s hard to feel absolutely confident until there&amp;#39;s 100% reporting, but I&amp;#39;m feeling pretty dang happy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
:D
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey says: Top way to spend your unexpected day off</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Survey-says-Top-way-to-spend-your-unexpected-day-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 19:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Survey-says-Top-way-to-spend-your-unexpected-day-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(Tongue firmly between&amp;nbsp;teeth.)&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In today&amp;#39;s world, what do you think the best way is to spend a day off? 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Survey says:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
... Working at your second job. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The rich get richer, the poor get poorer, and the middle does just a little worse ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment re: Go MIT!</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Comment-re-Go-MIT/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 08:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Comment-re-Go-MIT/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I couldn&amp;#39;t post this without creating an account, so &amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is in regards to &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://talkback.zdnet.com/5208-12355-0.html?forumID=1&amp;amp;threadID=50728&amp;amp;messageID=952822&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://education.zdnet.com/?p=1803&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full post&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    I agree with montysimmons - the attack on George Washington was uncalled for.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    However, he makes an interesting point that they&amp;#39;ve been able to make the technology easy enough for someone from the 18th Century to understand and use.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    This is in fact better than saying &amp;quot;easy enough for a child to use,&amp;quot; which may have been better, since even children use computers these days.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    So, it wasn&amp;#39;t really an attack on anything, was it &amp;hellip;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    (Of course, the fact that most politicians don&amp;#39;t deal with &amp;#39;normal&amp;#39; activities, such as Hillary Clinton pumping gas, suggests that even Obama and McCain might have trouble with Boston&amp;#39;s system. Maybe Christopher was pointing out that these systems should be easy for people to use, even if they&amp;#39;ve never used one before. But no, he probably wrote this just to be political.)
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if gas cost $10 a gallon?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-if-gas-cost-10-dollars-a-gallon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 19:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-if-gas-cost-10-dollars-a-gallon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Shirley Skeel wrote an interesting article on MSN Money titled &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://articles.moneycentral.msn.com/SavingandDebt/SaveonaCar/WhatIfGasCost10DollarsAGallon.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What if gas cost $10 a gallon?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All-in-all, pretty interesting article. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don&amp;#39;t know about anyone else, but I&amp;#39;ve been doing what I can to save money (ignoring the fact that I bought another monitor the other day), including using more energy efficient light bulbs in &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of my sockets. But I wish &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/vehicle_gas.xml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my gas mileage&lt;/a&gt; was&amp;nbsp;a bit better ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, what do you think? And where are more solar-powered alternatives for the average consumer? I&amp;#39;d love to have affordable solar panels that I could use to recharge or power devices, even if they only helped to offset the plug in the wall ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we elect judges?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Why-do-we-elect-judges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 20:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Why-do-we-elect-judges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is the second Supreme Court judicial campaign that I&amp;#39;ve been aware of. However, the question is, why do Wisconsin citizens even vote for judges? 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If judges can&amp;#39;t tell us how they would vote, why not just let them be elected by their own kind (whether that be judges or lawyers)? 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romney: A vote for a democrat president aids a surrender to terror</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Romney-A-vote-for-a-democrat-president-is-aids-a-surrender-to-terror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 13:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Romney-A-vote-for-a-democrat-president-is-aids-a-surrender-to-terror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Special edition over my lunch break ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It seems Mitt Romney, former presidential hopeful, has withdrawn from the race. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/uselections08/mittromney/story/0,,2254242,00.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guardian Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; quotes him as such: 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;quot;In this time of war I simply cannot let my campaign be a part of aiding a surrender to terror,&amp;quot; he told the Conservative Political Action Committee 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As with the 2004 race, once again a Republican is stating that a Democrat president would result in the United States surrendering to terror (sadly, it doesn&amp;#39;t look like that piece was moved over to the site, but I&amp;#39;ll see if I can&amp;#39;t dig it up and re-post it tonight). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I suppose the lesson learned by a NY-hopeful hasn&amp;#39;t fully reached the entire party yet (although said NY hopeful was pretty delusion to think 9/11 and campaigning in a couple of states would honestly win him much in the way of votes).&amp;nbsp; 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Daily Show is now available online</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Daily-Show-is-now-available-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2007 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Daily-Show-is-now-available-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
One of the view things I miss about cable is The Daily Show. Thankfully, I can now get my fix, as well as catch up on older shows, online, legally. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The archives are available from the Show&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailyshow.com/video/index.jhtml&#34;&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt; area. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Among the gems is this one on the recent healthcare veto: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedailyshow.com/video/index.jhtml?videoId=109136&amp;amp;title=headlines-kids-healthcare-veto&#34;&gt;Headlines - Kids&amp;#39; Healthcare Veto&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The short commercial at the beginning and end are fairly non-obtrusive, save when they cut into the end abruptly. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
More shows/stations should do this, especially when they have such a popular show. After all, the more people talk about a show, the more likely the show is to gain even more popularity. And, if I can watch clips on the show or station site, they have more control over what I&amp;#39;m shown, instead of one of the many sites out there were videos can be hosted. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I do like what Cartoon Network does with their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adultswim.com/video/index.html&#34;&gt;Adult Swim&lt;/a&gt; videos, however, so I definitely think they could borrow from that site as far as switching from one video to another. While The Daily Show is much more about the individual clips, you would think there would be a way to move throughout the show, or watch one segment after the other (with an ad thrown in every once in a while to make things even). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In short, it needs some work to be as good a user-interface as elsewhere, but it&amp;#39;s an excellent start, and a very good idea. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interesting monologue overheard - July 8, 2007</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/An%20interesting%20monologue%20overheard%20-%20July%208,%202007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 07:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/An%20interesting%20monologue%20overheard%20-%20July%208,%202007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This weekend we went down to the Capitol for Madison&amp;#39;s farmer&amp;#39;s market on the square.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While walking towards the square (the streets surrounding the Capitol building) I overheard a glimpse of a man&amp;#39;s speech. While I only heard part of, and I have no idea what was going on before or after the conversation, it sounded quite like a monologue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The gist of his speech was that there&amp;#39;s a fight to give illegal immigrants legal status in America. However, his brothers (I hesitate to say that, as I&amp;#39;m not sure that&amp;#39;s the word he said, but I can&amp;#39;t think of what else the word could have been) are sitting in jails.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While illegal immigrants have been on my mind, as a philosophical/political issue, this individual brought up a rather good point.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From his perspective, he was seeing some rather interesting actions coming from America.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To some sense, I share his wonder.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, as regards this general issue, I&amp;#39;m still thinking on it ...&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Andrew Fiala&#39;s Practical Pacifism</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-Andrew-Fialas-Practical-Pacifism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 21:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-Andrew-Fialas-Practical-Pacifism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is the review that I wrote for Amazon.com for the book &lt;cite&gt;Practical Pacifism&lt;/cite&gt; by Andrew Fiala.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can purchase this book online at Amazon.com: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/087586290X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=strivinglifen-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=087586290X&#34;&gt;Practical Pacifism&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Full-disclosure; I studied under Dr. Fiala when he was still teaching at the University of Wisconsin: Green Bay. It was, in fact, due to him that I ended up studying philosophy, and not simply ignoring the field as something which was rather boring. Therefore, I&amp;#39;d consider him one of the few people who were really pivotal in my life. In short, I&amp;#39;m probably biased.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That said, I had a fairly difficult time getting into his first work, The Philosopher&amp;#39;s Voice. Practical Pacifism, too, was a bit hard to get into at first, but was quite rewarding at the end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, while Fiala seems to suggest that this work is for non-philosophers (the first and only appendix is titled &amp;quot;For Philosophers Only&amp;quot;), I would have a hard time recommending this to anyone but philosophers and those who would go into politics. (In fact, I&amp;#39;d like to see universities have this as required reading for political scientists; it would perhaps be a better world if it was.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are a couple of reasons for the book&amp;#39;s difficulty;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1) The first couple of chapters seem to be highly repetitive. While I can understand why he does this, especially after reading the entire book, were I younger and/or not so inclined to read this book, I perhaps would have lost interest after the first few chapters.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
2) Again, while the appendix to the first chapter suggests this book is for non-philosophers, Fiala uses a deal of -isms throughout the book, often times with only a fleeting reference to what the -ism means. A listing at the end of the book, containing a definition of the -isms used in the book would be very welcome, and would help towards increasing the audience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
3) Because of #2, it&amp;#39;s hard to see Fiala&amp;#39;s ideas really coming to fruition. While I find Fiala to be correct on a number of points (some of which I may have disagreed with previous to reading this work), his &amp;#39;world&amp;#39; can only come about if there are more philosophers in the world - more people willing to honestly discuss the state of affairs in the world, with open minds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, philosophy is often seen as being outside of the realm of the practical, too inaccessible to the ordinary man, shepherds preaching to the flock (not that Fiala is doing that here).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, that&amp;#39;s not to say that only philosophers would gain from reading this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the contrary, as I said earlier, parts of this would naturally fit into courses on politics, and the pacifists would gain much from reading this work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyone could pick up this book and learn something from it, but I&amp;#39;d have a hard time recommending that someone read it cover to cover; rather, each chapter can, rather effectively, be read on its own.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had a difficult time trying to choose between four and five stars. Ultimately I went with the lower number as I really think the work could have been tightened up, especially in the first few chapters, and I think it could have been made a bit more accessible to non-philosophers, those who really need this work (although philosophers too have much to gain).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated DST happens - nothing else</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Updated-DST-happens-nothing-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 08:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Updated-DST-happens-nothing-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
From the looks of the various sites I&amp;#39;ve checked, it doesn&amp;#39;t appear that much happened, on a large scale, with the recent change of DST.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In other news, &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; candidate has entered into the race to 2008.  I guess that tells you something when there&amp;#39;s so many candidates entering, eh?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;300&lt;/em&gt; also promises to bring in big numbers over the rest of the weekend.  What&amp;#39;s interesting is that (in the reviews) women focus on the beauty of the film, while men focus on the violence.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cause of the salmonella outbreaks?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-cause-of-the-salmonella-outbreaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2007 09:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-cause-of-the-salmonella-outbreaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
If you listen to the news media, salmonella outbreaks are on a rampage. Spinach, cantaloupe, and now peanut butter. Unfortunately, the cause of these isn&amp;#39;t being investigated successfully. The cause, and on Prince Harry:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It&amp;#39;s refreshing to hear that Prince Harry will be heading over to Iraq. In a country where some of our leaders are willing to send children off to war, so long as they are not their own, it&amp;#39;s great to see a country where a leader&amp;#39;s child is going off to war. Of course, it also shows that, if he were to become leader, Prince Harry may just be one of the best.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As for salmonella, while some are thinking of terrorists only when it comes to Iraq, it&amp;#39;s time to remember our southern neighbor. Could Mexican-based terrorists be the cause of the salmonella outbreaks? I&amp;#39;m not the first to suggest it ...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>