<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akira Kurosawa on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/akira-kurosawa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Akira Kurosawa on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2006 19:23:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/akira-kurosawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie review: Yojimbo (1961)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Movie-review-Yojimbo-%281961%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2006 19:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Movie-review-Yojimbo-%281961%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The short review: another five star, classic, movie.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When I rented Yojimbo from Netflix, I wasn&amp;#39;t expecting anything less than a good movie.  My expectations were met.  However, I must admit that one of the later &amp;#39;copycats&amp;#39; of this movie, the 1996 Last Man Standing (starring Bruce Willis in the title role), ruined a deal of how the movie would play out and end.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, despite that, the movie was pretty darn good.  If you&amp;#39;ve seen Last Man Standing, I would recommend you see the movie that it borrowed from.  If you have seen and you liked &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/10/03/240/movie-review-seven-samurai-criterion-collection-1954/&#34;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;/a&gt;, then this also may be the movie for you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Masterless samurai Sanjuro Kuwabatake (Toshir&amp;ocirc; Mifune) finds himself in a feud-torn Japanese village in legendary director Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s darkly comic film. After pretending to work for merchants on both sides of the feud, Kuwabatake is imprisoned for treachery. He escapes in time to watch the two warring factions destroy each other, just as he had intended. Yojimbo served as the prototype for Clint Eastwood&amp;#39;s A Fistful of Dollars.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this movie was a part of a collection of Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s films, I&amp;#39;d definitely purchase the collection.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rated: UR&lt;br /&gt;
1 hr 50 min&lt;br /&gt;
1961
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Want to see what else Ive watched through Netflix? &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/09/26/237/netflix-shipping-for-madison-wi/&#34;&gt;Check out the list, and my attempt to track Netflix shipping for Madison WI&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie review: Ran (1985)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Movie-review-Ran-%281985%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 20:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Movie-review-Ran-%281985%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There are a number of movies out there that seem like they go on far longer than one would have thought.  Two hours long, but it feels like it&amp;#39;s over four.  Ran is one of these movies, but in the best possible light.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Legendary Japanese auteur Akira Kurosawa retells Shakespeare&amp;#39;s classic tragedy King Lear against a samurai backdrop. Tatsuya Nakadia is a warlord who transfers his kingdom to his eldest son. A power struggle ensues, incited by his two disinherited younger sons. Kurosawa is a master storyteller (almost on par with The Bard himself), and Ran ranks among the maestro&amp;#39;s most compelling films.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Akira Kurosawa is the same Akira Kurosawa of &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/10/03/240/movie-review-seven-samurai-criterion-collection-1954/&#34;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;#39;ve already reviewed, and which I also enjoyed.  While I actually picked up a copy of Ran from a local ShopKo, I had initially put it into &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/09/26/237/netflix-shipping-for-madison-wi/&#34;&gt;my Netflix queue&lt;/a&gt;, especially after having seen Seven Samurai.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While similar to Seven Samurai in many ways, Ran is actually, as the description above stated, based on Shakespeare&amp;#39;s King Lear.  A part of me, and no small part at that, now has a deep interest in pulling his Complete Works off of my shelf so that I can read this story.  In the meantime, I&amp;#39;ve made a note to put as many of Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s movies in my queue as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve given Ran a five stars rating, and have, as I said above, picked up a copy of the movie.  While points may seem to drag on, and it seems like it&amp;#39;s over three hours long, it&amp;#39;s a pretty darn good movie.  Unfortunately, not everyone will like this film, but it&amp;#39;s nonetheless worth watching at least once, especially if you like Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s other works, are interested in feudal Japan, or even Shakespeare and/or King Lear.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rated: R&lt;br /&gt;
160 min&lt;br /&gt;
1985
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie review: Seven Samurai: Criterion Collection (1954)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Movie-review-Seven-Samurai-Criterion-Collection-%281954%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 21:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Movie-review-Seven-Samurai-Criterion-Collection-%281954%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
My first Netflix movie was &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/09/28/239/movie-review-urusei-yatsura-movie-2-beautiful-dreamer-1984/&#34;&gt;Urusei Yatsura Movie 2: Beautiful Dreamer&lt;/a&gt;, and my second was another Japanese movie, albeit one a little more well known, Seven Samurai.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve seen recommendations regarding this movie many times before, and it&amp;#39;s been on my &amp;quot;purchase&amp;quot; list for almost the same amount of time.  However, I decided, since I had a trial to Netflix, that I may as well make it one of the first movies that I saw.  Now that I&amp;#39;ve watched the movie, I must admit that it&amp;#39;s still on my buy list.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Again, according to Netflix,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s heroic tale of honor and duty begins with master samurai Kambei (Takashi Shimura) posing as a monk to save a kidnapped child. Impressed by his bravery, a group of farmers begs him to defend their village from encroaching bandits. Kambei agrees and assembles a group of six other samurai, and together they build a militia with the villagers while the bandits loom nearby. Soon the raids begin, culminating in a bloody battle.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Numerous times during this movie I recalled the movie Lawrence of Arabia.  This movie truly contains a great story, but unlike Lawrence, it kept me captivated during the entire show.  (Although, full disclaimer, I did forward through the Intermission.)  Compared to most of the movies shot today, the movie is slow and the battle is truly less than epic.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, we can&amp;#39;t compare Seven Samurai to today&amp;#39;s movie, for it, unlike most today, is driven by the story, and the characters.  In fact, the characters are what you must really pay attention to in order to understand the movie for what (I believe) it&amp;#39;s trying to point out about the complexities of man.  Of course, it also takes place in a different era, with a different people, who believe in things much differently than people do today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But that&amp;#39;s not to say that the movie is dated, as the opposite is quite the case.  The movie is, in many ways, timeless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I give this movie high ratings in all areas save it&amp;#39;s ability to be watched by all.  The young can hardly be expected to pay attention to over three hours of one movie, and the dialogue is the true feature.  Likewise, since the movie is spoken Japanese and English subtitles, anyone that doesn&amp;#39;t like &amp;quot;foreign&amp;quot; films won&amp;#39;t like this one either.  Need a lot of action?  The action at the end may satisfy you, but it probably won&amp;#39;t.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Nonetheless, I enjoyed the movie, so if you happen to like a movie that&amp;#39;s driven by the characters and story, and you don&amp;#39;t mind reading, and you may have some interested in &amp;#39;feudal&amp;#39; Japan, check this movie out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rated: UR&lt;br /&gt;
3 hr 28 min&lt;br /&gt;
1954&lt;br /&gt;
Watched with Japanese with English Subtitles
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Want to see what else I&amp;#39;ve watched through Netflix?  &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/09/26/237/netflix-shipping-for-madison-wi/&#34;&gt;Check out the list, and my attempt to track Netflix shipping for Madison WI&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
