<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ran on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/ran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ran on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 20:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/ran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie review: Ran (1985)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Movie-review-Ran-%281985%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 20:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Movie-review-Ran-%281985%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There are a number of movies out there that seem like they go on far longer than one would have thought.  Two hours long, but it feels like it&amp;#39;s over four.  Ran is one of these movies, but in the best possible light.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Legendary Japanese auteur Akira Kurosawa retells Shakespeare&amp;#39;s classic tragedy King Lear against a samurai backdrop. Tatsuya Nakadia is a warlord who transfers his kingdom to his eldest son. A power struggle ensues, incited by his two disinherited younger sons. Kurosawa is a master storyteller (almost on par with The Bard himself), and Ran ranks among the maestro&amp;#39;s most compelling films.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Akira Kurosawa is the same Akira Kurosawa of &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/10/03/240/movie-review-seven-samurai-criterion-collection-1954/&#34;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;#39;ve already reviewed, and which I also enjoyed.  While I actually picked up a copy of Ran from a local ShopKo, I had initially put it into &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/09/26/237/netflix-shipping-for-madison-wi/&#34;&gt;my Netflix queue&lt;/a&gt;, especially after having seen Seven Samurai.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While similar to Seven Samurai in many ways, Ran is actually, as the description above stated, based on Shakespeare&amp;#39;s King Lear.  A part of me, and no small part at that, now has a deep interest in pulling his Complete Works off of my shelf so that I can read this story.  In the meantime, I&amp;#39;ve made a note to put as many of Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s movies in my queue as I can.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve given Ran a five stars rating, and have, as I said above, picked up a copy of the movie.  While points may seem to drag on, and it seems like it&amp;#39;s over three hours long, it&amp;#39;s a pretty darn good movie.  Unfortunately, not everyone will like this film, but it&amp;#39;s nonetheless worth watching at least once, especially if you like Akira Kurosawa&amp;#39;s other works, are interested in feudal Japan, or even Shakespeare and/or King Lear.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rated: R&lt;br /&gt;
160 min&lt;br /&gt;
1985
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>