<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2006 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First Debian install = unsuccessful</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/First-Debian-install-3D-unsuccessful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2006 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/First-Debian-install-3D-unsuccessful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
My first shot at installing Debian didn&amp;#39;t go quite so well.  I&amp;#39;m attempting to install on a HP Pavilion XE734, using pretty much the base system.  One addition appears to be a 3Com Fast Etherlink PCI card, from the late 90s ... (3C595-TX).&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My hope is to get this installed fairly quickly, and have instructions for anyone else that may have this model, and may want to do a similar installation.  I&amp;#39;m surprised by the lack of a site that documents which base systems people were able to install various flavours of Linux on.  After all, not everyone who installs Linux does so on a custom-built machine ... right?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Guess I&amp;#39;ll spend some time Sunday night doing a new installation, after clearing my hard drive of the initial shot.  I don&amp;#39;t really want to buy a new(er) machine just to install a flavour of Linux, but I guess I may have to ...  There&amp;#39;s always a couple other flavours of non-Windows OS that I have laying about - and I have a fast enough connection and enough blank CDs to burn a number more.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>