<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/cisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 17:24:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/cisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DD-WRT and my Linksys WRT54GL</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/DD-WRT-and-my-Linksys-WRT54GL/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 17:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/DD-WRT-and-my-Linksys-WRT54GL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been sitting on a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000BTL0OA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Linksys (Cisco) WRT54GL&lt;/a&gt; for a long while now. A long, long, while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally I was going to replace my &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00007KDVI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;WRT54G&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(don&#39;t get me wrong, it still works great) and install DD-WRT for the additional features. However, I just never got around to it.&amp;nbsp;Today I finally dusted off the box (I had opened it) and started getting it setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the deeper I dug into DD-WRT the more confused I became. The main Web site contains a database of routers, with information on which firmware to install, but if you dig into the forums you&#39;ll find that the database, and the firmware, are out-of-date and buggy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, although not too surprisingly, there&#39;s &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.dd-wrt.com/wiki/index.php/Linksys_WRT54GL&#34;&gt;a Wiki on the Linksys WRT54GL&lt;/a&gt;, which made installation pretty dang simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugged the router into my laptop via a wired connection,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disconnected from my existing wireless-enabled router,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;verified I could access the router with the stock firmware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did a hard reset on the router (30-30-30)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installed the new firmware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;had to manually change the password (it didn&#39;t prompt me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was set, since I decided to stick with the &#39;micro&#39; (called such because of how large it is) install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part was then replicating my existing settings on the new router, although that wasn&#39;t terrible since I was able to just connect to both from my laptop and iPad. I didn&#39;t put in my custom DNS lookups (I&#39;m not using Charter), so that caused some issues, although even after adding those didn&#39;t work, a power cycle of my &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00005T6GZ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;cable modem&lt;/a&gt; did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all, it was &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;easier than I thought it was going to be, and, best of all, I don&#39;t have a bricked router.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to inSSIDer, I already seem to have a better signal, so that&#39;s a good sign. I don&#39;t see myself investing too much time in additional settings, but ... it&#39;s there if I want to play around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if you&#39;re gotten this far, it&#39;s been a few months more than 2 years since I picked up the WRT54GL. Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>