<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:21:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Bang Gang&#39;s The Wolves Are Whispering (2015)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Bang-Gangs-The-Wolves-Are-Whispering-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 20:21:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Bang-Gangs-The-Wolves-Are-Whispering-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Bang Gang&#39;s 2015 album &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00X8IZFEW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Wolves Are Whispering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Another beautiful album&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: I find music to be very subjective and find it hard to explain why it is that I might like a song in words and without being able to sit someone down and let them listen with me. So the number of music reviews I do is very low. However, this album has been out for three days and has no reviews on Amazon. That&#39;s just not right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was browing around Google Play Music this evening and one of the recommendations was Bang Gang&#39;s The Wolves Are Whispering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After double checking that it was in fact the Bang Gang I knew of, and have enjoyed for a number of years, I started listening. After two songs I opened Amazon in my browser and purchased the MP3 album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual Bang Gang has created another beautiful album. It starts off strong with The Sin is Near and continues all the way through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having listened to and enjoyed all three previous albums, as well as his work with Keren Ann as part of Lady &amp;amp; Bird, I think he has a stronger voice in this one. That is, Keren Ann takes a slight edge in Lady &amp;amp; Bird, and in his previous albums sometimes the guest vocals would define (for me) the strongest songs. However, here he takes the center stage on his album in regards to vocals from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, should you purchase this album? If you&#39;ve enjoyed his previous three releases as Bang Gang, absolutely. If, like me, you found out about Bang Gang because of Keren Ann&#39;s work with him, then probably. You&#39;ll find a bit of her here, but much more in the background. If this is your first experience with Bang Gang, then give them a listen online and then come back. It&#39;s a great sound, with melodies you&#39;ll find yourself humming along with, even if you don&#39;t (yet) know the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bang Gang&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00X8IZFEW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Wolves Are Whispering&lt;/a&gt; gets a full five of five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well done, Amazon (re: Amazon Cloud)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Well-done-Amazon-re-Amazon-Cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 07:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Well-done-Amazon-re-Amazon-Cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well done, Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#39;ve been saying for quite a while that music was heading towards the &#39;cloud,&#39; and while it seemed for a while that everyone was betting on Apple doing it first, you&#39;ve trumped them, with what seems like a very consumer-friendly service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 GB for everyone? Check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free upgrade to 20 GB if you buy an Amazon MP3 album? Check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon MP3s purchased and stored to the cloud (seemingly at purchase) don&#39;t count against your limit? Check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you can still download said MP3s to your computer later? Check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way to go, Amazon. I&#39;m still afraid Wisconsin is going to force you to charge tax on purchases at the time of purchase, and it&#39;s going to result in the closure of my Associates account (I like being able to hold off until the end of the year when I file my taxes, but realize most people don&#39;t report), but overall I&#39;m very happy to be a proud Amazon.com customer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite new (to me) music of 2010</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 10:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2009.aspx&#34;&gt;the tradition started last year&lt;/a&gt;, I present my favorite albums purchased in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be on this list I must have purchased the album in 2010. This also doesn&#39;t include all albums I purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Easy winners&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013G64LY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;What Is Free To a Good Home?&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013G64TG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Knives Don&#39;t Have Your Back&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Emily Haines &amp;amp; The Soft Skeleton : Emily Haines was on my &#39;too hard to tell&#39; list last year, and this year I ended up picking up her four CD digital collection on iTunes. As you&#39;ll see later, all four of those CDs have made it on to my &#39;easy winners&#39; list this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0001ZX2L8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex Vol. 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00020VZVQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Vol. 1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Yoko Kanno : Yoko Kanno does some very wonderful things with music. I have copies of most of the albums now, and one of my biggest purchases this year was for a hard copy of the Solid State O.S.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013FZIP8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Live It Out&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013FZIUI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Grow Up and Blow Away&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Metric : As noted above, I picked up a four CD collection of Emily Haines&#39; music. I haven&#39;t listened to these as much as I have the ones above, but ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00383YC2S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Une Enfant Du Si&amp;egrave;cle&lt;/a&gt; - Aliz&amp;eacute;e : Only Aliz&amp;eacute;e can get me to consistently pay for physical copies of albums, instead of waiting for them to be released electronically. I probably liked &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WZ8RB2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Psych&amp;eacute;d&amp;eacute;lices&lt;/a&gt; more, but this is still pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TEVJI4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Disparition&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001JK4UD8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Not Going Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TEPEE4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Keren Ann&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Keren Ann : I&#39;ve become something of a big Keren Ann fan. The albums aren&#39;t all strong, but her total body of work elevates her into this heading. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXMS9A?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nolita&lt;/a&gt; remains my favorite album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000X71K0O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Lady &amp;amp; Bird&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Lady &amp;amp; Bird : Another of Keren Ann&#39;s, but this time with Bardi Johansen, who you&#39;ll see has made it onto my list (Bang Gang) further below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003B13QQU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Head First&lt;/a&gt; - Goldfrapp : I&#39;ve found Goldfrapp to be mostly hit (versus miss) with me, and this album has got a great 80&#39;s sound, that I generally find pretty near perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXOG4U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Understanding&lt;/a&gt; - R&amp;ouml;yksopp : The first R&amp;ouml;yksopp album that really clicked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TENKEK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Demon Days&lt;/a&gt; - Gorillaz : I really should have purchased this album years ago, but missed out on doing so until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Close calls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YBGU86?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Never For Ever&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Bush : Right after I got this I listened this quite a bit. I&#39;ve been very tempted to get her other works, but the ones that were highly recommended aren&#39;t available digitally yet. It&#39;s a great album, but not listening to it as much, and holding off on purchasing any more of her works makes me a bit nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YUERLO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Clocktower Park&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Walsh : As noted again below, I started with her &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002LOS33Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Acoustic EP&lt;/a&gt; and have begun looking into her other works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0034CEDAE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;IRM&lt;/a&gt; - Charlotte Gainsbourg : &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122ZAI2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;5:55&lt;/a&gt; remains my favorite of her albums. However, this has quite the different sound to it, in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002F6FQGK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Lungs (Deluxe Version)&lt;/a&gt; - Florence + The Machine : I played this album quite a bit when I first got it, but have started to let it sit unplayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QZXSXK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Tiny Cities&lt;/a&gt; - Sun Kil Moon : Heard one of his songs on the Gears of War trailer, and all-in-all I really enjoy this album. But, I&#39;ve yet to actually pick up one of his other albums ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003BB4VDW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Ballade Of Lady &amp;amp; Bird&lt;/a&gt; - Lady &amp;amp; Bird : After really enjoying &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000X71K0O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Lady &amp;amp; Bird&lt;/a&gt; I decided to pick up their other album. I gave the album 4 stars, and stick by that rating, but ... I&#39;m not sure why this stays here instead of further above ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001IASY40?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Historie De Melody Nelson&lt;/a&gt; - Serge Gainsbourg : An amazing album, with one of the first strong male singers I&#39;ve purchased this year. I also seem to be listening to it at a nice steady pace, which suggests it&#39;ll stay as one of my favorites for a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002MOL6DM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;11:11&lt;/a&gt; - Rodrigo Y Gabriela : Amazing guitar work. Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0041NG0VA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ghosts from the Past&lt;/a&gt; - Bang Gang : As mentioned above, I discovered his work thanks to his collaboration with Keren Ann. When another of his albums is re-released in approximately 10 days, I&#39;ll be picking it up. I&#39;m not so much as fan of the other album of his that I picked up, so ... we&#39;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7XUBE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Let&#39;s Get Out of This Country&lt;/a&gt; - Camera Obscura : Last year Camera Obscura was listed as&amp;nbsp;a disappointment for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTNA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Underachievers Please Try Harder&lt;/a&gt;. I think my point about it starting strong is still valid, yet here I went and purchased another of their albums. Clearly, there&#39;s something there, and I think having listened to Underachievers more has made that more visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Too hard to tell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DGJSTS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Tim&#39;s House&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Walsh : Her &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002LOS33Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Acoustic EP&lt;/a&gt; was an album that I had downloaded (I believe it was free at the time) and then forgot about until I &#39;discovered&#39; it one day. I started picking up more of her music, and while I enjoy this (&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YUERLO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Clocktower Park&lt;/a&gt; made it onto my list above), it may just be too soon to tell ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003JEJWP8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Ghost Who Walks&lt;/a&gt; - Karen Elson&amp;nbsp;: I played this album a lot, and fear I burned out on it. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003REX5VC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Five Ghosts&lt;/a&gt; - Stars : Stars has popped up in my &#39;research&#39; for music before. Really, I just haven&#39;t had the album enough to confirm that I enjoy the album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003A4X0T6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;R.E.T.R.O.&lt;/a&gt; - mind.in.a.box : Heard one of the songs somewhere, and since I liked the previews picked this up. I&#39;m not sure what to think of it yet, since it seems there&#39;s a lot of hits, and very few misses ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00370CDE6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Something Wrong&lt;/a&gt; - Bang Gang : The album doesn&#39;t seem to fit as a whole, but this may just be an issue with not having enough time with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disappointments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003A9OVS0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Plastic Beach&lt;/a&gt; - Gorillaz : Stylo is perfect. The rest of the album? Not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QQPRHE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Et Pourquoi les Crayons ?&lt;/a&gt; -&amp;nbsp;Am&amp;eacute;lie-les-crayons : An experiment trying to find foreign music that I really enjoyed. Just haven&#39;t listened to it as much as I should. There&#39;s a couple other albums that belong here too (by other artists), but this will serve as representing them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002POVIMS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Roux&lt;/a&gt; - La Roux : I should really like this, but I can&#39;t find a reason to press play, beyond a couple songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0040I95WC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drawing Down the Moon&lt;/a&gt; - Azure Ray : &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001RK1ZRY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Azure Ray&lt;/a&gt; was a good album, and while it may just be too soon, this doesn&#39;t live up to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122RF4O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;What We Forgot to Remember&lt;/a&gt; - Calamine : Like the previous entry, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ZU8M1Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Calamine&lt;/a&gt; was a good album, but this one doesn&#39;t have the same magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001G5VISQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Good, The Bad &amp;amp; The Ugly&lt;/a&gt; - Ennio Morricone : The soundtrack to &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003LVX7JG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Red Dead Redemption&lt;/a&gt; probably belongs here as well. Both have some great pieces, but the rest ends up sounding the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002JF9HEO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Beyond the Infinite&lt;/a&gt; - Juno Reactor : As happened with a couple other albums (not listed here), I&#39;d find one song I really like, the previews on the other songs would sound okay, and I&#39;d end up not liking the album as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004EI3ON4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Tron: Legacy&lt;/a&gt; - Daft Punk : Don&#39;t get me wrong. It&#39;s a good soundtrack, but not what I&#39;d consider a good Daft Punk album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122N0P2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Soviet Kitsch&lt;/a&gt; - Regina Spektor : Ode to Divorce is great, but I think I burned myself out on Regina Spektor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003X73QA8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Suburbs&lt;/a&gt; - Arcade Fire : &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTCG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Neon Bible&lt;/a&gt; wasn&#39;t that good. This had a good song, but wasn&#39;t much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V63CYO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Aja&lt;/a&gt; - Steely Dan : I used to love this kind of music. This proved to me that my music tastes have changed for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes since last year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXMS9A?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nolita&lt;/a&gt; has moved from a &#39;close call&#39; to one of my favorite albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it very&amp;nbsp;surprising that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V3VT42?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Old World Underground, Where Are You Now?&lt;/a&gt; was listed as a &#39;too hard to tell&#39; album last year. This too has become one of my favorite albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTNA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Underachievers Please Try Harder&lt;/a&gt; should probably be moved from &#39;disappointments&#39; to &#39;too hard to tell,&#39; since I&#39;ve picked up another album by Camera Obscura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No other real changes need be made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTunes Playlists to Xml: Parsing categories with LINQ</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-Parsing-categories-with-LINQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 08:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-Parsing-categories-with-LINQ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently had the need to determine what types of music I had within my collection of music. Since I&amp;nbsp;created &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/apps/iTunesPlaylists2Xml&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml&lt;/a&gt; so that I could export out my library on my iPod, it was easy enough to run that and then open &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.linqpad.net/&#34;&gt;LINQPad&lt;/a&gt; to run the following query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, you must export the Genre field in order for the following query to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;csharp&#34;&gt;// Location to the XML from iTunes Playlists to XML
String playlistXml = @&amp;ldquo;C:\Users\James\Projects\services\WcfRestService\App_Data\playlistXml.xml&amp;rdquo;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XDocument xml = XDocument.Load(playlistXml);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;var categories = from track in xml.Descendants(&amp;ldquo;track&amp;rdquo;)
    group track by track.Element(&amp;ldquo;genre&amp;rdquo;).Value into t
    orderby t.Key
    //orderby t.Count() descending
    select new {
        Category = t.Key,
        Count = t.Count()
    };&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;categories.Dump();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can switch the orderby lines depending upon how you want to sort the returned data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be something I eventually build into my application, along with other reporting features. I know that I&amp;rsquo;d love to have some comparision functionality, either built-in or as another application, so that I can see how my music tastes change, or if I&amp;rsquo;m consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sample output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some cleanup, sample output is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative - 279&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative &amp;amp; Punk - 154&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative Rock - 282&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blues - 120&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books &amp;amp; Spoken - 145&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Children&amp;rsquo;s Music - 12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classical - 255&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country - 104&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dance - 76&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dance &amp;amp; DJ - 220&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy Listening - 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronic - 278&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronica/Dance - 91&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folk - 319&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;French Pop - 90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gospel &amp;amp; Religious - 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Rock &amp;amp; Metal - 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hip Hop/Rap - 88&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holiday - 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;House - 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial - 107&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Metal - 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jazz - 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J-Pop - 48&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J-Rock - 23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lo-Fi - 35&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metal - 82&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Age - 270&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop - 1225&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop/Rock - 26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&amp;amp;B - 105&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&amp;amp;B/Soul - 81&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reggae - 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rock - 3125&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soundtrack - 348&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World - 57&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Nady Audio Stereo Headphones (HP-03)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Nady-Audio-Stereo-Headphones-HP-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Nady-Audio-Stereo-Headphones-HP-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001VO4TX8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nady Audio Stereo Headphones, model HP-03&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a pair of these headphones in a bundle, and wasn&amp;rsquo;t really expecting much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sitting around for a couple of months (okay, more like a handful) I finally opened them up one day and plugged them in. Surprisingly, they work pretty dang good. I&amp;rsquo;m in no way a sound expert, but I dare say for the average (music) listener these will work perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are built quite well, better than similarly priced Sony headphones, and the padding on the top is very comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I don&amp;rsquo;t like about these is I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find the perfect adjustment; they seem to push (ever so slightly) harder into my head above my ears as opposed to below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, they work quite well, and the volume adjustment on the cord is also quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: La Ballade Of Lady &amp; Bird : A Project By Keren Ann Zeidel &amp; Bardi Johannsson</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-La-Ballade-Of-Lady-Bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 08:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-La-Ballade-Of-Lady-Bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Ballade-Lady-Bird-Project-Johannsson/dp/B003BB4VDW/ref=cm_cr_pr_product_top?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Ballade Of Lady &amp;amp; Bird : A Project By Keren Ann Zeidel &amp;amp; Bardi Johannsson&lt;/a&gt;. I believe this is my first review of an album &amp;hellip;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a difficult time seeing how one can review the actual music on an album, since tastes are so personal, so I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty huge fan of Keren Ann&amp;rsquo;s work. I started with the absolutely beautiful Nolita, then the okay La Biographie De Luka Philipse, La Disparition, and then a big shopping spree of Not Going Anywhere, Keren Ann, and Lady &amp;amp; Bird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter featured some extremely beautiful songs. But even though I liked it, based on what I&amp;rsquo;d now collected of Keren Ann&amp;rsquo;s works, I had a difficult time with La Ballade of Lady &amp;amp; Bird, since it seemed many of the songs were already covered elsewhere, and only a few really jumped out at me. So I kept pushing it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I picked it up the other day, since my mind kept coming back to it, and it&amp;rsquo;s truly unfortunate that I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this was a live album (I though the last two bonus tracks at the end were the only live tracks), because it was definitely a wise purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keren Ann isn&amp;rsquo;t the main vocalist on every track, but that&amp;rsquo;s what gives it a Lady &amp;amp; Bird feel to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus far, extremely happy with my purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One note: you may be thinking that live tracks means that the audience will feature in the tracks, in some way. Outside of one song where they start clapping early, we only hear the audience at the end of each song, the one place where they clapped early, and right before the last two tracks begin, which I assume is an encore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After yet another listen, I also find that I neglected to mention how beautiful the orchestra is, which is unfortunate, since this is one of the major appeals of the album.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Recommendations Please! version 0.5 beta</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Music-Recommendations-Please%21-version-05-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 07:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Music-Recommendations-Please%21-version-05-beta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While not necessarily a step forward from &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Music-Recommendations-Please!-045-beta-released.aspx&#34;&gt;version 0.4.5 of Music Recommendations Please!&lt;/a&gt;, version 0.5 is nonetheless a positive step. Consider this an idea-based release. As such, this application is in no way final (but might be more complete after this long weekend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external download&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/applications/MusicRecommendationsPlease_0.5.zip&#34;&gt;Download Music Recommendations Please! version 0.5, beta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see a general idea of where I&#39;d like to end up by reading my &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Music-application-idea.aspx&#34;&gt;music application idea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://smallestdotnet.com/&#34;&gt;.NET Framework 4&lt;/a&gt; is required for this application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas, outside of the obvious ones (such as changing the window&#39;s title and icon; I know) appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music application idea</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Music-application-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 22:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Music-application-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, it was way back in September of last year that I realized &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Music-Recommendations-Please!-045-beta-released.aspx&#34;&gt;Music Recommendations Please!&lt;/a&gt;, which I hoped would help me discover new music (and perhaps help others as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then&amp;nbsp;I haven&#39;t used it as much as I would have hoped, but that&#39;s mostly because I&#39;m not happy with how easy it is to get more than one artist in at a time, and generate helpful &#39;reports&#39; from data returned for multiple artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-version-16-released.aspx&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;m able to generate very nice XML files which I can then parse with LINQPad, but again, outside of the couple statements I save (and which I seemingly haven&#39;t been sharing), there&#39;s no real reporting functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the best of both worlds would be to point to one of these generated XML files, get a listing of artists that are enjoyed, and then return a listing of artists that may also be enjoyed, with appropriate weighting applied, since artists showing up multiple times would necessarily have their rating increased. Similarly, if an artist was purchased, but not enjoyed, that too would impact the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if it was&amp;nbsp;a Web site I wouldn&#39;t necessarily want to allow users to upload XML files (mine is almost at 3.25 MB, with all data pulled), but it would offer much more flexibility. Perhaps a hybrid would be the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the desktop application, either point to an XML file (from iTunes Playlists to Xml) or allow one or more artists to be manually entered. The Web would only allow the latter. Once a button is pressed either Last.fm or Yahoo! would be called and similar artists would be returned, sorted by number of times they show up and &#39;rating.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returned results could then be filtered and/or removed, as well as dug into even further. The listing would need to be exportable, but having links to purchase from Amazon would also be more than okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing as how I&#39;ve already done the work, albeit in pieces, it seems it just needs to be put together now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead? The digital download is barely out of its teens</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Dead-The-digital-download-is-barely-out-of-its-teens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 09:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Dead-The-digital-download-is-barely-out-of-its-teens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Slate posted an article by Farhad Manjoo titled &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/id/2254532/pagenum/all/&#34;&gt;The Digital Download Is Dead: How Google&#39;s music-streaming venture will change the gadget and entertainment worlds forever&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After first, rightly, attacking Apple&#39;s iTunes and iPod (and related) platforms as being slow and unwieldy, especially on the predominate operating system Windows (not even mentioning Linux), and overall behind on the times, Farhad moves us from syncing our music collections out to the cloud. Which isn&#39;t much of a surprise given that, despite some rather large issues, the cloud has been &#39;in&#39; for a couple of years now. But even more surprising Farhad argues at the end of the article that &#34;[i]n the future, not only will you not get a CD when you buy an album, you won&#39;t even get a digital file.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&#39;s an elephant in the room. A rather large one, taking up every available inch of space. Namely the global music industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment I&#39;m listening to X Japan. If I do a search for this band I find the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon MP3: Two albums available - Blue Blood and Jealousy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon music: 236 results, seemingly with most of their releases covered (but I wasn&#39;t about to page through all those results). Of special note is the magical word &#39;Import&#39; next to the majority of the albums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunes: Same two albums as Amazon MP3 and the I.V. Single.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s better examples, I just happened to be listening to X Japan at the moment. Go ahead and look up some popular European bands and see if you can find their music on Amazon or iTunes, or any one of the other online sellers of music (for the United States). Chances are you&#39;ll find a good deal of music that you can&#39;t purchase, unless you&#39;re willing to pay import prices for a physical CD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with this in mind, Farhad expects physical media to disappear, &lt;em&gt;in the future&lt;/em&gt;. In lieu of an extremely ambigious timeframe, let&#39;s substitute that with &#39;in the next 5 years&#39; or &#39;in the next decade.&#39; With the music industry as slow as it is, do we expect not only for the industry to move to the cloud, but to also deal with the &#39;import&#39; situtation in a respectable way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of moving away from digital downloads, which by the way work better (for me) than a cloud service - and service it will be, with the associated recurring costs - I&#39;d much rather the industry finish show that they&#39;re willing to embrace digital &lt;em&gt;media&lt;/em&gt; and its promise. As things stand now they &lt;em&gt;haven&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; embraced digital media, and won&#39;t until everything (give or take) that&#39;s available in physical form is available digitally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you want to move to the cloud at that point, or alongside the expansion of digital downloads, fine. Go right ahead. Other groups have certainly tried, but until the global market elephant is removed from the room, any new services will run into the exact same issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And until we see &#39;foreign&#39; music available digitally to &#39;all,&#39; please don&#39;t suggest we get rid of physical media, or the issues now will just get pushed to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Side note: the gaming industry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar debate is going on in the gaming industry. Digital downloads of games is finally becoming more and more prevelant, not only with DLC, but the making of &#39;classic&#39; games available for purchase and download, whether that be through the Playstation Store, Xbox Live, or Good Old Games (GOG.com). They too are looking at cloud-based services, but they too have an issue with imports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress is moving forward, not stepping to the side, and until the promise of digital media/downloads is embraced, anything based on it will suffer the same issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTunes Playlists to Xml - version 1.6 released</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-version-16-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-version-16-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Version 1.6 of iTunes Playlists to Xml is now available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download &lt;a rel=&#34;external download&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/applications/iTunesPlaylistsToXml_1.6.zip&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml 1.6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing and more information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re new to iTunes Playlists to Xml, I&#39;ve created a &#39;product page&#39; for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/apps/iTunesPlaylists2Xml/&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml&lt;/a&gt; with all the information needed to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade from &lt;strong&gt;any version of 1.4 or 1.5&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;you need to replace the following files with those in the above archive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AlbumName.xslt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunesPlaylists2Xml.xslt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunesPlaylistsToXml.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NameArtistAlbumPlay.xslt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your configuration file&amp;nbsp;should be upgraded with the new functionality automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To upgrade from &lt;strong&gt;version 1.3 or earlier&lt;/strong&gt;, extract the contents of the zip replacing everything &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; the iTunesPlaylistsToXml.exe.config file; when you start the application after upgrading the configuration file &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be automatically upgraded with all new settings. If you get a configuration error, then replace this file with the new version. Remember to update your name in the Settings menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes from version 1.5.3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the release of .NET Framework 4 a few weeks ago, I figure it&#39;s safe to move from .NET Framework 2.0 to 3.5 in iTunes Playlists to Xml. Therefore, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://smallestdotnet.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.NET Framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 3.5&amp;nbsp;is now required&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the new requirement, version 1.6 of iTunes Playlists to Xml adds the ability to save playlists to HTML, in addition to XML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features for&amp;nbsp;future releases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A future release will allow you to change the elements that are output by default via the user interface (it&#39;s possible now via the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/applications/iTunesPlaylistsToXml.htm#advanced&#34;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Suggestions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, comments and suggestions are appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite new (to me) music of 2009</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping with the tradition started here, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2010.aspx&#34;&gt;list for 2010&lt;/a&gt; is also available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having only listened to the radio a few times over the last year, I have a good idea of just what music I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to, since my iPod keeps track of everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/apps/iTunesPlaylists2Xml/&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/?tag=/linqpad&#34;&gt;LINQPad&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s my favorite new (to me) album purchases of 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be on this list I must have purchased the album in 2009. This also doesn&amp;rsquo;t include all albums I purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Easy winners&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the albums that easily are my favorites of 2009. To be on this list I&amp;rsquo;ve had them for a while and enjoy almost every song on the album, and am almost always in the mood to listen to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001D7CYEY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Meiko&lt;/a&gt; - Meiko : My only problem with this album is that Meiko hasn&amp;rsquo;t seemed to have produced anything since. Near perfect album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001UIPI6W?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;(A)spera&lt;/a&gt; - Mirah : For whatever reason, I had to re-find Mirah on my iPod. Unfortunately when I later&amp;nbsp;picked up &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013D86FO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Advisory Committee&lt;/a&gt;, hoping I could find another album like this, it just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the same feel &amp;hellip; although the first song is of course great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TRVK5S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Fur and Gold&lt;/a&gt; - Bat for Lashes : Their cover of I&amp;rsquo;m On Fire was what originally got me interested in Bat for Lashes, but she&amp;rsquo;s got a very solid voice, with stories behind her lyris. After getting burned before, I hesitated picking up &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001YAG5DQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Two Suns&lt;/a&gt;. While I still like Fur and Gold more, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to get into the latter (especially after seeing the music video for Daniel, and realizing just how much imagery there is in that album as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0027D41PS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Still Night, Still Light&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QZY97E?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Verses of Comfort, Assurance &amp;amp; Salvation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Au Revoir Simone : With&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QZV616?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Bird of Music&lt;/a&gt; (not otherwise listed), I believe I have all of Au Revoir Simone&amp;rsquo;s albums (including the remix album, which is listed below). These two are easy to start when I want to fill up a short time with some nice music. I&amp;rsquo;m still undecided about Bird, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;d pick up a new Au Revoir Simone album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Close calls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following albums are those that I enjoy, but that don&amp;rsquo;t immediately come to mind, or require me to be in a particular mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001456HMK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Speak for Yourself&lt;/a&gt; - Imogen Heap : I think I found this on Last.fm. Unfortunately, while I was really looking forward to her new album &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002K3XECQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ellipse&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll admit I was expecting a &amp;lsquo;Speak for Yourself 2.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T9E7U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Flower Book&lt;/a&gt; - &amp;Eacute;milie Simon : When I first picked this album up I listened to again and again. While I&amp;rsquo;ve slowed down a bit, I still really like this, and picked up her &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015T9DTO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;March of the Empress&lt;/a&gt;, and have been very tempted to pick up her live album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0012EJVIA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Con&lt;/a&gt; - Tegan and Sara : Tegan and Sara is another hit-or-miss group, but I listened to this album quite a lot when I first picked it up. I really like this, but haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get into &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0014JIUX0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;So Jealous&lt;/a&gt;, which has stopped me from picking up their new album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122ZAI2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;5:55&lt;/a&gt; - Charlotte Gainsbourg : I listened to this quite a lot when I picked it up, and there&amp;rsquo;s some songs I love, but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that listening to it so much as decreased my appreciation of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXMS9A?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nolita&lt;/a&gt; - Keren Ann : Another that I listened to a lot when I first picked it up. She&amp;rsquo;s got a solid voice, and Song of Alice, song by another, is one of my favorite songs. I picked up &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXBRJW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Biographie De Luka Philipse&lt;/a&gt; and haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get into it as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like. Again, this has stopped me from picking up more of her work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WZ8RB2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Psych&amp;eacute;d&amp;eacute;lices&lt;/a&gt; - Aliz&amp;eacute;e : $25, this was by far the most expensive music purchase this year, but that&amp;rsquo;s what happens when you have to pay import pricing, and you can&amp;rsquo;t get it electronically. Didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to it as much as her other albums, but nonetheless it&amp;rsquo;s pretty solid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013DAC8I?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Let It Die&lt;/a&gt; - Feist : Between this and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V9D0XY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Reminder&lt;/a&gt; Feist has enough songs to keep me rather happy. But, I&amp;rsquo;ve got to be in just the right mood &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Too hard to tell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are albums that I like, but have a hard time putting into the above listing, for whatever reason. Or, they may be albums that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had for very long, so it&amp;rsquo;s too soon to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000VZO2S0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Melankton&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Havnevik : Really great music, but I have to keep remembering that I like this. Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t it jump out at me more? Is it like (A)spera where it&amp;rsquo;ll eventually click? This puzzles me. Maybe I just need to be in the mood for it? Or is it the length (oddly enough)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00150ASXS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;11:11&lt;/a&gt; - Maria Taylor and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001RK1ZRY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Azure Ray&lt;/a&gt; - Azure Ray : Maria Taylor being a part of Azure Ray, these two are closely related. I should just pick up another Azure Ray album and get it done with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V3VT42?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Old World Underground, Where Are You Now?&lt;/a&gt; - Metric : I picked up &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001W4LA3E?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Fantasies&lt;/a&gt; first, and enjoyed it enough to seek out more of Metric&amp;rsquo;s works, but like Old World more. This is another where I just need to pick up another of their album&amp;rsquo;s to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001KQGCVO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Happy Smiles&lt;/a&gt; - T.A.T.U. : T.A.T.U. is one of my guilty pleasures, after hearing about them and purchasing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000I2JH2M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;T.A.T.U.: The Best&lt;/a&gt;. I &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; found out they released another album &amp;hellip; which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably pick up after I finish this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001YAG5DQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Two Suns&lt;/a&gt; - Bat for Lashes : &lt;em&gt;See my note on Bat for Lashes above.&lt;/em&gt; Again, I really want to like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YMY1FY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Structure &amp;amp; Cosmetics&lt;/a&gt; - The Brunettes : This is one of a very few albums featuring a male singer that made it on the positive lists. The two work so well together on this album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001VEDBV4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Re-Arrange Us&lt;/a&gt; - Mates of State : Living in Madison, or knowing the people I knew, I saw a lot of Mates of State stickers, but I&amp;rsquo;d never really listened to them. Enjoy them, but have a hard time unconsciously pressing the play button when I get to them &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001Q1QF2O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not Me, It&amp;rsquo;s You&lt;/a&gt; - Lily Allen : Somehow a copy of Smile ended up on my computer, I believe from when I was trying to fix my sister&amp;rsquo;s computer (or at least get all her data back). &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TETLRA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Alright, Still&lt;/a&gt; is still a great album, and this one is a pretty good follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SX89TS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Moon Safari&lt;/a&gt; - Air : Sounds great, but since I&amp;rsquo;m okay with this being my only Air album, I have a hard time moving it higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001V7EQ24?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Blitz!&lt;/a&gt; - Yeah Yeah Yeahs : Played it quite a bit when I got it, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to press play unless I&amp;rsquo;m in the mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0011FDUR8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Too&lt;/a&gt; - Madita : I picked up this and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TT1PUQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Madita&lt;/a&gt; at the same time. Too starts very well, but I have a hard time getting excited much beyond that. I purchased this when I was iTunes-only for MP3s; I just now realized that Amazon seems to be short on her work, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to make of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00138F080?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Oracular Spectacular&lt;/a&gt; - MGMT : Listened to it a lot when I got it, but have had a hard time since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001R20GWW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Rendezvous&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- French Affair : I just need to purchase another album. I like this, but have to make a conscious decision to choose it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002L4BQVA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kate Earl&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Earl : Having just purchased this, it&amp;rsquo;s far too soon to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00260NOMS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Dancing The Whole Way Home&lt;/a&gt; - Miss Li : Another that I just purchased, but if I keep going as I am, this is one that will be near the top of my most played list &amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;ll have a few more of her albums in my collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disappointments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the albums that I wish I could take back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTNA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Underachievers Please Try Harder&lt;/a&gt; - Camera Obscura : Here&amp;rsquo;s another one that starts out good but quickly loses it&amp;rsquo;s flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001I851AM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Reverse Migration&lt;/a&gt; - Au Revoir Simone : While Au Revoir Simone made it on the top of my list, this album, consisting of remixes, is hit or miss. There are some songs I enjoy more here than the originals, but overall I should have just purchased one of their original albums sooner, saving this for last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TERLEK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;X &amp;amp; Y&lt;/a&gt; - Coldplay : If I wanted to listen to Bono, I&amp;rsquo;d listen to the U2 album I own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TEVHOU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Angel Milk&lt;/a&gt; - T&amp;eacute;l&amp;eacute;popmusik : I knew I needed to get something by this group, but it seems this was the wrong one to start with &amp;hellip; or was it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00168IJH6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Reasonable Doubt&lt;/a&gt; - Jay-Z : Maybe it was the wrong Jay-Z album to start with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0011YZ0VS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Four Thieves Gone - The Robbinsville Sessions&lt;/a&gt; - The Avett Brothers : I taped my feet while I was listening to previews, and thought it was a good recommendation, but haven&amp;rsquo;t listened to it after the first play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002K3XECQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ellipse&lt;/a&gt; - Imogen Heap : Speak for Yourself 2 it is not. It&amp;rsquo;s got some okay songs, but &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QQUXSM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Oaklandazulasylum&lt;/a&gt; - Why? : After some really good recommendations from my sister, I was hoping this would be another good one. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t, and even seeing them play in Madison didn&amp;rsquo;t help much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013D8G7C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Unplugged&lt;/a&gt; - Alicia Keys : A guilty pleasure, I&amp;rsquo;ve liked her other albums, but I just don&amp;rsquo;t find her as good live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001QD7SF0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Working On a Dream&lt;/a&gt; - Bruce Springsteen : I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Springsteen, but whether it&amp;rsquo;s because my tastes have changed, or he&amp;rsquo;s just not as good as he once was, this album was&amp;nbsp;a big disappointment for me. Seeing as how my feelings on his other albums have changed over time, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I just need to get a bit older to get into this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there it is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTunes Music to SQLite - version 0.1 beta released</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iTunes-Music-to-SQLite-version-01-beta-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2009 12:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iTunes-Music-to-SQLite-version-01-beta-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While it was at the same stage as it is now back on the 19th, I&#39;m finally releasing the beta version of iTunes Music to SQLite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This console application finds all Music playlists in iTunes and imports them into a SQLite database (called iTunesMusic.s3db).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can change this by passing the database and source names as parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;iTunesMusicToSQLite.exe &#34;datum.db&#34; &#34;James Skemp&#39;s 80 gig&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can run the executable and it will prompt for a key press before exiting, in case you want to view any messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a beta version, and was done more as a proof of concept than anything else, so this may be the only version released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;download&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/applications/iTunesMusicToSQLite_0.1.zip&#34;&gt;Download iTunes Music to SQLite 0.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.NET Framework 3.5 is recommended, and may be required (&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://smallestdotnet.com/&#34;&gt;check your version of .NET Framework&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Recommendations Please! - version 0.4.5 beta released</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Music-Recommendations-Please%21-045-beta-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 20:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Music-Recommendations-Please%21-045-beta-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An updated version of this application was released. &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Music-Recommendations-Please!-version-05-beta.aspx&#34;&gt;Download and find out more about version 0.5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one problem I have with music is when I try to find new music that I may like. Luckily there&amp;rsquo;s a number of services that will provide recommendations, but these are typically only based on one artist, or across my entire library (in the case of the iTunes Genius service).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this a bit easier, I looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Parsing-Lastfm-Web-Services-artistgetSimilar-with-C-and-LINQ-to-XML.aspx&#34;&gt;Last.fm&amp;rsquo;s Web services&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Parsing-Yahoo!-Musics-Artist-Web-Services-with-C-and-LINQ-to-XML-Search-for-artists.aspx&#34;&gt;Yahoo! Music&amp;rsquo;s Web services&lt;/a&gt;. After some playing around, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple working versions of a simple application that allows for artists to be found, based upon either one or more artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing Music Recommendations Please! This beta version will change significantly as I work towards version 1.0, but it&amp;rsquo;s a nice proof of concept. In fact, this may end up being a Web application &amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d also like to be able to tie it into the&amp;nbsp;output from &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/apps/iTunesPlaylists2Xml/&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml&lt;/a&gt;, so who knows. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to do both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application requires &lt;strong&gt;.NET Framework 3.5&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://smallestdotnet.com/&#34;&gt;check your version of the .NET Framework&lt;/a&gt;), an active Internet connection, and that should be it. Extract the contents to a directory, or just open the executable from the zip file, to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;download&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/applications/MusicRecommendationsPlease_0.4.5.zip&#34;&gt;Download Music Recommendations Please! version 0.4.5 beta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If&amp;nbsp;you have any suggestions on publically available APIs that I can use, please post them below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>