<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nintendo Ds on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/tags/nintendo-ds/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nintendo Ds on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 21:57:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/tags/nintendo-ds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Radiant Historia (2011)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Radiant-Historia-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 21:57:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Radiant-Historia-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004CVWETI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Radiant Historia&lt;/a&gt; (2011), released for the Nintendo DS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fantastic music and interesting branching story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ordered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004CVWETI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Radiant Historia&lt;/a&gt; back in February 2013 I&#39;ll readily admit that I played for only a few hours before I let it, and my 3DS, sit and gather dust. At the time the cheapest new copy of the game I could get was $70, so I was expecting much more from the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a few months ago, after finishing &lt;a href=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/words/Post/Review-Ghost-Trick-(2011)&#34;&gt;Ghost Trick&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to give Radiant Historia another chance. And now here I am, a little over a year and a quarter from when I first picked the game up, writing a review, having just finished it a few hours ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t exactly recall what caused me to put the game down, but having now gone through the game I think it may just been the wrong time for me, as both the story and music - two of the major reasons I typically enjoy RPGs over all other genres - are pretty dang good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The musical score at times reminds me of Final Fantasy VI, Nier, and Lost Odyssey. The branching storyline reminds me of Chrono Trigger (albeit it&#39;s definitely not as complex). The character art reminds me of Blue Dragon (or maybe just Raynie reminds me strongly of Zola).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay is perhaps the one slightly insignificant aspect, as while it does feature some complexity when it comes to moving the location of enemies on the 3x3 grid they inhabit, I found myself using 4 characters (including the main one who can&#39;t be swapped out) for most of the endgame, depending upon who I had access to in the storyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, I found the game to be really quite good, once I was able to really get into it. However, I&#39;m not sure how much of the 40+ hours I put into the game will stick with me down the road, especially given the fairly safe ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004CVWETI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Radiant Historia&lt;/a&gt; 4 of 5 stars, primarily because of the great music and story/mission structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Ghost Trick (2011)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Ghost-Trick-%282011%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 20:34:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Ghost-Trick-%282011%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002TDIEDG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Ghost Trick&lt;/a&gt;, released in 2011, for the Nintendo DS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What a very good game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very short while ago I watched a video that featured &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002TDIEDG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Ghost Trick&lt;/a&gt; briefly, and I fell in love with the graphic style of the game. After ordering it with some other DS games, for use on my 3DS XL, I decided that it would be the first of the batch that I would play, and therefore also one of the first games I had played on the system in months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this game I found myself saying &#39;what a great game&#39; aloud, after finding one thing or another that was amazing. While this is the first game of it&#39;s type that I think I&#39;ve played, I don&#39;t believe it&#39;ll be the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of the puzzles I had difficulty with, and ended up consulting a guide for the solution, but I&#39;m sure I would have figured them out, had I not been more interested in the story than my pride of completing it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is definitely the strongest aspect of the game, although the art style and gameplay are not too far behind. With a few twists and turns, and a fantastic (and slightly tear-invoking) conclusion, Ghost Trick will stay with me for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can easily give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002TDIEDG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Ghost Trick&lt;/a&gt; a full five of five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh why can&#39;t I find a reason to buy a current gen portable console?</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Oh-why-cant-I-find-a-reason-to-buy-a-current-gen-portable-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2010 17:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Oh-why-cant-I-find-a-reason-to-buy-a-current-gen-portable-console/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spent a great portion of the day researching current gen portable consoles; the Nintendo DS(i) and Sony PSP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLB for the latter was disappointing (I&#39;m not much of a sports fan, so no surprise), but the Pokemon (I&#39;m ashamed to admit) game was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of the stores in Madison actually carried the Metal Gear PSP bundle I would have purchased it, even though I logically have a difficult time justifying it. I think PSOne Classics and 3rd Birthday (which isn&#39;t even out until 2011) are the only things I keep consistently coming back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For variety the DS seems to be the winner, but with the 3DS coming out next year, reviewers say to hold off until then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&#39;s no reason to purchase an iTouch when my iPod is working just fine, and I could purchase a DS and a PSP for the price I&#39;d end up paying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the talk of classic Gameboy titles coming out for electronic download/purchase for the 3DS is true, as well as backwards support for DS games, I&#39;ll surely pick one of those up at some point next year, but otherwise ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
