<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philip K. Dick on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/philip-k/index.-dick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philip K. Dick on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 20:40:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/philip-k.-dick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Gospel According to Philip K. Dick</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-The-Gospel-According-to-Philip-K-Dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 20:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-The-Gospel-According-to-Philip-K-Dick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;m a fan of PKD, but this documentary fails in a number of major areas, making it almost useless in its scope. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First of all, the animations that are used in place of slides are annoying beyond _, but I suppose if they trimmed those up they&amp;#39;d only have an hour of play time. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The music reminded me of Assault on Precinct 13, and while it wasn&amp;#39;t too bad, it was utterly diabolical when it was close to drowning out the interviewed individuals while they spoke. Definitely some audio issues that needed to be taken care of before this film was rolled out. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The interviewed individuals mostly provided interesting perspectives, but, overall, much of this information can be found in any of the numerous books on PKD&amp;#39;s life. Some of the interviews should have been trimmed altogether, since they seemed to offer no real value. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I really wanted to like this documentary, but I truly struggled to watch the entire thing; the possibility that Williams or Wilson would offer some insight was all that kept me going ... Otherwise, the substance of this flick is pretty slim pickings. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Normally I&amp;#39;d give a film that I&amp;#39;m glad I watched, but didn&amp;#39;t overall care for, a three star rating, but the only reason I&amp;#39;m glad I watched this was because it showed me that I didn&amp;#39;t need to watch this. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ah well. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s a number of books on PKD that could be read instead, to much greater benefit, including Paul Williams&amp;#39; &amp;quot;Only Apparently Real&amp;quot;, and Emmanuel Carrere&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;I Am Alive And You Are Dead: A Journey Into the Mind of Philip K. Dick&amp;quot;. See also &amp;quot;The Shifting Realities of Philip K. Dick: Selected Literary and Philosophical Writings&amp;quot; for further insights.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Watched on Netflix online.)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Brian J. Robb&#39;s Counterfeit Worlds</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-Brian-J-Robbs-Counterfeit-Worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 20:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-of-Brian-J-Robbs-Counterfeit-Worlds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is the review that I wrote for Amazon.com for the book &lt;cite&gt;Counterfeit Worlds&lt;/cite&gt; by Brian J. Robb.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The book can be purchased online at Amazon.com: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1840239689?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=strivinglifen-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1840239689&#34;&gt;Counterfeit Worlds: Philip K. Dick on Film&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First off, I haven&amp;#39;t read too many books on films based upon the works of PKD. I bought this book because I&amp;#39;m a fan of Dick&amp;#39;s works, and the films that are closely linked to it (A Scanner Darkly primarily, but before that film came out, Blade Runner - the rest, to me, are like Vanilla Sky, and the Matrix; movies &amp;#39;using&amp;#39; Dick&amp;#39;s ideas).&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Secondly, I found this to be a very good overview of not only the films that were based on PKD&amp;#39;s works (Blade Runner, Total Recall, Screamers, Confessions d&amp;#39;un Barjo, Impostor, Minority Report, Paycheck, and A Scanner Darkly), but also his life (~32 pages), radio and TV adaptations, and upcoming/unmade projects (film and otherwise).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should read this book if;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
a) You&amp;#39;re interested in reading about PKD&amp;#39;s life,&lt;br /&gt;
b) You&amp;#39;re interested in reading about how some of his films ended up being made (those listed above),&lt;br /&gt;
c) You&amp;#39;re interested in reading about the influence that PKD&amp;#39;s works had on the realm of film in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You shouldn&amp;#39;t read this book if you want to find out more about the radio/tv programs based upon his works, since you won&amp;#39;t get too much from this book on these (not that you necessarily should).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you&amp;#39;re just interested in finding out more about Blade Runner, you&amp;#39;d probably be safe purchasing this book for that reason alone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s lots of pictures, the type is rather normal (small-ish, in a good way), and there&amp;#39;s some new content in this book - not just the author&amp;#39;s perspectives, but also new interviews, albeit only snippets from these - so you&amp;#39;ll certainly get your money&amp;#39;s worth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
4 stars because I didn&amp;#39;t &amp;#39;love it&amp;#39; - I thought it was very good, and I may end up looking at particular parts over again (and it got me to dust off my copy of Impostor for another viewing), but there&amp;#39;s no real reason to re-read the book, in my opinion.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scanner Darkly (2006) - best PKD movie ever?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/A-Scanner-Darkly-%282006%29-best-PKD-movie-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2006 20:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/A-Scanner-Darkly-%282006%29-best-PKD-movie-ever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This last weekend I watched A Scanner Darkly, which had just hit a local Madison theatre on Friday.  I&amp;#39;d been looking forward to the film since I&amp;#39;d heard about it, and since it promised to showcase a look like &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/waking-life-transcript-with-revisions/&#34;&gt;Waking Life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After watching the film, I was certainly impressed.  I was afraid that Linklater was going to add his own spin to it, but he actually did quite well.  Of the various movies based on pieces by Philip K. Dick, I&amp;#39;d say that A Scanner Darkly plays very close to the work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, when compared with Blade Runner, Scanner just doesn&amp;#39;t have the same stunning imagery.  Of course, it&amp;#39;s hard to compare any science fiction movie to Blade Runner, and especially difficult to compare a Dick-based movie to it (since PKD had some impact on Blade Runner - he was still alive for some of the shooting).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once Scanner hits DVD, perhaps it will become memorable, and I dare say it&amp;#39;s the second-best PKD movie thus far, and certainly one that mimics the novel the most (although a quick reading will show that it&amp;#39;s certainly not that close - less than 20 pages in will show one semi-major difference).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Great acting, and great imagery which was the best way this film could have been done (how else could they really do the suit?).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Definitely looking forward to purchasing the DVD - that&amp;#39;s what I&amp;#39;ll leave it at for now.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>