<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tablet on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/tablet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tablet on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 09:14:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/tablet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Belkin Universal Case and Cover for 7-Inch and 8-Inch Tablet, Ink</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Belkin-Universal-Case-and-Cover-for-7-Inch-and-8-Inch-Tablet-Ink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 09:14:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Belkin-Universal-Case-and-Cover-for-7-Inch-and-8-Inch-Tablet-Ink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00JKM0EQE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Belkin Universal Case and Cover for 7-Inch and 8-Inch Tablet, Ink&lt;/a&gt;, which I received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Actually like it more than my Supcase case&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Belkin Universal Case and Cover for 7-Inch and 8-Inch Tablet has a fairly low rating on Amazon as I write this, and has had a low rating since I ordered this a few weeks ago. However, having now used the case for a few weeks, I think I generally like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m using this with a second generation Nexus 7, instead of the Supcase case I had originally purchased for it. While I like Supcase products in general, I found that the power off was getting triggered too often when I moved the cover to the back of the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For better or worse this Belkin case doesn&#39;t have an auto-power on/off magnet, so that issue doesn&#39;t arise. However, it also means I must manually turn on the tablet, which after a few days of getting used to again, wasn&#39;t a big issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case also allows you to fold the back to angle the tablet. Unfortunately, after a few weeks use it&#39;s gotten fairly flexible, which means the available angles are limited. However, it does make for a nice holding spot, as I can grasp the angled cover in one hand, instead of resting the entire back on my palm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a 7-inch tablet there is a bit of extra space within the case. However, this hasn&#39;t been an issue, as I&#39;ve had no trouble with it getting tossed into my bag and then being messed up when I pull it out at work or home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I have experienced that the volume down button is close to the clasp keeping a side of the tablet in. However, it doesn&#39;t cover it up, so it&#39;s not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t use the camera on my tablet, but the folding corner does open a rather great deal, so as not to block any shots. It also flips back easily, so there shouldn&#39;t be an issue with it staying open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big issue is probably the price. At almost forty dollars the price is rather expensive. At half that it would be completely worth it. If you were using this for an 8-inch tablet it also might be worth around thirty. But with the quality of product you can get for less, I&#39;d recommend waiting for it to drop in price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based solely on the quality of the product, I give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00JKM0EQE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Belkin Universal Case and Cover for 7-Inch and 8-Inch Tablet&lt;/a&gt; 4 of 5 stars, as it&#39;ll be staying on my tablet. Taking into account the price I&#39;d have to drop off a star. However, since I&#39;d expect the price to drop, I&#39;ll stick with a 4 of 5 rating.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
