<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 19:09:51 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Amazon Fire 7 (2015 release) Case</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Amazon-Fire-7-2015-release-Case/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 19:09:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Amazon-Fire-7-2015-release-Case/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/21Crdpw&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire 7&amp;rdquo; (2015 release) Case - Slim Lightweight Standing Custom Fit Cover for Amazon Fire 7 Inch Tablet&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;not-as-good-a-fit-but-still-nigh-perfect:1e6bdfef9507fbe30ae96a8f4c7afa87&#34;&gt;Not as good a fit, but still nigh perfect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right around Christmas I was out shopping around for a replacement to my second generation Nexus 7, due to speed and battery issues. Within a couple days I had picked up one of the 2015 models of the Amazon Fire 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month later I received a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KASRLG&#34;&gt;Verso Fire 7 2015 Case&lt;/a&gt; for it, and while I tried it out, the material of the case, as well as it&amp;rsquo;s hinge and ribbon to keep it closed, were things that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too happy with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, around the same time I had the chance to try out one of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s cases for their Fire HD 8, and I loved it. Since it&amp;rsquo;s effectively the same thing in a smaller package, I&amp;rsquo;ll repeat some of what I said in my review of that here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first nice thing about the case is that it leaves all of the buttons free. While a case with button covers doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean the buttons require more pressure to be used, having them clear is so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case also features a pretty powerful magnet, which combined with the case wraps around the device, means that the cover stays in place, but can still be removed with relative ease. It also sticks quite well to the back of the case, which means that it has the same profile open or closed, with no slippage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I thought the oddest thing about these cases was that the cover folds in half diagonally. Within the box itself is the two ways this fold can be used to stand it up either in portrait or landscape view, but after three plus weeks, I still hadn&amp;rsquo;t gotten used to this, and had to play around with the flap a bit before I got it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the smaller model I&amp;rsquo;m quite used to it, and it basically feels natural. However, I do have a little trouble keeping my 8&amp;rsquo;s cover in place on some smooth surfaces. At this point I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this is because of usage, or if it&amp;rsquo;s because of the texture of the surface I&amp;rsquo;m setting it on. Time will tell if this is an issue with these cases in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the case feels pretty ridge, but still has some flex to it. It fits fairly snug around the tablet itself, but leaves enough of the device free for it be relatively flat on the top of the tablet itself. With the larger case this initially lead me to believe that it might pop out of the case, but thus far still have had no issues with it. However, with the case for the Fire 7 I have noticed that the Fire will very occasionally pop out a bit. It&amp;rsquo;s relatively minor, but I&amp;rsquo;m keeping my eye on whether the case is ever so slightly smaller than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, much like the Fire HD 8 case, I have to give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/21Crdpw&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire 7&amp;rdquo; (2015 release) Case - Slim Lightweight Standing Custom Fit Cover for Amazon Fire 7 Inch Tablet&lt;/a&gt; a full five of five stars. The case itself is pricey, especially compared with the AmazonBasics line, which I&amp;rsquo;m most familiar with, but the case quality is high, and works very well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Alienware Steam Machine ASM100-4980BLK Desktop Console (Intel Core i5, 8 GB RAM, 1 TB HDD) NVIDIA GeForce GTX GPU</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/review-alienware-steam-machine-asm100-4980blk-desktop-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 19:03:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/review-alienware-steam-machine-asm100-4980blk-desktop-console/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the [Alienware Steam Machine ASM100-4980BLK Desktop Console, featuring an Intel Core i5, 8 GB RAM, 1 TB HDD, and NVIDIA GeForce GTX GPU][1], received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-weird-hybrid:1c33e12b551c6ddfc11283fe6f1c9dff&#34;&gt;A weird hybrid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I&amp;rsquo;ve got to say I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to review the Alienware Steam Machine ASM100-4980BLK. Do I compare it to the consoles, as that&amp;rsquo;s what they&amp;rsquo;re trying to make (especially with SteamOS being the OS on this machine)? Or do I compare it to a Desktop computer, since the games you play are those you&amp;rsquo;d typically play on a PC? Or is it something new, like tablets were many years ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to think of it as a hybrid between the two, so that&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ll review it, for better or worse. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be focusing solely on the SteamOS version of this system. Since that&amp;rsquo;s how they sell it, that&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;m going to review it. If you want to know how it performs with Windows, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to look elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we compare it to a console. With the processing power being what it is, and the ability to upgrade some components of it, I consider the system to be on-par with a current gen console, which to me means the PlayStation 4 and Xbox One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the operating system, I put SteamOS somewhere between the PS4 and Xbone. The PS4 has, what I consider, to be a great interface. Not as good as the PS3&amp;rsquo;s, but good nonetheless. The Xbone&amp;rsquo;s interface is nowhere near as good as the 360&amp;rsquo;s interface was, and isn&amp;rsquo;t even as easy as the Windows 8.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; interface it tries to replicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SteamOS&amp;rsquo;s interface shares some similarities with the standard desktop interface, but does have a learning curve. This is especially noticeable when you use the Stream controller, as the d-pad must be used to navigate, as opposed to the d-pad or left stick. It baffles me that they&amp;rsquo;d do this. There&amp;rsquo;s also the issue of being unable to access pieces of the interface you see, such as being able to press up to get into the downloads/settings area, even though you see them, unless you back out far enough. Either don&amp;rsquo;t show components I can&amp;rsquo;t access, or show them differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games are definitely at the center of the SteamOS interface, much like on the PS4 (and not so much on the Xbone), but given the nature of the library being shared between all your PCs, the library, by default, contains all games you own, not just those that you can install and play on the console. The library can be filtered, but as far as I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this has to be done every single time. The games you&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded do display in a different area, so there&amp;rsquo;s at least that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up we have the controller itself, which the console (noted as &amp;lsquo;Console Only&amp;rsquo; on Amazon) does include. It&amp;rsquo;s, quite frankly, pretty dang cool. It&amp;rsquo;s effectively a reversed Xbox 360/One controller, but with only one actual stick. However, the pads work pretty dang good. However, the button placement, especially of the Start, Back, and bumpers, are still taking me a while to get used to. The face buttons too, mess me up for a little bit, as they&amp;rsquo;re placed in a location contrary to the PS and Xbox controllers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after a couple long sessions, I can honestly say I never noticed the controller in my hand, like I would with the Xbox 360/One, and to a lesser extent, the various PlayStation controllers. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s the balance, or the way the grips are bent, or something else, but it just feels good. Heck, it might even be the placement of the face buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also played one game with the controller mapping to a keyboard (I actually had to create a custom controller mapping for the game), and for the simple tasks I needed to do, it worked quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve looked at it from the console perspective, how about from a desktop? Since it&amp;rsquo;s running a version of Linux behind the curtain, Windows-only games aren&amp;rsquo;t going to run. However, some have had luck running non-SteamOS games, that would normally run on Linux, on this console. I was tempted to try this out with a couple GOG games, but after reading through the forum posts on it, decided it wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth a try yet (although might be if GOG releases a Linux client for their interface).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I wanted to try out the SteamOS, and not purchase a Windows license, about a quarter of the games I own on Steam could run on the [Alienware Steam Machine ASM100-4980BLK][1]. This included some high-end games (BioShock Infinite, Pillars of Eternity) and mid-range games (City Skylines), but also a lot of lower end, or indie, games. Sadly, for me this meant that while I tried to go SteamOS-only, I ended up back on my main machine more than I would have liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem is probably developer support, and having seen it first-hand, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the future of the SteamOS is. If Steam puts a lot of weight behind it, then it might do well. If developers don&amp;rsquo;t keep releasing their games for SteamOS/Linux, then &amp;hellip; at least you can install Windows on the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So compared to a console, it&amp;rsquo;s probably on par, more if you don&amp;rsquo;t expect to be able to play every Steam game on it, and less the smaller the percentage of games in your library that will run on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to a typical Windows machine running Steam, it&amp;rsquo;s a lesser experience, assuming SteamOS is left on the machine. The controller is nice, but you could save yourself some money and just purchase the controller by itself. Or just get the standard which is a wired Xbox 360 controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last note to make before my closing is that my machine restarted way more than I would have expected. It seemed to have been increased after installing the beta updates, but even before I was running into random restarts when navigating around the interface. Thankfully the system didn&amp;rsquo;t restart when I was playing any games, but it worries me when I&amp;rsquo;m just navigating around the interface and the machine just goes black and restarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had one game which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t download (0 bytes downloaded of 0 bytes). I tried numerous things to debug this, but it seems to strike some users with some games. Download speeds also seemed a little slower than usual, but I attribute this more to the Steam network, as I very rarely get the maximum speeds from even the Windows client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So all that said &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rate the [Alienware Steam Machine ASM100-4980BLK Desktop Console][1]. If you come into it expecting something on par with a Windows gaming PC, you&amp;rsquo;ll be sorely disappointed. But if you come into it as someone wanting to get a taste of what PC gaming is like, and you don&amp;rsquo;t have a big catalog of games, this might not be a bad way to get started. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to find a SteamOS game that doesn&amp;rsquo;t also run on Windows, so you&amp;rsquo;d be free to upgrade (and upgrade is what it would be) to a real gaming PC down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone with a big catalog of games, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid middle of the road for me; 3 of 5 stars. As a console, it&amp;rsquo;s 4 stars. As a gaming PC running SteamOS, it&amp;rsquo;s 3 stars. If this were the Windows version, the latter would probably (considering all else) jump to 4 stars. But would the console aspect suffer? That I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1L3RU4m&#34;&gt;http://amzn.to/1L3RU4m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: ZAGG Slim Cover, Ultra-Slim Bluetooth Tablet Keyboard for Microsoft Surface Pro 3 and 4 (MC3WKK-BB0)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/review-zagg-slim-cover-surface-4-mc3wkk-bb0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 20:17:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/review-zagg-slim-cover-surface-4-mc3wkk-bb0/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TxgNYG&#34;&gt;ZAGG Slim Cover, Ultra-Slim Bluetooth Tablet Keyboard for Microsoft Surface Pro 3 and 4 (MC3WKK-BB0)&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;actually-on-par-with-the-official-type-cover:0d9adfc3adb2cd2b0aef31302877af51&#34;&gt;Actually on par with the official type cover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I purchased my &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1WzBRfc&#34;&gt;Surface Pro 4&lt;/a&gt; a number of months ago I opted to spend the extra money to get the official type cover with it. Having used a couple other two-in-one machines, getting used to the keys wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the ZAGG Slim Cover up for review I jumped on it, as I wondered if they could do better. Having used it for a couple weeks now, I can honestly say the ZAGG Slim Cover is on par with the official covers, with some things being better, and some not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have the packaging. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to take this out of the packaging. Slice the tape, slip the bag with it out, and then then connect it to your Surface with Bluetooth. A USB cable to charge the keyboard (it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use the Surface for power) is also included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the device is about the same thickness as my Surface Pro 4. This is a bit of downside, since &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Txh1Pe&#34;&gt;the official type cover&lt;/a&gt; is really thin. Because of the size and weight it also doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily feel like it&amp;rsquo;s going to stay covering the Surface like the official one does. I didn&amp;rsquo;t run into any issues with this, but I put my Surface in an Amazon Basics case when I put it into my bag, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too many chances to test this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plus side of the depth of the keyboard is that the keys actually feel fairly normal. Not like a desktop keyboard, but closer to a traditional laptop. I also assume that the battery is another reason for the size. The only issue I had with the keys was a broken left arrow/Home key. The top of the key wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stay seated in the device. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the type cover this keyboard does have backlit keys, however they&amp;rsquo;re either on or off, unlike the type cover&amp;rsquo;s range of brightness. Having used the type cover&amp;rsquo;s variable brightness this is actually a bit of a disappointment. Had the ZAGG keyboard been my first, I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have cared as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up we have the battery. Surprisingly, I have yet to need to charge the battery on the device, although I did bounce between the two covers for all but the last week and a half. I also tend to use my Surface for some work meetings, and between 10 minutes to a couple hours after work / on the weekend. So, I can&amp;rsquo;t say I&amp;rsquo;ve put 40 hours of use into it over the last 3+ weeks, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely more than a couple days. So while I thought having to charge the device would be an issue, it actually seems pretty efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up we have how it connects to the Surface. This is actually the biggest downside, as if you connect it like you would the official type cover you&amp;rsquo;ll find that the taskbar is covered up slightly. At first this actually bothered me, but then I started disconnecting the keyboard from the Surface, and/or keeping it flat. The portability, especially when I was in bed at night, is something I&amp;rsquo;d miss if I had to go back to just my type cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s Bluetooth, this also means it can be used with other devices, with the ability to pair and bounce between two. I didn&amp;rsquo;t test this too much, but it worked as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a few minor points. I rarely used the trackpad on the device. Clicking felt odd to me, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably more because of how little I use it (I&amp;rsquo;ve used an external mouse since I got my Surface, and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t switch back). For the very occasional mouse usage it worked fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is still taking a while for me to get used to is the function keys. F1-F12 serve two purposes, with the default being the special functions. For example, F1 pairs with Bluetooth device 1, F2 with device 2, F5 pulls up settings, and F12 turns up the volume. As a web developer I use F5 and F12 a lot. And I keep screwing up and neglect to push the Fn key when I use these! F2 is another I mess up, but seemingly everytime I try to use it to rename a file. However, given that I rarely do this, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly muscle memory to blame. It would have been nice if the default was the function keys, much like how the Delete key acts as the power button if you hold down the Fn key while using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned above that I had a loose key, and used a replacement keyboard. I ended up contacting ZAGG support to see if they could assist me with the Home key issue. I was hoping they might be able to send a replacement key that I could swap in. I emailed in on a Saturday, around 11:30 a.m., stating the issue (leaving out that I was reviewing the product for Amazon), and received a response around four hours later. On Tuesday they had sent out a package with a replacement, which I thought was just going to be a key, but when I got it Friday (3-day shipping) it was a new keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have to contact them because I didn&amp;rsquo;t receive information on shipping the old product back, but (again on a Saturday) I received a response that I&amp;rsquo;d be getting an email with the necessary UPS shipping label. I still have to go through the rest of that process, and will update this review once the warranty is taken care of completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the ZAGG keyboard was going to be able to match what Microsoft did in the type cover. But while the type cover has some advantages (backlit key variability, size, power via the Surface), the ZAGG keyboard wins out in other cases (portability, keys, ability to use with other devices). Knowing what I know now, I think I might actually recommend that people take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TxgNYG&#34;&gt;ZAGG Slim Cover, Ultra-Slim Bluetooth Tablet Keyboard for Microsoft Surface Pro 3 and 4 (MC3WKK-BB0)&lt;/a&gt; when picking up a Surface Pro 4 (or 3), instead of just going with the Microsoft type cover. For effectively matching the type cover, I give the ZAGG Slim Cover a full five of five stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Belatedly, I received the UPS mailing label and was able to get the keyboard with the faulty left arrow shipped off without issue. I had no issue with them receiving it, and have had no issues with my replacement keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Sennheiser HD 471G Headset with Inline Mic and 3 Button Control</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/review-sennheiser-hd-471g-headset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 21:32:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/review-sennheiser-hd-471g-headset/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1QcXE7G&#34;&gt;Sennheiser HD 471G Headset with Inline Mic and 3 Button Control&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;high-build-quality-and-terrific-sound:86eff25c7b82a356b95ce46fde09bb58&#34;&gt;High build quality, and terrific sound&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably a decade ago I had a coworker who lent me a pair of her Sennheiser headphones for a couple hours one day. I was looking at picking up some nicer headphones, and she thought that listening to her&amp;rsquo;s might sway me, I think. While they certainly sounded good, I&amp;rsquo;m not much of an audiophile, so for me, compared to cheap headphones the difference in quality just wasn&amp;rsquo;t that different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;m getting older, but after trying out the Sennheiser HD 471G headphones I&amp;rsquo;m a convert. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s first talk about what comes in the box. We have the headphones themselves with a standard plug, as well as a 6.3 mm adapter. However, it also includes a second, longer cable, with the ability to swap them out. It also includes a nice bag to put the headphones in, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t end up using. It&amp;rsquo;s soft, instead of a hard case, so you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect it to keep them protected in bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headphones feel pretty dang good, with a nice balance between being light, but not feeling cheap. On the head they also feel quite nice. The thickness of the top portion did take me a little while to get used to, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal. Otherwise I generally didn&amp;rsquo;t even notice these were on, save when the top bumped up against something when I rested my head back. Super comfortable, with no risk of slipping off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;ve got the sound quality. I used these with a Nexus 7, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TY1Fmi&#34;&gt;Kindle Fire HD 8&lt;/a&gt;, an Asus Transformer Book, and a Surface Pro 4. Quality across all of them was great, with a mix of Google Play music, YouTube videos, Netflix, and hours of a series on Funimation. I tried a wide range of sound, from both quiet talking to louder shows/movies, and was quite impressed by the sound, with no distortion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this said, as someone who had looked at Sennheiser in the past, but not been impressed after a short time with them, I can honestly say that I might have just needed to do so in order to get an idea of how good they actually sound. If you&amp;rsquo;re already looking at these, I&amp;rsquo;d say they&amp;rsquo;re worth it. They sound great, and they seem to have a good build quality. If you&amp;rsquo;re on the fence about whether it&amp;rsquo;s worth dropping so much on a set of headphones, if you see yourself wearing them a couple hours a day, or every other day, it might actually be worth giving these a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1QcXE7G&#34;&gt;Sennheiser HD 471G Headset&lt;/a&gt; a full 5 of 5 stars. For better or worse, I think my time with them made me a convert.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Amazon Fire HD 8 (2015 release) Case</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Amazon-Fire-HD-8-2015-release-Case/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 19:50:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Amazon-Fire-HD-8-2015-release-Case/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1S7nlgy&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire HD 8 (2015 release) Case - Slim Lightweight Standing Custom Fit Cover with Auto Wake/Sleep for Amazon Fire HD 8 Tablet&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Nigh Perfect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was looking at tablets since my second generation Nexus 7 is starting to get rather slow, and doesn&#39;t seem to want to hold a charge as well as it once did. After taking a look at a handful of devices I decided to pick up a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1S7oIvx&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire 8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, when you buy a new tablet you have to buy a case for it, so I was glad to see Amazon&#39;s case up for review on Amazon Vine. While I had initially looked at the case when I was purchasing an SD card for the tablet, I was a little turned away by the price. In fact, I was definitely turned away by the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, having now used the case for over three weeks I can honestly say this is one of the best cases I&#39;ve had on a tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first nice thing about the case is that it leaves all of the buttons free. While a case with button covers doesn&#39;t necessarily mean the buttons require more pressure to be used, having them clear is so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case also features a pretty powerful magnet, which combined with the case wraps around the device, means that the cover stays in place, but can still be removed with relative ease. It also sticks quite well to the back of the case, which means that it has the same profile open or closed, with no slippage. Do note that since the case can switch the power off automatically, once you put it into place initially you will have to switch it back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The oddest thing about the case is that the cover folds in half diagonally. Within the box itself is the two ways this fold can be used to stand it up either in portrait or landscape view. Honestly, I still haven&#39;t gotten used to this, and have to play around with the flap a bit before I get it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the case feels pretty ridge, but still has some flex to it. It fits fairly snug around the tablet itself, but leaves enough of the device free for it be relatively flat on the top of the tablet itself. This initially lead me to believe that it might pop out of the case, but thus far have had no issues with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only minor complaint I have with this case is the fold to get the tablet standing up. However, since I do keep it mostly open, this is probably more due to lack of use. For this reason, I have to give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1S7nlgy&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire HD 8 (2015 release) Case - Slim Lightweight Standing Custom Fit Cover with Auto Wake/Sleep for Amazon Fire HD 8 Tablet&lt;/a&gt; a full five of five stars. The case itself is pricey, especially compared with the AmazonBasics line, which I&#39;m most familiar with, but the case quality is high, and works very well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Verso Fire 7 2015 Case - Sea Blue Classic Slim Fit Premium PU Leather Book Folio Style Protective Case (7 inch Display - 5th Generation, 2015 Release Only)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Verso-Fire-7-2015-Case-Sea-Blue-Classic-Slim-Fit-Premium-PU-Leather-Book-Folio-Style-Protective-Case-7-inch-Display-5th-Generation-2015-Release-Only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 19:50:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Verso-Fire-7-2015-Case-Sea-Blue-Classic-Slim-Fit-Premium-PU-Leather-Book-Folio-Style-Protective-Case-7-inch-Display-5th-Generation-2015-Release-Only/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KASRLG&#34;&gt;Verso Fire 7 2015 Case - Sea Blue Classic Slim Fit Premium PU Leather Book Folio Style Protective Case (7 inch Display - 5th Generation, 2015 Release Only)&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;If only the hinge were better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was looking at tablets since my second generation Nexus 7 is starting to get rather slow, and doesn&#39;t seem to want to hold a charge as well as it once did. After taking a look at a handful of devices I decided to pick up a new Amazon Fire 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, over the course of the next couple days the price of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KAT6q4&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire 7&lt;/a&gt; kept nagging at me, and since I&#39;m a developer, and had some interest in developing for the Amazon Appstore, decided that I could splurge and get myself an early Christmas gift. Of course, that also meant that I needed to get a new case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I immediately noticed was the material the case was made with, and the second was the smell. While I&#39;ve since forgotten the smell, it lingered for the first handful of days, but was gone within a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The texture of the materials is still about, but hard to explain. It&#39;s smooth, but it has something that gives it a very slight texture. It&#39;s hard to explain, and is better than the inside texture, which is much more noticeable. I&#39;m not sure what it is, but if I rub my thumbs back and forth on it the sound and texture causes &#39;tingles&#39; in my upper back/neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we have the hinge, which based upon my review title, is the key sticking point for me. Unlike many other cases the back doesn&#39;t stay attached to the back of the case, but instead about two thirds fold away and are used for the stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While nice in principle, I instead found that if I wanted to hold the device as I would with a book, that the flexibility of the back and hinge caused the hinge to either fold oddly, or the top and most of the bottom to be too loose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other feature of the note are the buttons on the top of the case that cover both volume buttons and the power. While the volume buttons seem fine, with little more pressure required, the power button does require more pressure to switch on/off. The impact of this is fairly minor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the case itself fits snugly around the Fire 7, and the top cover can be held in place, covering the screen, with the attached band. In practice I found that putting one edge of the band in place was sufficient most of the time. It seems sturdy enough, but time will tell how long it lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the hinge is the biggest issue I have with this cover. For the 7-inch tablet I feel like my use case is as reading device, which means I ran into the hinge either buckling or sliding down far too often. Because of this I knock a star off and give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1KASRLG&#34;&gt;Verso Fire 7 2015&lt;/a&gt; Case 4 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Fury of Dracula Third Edition Board Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Fury-of-Dracula-Third-Edition-Board-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 09:24:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Fury-of-Dracula-Third-Edition-Board-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OkfQMt&#34;&gt;Fury of Dracula Third Edition Board Game&lt;/a&gt;, which I received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So many pieces, but easy after a week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t played any of the previous editions of Fury of Dracula, so I can&#39;t speak to the changes made in this third edition. However, as I understand it, the game has changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This supports 2 to 5 players, with one player controlling Dracula and the others controlling one or more of the hunters. This does mean that in a two player game one person is controlling all four hunters, which is how I played it for the purposes of this review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game has an approximate run time of 2 to 3 hours, which is why I&#39;m reviewing it from a 2-player perspective; it was difficult to find others to invest that much time, with the perceived difficulty, given the amount of pieces in the box. However, to some extent the difficult is lessened since certain cards that one would think are different, are actually the same. For example, while there are hunter and Dracula event cards, these are combined into a single pile during play. After playing a week of rounds in the game, we had it down pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&#39;ve seen them played, I haven&#39;t played a hidden movement game like this before. I rather enjoyed how it worked, with location cards being used to track where Dracula has moved, instead of using some sort of sheet and writing locations down. It also lessens the ability for Dracula to move backwards (although he can still be tricky to locate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game works with the hunters playing once during the day and then once at night, with Dracula then going at night. This cycle repeats for each day of the week, until either Dracula is defeated, or he wins. However, if the game doesn&#39;t end after a few weeks Dracula starts gaining influence (his way of winning) at a very steady rate. So the game does have some maximum number of turns, based upon how the players do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game itself seemed relatively balanced, which I understand wasn&#39;t the case in earlier editions, with Dracula having a slight advantage. At first I found this to be slightly interesting since Dracula has a number of disadvantages, having less turns and allowing the players to find where he&#39;s been, since Dracula&#39;s last six locations can (generally) be discovered. He also can&#39;t backtrack, since the last six locations aren&#39;t part of the location deck he uses to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as was evident when Dracula was discovered to have moved into Italy, it&#39;s still possible for him to evade capture, as he did when he traveled by sea for three turns, opening up the number of possible locations he could have landed at. He can also leave behind encounters at locations he visited, which may either cause immediate harm, or if left as-is, help him slow down the hunters or finish the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last note is that unlike some games, in Fury of Dracula no player is completely out of the game. While hunters can be defeated, they eventually recover health and can continue on the quest. Each hunter has their own advantages and disadvantages, so no one hunter necessarily dominates over the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the board components themselves are of quite nice quality. The game includes five figures, which are of nice quality (and could potentially be painted), a nice quality board and cardboard pieces, and nice cards. The artwork is of note since it matches the style of the game relatively well. We did find that two of the figures were easy to mistake at a quick glance, which unfortunately did lead to combat happening with a character that should not have been in combat. However, with three or more players, closer attention, or perhaps a paint job, this wouldn&#39;t be an issue. It also only happened once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the only downside I found was the amount of time it took, which was closer to four hours, but was also our first time. Otherwise, when I can find people that will play it, much like Betrayal at House on the Hill and BioShock, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OkfQMt&#34;&gt;Fury of Dracula, Third Edition&lt;/a&gt; will be a game I&#39;ll recommend we try. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Adonit Jot Dash - Fine Point Precision Stylus</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Adonit-Jot-Dash-Fine-Point-Precision-Stylus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 11:29:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Adonit-Jot-Dash-Fine-Point-Precision-Stylus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the Adonit Jot Dash - Fine Point Precision Stylus, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Not what I was expecting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part I&#39;m not yet at the point in my life where I need to use a stylus pen for my electronic devices. My fingers are the right size, and with devices getting larger, I don&#39;t need the precision. I&#39;m also not much of an artist, so it&#39;s not necessary to draw. However, with Windows 10 ending up on almost all my devices, and touch screens on all my laptops, I did want to try using a stylus for some creative outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before receiving this as part of the Amazon Vine program I was using, off and on, a pen with the nub on the eraser part that would be picked up by touch devices. However, since I had played with it, or because it was cheap, the nub wouldn&#39;t stay on. The opportunity to try a real stylus was something I was looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1HPVyaN&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Adonit Jot Dash - Fine Point Precision Stylus&lt;/a&gt; wasn&#39;t what I was looking for. I love how the stylus feels in my hand, and I like how it looks. The magnetic charging base is pretty nice, as it allowed me to hang it down from the USB drive on my primary PC during charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested it with a Samsung Galaxy S4, 2nd Gen Nexus 7, and two Asus tablets/laptops running Windows 10. On all devices it was recognized without issue, without having to install or enable anything. However, it didn&#39;t perform as well as I would like. On both my Android devices it seemed a little off. What may have been the cause is how I actually used it, since the tip isn&#39;t as soft as I would have liked. Instead, every time I used it I felt as though if I pressed down too hard I&#39;d end up with a scratch in my screen or screen protector. While it hasn&#39;t caused any damage, I do wish it had a bit of give, or was more rounded than it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did like the simple indicator when the device is powered on/off (green or red light). It&#39;s relatively simple to use, so it doesn&#39;t include any instructions in the box, just a few paragraphs on the back on how to power it on. It being rechargeable is also quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, however, since it doesn&#39;t include any software, multi-touch devices may still register other input (such as palm) when this device is used. I also really wish the tip felt softer, so I wasn&#39;t afraid to use it. For these reasons I give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1HPVyaN&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Adonit Jot Dash - Fine Point Precision Stylus&lt;/a&gt; a neutral 3 of 5 stars, which would have translated to a 3.5 if I could have. It definitely works with every device I tried it with, but I think my usage will be limited, and only with devices that have screen protection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Panasonic ER-GB60-K Precision Beard and Hair Trimmer for Face/Hair</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Panasonic-ER-GB60-K-Precision-Beard-and-Hair-Trimmer-for-FaceHair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 17:20:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Panasonic-ER-GB60-K-Precision-Beard-and-Hair-Trimmer-for-FaceHair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1O06RSk&#34;&gt;Panasonic ER-GB60-K Precision Beard and Hair Trimmer for Face/Hair&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program. Spoiler: I really like them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finally, something that works with my beard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right away I&#39;ll say that I haven&#39;t used these to clip the hair on the top of my head. I have some barbershop-quality clippers from Wahl that I use for that, and I&#39;ve had no reason to try anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for my beard I&#39;ve tried a few clippers, the last of which were a lower-end set of Wahl clippers. They worked okay but they just didn&#39;t seem to clip as well as they should. Since I&#39;m on a quest to find something that will work for my beard, when I saw these through the Amazon Vine program I knew I had to give them a go. And now, after trying the Panasonic ER-GB60-K Precision Beard and Hair Trimmer, I have no reason to search any further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Panasonic ER-GB60-K is pretty simple, with only two set of clipper guards. However, these can be moved by the adjustable knob built into the body of the clippers to support a wide range of beard lengths. The maximum length is 20mm, so if you want something longer you&#39;ll have to look elsewhere. However, between the two guards you can get 1-20mm of length, so a great range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really does it for me is how well these clips. My professional Wahl clippers cut every time, while the lower end ones would end up tugging a bit on hairs (I blame the short blades). The blades on these clippers are on par with the professional Wahl ones, which means that you can expect hairs to be cut each time, no pulling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no problem with holding the clippers, and the cut angle feels natural. This doesn&#39;t have any attachments, however, so if you want to trim any smaller areas these won&#39;t work. However, for the beard this won&#39;t be an issue, and you might use scissors to be a little more precise on a mustache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing that slightly worries me is the adjustable knob itself. I&#39;ve never had it slip, but for some reason it just doesn&#39;t click as solidly as I&#39;d like. Again, I haven&#39;t experienced any issues with it, but it&#39;s something I&#39;ll keep an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1O06RSk&#34;&gt;Panasonic ER-GB60-K Precision Beard and Hair Trimmer&lt;/a&gt; exceeded my expectations, and is absolutely worth a full 5 of 5 stars. If you have a beard in the 1-20mm range, definitely give this a look.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Homeland: The Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Homeland-The-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:51:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Homeland-The-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OH1avz&#34;&gt;Homeland: The Game&lt;/a&gt;, provided to me as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A sort of board game Resistance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading through the rules for the first time I kept thinking about the game &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1PFllJu&#34;&gt;The Resistance&lt;/a&gt; (although there are many games like this). In The Resistance every character is either part of the resistance, or part of a group trying to sabotage them. As the game progresses you start to figure out who&#39;s who, in an attempt to score a win for your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homeland: The Game, is sort of like that, although here you have terrorists, politicians, and the feds, with the terrorist trying to cause havoc, the feds trying to prevent it, and the politicians trying for a &#39;healthy&#39; amount of both. Like other variants missions come in, with each player playing as needed. However, in this game it might turn out that you can only play cards that will threaten the mission, even though you want it to be squashed, and vice versa. There&#39;s also, depending upon how many people you play with, a chance that there won&#39;t even be a terrorist or politician in the game (there&#39;s always at least one of two though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first open the box you might be surprised by the thickness of the rules, combined with the number of pieces you need to punch out. However, the rules do have a number of photos from the show (which I have not seen). They&#39;re still a little complicated, but as you play you&#39;ll get the hang of it pretty quickly. It also comes with cards detailing the turn actions, which is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board itself is a little unfortunate. It&#39;s constructed well enough, but it&#39;s sliced in an odd spot. As the game progresses you end up moving cards from one end of the board to the other. However, the way it was cut results in the inability to smoothly slide half the board&#39;s cards up. A cut from north to south, instead of left to right, would have been preferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the cards are also half-sized, but the way these are actually used during play works out rather well. It just results in a little trouble shuffling them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game will play 3 to 6 players, with a length of 90 minutes. The more players you have the more tricky it might be (in a good way), but you can also expect play to go longer as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many others I haven&#39;t seen the show, so I can&#39;t speak to that, but I hope to get in a game with someone who has seen it (and also loves these types of games), and will update the review once that&#39;s happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OH1avz&#34;&gt;Homeland: The Game&lt;/a&gt; a 5 of 5. I&#39;ll update once I&#39;ve had the opportunity to play with more people, but the components are well constructed (minus the cut placement in the board), the game plays well without needing to know the source material, and it even comes with, very nice, little marines and agents you can use during the game. Recommended for people who like games like The Resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Nightmares from the Deep: The Cursed Heart (2012)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Nightmares-from-the-Deep-The-Cursed-Heart-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 12:14:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Nightmares-from-the-Deep-The-Cursed-Heart-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/259740/&#34;&gt;Nightmares from the Deep: The Cursed Heart&lt;/a&gt; (2012), available on Steam and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1WbKptb&#34;&gt;for physical purchase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A good way to get into the genre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I played the Steam version of this game, and this review is based upon that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first real hidden object game I played, thanks to a kind Reddit user who gifted me a key. It was actually quite good, with great artwork. The animated bits suffer from a bit of pixelation, but it doesn&#39;t detract too much from the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The puzzles are relatively easy, but the hint option is there if you need it (just make sure you don&#39;t accidentally hit it while walking about :( ). It took me about four and a half hours to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/259740/&#34;&gt;Nightmares from the Deep: The Cursed Heart&lt;/a&gt; gets four of five stars, and seems to be a good way to get into the genre.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous Base Set</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Pathfinder-Adventure-Card-Game-Wrath-of-the-Righteous-Base-Set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 17:52:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Pathfinder-Adventure-Card-Game-Wrath-of-the-Righteous-Base-Set/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1FLqFDn&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous Base Set&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Too soon to tell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the Pathfinder Adventure Card Game available from Amazon Vine I jumped on the chance to give it a try. Unfortunately the complexities of the game currently result in this partial review. This review will be updated in the coming days and weeks as we further play the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason the Pathfinder Adventure Card Game jumped out at me is because the idea of a tabletop RPG has appealed to me for a very long time, but I don&#39;t have the group of friends that (I thought) would be interested in it. It seems you need someone who&#39;s interested in DMing or GMing, and I just don&#39;t know anyone like that anymore. The premise behind the card game version of Pathfinder is that you don&#39;t need a gamemaster (GM), as each player is, to some extent, that role. See also the Sentinels card game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The box itself contains another room for the base set and the eventual expansions. I think I would have liked it to be a bit more like Dominion, where you could see where the cards went without consulting the rules, and so that the various expansions could be slipped in without keeping their original packaging. However, it works for what it is, and I think it&#39;s fine in the sense of each player keeping a consistent character over the course of the game. I have no fear about the components getting mixed up when the box is closed (although one corner or another tended to stick a bit every time I tried to close it), and it tends to sit on it&#39;s side when not in use. It&#39;s a big box though, so lugging it back and forth resulted in me giving up and just leaving it at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules are pretty dense, and while I had read them before hand we ended up reading them as a group before starting as well. You can also expect the initial setup to take at least 30 minutes, so plan accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards themselves seem to be of a good stock, and feature some really fantastic artwork. In a way it almost made me recall decades ago when I played Magic: The Gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ... that&#39;s sadly all I can really say at this point, since we realized we were playing wrong and restarted our adventure. But from what I&#39;ve seen thus far, the quality of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1FLqFDn&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous Base Set&lt;/a&gt; gives it a current 4 star rating. Updates will be woven into the review, and noted at the bottom of this review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Dimension: The Spherical Stackable Fast Paced Puzzle Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Dimension-The-Spherical-Stackable-Fast-Paced-Puzzle-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 18:20:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Dimension-The-Spherical-Stackable-Fast-Paced-Puzzle-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Y5qoXn&#34;&gt;Dimension: The Spherical Stackable Fast Paced Puzzle Game&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fun, but I don&#39;t think it&#39;ll turn into a staple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Normally I&#39;d work this into my review, but it&#39;s a little harder this time. As noted above this is a review of a product I received for free, through Amazon. I try very hard to not let that impact my rating.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lauge Luchau, the creator of Dimension, was once an architect. After first opening the game, reading the instructions, and after playing it, I can definitely see that&#39;s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dimension is a fairly simple game. You&#39;re given a total of 15 balls - three of five different colors - and a board to use to stack them into a pyramid. Each other player (1-4 players can play at a time) has the same setup. A set of six cards are flipped up, which determines the rules of the first round of play, and then each player has a set amount of time to create a pyramid of balls that follow those rules. Rules might include that the number of green balls need to be higher than the number of orange ones. Or every black ball must touch a blue ball (and vice versa).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can break some of the rules, and lose a few points, but sometimes you have to to get one or two more points (or end up balancing out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a relatively simple idea, but it can lead to some rather different structures. When it does. Unfortunately sometimes the random selection of rules is pretty clear-cut, and the &#39;smartest&#39; people will end up with the same score, with others falling a few points behind because they ran out of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The build quality of the pieces is extremely high. The balls appear to be very high quality, and should last through years of play. The boards are simple, and as long as they&#39;re treated well, should also last (they&#39;re a fairly heavy stock, with a nice thickness). The cards are on the smaller size, so shuffling for an adult isn&#39;t the easiest, but they work fine enough (just don&#39;t expect the first half dozen rounds to be very diverse :) ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately the question I have about games is whether they&#39;ll become a gaming staple. And sadly, I&#39;m not sure Dimension will be. I kind of think of it like &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1LuVY7k&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Mad City&lt;/a&gt;, which involves building a 3 x 3 city from square tiles. One of my co-workers really enjoyed the game, but the rest of the group would tend to gravitate toward something a little more complex, or ... strategic. Yet, Dimension does have a complexity to it, but more &#39;scientific,&#39; in a way. I unfortunately don&#39;t have access to any, but part of me wonders if children might like the game more, as I think it would be a fairly good way to really get them thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with all that said I bounce between whether this is a 4 or 3 star game. On the one hand it features a high build quality and is fairly fun to play. On the other hand, it, as others have mentioned, is a little niche, and probably outside of what I&#39;d generally go for. You can have high build quality in a crap game (and this isn&#39;t a crap game), so that has to be tempered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ultimately I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Y5qoXn&#34;&gt;Dimension: The Spherical Stackable Fast Paced Puzzle Game&lt;/a&gt; a high three of five stars. If I had kids, and they enjoyed this, I think my rating might be a little higher, but personally it&#39;s not going to be in my top half dozen choices for a game I&#39;m going to grab to play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Batman Fluxx</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Batman-Fluxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 06:41:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Batman-Fluxx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onhv54&#34;&gt;Batman Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Not just a minor tweak of Fluxx&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was introduced to Fluxx well over a year ago (I think it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onh4aI&#34;&gt;Oz Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;) I&#39;ve been interested in the game. Thus far I&#39;ve played &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onh4aI&#34;&gt;Oz Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OnhfCY&#34;&gt;Zombie Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1g3jrnl&#34;&gt;Pirate Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1EIvoLe&#34;&gt;Cthulhu Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, having purchased the latter in July 2014. When I saw that a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onhv54&#34;&gt;Batman Fluxx&lt;/a&gt; was up for review I wondered how the game would play compared to the others, and requested a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now played Batman Fluxx in our lunch gaming group I can honestly say it plays quite well, and will definitely keep it in my bag for future lunches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick and dirty about Fluxx is that the game starts with the rule of draw one card and play one card (starting with three cards in your hand), with no win condition. However, as play proceeds new rules can be played, such as draw 3 or play 4, as well as win conditions, such as having four villains. Ever-changing rules and goals (win conditions) lead to a very interesting game, where one person might think they&#39;ll win in a particular way, but conditions change before they can (such as a hand limit 3 getting played).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each variant of Fluxx adds something to the game, and for Batman Fluxx I would say it adds tools and ways to deal with villains (creepers, which either prevent you from winning or satisfy win conditions). The tools include ways to increase your draw, play count, and hand size, as well as ways to steal keepers (cards that satisfy win conditions) and handle creepers. The action cards are pretty standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the cards each variant of Fluxx seems to have a general play time. Cthulhu Fluxx, for example, can tend toward shorter play times, as it can have multiple goals in play (goals and ungoals) and no one can win. Zombie Fluxx, from what we could remember, tends to have longer play times. Thus far I&#39;d say Batman Fluxx tends toward longer sessions as well. A number of rules allow for a variety of free actions, so depending upon which are selected, and what keeper free actions there are in play, each person&#39;s turn can go longer than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the artwork is based upon the cartoon version of Batman. It looks good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onhv54&#34;&gt;Batman Fluxx&lt;/a&gt; is a good deal of fun, and is different enough from the other variants that it&#39;s worth a pickup even if you have a different variant already. If you&#39;ve never played Fluxx, but it sounds interesting, and you like Batman, give this game a try. I&#39;m sure you can find a reason to say &#34;I&#39;m Batman,&#34; in a deep growl, while playing it. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the above reasons I give Batman Fluxx a full five of five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2015 tablet recommendations</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/July-2015-tablet-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 15:12:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/July-2015-tablet-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is an email I sent on July 23, 2015, to someone who was looking to purchase her first tablet. It&#39;s now a month out of date, but I hope it helps someone, or is historically interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair warning this is a long email, but you don&#39;t have to read it all. If you want to skip ahead I&#39;ve put bold text to help you skip around. You can either keep reading now, or skip ahead to the bold text in parens below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first question was going to be whether you have a smartphone, but when I was talking to Jenn this morning she told me that you have a Samsung smartphone, which I&#39;m guessing means you have an Android-based phone. If that&#39;s not the case, let me know, as that opens options a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d say if you&#39;re comfortable with your phone, that&#39;s good, as you have tons of Android-based tablets to select from (and they&#39;re cheaper than the iPad variants :)). There are some nice 2-in-1 tablets, but based upon what you&#39;ve said I don&#39;t think you need one. And if you stick with Android any games or apps you purchase should be able to be installed on either your phone or tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next question is price range. I&#39;m going to keep it near the low end, but not cheap range. Ignoring the iPad I bought years ago, I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve spent more than $300 on any of the three tablets I&#39;ve purchased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my standard recommendation appears to be harder to find (Nexus 7), I&#39;m going to pretend that I&#39;m going to purchase one. I did talk to my mom, who got my old Nexus 7 tablet, and who appears to have usage similar to what you&#39;re looking for. She noted she would like one that has a larger screen, so I&#39;ll keep that in mind. I&#39;m also going to try to recommend stuff that is local, so you can hopefully go to a store and actually try them out (and take a look at how nice it looks, speaker sound, and weight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Here&#39;s the first area you can skip to.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something you might want to keep in mind is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1CT70Wo&#34;&gt;Amazon Fire TV Stick&lt;/a&gt;. They&#39;re about $40 from Amazon and use an HDMI connection on your TV. It uses your home&#39;s wireless to connect into a number of streaming services like Netflix, Hulu, Amazon Video, and YouTube. I&#39;ve been happy with mine and my mom has had no issues with the one I got for her. You can use an Android phone or tablet as a remote, and at least for the YouTube part you can search for a video and then have your TV actually play it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another alternative is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1JhZzc6&#34;&gt;Chromecast&lt;/a&gt; which offers similar functionality. I haven&#39;t personally used one, but I have some friends who purchased them and were happy with them. They&#39;re a little older now, but $10 cheaper. I think this might also require either a laptop, phone, or tablet, while the Amazon stick can be standalone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I mention these is because casting from a tablet to your TV is either going to require that your tablet have an AV connection out (rare, and then you&#39;ve got a cord) or some sort of dongle for your TV. So, it&#39;s another piece of hardware, but it might be cheaper and easier than buying a tablet that supports the connection out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, tablet time. &lt;strong&gt;If you don&#39;t want to read through all that I wrote (I don&#39;t blame you, I wrote way more than I thought I would :) ), if you scroll to the end of this message I list my three recommendations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I&#39;m going to do is head over to bestbuy.com so we can actually physically see the tablet. They&#39;ve got decent prices, but they do tend to cycle through items fast. I&#39;m going to limit my search to tablets in the $100-$500 range (but realistically $100-$300), Android, 4 or 5 star, and available through Best Buy, and not their marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how many good results this gives us, I&#39;m going to change my limit to the $100 to $249 range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve used Samsung, Asus, and Lenovo hardware and have been pretty happy with all three, except the Lenovo had mediocre screen resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s not many Lenovo models, so I&#39;m going to strike those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asus has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestbuy.com/site/asus-zenpad-7-85-intel-atom-32gb-black/7650139.p?id=1219681450081&amp;amp;skuId=7650139&#34;&gt;ZenPad&lt;/a&gt;, but it just came out last month. Despite positive reviews so far, I wouldn&#39;t want to recommend that to you at this point. It also has no reviews on Amazon, and I always like to look at Amazon reviews. But, it does have a nice amount of space, Android 5.x (current), and a very nice screen. Seeing speakers on the front also suggests it might have nice sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us down basically to the Samsung Galaxy Tab A and Tab 4. I&#39;m striking the Tab 3 because they&#39;re putting them on clearance to get them out the door, and they&#39;re an older version of Android, which means they might not get new updates. I&#39;m also not a fan of the border size on them, and the screen resolution isn&#39;t that hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tab 4 has Android 4.x, while the Tab A has 5.x. Honestly, version 4 of Android is pretty stable, so I wouldn&#39;t instantly jump to the Tab A. You&#39;ll also notice that the Tab A has a lower resolution, despite being an inch larger. Amazon reviews seem to consistently bring up the poor resolution. Given your requirements, and my personal experience with a tablet with a poor resolution (but great sound), I&#39;d take the Tab A out of the running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leaves us with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-4-7-8gb-black/5420045.p?id=1219127073673&amp;amp;skuId=5420045&#34;&gt;Tab 4&lt;/a&gt;. Reviews are quite good about this, and while the 8 GB of space is pretty low, it does support a microSD card up to 32 GB. But it&#39;s also a 7 inch tablet, which might be a little small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, while Best Buy lists an 8.4 inch Tab Pro, it&#39;s on clearance and there doesn&#39;t appear to be any in stock locally. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1MqO2cq&#34;&gt;Amazon has one listed&lt;/a&gt; for ~$240. Reviews are positive, and the screen resolution appears to be (from reviews and specs) pretty dang good. It&#39;s also got double the space and supports an SD card too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switching over to Amazon and starting fresh, with similar filtering, the Samsung Tab 4 tops &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1ekH4qy&#34;&gt;that list&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All that said ... if it were me, I would:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestbuy.com/site/samsung-galaxy-tab-4-7-8gb-black/5420045.p?id=1219127073673&amp;amp;skuId=5420045&#34;&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab 4&lt;/a&gt; at a local Best Buy. $150&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you might like the extra 1.4 inches, you could see if you could find a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1MLnb88&#34;&gt;Samsung Galaxy Tab Pro 8.4&lt;/a&gt; locally, or take a chance and buy one online. $240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to live on the edge, maybe take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bestbuy.com/site/asus-zenpad-7-85-intel-atom-32gb-black/7650139.p?id=1219681450081&amp;amp;skuId=7650139&#34;&gt;Asus ZenPad 7.85&#34;&lt;/a&gt; at a local Best Buy. It&#39;s early in the product&#39;s lifecycle, so if you&#39;re not in a hurry you should be able to wait and see how it reviews over the next couple months. $200&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry about the length of the email, but hopefully that helps. I&#39;d be curious what you end up doing, and if you decide to wait a bit can certainly take another look at things for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>