<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wacom on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/wacom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wacom on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 20:07:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/wacom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wacom and Digital Innovator</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Wacom-and-Digital-Innovator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 20:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Wacom-and-Digital-Innovator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Some time ago, I purchased a Wacom Graphire (the larger 6 x 8 model) direct from Wacom (since the local shops either didn&amp;#39;t carry or were sold out).  Since then, I&amp;#39;ve completed two surveys and received two DVDs from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalinnovator.com/&#34;&gt;Digital Innovator&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the one hand, the Digital Innovator series is a big plug for Wacom&amp;#39;s digital pen solutions.  The users in the videos primarily use the Cintiq family of products which, quite frankly, are amazing.  Yet, at the same time, you&amp;#39;re given pretty good tips on how to use the technology - both hard and soft - to both create something amazing, and do it quickly and easily.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For what the DVDs provide, $30 is a bit steep.  Yet, as an incentive, they&amp;#39;re worth their weight in gold to Wacom.  Having used my Graphire tablet at home for the last number of months, I&amp;#39;ve found it to extremely intuitive, and it seems as though my wrist has been hurting less because of it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, a) I work with text so much that a mouse (something that I can easily set down, nudge, ...) has it&amp;#39;s benefits and b) I only use it at home - I have a standard mouse at home.  Nonetheless, I would only trade my Graphire for one of Wacom&amp;#39;s other products.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>