<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strivinglife on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/categories/strivinglife/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strivinglife on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 14:04:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/categories/strivinglife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye BlogEngine.NET</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Goodbye-BlogEngine-NET/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 14:04:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Goodbye-BlogEngine-NET/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/Post/BlogEngineNET-now-used-by-StrivingLife&#34;&gt;July 13, 2007&lt;/a&gt; I converted my blog over from WordPress to BlogEngine.NET (having previously used custom code written in PHP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great switch, as I was beginning to really dig into .NET, and I&#39;ve found there&#39;s no better way to learn something than actually doing something with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don&#39;t think I did much with the beta, I was in on 1.0 and was fairly active at first. Mads eventually switched focus, and there were much more vocal users, so I slowed down, and eventually stopped visiting the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This switch is long overdue, but a short while ago I started on the process of moving away from BlogEngine.NET, and late last night (or very early this morning) I pulled the switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have some work to do on the functionality to actually create/edit data, but at this point it&#39;s been running pretty solid, with considerably less of a memory footprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m hoping for a nicer design at some point, as well as additional tweaks to the functionality, but moving away from BlogEngine.NET is the first step towards those goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief thoughts after 1 month of GitHub</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Brief-thoughts-after-1-month-of-GitHub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 08:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Brief-thoughts-after-1-month-of-GitHub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using GitHub for a little more than a month now, and it&#39;s been about 2 weeks since I shut down the machine running my local Subversion instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub for Windows needs some work, but given that Phil Haack is/was working on the Windows aspect, I feel pretty confident that it&#39;ll continue to get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving to a system that allows for public repositories also allowed me to publish some really old code, that might be of benefit to someone. However, I am now paying $7 a month something that I wasn&#39;t before. There is a free Git provider that I&#39;ve looked at (and that I might use as a backup), but there&#39;s a benefit to having everything in one place. And GitHub seems pretty solid in the Git space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/JamesSkemp&#34;&gt;View all my public repositories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to .NET 4 on an IIS site supporting a .NET 2.0 child application</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Upgrading-to-NET-4-on-an-IIS-site-supporting-a-NET-20-child-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 14:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Upgrading-to-NET-4-on-an-IIS-site-supporting-a-NET-20-child-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I decided to finally make progress on a couple pending applications. As part of that process I needed to upgrade one of my sites to .NET 4. Unfortunately it has a child application that needs to say as .NET 2.0/3.5. After approximately 30 minutes of downtime, I finally got things configured correctly (seemingly). Here&#39;s what I ended up having to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This assumes IIS 7.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrap the system.web and system.webServer elements in the parent Web.config with the following:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;location path=&#34;.&#34; inheritInChildApplications=&#34;false&#34; allowOverride=&#34;true&#34;&amp;gt;
...
&amp;lt;/location&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have the following set in system.webServer, you&#39;ll want to &lt;em&gt;move&lt;/em&gt; that outside of the location wrapper you added in step 1. Otherwise the site doesn&#39;t appear to capture that, and you&#39;ll 500.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;validation validateIntegratedModeConfiguration=&#34;false&#34;/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the application pool settings on the parent application to .NET Framework 4.0 and push the above change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the only change it appears I needed to make. Instead I made a number of minor changes, all over the place, which resulted in the downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my particular case I also had both the parent and child applications running on the same application pool. I ended up creating a new application pool for the child application, switched it over to that&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;, but neglected to set the identity as NETWORK SERVICE, which resulted in a few moments of questioning&lt;/span&gt;. Actually, I correctly set this to the application pool identity, but had actually neglected to give the correct directories the new permissions (since I changed the applicaton pool).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I&#39;ll be very happy when I re-write the child application over to .NET 4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 6 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-6-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 09:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-6-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will cover September 26, 2011 to approximately March 25, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;year 5, part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plan changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many years, on October 7, 2011, I dropped DVDs from my plan. I&#39;m running low on time to get to DVDs with all the great games being released, and the price jump is a bit more than I&#39;d like at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 3: Episodes 11 and 12.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 3: Episodes 13 through 15. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 4: Episodes 16 through 18.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 4: Episodes 19 and 20. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 5: Episodes 21 through 24, which finishes the season on a bang. I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday. (I did the latter, but since it&#39;s Columbus Day, mail isn&#39;t going out.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Per the advice of Bill Kummer, watched Hobo with a Shotgun (2011) streaming on my Roku. Giving it 2 stars because while the beginning credits were nice, Rutger Hauer and the main female character were both underutilized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - My DVD availability is no more. I now only have streaming access.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Mythbusters: Season 7 (2009): Episodes 1 and 2 streaming on my Roku, after trying a couple other shows out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Movie received by Netflix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Mythbusters: Season 7 (2009): Episode 3 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - While initially being turned off from the series, watched High School of the Dead: Season 1 (2010): Episodes 1 through 6 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched High School of the Dead: Season 1 (2010): Episodes 7 through 12, streaming on my Roku, which finishes the series. 3 of 5 stars, but it would have easily gotten 4 for great animation and a good dub, had the fan service not been so strong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 years of posts = a lot of comments</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/12-years-of-posts-equals-a-lot-of-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 17:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/12-years-of-posts-equals-a-lot-of-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I moved from my custom system to WordPress to BlogEngine.NET I never did end up copying over all the old comments on my posts. Heck, I don&#39;t even think I moved over all my posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But since I&#39;m sticking with DISQUS I decided to move all my BE.NET comments over to DISQUS, and over the last few hours have been making the necessary changes and performing the necessary cleanup.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a great extension that generated the XML for me (thankfully), but since I&#39;m me I&#39;m actually going through and removing the extra comments, so my data source is clean. And that may not have been the best idea ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I have to believe it is for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery Mobile version of my video game listing</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/jQuery-Mobile-version-of-my-video-game-listing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/jQuery-Mobile-version-of-my-video-game-listing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked up an electronic copy of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/1449306683?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;jQuery Mobile by Jon Reid&lt;/a&gt; a little while ago and have been slowly making my way through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve finally gotten to the point where I wanted to try creating a jQuery Mobile version of my video game listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xmlHtml/VideoGamesMobile.html&#34;&gt;View the jQuery Mobile version of my video games listing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jquerymobile.com/&#34;&gt;jQuery Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, this also uses &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.oxygenxml.com/&#34;&gt;oXygen XML Editor&lt;/a&gt;, for taking the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/video_games.xml&#34;&gt;original XML source&lt;/a&gt; and transforming it via &lt;a rel=&#34;external download&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xslt/VideoGamesMobile.xsl&#34;&gt;an XSLT 2.0 solution&lt;/a&gt; to generate the HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log Parser Plus June/July 2011 plans</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Log-Parser-Plus-June-July-2011-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 21:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Log-Parser-Plus-June-July-2011-plans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somehow, while I wasn&#39;t looking, the Log Parser Plus Web site has grown to what I consider a nice size over the last handful of months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/&#34;&gt;Log Parser Plus Web site&lt;/a&gt; moves towards 2000 visits a month I&#39;ll be making a number of changes in an attempt to make it even more useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some changes I&#39;ve already made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/New-Log-Parser-Plus-Web-site-design.aspx&#34;&gt;a new design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added login functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added ELMAH support. (Administrative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current plan with item number 2 is to potentially tie in OpenID functionality so that individuals can easily submit their own examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional changes planned for the coming weeks/months:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrate from XML sources to SQL. (Administrative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add information about XML parsing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add information about parsing text documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add information about running SQL from a file instead of via the command line (my preferred way to run queries).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add functionality for users to comment on individual examples. (May not happen, since I&#39;m not sure about demand.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add functionality to export queries to files, which goes along with item 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of the Log Parser book. (Having only skimmed it, this would be after I sat down and read it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an idea about something else? I&#39;ve just added a page to collect &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/Home/Feedback&#34;&gt;feedback on Log Parser Plus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Log Parser Plus Web site design</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/New-Log-Parser-Plus-Web-site-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 12:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/New-Log-Parser-Plus-Web-site-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/&#34;&gt;My Web site on Microsoft Log Parser&lt;/a&gt; gets a fair amount of monthly traffic, but I&#39;ve never really been happy with the design, which has been in place since I created the site back in September of 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was fully intending on updating the site last week (as well as doing a slew of other productive things), I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; did so this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/Content/Design-Version-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width: 480px;&#34; src=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/Content/Design-Version-1.small.png&#34; alt=&#34;LogParserPlus.com initial design&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/Content/Design-Version-2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width: 480px;&#34; src=&#34;http://logparserplus.com/Content/Design-Version-2.small.png&#34; alt=&#34;LogParserPlus.com second (current) design&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&#39;d say that&#39;s a positive change, for a non-designer such as myself. It&#39;s also the first of at least eight changes I&#39;ll be making to the site, in an attempt to increase traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the new design I upgraded to jQuery 1.6.1, from jQuery 1.5.2, and am now using NuGet to manage that, and also put in place the async Google Analytics code, amongst other, behind-the-scenes, changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I just have to redesign my professional site, although realistically I&#39;ll probably add the new functionality I&#39;ve been wanting to add first ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 5 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 21:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will cover March 26 2011 to approximately September 25 2011. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;year 5, part 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Castle: Season 2: Episodes 6 and 7 (2009).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Finished off the second disc of&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2, by watching Episodes 8 through 10 (2009). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Actually, the second one, which is disc 4, since disc 3 is still unavailable. Unfortunate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Changed to two DVDs at a time plan, for a little under $2 more, so I&#39;m not getting just a 25 minute movie and a movie I&#39;ve already seen this week. So, next one shipped. Received and watched Black Lagoon: Season 1: Disc 4 (2006), which, again, was unfortunate, since I&#39;d prefer disc 3 first. At least no spoilers. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 5, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Castle: Season 2: Episodes 11 through 13 (2009). Such a good series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2: Episodes 14 through 15 (2009). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, since I missed the mail person by just a dozen minutes today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie. Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 6, 7 and 8, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 9, streaming on my laptop. Watched Die Hard 2: Die Harder (1990), which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Firefly: The Complete Series (2002): Episodes 4 and 5, streaming on my PS3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 10, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2: Episodes 16 through 18 (2009) on my laptop. Perfect series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie, but I don&#39;t have time for it yet because ... I&amp;nbsp;watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2: Episodes 19 through 20 (2009) on my laptop, which finishes off that disc, which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2 (2009): Disc 5 (all four episodes). Such a sad ending, but ... five stars for the series that&#39;s given me so many ups and downs ... Home sick so hopefully it&#39;ll get picked up with the other disc later today.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 12 and 13, streaming on my laptop (episode 11 had audio issues). (Mail didn&#39;t get picked up, so I dropped off on Friday.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 14, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Times two.&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 15 was I had seen everything but the very beginning to (before the opening credits), and now I&#39;ve seen those few minutes. Watched Freeze Frame (2004), streaming on my laptop, which was a great thriller, with a good ending. Five stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Blackadder: Season 1: Episode 1 (1983), streaming on my laptop, which wasn&#39;t all that good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received next two movies. Watched The Walking Dead: Season 1 (2010): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 3. I remember why I didn&#39;t mind when I stopped reading the series ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched&amp;nbsp;The Walking Dead: Season 1 (2010): Disc 1: Episode 4, and&amp;nbsp;The Walking Dead: Season 1 (2010): Disc 2: Episodes 5 and 6. They&#39;ve changed things up, which is okay, as it keeps us guessing a bit. But I probably won&#39;t watch any more of the series, so 4 stars. I&#39;ll drop both off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer that I received with the first disc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Recieved next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched The Limits of Control (2008), which was relaxing, and completely not what was advertised. Instead, you have a sort of thinkers film, paced slowly, leading up to what you assume will occur. Watched some of the bonus feature, but not all. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Notting Hill (1999), which wasn&#39;t that horrible, and Firefly: The Complete Series (2002): Episode 6, which is still a good episode (and which features both of the SOCOM 4 trophy titles in it - perfect timing). Watched&amp;nbsp;The Twilight Zone: Season 1 (1959): Episodes 5 and 6. All of the above was streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Gothika (2003), which was really good, and kept reminding me of Drag Me to Hell. Although I don&#39;t think Halle Berry would have been wearing a bra in prison.&amp;nbsp;4 stars.&amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Unknown (2006), which was a rather good movie, with a good number of twists. I&#39;ll either drop it off or&amp;nbsp;let it get picked up today, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. 4 of 5 stars. Watched The Craft (1996) streaming on my laptop, which I had completely watched before. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Crazies (2009) streaming on my laptop, which was an average zombie movie. More of a maniac-type virus, though. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Berserk: Volume 1 (1997): Disc 1, all five episodes. The theme songs remind me strongly of some other anime series, which is escaping me at the moment. The first few episodes are a little confusing, but it does seem to be an anime for non-anime watchers. Moved the other discs to the top of my queue. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow. (Which it wasn&#39;t, so I&#39;m going to drop off Thursday.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Trailer Park Boys: Season 1 (2001): Episodes 1 through 4, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) -&amp;nbsp;Watched Trailer Park Boys: Season 1 (2001): Episodes 5 through 6, streaming on my laptop. They&#39;ll probably be the last episodes I watch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;The Twilight Zone: Season 1 (1959): Episode 13 and The Stand (1994): Episode 1, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched&amp;nbsp;The Stand (1994): Episode 2, streaming on my laptop, even though I said I wasn&#39;t going to watch any more. Received and watched Berserk: Volume 1 (1997): Disc 2, all four episodes. I get the impression that he&#39;ll soon break from the Griffith&#39;s group ... but I still don&#39;t understand if it&#39;s he that he fights later. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday. Watched&amp;nbsp;Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Corpse Vanishes (1989), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched Trailer Park Boys: Season 2 (2002): Episodes 1 through 3, streaming on my laptop. Watched Gamer (2009) streaming on my laptop, which, other than a few naseau-inducing scenes (camera), was pretty good. I&#39;ll give it 3 of 5 stars only because I won&#39;t watch it again, but it&#39;s otherwise a 4 star movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched all four episodes on Berserk: Volume 1 (1997): Disc 3 on my laptop. Great series. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Upped my plan tonight to 2 at a time (for 83 cents) so I can hopefully get another disc as soon as possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Another movie shipped, since I&#39;m at 2 at a time. Changed plan back to 1 at a time, that afternoon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Received and watched Berserk (1997): Volume 4, episodes 14 through 17, on my laptop. Getting close to the end ... Anyway, I&#39;ll probably let it get picked up tomorrow. Watched Gun X Sword (2005): Episode 1, streaming on my laptop, english dubbed. I think the ending theme of this is what I was thinking of regarding Berserk, but it&#39;s not the same ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Didn&#39;t get my next movie as expected. Watched Thirst (2009) streaming on my laptop. 4 of 5 stars, since it&#39;s a solid movie directed by Chan-Wook Park (Sympathy for Mr. Vengeance, Oldbody, Lady Vengeance).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Finally received Berserk (1997): Disc 5, and watched all four episodes on the disc. One more disc remaining ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Berserk (1997): Disc 6, all four episodes. Really disappointed that it&#39;s part of a manga and the show got cancelled before telling the entire tale ... Grr. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. 3 stars. Oh, and the anime probably isn&#39;t for first-time anime watchers. I&#39;m tempted to say more extreme than Drakengard, due to what happens to Caska.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Per the recommendation of Bill Kummer, watched Trinity and Beyond: The Atomic Bomb Movie () streaming on my laptop. It was unfortunately rather slow, and I think a little short on content, versus explosions/footage. 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Trigun: The Complete Series: Episode 1 streaming on my laptop. Maybe it&#39;s just the voice acting, but I can&#39;t find myself interested in this. Watched Session 9 (2001) streaming on my laptop. A lot of CSI crew at the beginning, but a good enough &#39;twist,&#39; albeit about what you&#39;d expect. 3 stars since I wouldn&#39;t go out of my way to watch it again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Didn&#39;t get the movie as expected. Watched The Twilight Zone: Season 1 (1959): Episodes 20, 16, 7, and 34, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Assume I received the next movie; I was out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Battle Royale (2001), again. Still as good as I remember it. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Dancer in the Dark (2000), which was very depressing (hence sitting on it for so many days). I&#39;ll let it get picked up today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Masque of the Red Death (1964) streaming on my laptop. 3 of 5 stars, since it&#39;s not his best work. Watched The Kids in the Hall: Season 1 (1989): Episodes 1 and 2. Must have watched these on Comedy Central way back in the day, since I think I&#39;ve seen both. Despite having seen it, watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 16 and Episode 17, which I had also seen, but a much longer time ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Getaway (1972), which was pretty dang good. One of the top heist/chase/get away movies I&#39;ve seen. 4 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Monty Python&#39;s Flying Circus (1969): Episode 1 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched MASH: Season 1 (1972): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 5. Removing the other discs from my queue, and I&#39;m up in the air on whether I&#39;ll watch any more episodes on the disc. It&#39;s a good show, but I could have gotten away with just watching a couple of episodes, instead of entire discs. Decided to just drop it off tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in, but I ended up dropping off Sunday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Wathced&amp;nbsp;Aaah! Zombies!! (2007) streaming on my laptop, which was actually pretty good. I liked what they did with the color - black and white for the world in which they are monsters, and color when it&#39;s just the group trying to stay alive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Recieved and watched The Mechanic (2011), which was a pretty dang good Jason Statham movie. Not sure about the ending, but it is hard to kill him. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Pilot Episode.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Episodes 1 and 2. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Recieved and&amp;nbsp;watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Episodes 3 through 5, of which I&#39;ve seen the last one before, with the crazy doll. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Cyber Wars (2006) streaming on my laptop. Slow pacing, and a kind of lower budget Johnny Mnemonic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Episode 6 and &#39;Bonus Episodes&#39; 1 through 3. More odd than good were these. 3 of 5 stars for the season. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, unless I&#39;m out driving tonight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Alice in Wonderland (2010) streaming on my laptop, which was really quite good. 4 of 5 stars. Watched Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 1 and 2 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episode 3 streaming on my laptop. I like the show, but I&#39;m a bit confused on how Buffy here is 16 years old, while I thought in the movie (which they keep alluding to) she was a Senior (dance/prom/whatever).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 1 through 5. I remember bits of the episodes, but don&#39;t recall the ending theme at all, nor the beginning theme being quite like it is. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episode 4 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 5 through 7 streaming on my laptop. Addicted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 6 through 10. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday morning.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 8 through 10 streaming on my laptop. Found an issue where episode 8 or 9 (demon in the network) lists her birth year as 1980, but episode 10 has it as 1981 on her gravestone. Whoops!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 11 through 12 streaming on my laptop, which completes the season. I&#39;ll be watching another.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched The Stupids (1996), leant to me by &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://conderman.com/&#34;&gt;Dan Conderman&lt;/a&gt;. Giving it 4 stars since I actually laughed out loud, and could watch it again (at which point I&#39;d probably drop it down to 3 stars).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 11 through 15. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 1 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and&amp;nbsp;watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 16 through 20. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt; or Monday morning&lt;/span&gt;. I&#39;m on a roll with Madison mailers ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episodes 2 through 3, and then later 4 through 5, streaming on my new Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 21 through 25. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 6, South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 1 and 2, and Married... with Children: Season 1 (1987): Episodes 1 and 2, all streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie, but I wasn&#39;t around.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 26 through 30. I&#39;ll drop it off in the next couple of days, since mail won&#39;t get picked up until Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 7 and South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 3 and 4, streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 5 and 6, streaing on my laptop.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 8 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 7 and 8, streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 31 through 35. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episode 9, streaming on my Roku. Also watched&amp;nbsp;Repo! The Genetic Opera (2008) on my Roku, and found the movie extremely good. 4 stars since I at least plan on telling others about this. Surprisingly, she&#39;s been in nothing I&#39;d consider good (based on a quick glance at titles and some descriptions).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 10 and 11, streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Streaming on my Roku I watched The Golden Child (1986), which I found to have poor pacing (3/5 stars), South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 12 and 13, which finishes the season and my time with it, and Kick-Ass (2010) which I found to be an extremely good movie. 4 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) -&amp;nbsp;Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 36 through 40. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episodes 9 and 10 streaming on my Roku. (And being sick, a bunch of the Ben Heck Show from Revision 3.)&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episodes 11 and 12 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 41 through 45. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Titan A.E. (2000) streaming on my Roku. The audio wasn&#39;t in sync and it was an overal &#39;eh&#39; movie. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 13 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000); Episodes 46 through 49, which ends the series. 4 of 5 stars, and features a nice bit of backstory, like the fact that White Fang (or the old man) seems to have been the driving force behind the Gundam pilots going to Earth, until the five scientists take control. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Sleepy Hollow (1999), which was actually pretty good. I was expecting the spirtual element to be fake, but was pleasantly suprised when it turned out that it was not. Initially gave it 3 stars, but bumped up to 4, although that would only last after one additional viewing. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Buffy the Vampire Slapyer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 14 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Sucker Punch (2011), which is surprising since it just came out, and which I found to be fairly good. At first I was expecting something akin to Brazil, but got something that featured a flashback instead. Not quite the ending I expected, but good nonetheless. 4 of 5 stars. Featured unskipable previews, but fast forward fixed that. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie. Watched Night of the Comet (1984), streaming on my Roku. It was actually a fairly good zombie movie, where here they&#39;re generated by dehydration. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Unknown (2011), which proves that Liam Neeson is becoming a rather good action/thriller/mystery genre actor. 4 of 5 stars. Once again featured unskipable previews. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday morning. Watched Tales From the Hood (1995) streaming on my Roku, which I had seen before a long time ago, and remembered being interesting (and I wanted something simple before I went to bed). 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Four Rooms (1995) streaming on my Roku. Fairly good, but once is enough, so 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Lady from Shanghai (1948), which was fine. The twists at the end were nice. 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched In the Name of the King: A Dungeon Siege Tale (2007), which was actually rather good, and had some fairly big-name talent. 3 of 5 stars, only because I wouldn&#39;t watch it again on my own, and I know of no one I&#39;d watch it with (currently). I&#39;ll drop it off today or tomorrow morning. Watched Lifeforce (1985) streaming on my Roku. Dan O&#39;Bannon had a part in this one, and I&#39;d honestly say it shows. 3 of 5 stars only because I wouldn&#39;t watch it again per se, but it&#39;s not too bad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Last Unicorn (1982), which is as good as a I remember it, though the ending really does come up quickly, doesn&#39;t it? 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched House of the Dead (2003), which was another Uwe Boll movie, and wasn&#39;t all that bad, although cutting to the game screens was annoying. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The American Nightmare (2000), which was much more about Vietnam than I expected. 2.5 of 5 stars, so 3. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Ichi (2008), which I found to be pretty good. I was initially going to give it 3 stars but decided upon 4 at the last moment. Recommended by Bill Kummer. I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched MST3K: Soultaker (1999) streaming on my Roku. I laughed out loud at a handful of parts, so 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Religulous (2008) which was interesting, but the focus was odd. 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. It was the third on my list for some reason.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mad Men: Season 1 (2007): Disc 1, which contained three episodes. Pretty good, but I&#39;m not sure I really want to watch the whole series ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Again, third movie on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Near Dark (1987), which was surprisingly good. Lance Henriksen plus a soundtrack provided by Tangerine Dream equals a fairly good experience. The ending is a bit weak, but not too shabby. 4 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Again, third movie on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Informant! (2009), which was slow, but okay. 3 of 5 stars. Watched From Dusk Till Dawn (1996), again, streaming on my Roku. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday, but since Monday is Labor Day it won&#39;t get picked up until Tuesday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Conan the Barbarian (1982) streaming on my Roku. 3 of 5 stars because of length, but otherwise I found it be rather good. Very De Laurentiis-like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Fire and Ice (1983) streaming on my laptop, since it doesn&#39;t want to load on my Roku. 3 of 5 stars since, once again, the ending flies through things. Pacing, folks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Again, third in my queue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched The Happening (2008), which I found to be pretty good, actually. 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. This time it&#39;s the second one! Watched X-Men: Season 1 (1992): Episodes 1 and 2 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched The Hobbit (1977), which was worse than I expected. Definitely for children who can&#39;t read and need something utterly mindless. 2 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Ninja Assassin (2009), which was slow at the beginning, and featured a lot of dark fight scenes. What I saw of the action looked good, but that they needed to hide it suggests the quality may not have been there. 3 of 5 stars primarily because I couldn&#39;t get a good look at the action. I&#39;ll try to drop it off tomorrow before noon (and I succeeded).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Kung Pow: Enter the Fist (2002) streaming on my Roku. I laughed at a number of spots, so 3 of 5 stars. Recommended by Jim Behan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 1: Episodes 4 through 5. I&#39;ll drop off in the mail tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 2: Episodes 6 through 9.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 2: Episode 10. I&#39;ll drop off the disc on my way to work this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite new (to me) music of 2010</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 10:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Favorite-new-to-me-music-of-2009.aspx&#34;&gt;the tradition started last year&lt;/a&gt;, I present my favorite albums purchased in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be on this list I must have purchased the album in 2010. This also doesn&#39;t include all albums I purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Easy winners&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013G64LY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;What Is Free To a Good Home?&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013G64TG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Knives Don&#39;t Have Your Back&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Emily Haines &amp;amp; The Soft Skeleton : Emily Haines was on my &#39;too hard to tell&#39; list last year, and this year I ended up picking up her four CD digital collection on iTunes. As you&#39;ll see later, all four of those CDs have made it on to my &#39;easy winners&#39; list this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0001ZX2L8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex Vol. 2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00020VZVQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Vol. 1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Yoko Kanno : Yoko Kanno does some very wonderful things with music. I have copies of most of the albums now, and one of my biggest purchases this year was for a hard copy of the Solid State O.S.T.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013FZIP8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Live It Out&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013FZIUI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Grow Up and Blow Away&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Metric : As noted above, I picked up a four CD collection of Emily Haines&#39; music. I haven&#39;t listened to these as much as I have the ones above, but ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00383YC2S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Une Enfant Du Si&amp;egrave;cle&lt;/a&gt; - Aliz&amp;eacute;e : Only Aliz&amp;eacute;e can get me to consistently pay for physical copies of albums, instead of waiting for them to be released electronically. I probably liked &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WZ8RB2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Psych&amp;eacute;d&amp;eacute;lices&lt;/a&gt; more, but this is still pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TEVJI4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Disparition&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001JK4UD8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Not Going Anywhere&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TEPEE4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Keren Ann&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Keren Ann : I&#39;ve become something of a big Keren Ann fan. The albums aren&#39;t all strong, but her total body of work elevates her into this heading. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXMS9A?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nolita&lt;/a&gt; remains my favorite album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000X71K0O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Lady &amp;amp; Bird&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Lady &amp;amp; Bird : Another of Keren Ann&#39;s, but this time with Bardi Johansen, who you&#39;ll see has made it onto my list (Bang Gang) further below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003B13QQU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Head First&lt;/a&gt; - Goldfrapp : I&#39;ve found Goldfrapp to be mostly hit (versus miss) with me, and this album has got a great 80&#39;s sound, that I generally find pretty near perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXOG4U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Understanding&lt;/a&gt; - R&amp;ouml;yksopp : The first R&amp;ouml;yksopp album that really clicked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TENKEK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Demon Days&lt;/a&gt; - Gorillaz : I really should have purchased this album years ago, but missed out on doing so until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Close calls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YBGU86?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Never For Ever&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Bush : Right after I got this I listened this quite a bit. I&#39;ve been very tempted to get her other works, but the ones that were highly recommended aren&#39;t available digitally yet. It&#39;s a great album, but not listening to it as much, and holding off on purchasing any more of her works makes me a bit nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YUERLO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Clocktower Park&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Walsh : As noted again below, I started with her &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002LOS33Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Acoustic EP&lt;/a&gt; and have begun looking into her other works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0034CEDAE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;IRM&lt;/a&gt; - Charlotte Gainsbourg : &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122ZAI2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;5:55&lt;/a&gt; remains my favorite of her albums. However, this has quite the different sound to it, in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002F6FQGK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Lungs (Deluxe Version)&lt;/a&gt; - Florence + The Machine : I played this album quite a bit when I first got it, but have started to let it sit unplayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QZXSXK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Tiny Cities&lt;/a&gt; - Sun Kil Moon : Heard one of his songs on the Gears of War trailer, and all-in-all I really enjoy this album. But, I&#39;ve yet to actually pick up one of his other albums ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003BB4VDW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Ballade Of Lady &amp;amp; Bird&lt;/a&gt; - Lady &amp;amp; Bird : After really enjoying &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000X71K0O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Lady &amp;amp; Bird&lt;/a&gt; I decided to pick up their other album. I gave the album 4 stars, and stick by that rating, but ... I&#39;m not sure why this stays here instead of further above ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001IASY40?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Historie De Melody Nelson&lt;/a&gt; - Serge Gainsbourg : An amazing album, with one of the first strong male singers I&#39;ve purchased this year. I also seem to be listening to it at a nice steady pace, which suggests it&#39;ll stay as one of my favorites for a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002MOL6DM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;11:11&lt;/a&gt; - Rodrigo Y Gabriela : Amazing guitar work. Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0041NG0VA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ghosts from the Past&lt;/a&gt; - Bang Gang : As mentioned above, I discovered his work thanks to his collaboration with Keren Ann. When another of his albums is re-released in approximately 10 days, I&#39;ll be picking it up. I&#39;m not so much as fan of the other album of his that I picked up, so ... we&#39;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7XUBE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Let&#39;s Get Out of This Country&lt;/a&gt; - Camera Obscura : Last year Camera Obscura was listed as&amp;nbsp;a disappointment for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTNA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Underachievers Please Try Harder&lt;/a&gt;. I think my point about it starting strong is still valid, yet here I went and purchased another of their albums. Clearly, there&#39;s something there, and I think having listened to Underachievers more has made that more visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Too hard to tell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DGJSTS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Tim&#39;s House&lt;/a&gt; - Kate Walsh : Her &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002LOS33Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Acoustic EP&lt;/a&gt; was an album that I had downloaded (I believe it was free at the time) and then forgot about until I &#39;discovered&#39; it one day. I started picking up more of her music, and while I enjoy this (&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000YUERLO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Clocktower Park&lt;/a&gt; made it onto my list above), it may just be too soon to tell ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003JEJWP8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Ghost Who Walks&lt;/a&gt; - Karen Elson&amp;nbsp;: I played this album a lot, and fear I burned out on it. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003REX5VC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Five Ghosts&lt;/a&gt; - Stars : Stars has popped up in my &#39;research&#39; for music before. Really, I just haven&#39;t had the album enough to confirm that I enjoy the album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003A4X0T6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;R.E.T.R.O.&lt;/a&gt; - mind.in.a.box : Heard one of the songs somewhere, and since I liked the previews picked this up. I&#39;m not sure what to think of it yet, since it seems there&#39;s a lot of hits, and very few misses ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00370CDE6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Something Wrong&lt;/a&gt; - Bang Gang : The album doesn&#39;t seem to fit as a whole, but this may just be an issue with not having enough time with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disappointments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003A9OVS0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Plastic Beach&lt;/a&gt; - Gorillaz : Stylo is perfect. The rest of the album? Not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000QQPRHE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Et Pourquoi les Crayons ?&lt;/a&gt; -&amp;nbsp;Am&amp;eacute;lie-les-crayons : An experiment trying to find foreign music that I really enjoyed. Just haven&#39;t listened to it as much as I should. There&#39;s a couple other albums that belong here too (by other artists), but this will serve as representing them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002POVIMS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;La Roux&lt;/a&gt; - La Roux : I should really like this, but I can&#39;t find a reason to press play, beyond a couple songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0040I95WC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drawing Down the Moon&lt;/a&gt; - Azure Ray : &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001RK1ZRY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Azure Ray&lt;/a&gt; was a good album, and while it may just be too soon, this doesn&#39;t live up to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122RF4O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;What We Forgot to Remember&lt;/a&gt; - Calamine : Like the previous entry, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ZU8M1Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Calamine&lt;/a&gt; was a good album, but this one doesn&#39;t have the same magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001G5VISQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Good, The Bad &amp;amp; The Ugly&lt;/a&gt; - Ennio Morricone : The soundtrack to &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003LVX7JG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Red Dead Redemption&lt;/a&gt; probably belongs here as well. Both have some great pieces, but the rest ends up sounding the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002JF9HEO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Beyond the Infinite&lt;/a&gt; - Juno Reactor : As happened with a couple other albums (not listed here), I&#39;d find one song I really like, the previews on the other songs would sound okay, and I&#39;d end up not liking the album as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004EI3ON4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Tron: Legacy&lt;/a&gt; - Daft Punk : Don&#39;t get me wrong. It&#39;s a good soundtrack, but not what I&#39;d consider a good Daft Punk album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00122N0P2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Soviet Kitsch&lt;/a&gt; - Regina Spektor : Ode to Divorce is great, but I think I burned myself out on Regina Spektor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003X73QA8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Suburbs&lt;/a&gt; - Arcade Fire : &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTCG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Neon Bible&lt;/a&gt; wasn&#39;t that good. This had a good song, but wasn&#39;t much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V63CYO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Aja&lt;/a&gt; - Steely Dan : I used to love this kind of music. This proved to me that my music tastes have changed for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes since last year&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000SXMS9A?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nolita&lt;/a&gt; has moved from a &#39;close call&#39; to one of my favorite albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it very&amp;nbsp;surprising that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000V3VT42?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Old World Underground, Where Are You Now?&lt;/a&gt; was listed as a &#39;too hard to tell&#39; album last year. This too has become one of my favorite albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000U7VTNA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Underachievers Please Try Harder&lt;/a&gt; should probably be moved from &#39;disappointments&#39; to &#39;too hard to tell,&#39; since I&#39;ve picked up another album by Camera Obscura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No other real changes need be made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTunes Playlists to Xml: Parsing categories with LINQ</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-Parsing-categories-with-LINQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 08:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/iTunes-Playlists-to-Xml-Parsing-categories-with-LINQ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently had the need to determine what types of music I had within my collection of music. Since I&amp;nbsp;created &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/apps/iTunesPlaylists2Xml&#34;&gt;iTunes Playlists to Xml&lt;/a&gt; so that I could export out my library on my iPod, it was easy enough to run that and then open &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.linqpad.net/&#34;&gt;LINQPad&lt;/a&gt; to run the following query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, you must export the Genre field in order for the following query to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;csharp&#34;&gt;// Location to the XML from iTunes Playlists to XML
String playlistXml = @&amp;ldquo;C:\Users\James\Projects\services\WcfRestService\App_Data\playlistXml.xml&amp;rdquo;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XDocument xml = XDocument.Load(playlistXml);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;var categories = from track in xml.Descendants(&amp;ldquo;track&amp;rdquo;)
    group track by track.Element(&amp;ldquo;genre&amp;rdquo;).Value into t
    orderby t.Key
    //orderby t.Count() descending
    select new {
        Category = t.Key,
        Count = t.Count()
    };&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;categories.Dump();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that you can switch the orderby lines depending upon how you want to sort the returned data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be something I eventually build into my application, along with other reporting features. I know that I&amp;rsquo;d love to have some comparision functionality, either built-in or as another application, so that I can see how my music tastes change, or if I&amp;rsquo;m consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sample output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some cleanup, sample output is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative - 279&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative &amp;amp; Punk - 154&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternative Rock - 282&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blues - 120&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books &amp;amp; Spoken - 145&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Children&amp;rsquo;s Music - 12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classical - 255&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country - 104&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dance - 76&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dance &amp;amp; DJ - 220&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy Listening - 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronic - 278&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronica/Dance - 91&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folk - 319&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;French Pop - 90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gospel &amp;amp; Religious - 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Rock &amp;amp; Metal - 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hip Hop/Rap - 88&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holiday - 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;House - 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial - 107&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Metal - 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jazz - 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J-Pop - 48&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J-Rock - 23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lo-Fi - 35&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metal - 82&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Age - 270&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop - 1225&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop/Rock - 26&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&amp;amp;B - 105&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R&amp;amp;B/Soul - 81&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reggae - 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rock - 3125&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soundtrack - 348&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World - 57&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 5 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 21:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, although only in how fast time has gone by, my fifth year of Netflix has begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers shipping with Netflix from September 26 2010 to approximately March 25 2011. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;the second half of year 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MRNOS = Movie received and next one shipped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Iron Man 2 (2010), which I actually really liked, and am surprised I received so soon after release. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Dreamscape: Special Edition (1984) streaming on my laptop. Quite a bit seems to have hit the cutting room floor ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Chasing Amy (1997). Haven&#39;t seen it all after all, although that&#39;s not too surprising. I&#39;ll probably let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Cool World (1992) streaming on my laptop. Eh. Surprised by cast and David Bowie singing closing song.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 1 through 7 (1996). Decided to watch the English versions, although geez that kid is a brat. I must have watched Season 2 or something, as the guy I&#39;m thinking of doesn&#39;t yet appear to be a part of this one. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episodes 1 and 2 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 8 through 14 (1996). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episode 3 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. I don&#39;t believe mail is being delivered today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received (a day earlier than Netflix thought) and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 15 through 21 (1996). I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 22 through 28 (1996). Saw the &#39;9000&#39; bit. And yes, they do stretch out these episodes ... I&#39;ll either drop it off this weekend or let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (Turned out to be the latter.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episodes 4 and 5 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episode 6 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Later watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episode 7 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 29 through 35 (1996), also known as big disappointments. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 36 through 39 (1996). And that is the end of season 1. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (I ended up dropping it off before the noon pickup.) Re-watched my copy of Sin City (2005). Really is a good movie. Bar scene with Nancy is one of the greatest, where color starts to soak in ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episodes 8 and 9 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Laughed hard during the second to last episode. Finally started watching Samurai 7, watching Episodes 1 through 6 (2004). It&#39;s been a while since I watched the film, but there&#39;s quite a bit I&#39;m remembering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 7 through 9 (2004) streaming on my laptop. Pace is picking up now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 10 through 13 (2004) streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Sling Blade (1996), which was actually really good. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. Watched Samurai 7: Episode 14 (2004) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Samurai 7: Episode 15 and 16 (2004) streaming on my laptop. Almost to the point where the movie ended.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Samurai 7: Episode 17 and 18 (2004) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched - the Director&#39;s Cut of - Max Payne (2008), which wasn&#39;t that bad. Granted, I don&#39;t know much about the video games, so ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 19 through 21 (2004), which was a bad place to stop, but ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 22 through 26 (2004), ending the series. Rather good, all-in-all, and ends about where the movie did. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Special Victims Unit: The First Year: Episode 1 (1999) streaming on my laptop. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 1 (2009) streaming on my laptop. Must remember not to fly through these this time ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/31/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 2 (2009) streaming on my laptop. Watched They Live (1988) again, via Google Video.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 3 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Mystery Men (1999), which was okay. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Romeo Must Die (2000), which was okay, thanks to the three (known to me) main actors. Not exactly sure that it&#39;s all that based on Romeo and Juliet, though ... I&#39;ll either let it get picked up tomorrow or drop it off.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 4 and 5 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 6 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Got in late, so only watched the first four episodes on It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 1 (2005).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched the rest of It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 1 (2005). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 7 and 8 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 9 and 10 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Sunshine (2007), which I&#39;m going to give 5 stars to. Part Alien, part Solaris. Predicatable, but good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 2 (2005). Turns out these aren&#39;t in the order they were released, but ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched The Cat Returns (2002), which had me smiling many times. What a delightful film. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Faster, Pussycat! Kill! Kill! (1965) on Google Video, since it&#39;s not available on Netflix streaming, which is one of the movies hanging up in my co-worker&#39;s cube. Eh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Thanksgiving is tomorrow, so I won&#39;t get it until Friday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 3 (2005). I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. I probably won&#39;t be watching any more of the series. Watched The Thing With Two Heads (1972) streaming on my laptop. Another from co-worker Dan Conderman&#39;s cube wall. Eh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Atlantis (1991), which was good, but when they tell you to forget the city and then have music/effects that feature city noises ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Wanted (2008), which was actually really good. I&#39;ll probably just let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (It wasn&#39;t picked up for some reason, so I&#39;ll drop it off on Monday.) Watched Christine (1983) streaming on my laptop, which it turns out I&#39;ve completely watched before now. Also makes me want to read some classic Stephen King.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 1 through 4, all streaming on my laptop. I didn&#39;t like the series a while back, but it&#39;s been growing on me, and starting from the beginning has vastly improved my opinion of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 5 through 6, all streaming on my laptop. Yup, I do enjoy the series now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 7 through 8, all streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 9 through 10, streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Cronos (1993), which was just re-released yesterday on DVD, and was about what I&#39;d expect from a Guillermo del Toro film. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 11 through 12, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Fast Times at Ridgemont High (1982), which was about what I expected. I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday morning, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 13, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 14, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 15 through 16, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 17, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched 25th Hour (2002). I forgot how September 11th focused the middle-ish was. It keeps the 4 star ranking. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched 8 Mile (2002), which I enjoyed well enough. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday morning. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 18, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order; Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 19 through 21, streaming on my laptop. Re-watched my copy of Blade (1998). I was going to re-watch the entire trilogy, and it&#39;s still tempting, but ... Finished Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), by watching episode 22, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched The Good, the Bad, the Weird (2008) streaming on my laptop, per the recommendation of Bill Kummer. Pretty good, with some very stylish parts. I&#39;m not exactly sure who the &#39;weird&#39; is, though.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Dance &#39;Til Dawn (1988), which really did start a classic 80s cast, including the beautiful Alyssa Milano. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. With the holiday, they say I&#39;ll get it Monday. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Crminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 1 through 4 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order; Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 5 through 7 streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Read or Die (2003), which was composed of what appears to be three episodes, making up a movie. Pretty good. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order; Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 8 through 10 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episode 11 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received next movie. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 12 and 13 streaming on my laptop. The family story begins to surface.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/31/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Ghost Dog: The Way of the Samurai: Special Edition (2000), which probably deserves another viewing to get a deeper meaning into it. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 14 through 16 through 19 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episode 23 (had already seen episodes 20 through 22 on tv) streaming on my laptop, which finishes up the season. Watched Rampage (2009), a movie that proves Uwe Boll isn&#39;t all that bad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 1, streaming on my laptop. Re-watched my copy of Blade II (2002).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 2 and 3, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Despite the unskippable trailers at the beginning, Inception (2010), which I received today, was amazing. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 4, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 5, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 6 and 7, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Ghost in the Shell 2: Music Videos (2004). It was okay. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 8 through 13, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 14, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Are You Being Served: Vol. 1 (1972), which consisted of six episodes. Funny parts, but generally okay. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the mangled mailer I received it in. (Was home ill, so it actually just got picked up.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 15 through 16, then 17 through 19 later, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 20 through 21, streaming on my laptop, which finishes off the season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Black Lagoon: Season 1: Disc 1 (2006), which contained episodes 1 through 4. I really enjoyed the series, and think the ending (show ending) suggests an ending like Cowboy Bebop, although maybe not ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Today is MLK Day, so I&#39;ll receive Wednesday. Watched Postal (2007), streaming on my laptop. Ridiculous and offensive. But, I laughed, so 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Surprisingly, received Black Lagoon: Season 1: Disc 2 (2006) today. Yet again the disc ended at a horrible spot, but I&#39;m still engrossed in the main character. The description on the slip is also completely wrong, and the ending is still an enigma. It&#39;s snowed quite a bit, and there&#39;s supposedly a very long wait until I get disc 3, so ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Actually, since 1 and 3 have a wait, and 2 and 4 are discs after those, they shipped number 5 on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Episodes 1 through 7 (1957), which is thus far an excellent series. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Street Thief (2006) streaming on my laptop. Pretty good fake documentary.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Again, this was actually number 5 on my list, although number 3 (number 4 is part 2) is available, so ...?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received next movie. Watched Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Episodes 8 through 9 (1957).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Episodes 10 through 13 (1957); two in the morning, and two in the evening. That finishes the disc, so I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. This time they sent the third movie on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Archer: Season 1: Disc 1 (2010), which contains the first 5 episodes. Laughed a handful of times. Not sure if I&#39;m going to get the next disc or not ... I&#39;m thinking I&#39;ll put it after Have Gun - Will Travel. Will either drop it off tomorrow or let it get picked up on Monday in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Everything is effectively closed down, so I didn&#39;t get the next movie today. Instead watched my new copy of L&amp;eacute;on: The Professional (1994) on Blu-ray. Watched the extended version for the first time. Really good. Think I&#39;ll pick up The Fifth Element on Blu-ray now ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Archer: Season 1: Disc 1 (2010), which contained the last 5 episodes. I&#39;m glad I finished the season off, but I think I&#39;m going to have to give the series 3 stars. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched 5ive Girls (2006) streaming on my laptop. Good. Reminds me of Drag Me To Hell a bit. Or at least the ending does.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched the first four episodes on Have Run Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 3 (1957). Still really like the show.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched the next two episodes on Have Run Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 3 (1957), in the morning. One episode left, which I watched after work. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Next movie received, but I was actually out for the entire day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched all six episodes on Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 4 (1957). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Close Encounters of the Third Kind (1977) streaming on my laptop. Giving it three stars, since this is the second time I&#39;ve watched it, but it&#39;s just alright.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched the first three episodes of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 5 (1957).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched the rest of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 5 (1957), which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched Commando (1985) streaming on my laptop. I feel like I&#39;ve seen parts of this before, but I&#39;m thinking not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched the first three episodes of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 6 (1957).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched the fourth episode in the morning, and the rest in the evening, of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 6 (1957). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Porky&#39;s (1981), which I can now say I&#39;ve seen. Eh. I&#39;ll let it get picked up Monday, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Futurama: Vol. 2: Episode 1 (1999) and Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 1 (2005) streaming on my iPod Touch with the Netflix app, that worked rather well.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;02/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Red Sonja (1985) streaming on my laptop. There&#39;s something about the movies like this of this period in cinema ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Sick, so I watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episodes 2 through 10 (2005) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Castle: Season 1: Disc 1 (2009), which contains the first four episodes. After the first episode I wasn&#39;t sure, but I think I&#39;ve grown to really enjoy the series. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Needed to kill some time, so I watched&amp;nbsp;Futurama: Vol. 2: Episode 2 (1999).&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 11 (2005) streaming on my iPad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched The Shining (1980) streaming on my PS3, with Laura. Changed my rating from 4 stars to 3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched my copy of Alien (1979) (although actually the Director&#39;s Cut) and Batman (1989), streaming on my PS3, with Laura. Changed my rating of the later from 4 to 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Castle: Season 1: Disc 2 (2009): Episodes 5 and 6. Really like the series now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched the last two episodes on&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 1: Disc 2 (2009). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 12 and 13 (2005), streaming on my iPad/laptop. Received and watched The Exorcist (1973), with Laura, which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. 4 stars. Watched Firefly: The Complete Series: Episode 1 (2002) streaming on my PS3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 14 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 15 (2005), streaming on my laptop. Watched my copy of Demolition Man (1993) on my laptop, and&amp;nbsp;Firefly: The Complete Series: Episode 2 (2002), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 16 and 17 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Castle: Season 1: Disc 3 (2009): Episodes 9 and 10. Really great series; put the next season at the top my list because of it. Tempted to give it 5 stars, but went with 4 ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 18 and 19 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Su) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 20 and 21 (2005), streaming on my laptop. Watched Spartacus (1960) with Laura. It was a bit longer than it should have been, but ... Will let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&amp;nbsp;Watched Firefly: The Complete Series: Episode 3 (2002) streaming on my PS3, also with Laura.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 22 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 23 (2005), streaming on my laptop, which finishes up the season. So ... watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5: Episode 1 (2005) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5: Episode 2 (2005) streaming on my laptop. Supposedly every other episode switches the cops, and they don&#39;t focus on the crimes as much as the main characters, so ... I might not watch many of these. Received and watched Castle: Season 2 (2009): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 5. Great start to the season. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5: Episode 3 and 4 (2005) streaming on my laptop. Nothing personal in these two episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon delivery schedules to Madison WI</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Amazon-delivery-schedules-to-Madison-WI/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 08:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Amazon-delivery-schedules-to-Madison-WI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been keeping track of this for a while locally, but since I have a hard time remembering where the file is, as well as to update it every time ... here&#39;s the delivery schedule I&#39;ve experienced with Amazon.com, for the free shipping option (unless otherwise noted). Most recent at the top, and does not include all deliveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;USPS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 6, 2010&amp;nbsp;03:51:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;December 6, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:27:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Out for delivery&lt;br /&gt;(M) December 6, 2010&amp;nbsp;04:29:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;December 4, 2010&amp;nbsp;04:51:07 AM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Departure Scan&lt;br /&gt;(Sa) December 4, 2010&amp;nbsp;04:51:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;December 3, 2010&amp;nbsp;06:17:56 PM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;(F) December 3, 2010&amp;nbsp;01:54:00 AM&amp;nbsp;US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Standard shipping)&lt;br /&gt;November 18, 2010&amp;nbsp;02:45:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;November 18, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:05:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;November 17, 2010&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Standard shipping)&lt;br /&gt;September 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;01:59:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;September 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:15:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Out for delivery&lt;br /&gt;September 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;05:06:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;September 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;04:23:46 AM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Departure Scan&lt;br /&gt;(T) September 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;04:23:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;September 13, 2010&amp;nbsp;05:05:27 PM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;(M) September 13, 2010&amp;nbsp;08:12:00 AM&amp;nbsp;US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(R) September 9, 2010&amp;nbsp;02:33:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;September 9, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:41:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Out for delivery&lt;br /&gt;September 8, 2010&amp;nbsp;10:14:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;September 8, 2010&amp;nbsp;07:14:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;September 8, 2010&amp;nbsp;05:31:42 AM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Departure Scan&lt;br /&gt;September 8, 2010&amp;nbsp;05:31:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;(T) September 7, 2010&amp;nbsp;03:12:56 PM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;(F) September 3, 2010&amp;nbsp;11:55:00 PM&amp;nbsp;US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sa August 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;01:48:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;August 14, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:38:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Out for delivery&lt;br /&gt;F August 13, 2010&amp;nbsp;10:09:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;August 13, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:03:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;August 13, 2010&amp;nbsp;03:39:08 AM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Departure Scan&lt;br /&gt;August 13, 2010&amp;nbsp;03:39:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;R August 12, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:05:02 PM&amp;nbsp;Fedex Smartpost New Berlin WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;W August 11, 2010&amp;nbsp;11:19:00 PM&amp;nbsp;US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T July 20, 2010&amp;nbsp;02:27:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;T July 20, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:52:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Unable to forward shipment to different address&lt;br /&gt;M July 19, 2010&amp;nbsp;07:52:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;F July 16, 2010&amp;nbsp;10:45:00 PM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;F July 16, 2010&amp;nbsp;08:15:18 AM&amp;nbsp;Whitestown IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 22, 2010&amp;nbsp;01:34:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;June 21, 2010&amp;nbsp;10:21:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;June 20, 2010&amp;nbsp;08:11:00 PM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;June 20, 2010&amp;nbsp;05:48:56 AM&amp;nbsp;Whitestown IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 8, 2010 (T)&amp;nbsp;03:05:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;June 7, 2010&amp;nbsp;11:25:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;June 6, 2010&amp;nbsp;06:27:00 PM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;June 5, 2010 (Sa)&amp;nbsp;01:45:57 AM&amp;nbsp;Lexington KY US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 28, 2010 (F)&amp;nbsp;02:35:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;May 28, 2010&amp;nbsp;12:11:00 PM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;May 25, 2010 (T)&amp;nbsp;08:13:59 AM&amp;nbsp;Whitestown IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 20, 2010 (R)&amp;nbsp;03:05:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;May 19, 2010&amp;nbsp;07:45:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;May 18, 2010&amp;nbsp;02:36:00 PM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;May 18, 2010 (T)&amp;nbsp;05:41:10 AM&amp;nbsp;Whitestown IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 20, 2010 (R)&amp;nbsp;03:12:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;May 19, 2010&amp;nbsp;07:45:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;May 18, 2010&amp;nbsp;12:21:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;May 17, 2010 (M)&amp;nbsp;08:21:52 AM&amp;nbsp;Whitestown IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T April 20, 2010&amp;nbsp;02:44:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;M April 19, 2010&amp;nbsp;07:07:00 AM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;F April 16, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:13:00 PM&amp;nbsp;---&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;F April 16, 2010&amp;nbsp;08:11:21 AM&amp;nbsp;Whitestown IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Standard shipping)&lt;br /&gt;T December 22, 2009 03:12:00 PM Madison WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;M December 21, 2009 12:19:00 PM Madison WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;Su December 20, 2009 04:50:00 PM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;Sa December 19, 2009 09:38:27 AM Whitestown IN US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 1, 2009 02:19:00 PM Madison WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;T December 1, 2009 04:24:00 AM Madison WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;M November 30, 2009 06:15:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;November 29, 2009 06:11:00 PM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;Su November 29, 2009 05:25:34 AM Whitestown IN US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F November 27, 2009 02:34:00 PM Madison WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;(Thursday was Thanksgiving)&lt;br /&gt;W November 25, 2009 11:01:00 AM Madison WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;T November 25, 2009 07:19:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;M November 24, 2009 10:40:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;W November 18, 2009 08:49:47 PM Fernley NV US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M November 23, 2009 02:51:00 PM Madison WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;Sa November 21, 2009 10:24:00 AM Madison WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;F November 20, 2009 06:29:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;November 19, 2009 05:43:00 PM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;R November 19, 2009 06:23:34 AM Whitestown IN US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November 13, 2009 02:34:00 PM MADISON WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;F November 13, 2009 03:30:00 AM MADISON WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;R November 12, 2009 06:51:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;W November 11, 2009 09:36:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;M November 9, 2009 09:20:26 PM Lexington KY US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October 14, 2009 02:45:00 PM MADISON WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;W October 14, 2009 03:29:00 AM MADISON WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;T October 13, 2009 08:00:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;Su October 11, 2009 07:29:00 PM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;R October 8, 2009 02:10:56 PM Campbellsville KY US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R October 15, 2009 02:56:00 PM MADISON WI Delivered &lt;br /&gt;October 14, 2009 10:24:00 AM MADISON WI Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;W October 14, 2009 07:23:00 AM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;October 13, 2009 05:18:00 PM --- Arrival Scan &lt;br /&gt;T October 13, 2009 07:39:50 AM Whitestown IN US Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FedEx&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 24, 2010&amp;nbsp;12:55:22 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Delivered&lt;br /&gt;July 24, 2010&amp;nbsp;06:07:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Out for delivery&lt;br /&gt;July 23, 2010&amp;nbsp;02:37:39 PM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Delivery attempted&lt;br /&gt;July 23, 2010&amp;nbsp;07:45:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Out for delivery&lt;br /&gt;July 23, 2010&amp;nbsp;06:38:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Madison WI US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;July 23, 2010&amp;nbsp;03:05:43 AM&amp;nbsp;Chicago IL US&amp;nbsp;Departure Scan&lt;br /&gt;July 23, 2010&amp;nbsp;01:01:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Chicago IL US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;July 22, 2010&amp;nbsp;10:31:51 PM&amp;nbsp;Indianapolis IN US&amp;nbsp;Departure Scan&lt;br /&gt;July 22, 2010&amp;nbsp;06:17:00 PM&amp;nbsp;Indianapolis IN US&amp;nbsp;Arrival Scan&lt;br /&gt;July 22, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:47:00 AM&amp;nbsp;Indianapolis IN US&amp;nbsp;Shipment received by carrier&lt;br /&gt;July 22, 2010&amp;nbsp;09:45:00 AM&amp;nbsp;US&amp;nbsp;Shipment has left seller facility and is in transit&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal NetBeans IDE 6.9.1 setting tweaks</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Personal-NetBeans-IDE-691-setting-tweaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2010 10:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Personal-NetBeans-IDE-691-setting-tweaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my own personal reference, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the following tweaks to the default install of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://netbeans.org/&#34;&gt;NetBeans&lt;/a&gt; IDE 6.9.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Options
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formatting
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: All Languages / Category: Tabs and Indents
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand Tabs to Spaces: unchecked (from checked)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Spaces per Indent: 4 (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab Size: 4 (from 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Silverlight Web application</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/My-first-Silverlight-Web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 22:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/My-first-Silverlight-Web-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more I do with Microsoft technologies the hard it becomes for me to want to move outside of them. With the .NET Framework and Visual Studio 2010, which is the best development tool I think I&#39;ve ever used, it&#39;s easy to get sucked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&#39;ve wanted to experiment with it for a while, and since I needed to do some kind of development after slacking off this weekend, I looked into creating a simple Silverlight application that would use the same &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Tutorial-ASPNET-C-sharp-WCF-WebHttp-service-with-jQuery-Table-of-Contents.aspx&#34;&gt;Web service I created late last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t hooked it up to any pages within the site yet, since it still needs some styling work, but ... here&#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/Projects/MusicServiceSilverlight&#34;&gt;a Silverlight application using&amp;nbsp;my MusicService project&lt;/a&gt;. Note this requires Silverlight 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time it only works with one of the methods, and the output is a little clunky, but when I have time this week over lunch, or over the weekend, I&#39;ll try to clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a nice little exercise, involving a purely test project/solution to figure out how to make it work, and then adding a&amp;nbsp;new project to my ASP.NET MVC 2.0 project that is the Web site. A cross domain policy file had to be added to the services site so that Silverlight could access it (otherwise it was erroring but seemingly without a message).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s about two hours of work, and outside of about 15 minutes wasted because of some stupidity on my part (I&#39;ll blame the small amount of real-estate on my laptop monitor), it went fairly smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>