<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dvd / Movie on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/categories/dvd-/-movie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dvd / Movie on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 18:53:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/categories/dvd-/-movie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Cyberlink PowerDVD 15 Ultra</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Cyberlink-PowerDVD-15-Ultra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 18:53:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Cyberlink-PowerDVD-15-Ultra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00UV3VCLC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Cyberlink PowerDVD 15 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;, provided to me for free as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Error 0110&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was building my gaming PC I picked up a Blu-ray drive after a few weeks, to compliment the DVD player, and so I wouldn&#39;t need to power on my PlayStation 3 to watch certain movies. However, despite hearing good things about the free options I found the setup to be too large of a pain. At the time I knew of PowerDVD, having used bundled versions years before, but wasn&#39;t yet ready to spend over $75 on a version that would support Blu-ray playback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my Blu-ray drive sat empty, and I eventually picked up a Sony Blu-ray player that was on sale. That is until I received Cyberlink PowerDVD 15 Ultra as part of the Amazon Vine program. So this review will be influenced based upon this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have installation. Cyberlink does provide an electronic version of the installer, so the physical media isn&#39;t required. However, unlike what I&#39;m used to, it appears the download isn&#39;t generally available, and seemingly can&#39;t be downloaded after a certain amount of time has gone by. It would be great if I could download a version from the site and use the serial I received as part of the product to unlock it. But that&#39;s a minor issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the software was installed I decided to try out my Blu-ray copy of Steins;Gate, which is set to Region A. Sadly, I couldn&#39;t get the discs to play, despite them working fine on my dedicated blu-ray player. After a few tries I opted to try out the CyberLink BD &amp; 3D Advisor, recommended from the error message. However, for better or worse I ended up getting no errors in the advisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I tried another Blu-ray movie, this time in English. That too wouldn&#39;t play, and I believe that at this point for some reason it decided that I need to change my language from Japanese to English, using one of my switches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opted at this point to just use my Blu-ray player, and while I tried a few more times later, I couldn&#39;t get it working. DVD playback worked just fine (although the ASUS DVD drive I have is louder than my player), except for a bar at the top of the player which eventually went away after putting the software in and out of fullscreen mode a couple of times. However, there are plenty of free alternatives if you&#39;re just looking for DVD playback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually (very recently in fact) I discovered that what might have been causing the error was the fact that I had two screens hooked up to my computer. The first and primary is a television through HDMI, and the second a computer monitor via a DVI cable. After unplugging the DVI cable I&#39;m now seemingly able to play videos. What would have been great, however, is for that possibility to display in the advisor, especially since dual monitors has been a fairly common setup for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ultimately I just haven&#39;t been that impressed with the functionality. However, I will say that I do like the information that is shown when you put a DVD into the player. Outside of one movie it&#39;s been able to pick up what DVD/Blu-ray I&#39;ve put in and given some nice information about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With prices of players what they are, I think I&#39;d argue that it would be more cost effective to just purchase a dedicated Blu-ray player, even if you just have a computer monitor that has HDMI in. If you&#39;re looking for DVD playback, try one of the free alternatives. It works, but I can&#39;t recommend it when there are better alternatives, so I have to give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00UV3VCLC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Cyberlink PowerDVD 15 Ultra&lt;/a&gt; 3 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 6 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-6-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 09:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-6-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will cover September 26, 2011 to approximately March 25, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;year 5, part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plan changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many years, on October 7, 2011, I dropped DVDs from my plan. I&#39;m running low on time to get to DVDs with all the great games being released, and the price jump is a bit more than I&#39;d like at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 3: Episodes 11 and 12.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 3: Episodes 13 through 15. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 4: Episodes 16 through 18.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 4: Episodes 19 and 20. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 5: Episodes 21 through 24, which finishes the season on a bang. I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday. (I did the latter, but since it&#39;s Columbus Day, mail isn&#39;t going out.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Per the advice of Bill Kummer, watched Hobo with a Shotgun (2011) streaming on my Roku. Giving it 2 stars because while the beginning credits were nice, Rutger Hauer and the main female character were both underutilized.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - My DVD availability is no more. I now only have streaming access.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Mythbusters: Season 7 (2009): Episodes 1 and 2 streaming on my Roku, after trying a couple other shows out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Movie received by Netflix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Mythbusters: Season 7 (2009): Episode 3 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - While initially being turned off from the series, watched High School of the Dead: Season 1 (2010): Episodes 1 through 6 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched High School of the Dead: Season 1 (2010): Episodes 7 through 12, streaming on my Roku, which finishes the series. 3 of 5 stars, but it would have easily gotten 4 for great animation and a good dub, had the fan service not been so strong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 5 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 21:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will cover March 26 2011 to approximately September 25 2011. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;year 5, part 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Castle: Season 2: Episodes 6 and 7 (2009).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Finished off the second disc of&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2, by watching Episodes 8 through 10 (2009). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Actually, the second one, which is disc 4, since disc 3 is still unavailable. Unfortunate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Changed to two DVDs at a time plan, for a little under $2 more, so I&#39;m not getting just a 25 minute movie and a movie I&#39;ve already seen this week. So, next one shipped. Received and watched Black Lagoon: Season 1: Disc 4 (2006), which, again, was unfortunate, since I&#39;d prefer disc 3 first. At least no spoilers. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 5, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Castle: Season 2: Episodes 11 through 13 (2009). Such a good series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2: Episodes 14 through 15 (2009). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, since I missed the mail person by just a dozen minutes today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie. Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 6, 7 and 8, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 9, streaming on my laptop. Watched Die Hard 2: Die Harder (1990), which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Firefly: The Complete Series (2002): Episodes 4 and 5, streaming on my PS3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 10, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2: Episodes 16 through 18 (2009) on my laptop. Perfect series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie, but I don&#39;t have time for it yet because ... I&amp;nbsp;watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2: Episodes 19 through 20 (2009) on my laptop, which finishes off that disc, which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 2 (2009): Disc 5 (all four episodes). Such a sad ending, but ... five stars for the series that&#39;s given me so many ups and downs ... Home sick so hopefully it&#39;ll get picked up with the other disc later today.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 12 and 13, streaming on my laptop (episode 11 had audio issues). (Mail didn&#39;t get picked up, so I dropped off on Friday.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 14, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Times two.&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 15 was I had seen everything but the very beginning to (before the opening credits), and now I&#39;ve seen those few minutes. Watched Freeze Frame (2004), streaming on my laptop, which was a great thriller, with a good ending. Five stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Blackadder: Season 1: Episode 1 (1983), streaming on my laptop, which wasn&#39;t all that good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received next two movies. Watched The Walking Dead: Season 1 (2010): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 3. I remember why I didn&#39;t mind when I stopped reading the series ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched&amp;nbsp;The Walking Dead: Season 1 (2010): Disc 1: Episode 4, and&amp;nbsp;The Walking Dead: Season 1 (2010): Disc 2: Episodes 5 and 6. They&#39;ve changed things up, which is okay, as it keeps us guessing a bit. But I probably won&#39;t watch any more of the series, so 4 stars. I&#39;ll drop both off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer that I received with the first disc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Recieved next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched The Limits of Control (2008), which was relaxing, and completely not what was advertised. Instead, you have a sort of thinkers film, paced slowly, leading up to what you assume will occur. Watched some of the bonus feature, but not all. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Notting Hill (1999), which wasn&#39;t that horrible, and Firefly: The Complete Series (2002): Episode 6, which is still a good episode (and which features both of the SOCOM 4 trophy titles in it - perfect timing). Watched&amp;nbsp;The Twilight Zone: Season 1 (1959): Episodes 5 and 6. All of the above was streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Gothika (2003), which was really good, and kept reminding me of Drag Me to Hell. Although I don&#39;t think Halle Berry would have been wearing a bra in prison.&amp;nbsp;4 stars.&amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Unknown (2006), which was a rather good movie, with a good number of twists. I&#39;ll either drop it off or&amp;nbsp;let it get picked up today, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. 4 of 5 stars. Watched The Craft (1996) streaming on my laptop, which I had completely watched before. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Crazies (2009) streaming on my laptop, which was an average zombie movie. More of a maniac-type virus, though. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Berserk: Volume 1 (1997): Disc 1, all five episodes. The theme songs remind me strongly of some other anime series, which is escaping me at the moment. The first few episodes are a little confusing, but it does seem to be an anime for non-anime watchers. Moved the other discs to the top of my queue. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow. (Which it wasn&#39;t, so I&#39;m going to drop off Thursday.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Trailer Park Boys: Season 1 (2001): Episodes 1 through 4, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) -&amp;nbsp;Watched Trailer Park Boys: Season 1 (2001): Episodes 5 through 6, streaming on my laptop. They&#39;ll probably be the last episodes I watch.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;The Twilight Zone: Season 1 (1959): Episode 13 and The Stand (1994): Episode 1, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched&amp;nbsp;The Stand (1994): Episode 2, streaming on my laptop, even though I said I wasn&#39;t going to watch any more. Received and watched Berserk: Volume 1 (1997): Disc 2, all four episodes. I get the impression that he&#39;ll soon break from the Griffith&#39;s group ... but I still don&#39;t understand if it&#39;s he that he fights later. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday. Watched&amp;nbsp;Mystery Science Theater 3000: The Corpse Vanishes (1989), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched Trailer Park Boys: Season 2 (2002): Episodes 1 through 3, streaming on my laptop. Watched Gamer (2009) streaming on my laptop, which, other than a few naseau-inducing scenes (camera), was pretty good. I&#39;ll give it 3 of 5 stars only because I won&#39;t watch it again, but it&#39;s otherwise a 4 star movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched all four episodes on Berserk: Volume 1 (1997): Disc 3 on my laptop. Great series. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Upped my plan tonight to 2 at a time (for 83 cents) so I can hopefully get another disc as soon as possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Another movie shipped, since I&#39;m at 2 at a time. Changed plan back to 1 at a time, that afternoon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Received and watched Berserk (1997): Volume 4, episodes 14 through 17, on my laptop. Getting close to the end ... Anyway, I&#39;ll probably let it get picked up tomorrow. Watched Gun X Sword (2005): Episode 1, streaming on my laptop, english dubbed. I think the ending theme of this is what I was thinking of regarding Berserk, but it&#39;s not the same ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Didn&#39;t get my next movie as expected. Watched Thirst (2009) streaming on my laptop. 4 of 5 stars, since it&#39;s a solid movie directed by Chan-Wook Park (Sympathy for Mr. Vengeance, Oldbody, Lady Vengeance).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Finally received Berserk (1997): Disc 5, and watched all four episodes on the disc. One more disc remaining ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Berserk (1997): Disc 6, all four episodes. Really disappointed that it&#39;s part of a manga and the show got cancelled before telling the entire tale ... Grr. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. 3 stars. Oh, and the anime probably isn&#39;t for first-time anime watchers. I&#39;m tempted to say more extreme than Drakengard, due to what happens to Caska.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Per the recommendation of Bill Kummer, watched Trinity and Beyond: The Atomic Bomb Movie () streaming on my laptop. It was unfortunately rather slow, and I think a little short on content, versus explosions/footage. 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Trigun: The Complete Series: Episode 1 streaming on my laptop. Maybe it&#39;s just the voice acting, but I can&#39;t find myself interested in this. Watched Session 9 (2001) streaming on my laptop. A lot of CSI crew at the beginning, but a good enough &#39;twist,&#39; albeit about what you&#39;d expect. 3 stars since I wouldn&#39;t go out of my way to watch it again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Didn&#39;t get the movie as expected. Watched The Twilight Zone: Season 1 (1959): Episodes 20, 16, 7, and 34, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Assume I received the next movie; I was out.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Battle Royale (2001), again. Still as good as I remember it. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Dancer in the Dark (2000), which was very depressing (hence sitting on it for so many days). I&#39;ll let it get picked up today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Masque of the Red Death (1964) streaming on my laptop. 3 of 5 stars, since it&#39;s not his best work. Watched The Kids in the Hall: Season 1 (1989): Episodes 1 and 2. Must have watched these on Comedy Central way back in the day, since I think I&#39;ve seen both. Despite having seen it, watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5 (2005): Episode 16 and Episode 17, which I had also seen, but a much longer time ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Getaway (1972), which was pretty dang good. One of the top heist/chase/get away movies I&#39;ve seen. 4 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Monty Python&#39;s Flying Circus (1969): Episode 1 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched MASH: Season 1 (1972): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 5. Removing the other discs from my queue, and I&#39;m up in the air on whether I&#39;ll watch any more episodes on the disc. It&#39;s a good show, but I could have gotten away with just watching a couple of episodes, instead of entire discs. Decided to just drop it off tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in, but I ended up dropping off Sunday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Wathced&amp;nbsp;Aaah! Zombies!! (2007) streaming on my laptop, which was actually pretty good. I liked what they did with the color - black and white for the world in which they are monsters, and color when it&#39;s just the group trying to stay alive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Recieved and watched The Mechanic (2011), which was a pretty dang good Jason Statham movie. Not sure about the ending, but it is hard to kill him. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Pilot Episode.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Episodes 1 and 2. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Recieved and&amp;nbsp;watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Episodes 3 through 5, of which I&#39;ve seen the last one before, with the crazy doll. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Cyber Wars (2006) streaming on my laptop. Slow pacing, and a kind of lower budget Johnny Mnemonic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Night Gallery: Season 1 (1970): Episode 6 and &#39;Bonus Episodes&#39; 1 through 3. More odd than good were these. 3 of 5 stars for the season. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, unless I&#39;m out driving tonight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Alice in Wonderland (2010) streaming on my laptop, which was really quite good. 4 of 5 stars. Watched Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 1 and 2 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episode 3 streaming on my laptop. I like the show, but I&#39;m a bit confused on how Buffy here is 16 years old, while I thought in the movie (which they keep alluding to) she was a Senior (dance/prom/whatever).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 1 through 5. I remember bits of the episodes, but don&#39;t recall the ending theme at all, nor the beginning theme being quite like it is. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episode 4 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 5 through 7 streaming on my laptop. Addicted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 6 through 10. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday morning.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 8 through 10 streaming on my laptop. Found an issue where episode 8 or 9 (demon in the network) lists her birth year as 1980, but episode 10 has it as 1981 on her gravestone. Whoops!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 11 through 12 streaming on my laptop, which completes the season. I&#39;ll be watching another.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched The Stupids (1996), leant to me by &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://conderman.com/&#34;&gt;Dan Conderman&lt;/a&gt;. Giving it 4 stars since I actually laughed out loud, and could watch it again (at which point I&#39;d probably drop it down to 3 stars).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 11 through 15. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 1 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and&amp;nbsp;watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 16 through 20. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt; or Monday morning&lt;/span&gt;. I&#39;m on a roll with Madison mailers ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episodes 2 through 3, and then later 4 through 5, streaming on my new Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 21 through 25. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 6, South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 1 and 2, and Married... with Children: Season 1 (1987): Episodes 1 and 2, all streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie, but I wasn&#39;t around.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 26 through 30. I&#39;ll drop it off in the next couple of days, since mail won&#39;t get picked up until Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 7 and South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 3 and 4, streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 5 and 6, streaing on my laptop.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 8 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 7 and 8, streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 31 through 35. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episode 9, streaming on my Roku. Also watched&amp;nbsp;Repo! The Genetic Opera (2008) on my Roku, and found the movie extremely good. 4 stars since I at least plan on telling others about this. Surprisingly, she&#39;s been in nothing I&#39;d consider good (based on a quick glance at titles and some descriptions).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 10 and 11, streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Streaming on my Roku I watched The Golden Child (1986), which I found to have poor pacing (3/5 stars), South Park: Season 1 (1997): Episodes 12 and 13, which finishes the season and my time with it, and Kick-Ass (2010) which I found to be an extremely good movie. 4 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) -&amp;nbsp;Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 36 through 40. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episodes 9 and 10 streaming on my Roku. (And being sick, a bunch of the Ben Heck Show from Revision 3.)&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episodes 11 and 12 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Gundam Wing (2000): Episodes 41 through 45. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Titan A.E. (2000) streaming on my Roku. The audio wasn&#39;t in sync and it was an overal &#39;eh&#39; movie. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched&amp;nbsp;Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 13 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Gundam Wing (2000); Episodes 46 through 49, which ends the series. 4 of 5 stars, and features a nice bit of backstory, like the fact that White Fang (or the old man) seems to have been the driving force behind the Gundam pilots going to Earth, until the five scientists take control. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Sleepy Hollow (1999), which was actually pretty good. I was expecting the spirtual element to be fake, but was pleasantly suprised when it turned out that it was not. Initially gave it 3 stars, but bumped up to 4, although that would only last after one additional viewing. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Buffy the Vampire Slapyer: Season 2 (1997): Episode 14 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Sucker Punch (2011), which is surprising since it just came out, and which I found to be fairly good. At first I was expecting something akin to Brazil, but got something that featured a flashback instead. Not quite the ending I expected, but good nonetheless. 4 of 5 stars. Featured unskipable previews, but fast forward fixed that. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie. Watched Night of the Comet (1984), streaming on my Roku. It was actually a fairly good zombie movie, where here they&#39;re generated by dehydration. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Unknown (2011), which proves that Liam Neeson is becoming a rather good action/thriller/mystery genre actor. 4 of 5 stars. Once again featured unskipable previews. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday morning. Watched Tales From the Hood (1995) streaming on my Roku, which I had seen before a long time ago, and remembered being interesting (and I wanted something simple before I went to bed). 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Four Rooms (1995) streaming on my Roku. Fairly good, but once is enough, so 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Lady from Shanghai (1948), which was fine. The twists at the end were nice. 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched In the Name of the King: A Dungeon Siege Tale (2007), which was actually rather good, and had some fairly big-name talent. 3 of 5 stars, only because I wouldn&#39;t watch it again on my own, and I know of no one I&#39;d watch it with (currently). I&#39;ll drop it off today or tomorrow morning. Watched Lifeforce (1985) streaming on my Roku. Dan O&#39;Bannon had a part in this one, and I&#39;d honestly say it shows. 3 of 5 stars only because I wouldn&#39;t watch it again per se, but it&#39;s not too bad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Last Unicorn (1982), which is as good as a I remember it, though the ending really does come up quickly, doesn&#39;t it? 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched House of the Dead (2003), which was another Uwe Boll movie, and wasn&#39;t all that bad, although cutting to the game screens was annoying. 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The American Nightmare (2000), which was much more about Vietnam than I expected. 2.5 of 5 stars, so 3. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Ichi (2008), which I found to be pretty good. I was initially going to give it 3 stars but decided upon 4 at the last moment. Recommended by Bill Kummer. I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched MST3K: Soultaker (1999) streaming on my Roku. I laughed out loud at a handful of parts, so 3 of 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Religulous (2008) which was interesting, but the focus was odd. 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. It was the third on my list for some reason.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mad Men: Season 1 (2007): Disc 1, which contained three episodes. Pretty good, but I&#39;m not sure I really want to watch the whole series ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/30/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Again, third movie on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/31/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Near Dark (1987), which was surprisingly good. Lance Henriksen plus a soundtrack provided by Tangerine Dream equals a fairly good experience. The ending is a bit weak, but not too shabby. 4 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Again, third movie on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Informant! (2009), which was slow, but okay. 3 of 5 stars. Watched From Dusk Till Dawn (1996), again, streaming on my Roku. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday, but since Monday is Labor Day it won&#39;t get picked up until Tuesday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Conan the Barbarian (1982) streaming on my Roku. 3 of 5 stars because of length, but otherwise I found it be rather good. Very De Laurentiis-like.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Fire and Ice (1983) streaming on my laptop, since it doesn&#39;t want to load on my Roku. 3 of 5 stars since, once again, the ending flies through things. Pacing, folks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Again, third in my queue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched The Happening (2008), which I found to be pretty good, actually. 3 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. This time it&#39;s the second one! Watched X-Men: Season 1 (1992): Episodes 1 and 2 streaming on my Roku.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched The Hobbit (1977), which was worse than I expected. Definitely for children who can&#39;t read and need something utterly mindless. 2 of 5 stars. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Ninja Assassin (2009), which was slow at the beginning, and featured a lot of dark fight scenes. What I saw of the action looked good, but that they needed to hide it suggests the quality may not have been there. 3 of 5 stars primarily because I couldn&#39;t get a good look at the action. I&#39;ll try to drop it off tomorrow before noon (and I succeeded).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Kung Pow: Enter the Fist (2002) streaming on my Roku. I laughed at a number of spots, so 3 of 5 stars. Recommended by Jim Behan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 1: Episodes 4 through 5. I&#39;ll drop off in the mail tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 2: Episodes 6 through 9.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Castle: Season 3 (2010): Disc 2: Episode 10. I&#39;ll drop off the disc on my way to work this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing watched movies and Netflix shipping/receiving in XML format</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Storing-watched-movies-and-Netflix-shipping-receiving-in-XML-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 13:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Storing-watched-movies-and-Netflix-shipping-receiving-in-XML-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI.aspx&#34;&gt;my Netflix subscription in September 2006&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;ve been keeping track of what movies I receive and when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as the years have gone by I&#39;ve found it more and more difficult to easily look through the listings to see when I last watched a movie. Additionally, I&#39;ve no longer been keeping track of what ratings I give movies, and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial goal was really to track when Netflix shipped and received movies, as well as when I mailed and received. This would suggest a pretty easy XML schema, since the key parts are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of update (Netflix shipped/received, I mailed/received, I streamed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name of movie/disc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year of movie/series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location mailed to (if I&#39;m mailing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if I wish also to be able to store ratings, this format doesn&#39;t necessarily work, as multi-disc episodes, or re-watching a movie/show, would require the rating be placed multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet one might wonder if that&#39;s really that big of a deal, since we could always just pull the last rating, or rating could be optional to use whatever rating was given before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if I make the listing Netflix centric then I always tie it to that service. While I have no plans on dropping my subscription (completely - I&#39;ve been tempted to go streaming only for a couple of months), it also means I can&#39;t track movies that I own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which then suggests we make the XML schema movie-focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our list of Movies would consist of Movie objects, which have a Title, Year, and Rating. Then within that would be a list of times I&#39;ve watched the movie. Which might then really mean we do have two different XML files, since it doesn&#39;t necessarily make sense to keep track of that as part of the Movies XML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Netflix we could focus on Dates. We&#39;d also want to keep track of the type of media (physical or streaming), and if physical, whether it was coming or going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What mailers they send out is also important, so we can determine whether there&#39;s a method to what mailers are shipped. For example, is it always the location you receive a disc from, or are different mailing locations used?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 5 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 21:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-5-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, although only in how fast time has gone by, my fifth year of Netflix has begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers shipping with Netflix from September 26 2010 to approximately March 25 2011. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;the second half of year 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MRNOS = Movie received and next one shipped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Iron Man 2 (2010), which I actually really liked, and am surprised I received so soon after release. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Dreamscape: Special Edition (1984) streaming on my laptop. Quite a bit seems to have hit the cutting room floor ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Chasing Amy (1997). Haven&#39;t seen it all after all, although that&#39;s not too surprising. I&#39;ll probably let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Cool World (1992) streaming on my laptop. Eh. Surprised by cast and David Bowie singing closing song.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 1 through 7 (1996). Decided to watch the English versions, although geez that kid is a brat. I must have watched Season 2 or something, as the guy I&#39;m thinking of doesn&#39;t yet appear to be a part of this one. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episodes 1 and 2 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 8 through 14 (1996). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episode 3 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. I don&#39;t believe mail is being delivered today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received (a day earlier than Netflix thought) and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 15 through 21 (1996). I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 22 through 28 (1996). Saw the &#39;9000&#39; bit. And yes, they do stretch out these episodes ... I&#39;ll either drop it off this weekend or let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (Turned out to be the latter.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episodes 4 and 5 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episode 6 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Later watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episode 7 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 29 through 35 (1996), also known as big disappointments. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dragon Ball Z: Season 1: Episodes 36 through 39 (1996). And that is the end of season 1. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (I ended up dropping it off before the noon pickup.) Re-watched my copy of Sin City (2005). Really is a good movie. Bar scene with Nancy is one of the greatest, where color starts to soak in ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Dog Bites Man: The Complete Series: Episodes 8 and 9 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Laughed hard during the second to last episode. Finally started watching Samurai 7, watching Episodes 1 through 6 (2004). It&#39;s been a while since I watched the film, but there&#39;s quite a bit I&#39;m remembering.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 7 through 9 (2004) streaming on my laptop. Pace is picking up now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 10 through 13 (2004) streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Sling Blade (1996), which was actually really good. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. Watched Samurai 7: Episode 14 (2004) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Samurai 7: Episode 15 and 16 (2004) streaming on my laptop. Almost to the point where the movie ended.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Samurai 7: Episode 17 and 18 (2004) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched - the Director&#39;s Cut of - Max Payne (2008), which wasn&#39;t that bad. Granted, I don&#39;t know much about the video games, so ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 19 through 21 (2004), which was a bad place to stop, but ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Samurai 7: Episodes 22 through 26 (2004), ending the series. Rather good, all-in-all, and ends about where the movie did. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Special Victims Unit: The First Year: Episode 1 (1999) streaming on my laptop. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 1 (2009) streaming on my laptop. Must remember not to fly through these this time ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/31/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 2 (2009) streaming on my laptop. Watched They Live (1988) again, via Google Video.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 3 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Mystery Men (1999), which was okay. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Romeo Must Die (2000), which was okay, thanks to the three (known to me) main actors. Not exactly sure that it&#39;s all that based on Romeo and Juliet, though ... I&#39;ll either let it get picked up tomorrow or drop it off.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 4 and 5 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 6 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Got in late, so only watched the first four episodes on It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 1 (2005).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched the rest of It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 1 (2005). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 7 and 8 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 6: Episode 9 and 10 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Sunshine (2007), which I&#39;m going to give 5 stars to. Part Alien, part Solaris. Predicatable, but good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 2 (2005). Turns out these aren&#39;t in the order they were released, but ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched The Cat Returns (2002), which had me smiling many times. What a delightful film. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Faster, Pussycat! Kill! Kill! (1965) on Google Video, since it&#39;s not available on Netflix streaming, which is one of the movies hanging up in my co-worker&#39;s cube. Eh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Thanksgiving is tomorrow, so I won&#39;t get it until Friday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched It&#39;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia: Seasons 1 &amp;amp; 2: Disc 3 (2005). I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. I probably won&#39;t be watching any more of the series. Watched The Thing With Two Heads (1972) streaming on my laptop. Another from co-worker Dan Conderman&#39;s cube wall. Eh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Atlantis (1991), which was good, but when they tell you to forget the city and then have music/effects that feature city noises ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Wanted (2008), which was actually really good. I&#39;ll probably just let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (It wasn&#39;t picked up for some reason, so I&#39;ll drop it off on Monday.) Watched Christine (1983) streaming on my laptop, which it turns out I&#39;ve completely watched before now. Also makes me want to read some classic Stephen King.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 1 through 4, all streaming on my laptop. I didn&#39;t like the series a while back, but it&#39;s been growing on me, and starting from the beginning has vastly improved my opinion of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 5 through 6, all streaming on my laptop. Yup, I do enjoy the series now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 7 through 8, all streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 9 through 10, streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Cronos (1993), which was just re-released yesterday on DVD, and was about what I&#39;d expect from a Guillermo del Toro film. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 11 through 12, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Fast Times at Ridgemont High (1982), which was about what I expected. I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday morning, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 13, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 14, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 15 through 16, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 17, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched 25th Hour (2002). I forgot how September 11th focused the middle-ish was. It keeps the 4 star ranking. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched 8 Mile (2002), which I enjoyed well enough. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday morning. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episode 18, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order; Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), episodes 19 through 21, streaming on my laptop. Re-watched my copy of Blade (1998). I was going to re-watch the entire trilogy, and it&#39;s still tempting, but ... Finished Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: The First Year (2001), by watching episode 22, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched The Good, the Bad, the Weird (2008) streaming on my laptop, per the recommendation of Bill Kummer. Pretty good, with some very stylish parts. I&#39;m not exactly sure who the &#39;weird&#39; is, though.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Dance &#39;Til Dawn (1988), which really did start a classic 80s cast, including the beautiful Alyssa Milano. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. With the holiday, they say I&#39;ll get it Monday. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Crminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 1 through 4 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order; Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 5 through 7 streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Read or Die (2003), which was composed of what appears to be three episodes, making up a movie. Pretty good. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order; Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 8 through 10 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episode 11 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received next movie. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 12 and 13 streaming on my laptop. The family story begins to surface.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/31/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Ghost Dog: The Way of the Samurai: Special Edition (2000), which probably deserves another viewing to get a deeper meaning into it. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episodes 14 through 16 through 19 streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 2 (2002), episode 23 (had already seen episodes 20 through 22 on tv) streaming on my laptop, which finishes up the season. Watched Rampage (2009), a movie that proves Uwe Boll isn&#39;t all that bad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 1, streaming on my laptop. Re-watched my copy of Blade II (2002).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 2 and 3, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Despite the unskippable trailers at the beginning, Inception (2010), which I received today, was amazing. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 4, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 5, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 6 and 7, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Ghost in the Shell 2: Music Videos (2004). It was okay. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/09/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 8 through 13, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episode 14, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Are You Being Served: Vol. 1 (1972), which consisted of six episodes. Funny parts, but generally okay. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the mangled mailer I received it in. (Was home ill, so it actually just got picked up.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 15 through 16, then 17 through 19 later, streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 3 (2003), episodes 20 through 21, streaming on my laptop, which finishes off the season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Black Lagoon: Season 1: Disc 1 (2006), which contained episodes 1 through 4. I really enjoyed the series, and think the ending (show ending) suggests an ending like Cowboy Bebop, although maybe not ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Today is MLK Day, so I&#39;ll receive Wednesday. Watched Postal (2007), streaming on my laptop. Ridiculous and offensive. But, I laughed, so 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Surprisingly, received Black Lagoon: Season 1: Disc 2 (2006) today. Yet again the disc ended at a horrible spot, but I&#39;m still engrossed in the main character. The description on the slip is also completely wrong, and the ending is still an enigma. It&#39;s snowed quite a bit, and there&#39;s supposedly a very long wait until I get disc 3, so ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Actually, since 1 and 3 have a wait, and 2 and 4 are discs after those, they shipped number 5 on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Episodes 1 through 7 (1957), which is thus far an excellent series. I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Street Thief (2006) streaming on my laptop. Pretty good fake documentary.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/24/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Again, this was actually number 5 on my list, although number 3 (number 4 is part 2) is available, so ...?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received next movie. Watched Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Episodes 8 through 9 (1957).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Episodes 10 through 13 (1957); two in the morning, and two in the evening. That finishes the disc, so I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/28/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. This time they sent the third movie on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/29/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Archer: Season 1: Disc 1 (2010), which contains the first 5 episodes. Laughed a handful of times. Not sure if I&#39;m going to get the next disc or not ... I&#39;m thinking I&#39;ll put it after Have Gun - Will Travel. Will either drop it off tomorrow or let it get picked up on Monday in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Everything is effectively closed down, so I didn&#39;t get the next movie today. Instead watched my new copy of L&amp;eacute;on: The Professional (1994) on Blu-ray. Watched the extended version for the first time. Really good. Think I&#39;ll pick up The Fifth Element on Blu-ray now ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Archer: Season 1: Disc 1 (2010), which contained the last 5 episodes. I&#39;m glad I finished the season off, but I think I&#39;m going to have to give the series 3 stars. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched 5ive Girls (2006) streaming on my laptop. Good. Reminds me of Drag Me To Hell a bit. Or at least the ending does.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched the first four episodes on Have Run Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 3 (1957). Still really like the show.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched the next two episodes on Have Run Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 3 (1957), in the morning. One episode left, which I watched after work. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Next movie received, but I was actually out for the entire day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched all six episodes on Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 4 (1957). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Close Encounters of the Third Kind (1977) streaming on my laptop. Giving it three stars, since this is the second time I&#39;ve watched it, but it&#39;s just alright.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/16/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched the first three episodes of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 5 (1957).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched the rest of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 5 (1957), which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched Commando (1985) streaming on my laptop. I feel like I&#39;ve seen parts of this before, but I&#39;m thinking not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched the first three episodes of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 6 (1957).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched the fourth episode in the morning, and the rest in the evening, of Have Gun Will Travel: Season 1: Disc 6 (1957). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/26/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Porky&#39;s (1981), which I can now say I&#39;ve seen. Eh. I&#39;ll let it get picked up Monday, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Futurama: Vol. 2: Episode 1 (1999) and Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 1 (2005) streaming on my iPod Touch with the Netflix app, that worked rather well.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;02/27/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Red Sonja (1985) streaming on my laptop. There&#39;s something about the movies like this of this period in cinema ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/01/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Sick, so I watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episodes 2 through 10 (2005) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/02/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/03/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Castle: Season 1: Disc 1 (2009), which contains the first four episodes. After the first episode I wasn&#39;t sure, but I think I&#39;ve grown to really enjoy the series. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/04/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Needed to kill some time, so I watched&amp;nbsp;Futurama: Vol. 2: Episode 2 (1999).&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 11 (2005) streaming on my iPad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched The Shining (1980) streaming on my PS3, with Laura. Changed my rating from 4 stars to 3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/06/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched my copy of Alien (1979) (although actually the Director&#39;s Cut) and Batman (1989), streaming on my PS3, with Laura. Changed my rating of the later from 4 to 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/07/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Castle: Season 1: Disc 2 (2009): Episodes 5 and 6. Really like the series now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/08/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched the last two episodes on&amp;nbsp;Castle: Season 1: Disc 2 (2009). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/10/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/11/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 12 and 13 (2005), streaming on my iPad/laptop. Received and watched The Exorcist (1973), with Laura, which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. 4 stars. Watched Firefly: The Complete Series: Episode 1 (2002) streaming on my PS3.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/12/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 14 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/13/2011&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Su) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 15 (2005), streaming on my laptop. Watched my copy of Demolition Man (1993) on my laptop, and&amp;nbsp;Firefly: The Complete Series: Episode 2 (2002), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/14/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 16 and 17 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/15/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Castle: Season 1: Disc 3 (2009): Episodes 9 and 10. Really great series; put the next season at the top my list because of it. Tempted to give it 5 stars, but went with 4 ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/17/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/18/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/19/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 18 and 19 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/20/2011&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Su) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 20 and 21 (2005), streaming on my laptop. Watched Spartacus (1960) with Laura. It was a bit longer than it should have been, but ... Will let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&amp;nbsp;Watched Firefly: The Complete Series: Episode 3 (2002) streaming on my PS3, also with Laura.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 22 (2005), streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/21/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (M) -&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 4: Episode 23 (2005), streaming on my laptop, which finishes up the season. So ... watched Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5: Episode 1 (2005) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/22/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/23/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5: Episode 2 (2005) streaming on my laptop. Supposedly every other episode switches the cops, and they don&#39;t focus on the crimes as much as the main characters, so ... I might not watch many of these. Received and watched Castle: Season 2 (2009): Disc 1: Episodes 1 through 5. Great start to the season. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/25/2011&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&amp;nbsp;Watched&amp;nbsp;Law &amp;amp; Order: Criminal Intent: Season 5: Episode 3 and 4 (2005) streaming on my laptop. Nothing personal in these two episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 4 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 14:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second half of year 4 with Netflix is contained below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers shipping from March 26, 2010 to approximately September 25, 2010. See also the &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;first half of year 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MRNOS = Movie Received and Next One Shipped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched 1408 (2007) at my mom&#39;s (via Charter On Demand), which was pretty dang good. Received next movie, but since it&#39;s noticeably cracked, and I don&#39;t want to risk it, putting it right back in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched BloodRayne (2006), of which the only redeeming factor was Kristanna Loken (and of that, only somewhat), streaming on my laptop. Surprised Michelle Rodriguez was in it, as well as some fairly big names.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched MythBusters: Big Blasts Collection: Episode 1 (2008)&amp;nbsp;streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Replacement movie shipped.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Damaged movie received by Netflix. Watched MythBusters: Big Blasts Collection: Episodes 9 and 10 (2008) streaming on my laptop. Received and was finally able to watch The Butterfly Effect: Director&#39;s Cut (2004). Amazing movie. I&#39;m disappointed I didn&#39;t watch it sooner.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix, but my next two choices not being available, third movie shipped. (I&#39;m pretty sure it was third.) Watched MythBusters: Collection 4: Episode 5 (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Through a Glass Darkly (1961) which was okay, but I probably won&#39;t watch the other two films of the trilogy. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, mailing using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 4: Episodes 8, 1 and 7 (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Delicatessan (1991) streaming on my laptop. What an interesting movie. Two scenes in the beginning where the characters hear the music and act in time with it is fairly good; too bad it doesn&#39;t repeat after that. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 4: Episode 4 (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Tokyo Drifter (1966) streaming on my laptop. I think I watched another (I think even Japanese) film like this, where it seems parts of the movie have been cut. Pretty good. 3 stars. (It was also interesting that you think it&#39;s black and white at the beginning, but is in color from the opening on.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Lost Boys (1987), which is still a fantastic movie. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, as they&#39;re doing construction on the road I&#39;d normally take to drop it off. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 4: Episodes 10 and 11 (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 4: Episode 6 (2008) and Mythbusters: Collection 3: Episode 9 (2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - For whatever reason, another movie shipped. (Turns out it was because the movie I received &amp;nbsp;today wasn&#39;t in slot number 1.)&amp;nbsp;Received and watched Hellboy II: The Golden Army (2008). Long movie, and pretty good. Really should watch more Ron Perlman movies soon. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 5: Episode 3 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 5: Episodes 2 and 5 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 5: Episodes 7 and 10&amp;nbsp;(2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Received and watched Yakuza Graveyard (1976), which was okay, but a little too ... vague? Was going to ditch the PO Box 94533, Cleveland OH 44101-9979 mailer, but since they shipped another, I&#39;ll use it, and let it get picked up tomorrow. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 5: Episode 4 (2009) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Mail person didn&#39;t pick up mail, but delivered Smokey and the Bandit: Special Edition (1977), which I watched and enjoyed. Putting both items in Madison mailer I received.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movies received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Starz Inside: Comic Books Unbound (2008) and Mythbusters: Collection 5: Episode 8 (2009)&amp;nbsp;streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Moon (2009) streaming on my laptop. Pretty darn good, with music like Solaris (re-make), but not so mystifying that I&#39;d need to watch it a second time. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 5: Episodes 1 and 9 (2009) streaming on my laptop. Received and watched Narc (2002), which was also pretty good. Ray Liotta makeup was top-notch. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 4: Episode 2 (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Kiss of the Dragon (2001), which was pretty darn good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Basic Instinct (1992), which was, dare I say, suspenseful, with a great ending. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Mythbusters: Collection 4: Episode 12 (2008) and Boy Eats&amp;nbsp;Girl (2005), which wasn&#39;t too bad,&amp;nbsp;streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Since Netflix lost track of my rate, watched The Seventh Seal (1957) again, streaming on my laptop. I believe I gave it five stars last time; gave it four this time. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 3: Episode 4 (2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Charade (1963) streaming on my laptop, which was full of delightful twists and turns. Watched Mythbusters: Collection 3: Episode 12 (2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Number 23 (2007), which was really quite good, with a nice twist at the end, that I wasn&#39;t really expecting. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Fawlty Towers: The Complete Set Episode 1 (1975), which was pretty funny, and re-watched The IT Crowd (2006): Series 1: Episode 6,&amp;nbsp;streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Identity (2003), which was pretty dang good, and seemed to just fly along. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Re-watched The IT Crowd: Series 1: Episode 1 and 2&amp;nbsp;(2006) and The IT Crowd: Series 2: Episode 2 (2007), streaming on my PC.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Natural City (2003) streaming on my laptop. Okay, albeit a little vague. Borrows heavily from Blade Runner, and others of that genre.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Zombieland (2009), which was hilarious and a pretty great movie. Would definitely watch again. Had some pretty great songs as well, and Emma Stone looks a little like Bat For Lashes ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched My Young Auntie (1981), which seemed much longer than the 85 minutes it actually is (like almost 40 minutes longer), but the kung fu is pretty darn good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched 30 Rock: Season 1: Episodes 1 to 6 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Almost died watching Episode 5 (IIRC).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched 30 Rock: Season 1: Episodes 7 to 15 (2006) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Additional movie shipped for delivery on the 14th. Received and watched Children of Men (2006), which I didn&#39;t quite realize that they had such long takes during it, but mostly did I think and&amp;nbsp;watching the bonus feature made it obvious. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched 30 Rock: Season 1: Episodes 16 to 18 (2006) streaming on my Wii.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Eerie Indiana (1991), which only contained 3 of the 19 episodes that aired (and these I&#39;ve all watched and remember, the Forever Ware one the most strongly). Also received and watched The Cannonball Run (1981), which featured a lot of skin, and had me laughing a couple of times, but this one seemed longer than the 96 minute running time. The PO Box 49021, San Jose CA 95161-9959 mailer that I received the first in was ripped, so putting both in a Madison mailer, which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched 2012 (2009) and The Curious Case of Benjamin Button (2008)&amp;nbsp;at my mom&#39;s. The latter was okay, but I felt much longer than it should have been. Much much longer. The first had a lot of action, and was altogether okay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Since it turns out I had already seen episodes 6 through 10, watched Top Gear: Series 10: Episode 5 (2007) streaming on my laptop. Watched 30 Rock: Season 1: Episodes 19 through 21 (2006), finishing up the season. Pretty good, but I probably won&#39;t be watching any more anytime soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Both movies received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - For the first time, movie returned to Netflix before I received it. Re-shipped. Watched The Octagon (1980) streaming on my laptop, which wasn&#39;t much of a movie, but wasn&#39;t all that bad I suppose.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched My Neighbors the Yamadas (1999). Amazing art design, with differing styles every once in a while. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (Ended up just dropping it off that night instead.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Top Gear: Series 10: Episodes 1 and 3 (2007) streaming on my laptop. I&#39;ve seen all the other episodes, including the one that isn&#39;t available streaming. Finally started watching Dexter: Season 1: Episodes 1 and 2 (2006). Don&#39;t really feel for the main character, but I&#39;ll keep watching through at least the season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Firemen&#39;s Ball (1967), during which I laughed out loud a couple of times, but which I thought was just okay. I&#39;m going to try to drop it off Sunday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Dexter: Season 1: Episodes 3 and 4 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Getting to like the characters more, but knowing that there&#39;s seasons after this one, the suspense isn&#39;t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as strong as it could be. But is still pretty strong.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Dexter: Season 1: Episode 5 (2006) streaming on my&amp;nbsp;laptop. Starting to get a little riskier for him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Barbarella (1968). PG rating, but the trailer suggested mature audiences. Clearly a movie from the 60s. Pretty good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Dexter: Season 1: Episodes 6 and 7 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Starting to get really good now, with suspense, even though I know he lasts at least a couple more seasons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Dexter: Season 1: Episode 8 (2006) streaing on my laptop. Getting really really good now. Watched Dilbert: The Complete Series: Episodes 1 through 4 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Super Mario Bros. (1993), which is about what I remembered. Since Monday is probably observed, I&#39;ll drop it off in time for a Tuesday pickup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Dilbert: The Complete Series: Episodes 5 and 6 (1999) and Dexter: Season 1: Episode 9 (2006) streaming on my laptop. Part of me doesn&#39;t want to watch the latter any more, because I don&#39;t want it to end. After a short break, watched Dexter: Season 1: Episodes 10 through 12 (2006), streaming on my laptop, finishing up the series. Pretty dang good. I&#39;ll probably be watching season 2. Watched Dilbert: The Complete Series: Episodes 7 through 10 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Dilbert: The Complete Series: Episodes&amp;nbsp;11 through 13 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Watched Dilbert: The Complete Series: Episodes&amp;nbsp;14 through 16 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit in Three Amazing Adventures (2001), which was just okay. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Dilbert: The Complete Series: Episodes&amp;nbsp;17 and 18 (1999) streaming on my laptop, although it appears I&#39;ve been watching the latter ones in the wrong order.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched Cosmos: The Complete Collection: Episode 10 (1980) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Gabriel (2007) streaming on my laptop. Pretty good, and basically what I expected for an ending. Watched Cosmos: The Complete Collection: Episode 11 (1980) (although it featured a&amp;nbsp;video of someone using an early&amp;nbsp;version of Netscape)&amp;nbsp;streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Black Dynamite (2009), which had&amp;nbsp;a handful of funny parts. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Tommy Boy (1995), which is a pretty classic Farley and Spade movie; probably the best of theirs. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, using an old Milwaukee (3079) mailer, instead of the Madison one I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Tried watching Wisconsin Death Trip (2001) streaming on my laptop, but only suffered around 47 minutes before giving up. Watched The Signal (2006) streaming on my laptop instead, and it was very good. Highly recommend for someone who likes &#39;smart&#39; horror films.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Beyond the Valley of the Dolls (1970). I believe it was Kotaku that featured an article telling Roger Ebert not to review games, and mentioned this in passing, and I&#39;m glad it did. Catching music, a bit disjointed at parts, but fairly okay. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow&amp;nbsp;in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Tales from the Darkside: Season 1: Disc 1 (1984). There were more than a couple that I remembered, and definitely some that I must have watched, because they&#39;re still fears even today. Episodes, with my thoughts, are as follows; Trick or Treat wasn&#39;t that good, The New Man was okay, I&#39;ll Give You a Million was okay, Pain Killer was good to okay (Hitchcock-ian), The Odds wasn&#39;t too shabby, Mookie and Pookie started an attract female in the lead but was otherwise eh, Slippage I remember fairly well, and Inside the Closet was dang creepy, prooving that it&#39;s scarier not to see than to see. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Legion (2010), which was pretty good. I think I liked Gabriel more, but the two aren&#39;t quite the same. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Aeon Flux (2005), which wasn&#39;t anywwhere near as &#39;dumb&#39; as I thought it was going to be. Fairly good science fiction in fact. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (Wasn&#39;t picked up until Saturday.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched my copy of Ghost in the Shell (1995), and it&#39;s been a while. Still pretty good, but there&#39;s some oddities, probably due to the translation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched 48 Hrs. (1983) streaming on my laptop. The 80s did have pretty good theme music ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/29/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Transporter 3 (2008).&amp;nbsp;I get the impression he&#39;s an ass in real life, but I&#39;ll be the first to admit that I enjoy Jason Statham movies. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Dirty Pretty Things (2002). Amazingly good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched The Gamers: Dorkness Rising (2008) for some reason, and it was actually pretty okay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Surrogates (2009) streaming on my laptop. Pretty dang good. Watched Cosmos: The Complete Collection: Episode 12 (1980) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched the odd Alice (1988) streaming on my laptop. Slow, but very interesting stop-action and design. Watched Gun Sword: Episodes 1 through 3 (2005) streaing on my laptop. Great ending song, and while the first battle made me laugh out loud, it&#39;s a pretty addicting show; makes me think of Cowboy Bebop because of why it appears he wears a tuxedo.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched Gun Sword: Episodes 3 through 7 (2005). Great opening and closing themes and animations, especially the shadowing of characters until they come into play. Looked at purchasing even, but it doesn&#39;t look like there&#39;s any collections on Amazon or Deep Discount ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Fermat&#39;s Room (2007), which was a&amp;nbsp;pretty good recommendation from my sister. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Gun Sword: Episodes 8 and 9 (2005) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Gun Sword: Episodes 10 through 13 (2005) streaming on my laptop. Almost half way through and only one shadow remaining.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Gun Sword: Episodes 14 through 23 (2005) streaming on my laptop. They swapped out the opening for a new one, but I think I&#39;m more a fan of the first. Still a great show. After a short break, watched Episodes 24 through 26 (2005), which finished the series. I must have been a junior (and the first semester&amp;nbsp;of that)&amp;nbsp;in college the last time I watched Mallrats (1995), which I watched streaming on my laptop, instead of on a television like last time. Watched Revenge of the Nerds (1984) streaming on my laptop. I didn&#39;t think I&#39;d seen the entire thing, but it seems I had. I&#39;m torn on 3 or 4 stars, since I&#39;ve clearly watched it more than once, and enjoyed watching it ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Capote (2005), which didn&#39;t seem nearly as long as it&#39;s running time. Good, but one watch is enough. I&#39;ll &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;either let it get picked up on Monday or&lt;/span&gt; drop it off Sunday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Finished Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980), by watching Episode 13. Watched Conan the Destroyer (1984) streaming on my laptop. Pretty good, and definitely a solid action movie. Producer/director seem familar ... (Dino De Laurentiis, who&#39;s name was attached to&amp;nbsp;Barbarella)&amp;nbsp;Didn&#39;t realize this was the second film before I watched it, but oh well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Targets (1968) streaming on my laptop. Fairly okay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Arsenic &amp;amp; Old Lace (1944), which had a weak ending (since it left too much open), but was otherwise frantic and fairly good. The actor playing Dr. Einstein is always a blast as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched The IT Crowd: Series 2: Episode 1 (2007) again. Received and watched Before Sunrise (1995). It was okay. I&#39;ll let it get picked up Monday or drop it off Sunday using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Re-watched Blood: The Last Vampire (2000) streaming on my laptop. Changing from five stars to four. Watched The Mask (1994) streaming on my laptop, since it&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve seen it. Watched Die Hard 2: Die Harder (1990) streaming on my laptop, which I&#39;m not too surprised to find I&#39;ve never seen before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Darjeeling Limited (2007). I&#39;m not sure what to make of it, so giving it 3 stars, but it was probably a 4 star film. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Blood: The Last Vampire (2009) streaming on my laptop. Not at all as good as the animated film. At all.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Chitty Chitty Bang Bang (1968), which was pretty good, until it couldn&#39;t play the abduction scene, but ... if&amp;nbsp;I had kids I&#39;d watch it again. I&#39;ll let it get picked up Monday or drop it off Sunday, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Pusher (1996) streaming on my laptop. Neither the good nor the bad are free from the hand of fate. Watched Them (2007) streaming on my laptop. Really good, although about what I expected &#39;them&#39; to be.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Run Lola Run (1998) again. Bumping down to 4 stars, but I still really like it (and don&#39;t regret getting it again). I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched The Crimson Rivers (2000) streaming on my laptop. Surprise at the end (which&amp;nbsp;made things&amp;nbsp;consistent),&amp;nbsp;and definitely very good. Watched Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995) streaming on my laptop. Now I&#39;ve (finally) watched all the Die Hard films.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/31/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Real next movie shipped. I received the movie shipped yesterday, but since I wasn&#39;t home ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Down in the Valley (2005), which was sad, but inconsistent. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS, surprisingly. Received and watched 21 Grams (2003), which was good, but too disjointed for too long, for me. Understandable at the end, but to what end? I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the PO Box 548008, Flushing NY 11354-8008 mailer I received it in, since they sent me another.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie, but don&#39;t feel like watching it tonight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix. Watched MirrorMask (2005), which was really odd, but also really good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up, or drop it off, tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I recieved it in. Probably the latter since I have to go to the bank anyways.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received Breaking Bad from &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://rmlumley.com/&#34;&gt;Rob Lumley&lt;/a&gt;, and watched Season 1: Episode 1 (2008). Just okay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched The IT Crowd: Season 4: Episodes 1 and 2&amp;nbsp;(2010) thanks to &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://mrrofl.com/&#34;&gt;Dan Conderman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Starz Inside: Fantastic Flesh (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Sherlock Holmes (2009), which was pretty good, as a smart action movie. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Breaking Bad Season 1: Episode 2 (2008) which was better than the first. I could get into the show, but I&#39;m going to opt not to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched The Goonies (1985), which was pretty good (all that profanity and up skirts though, for a PG film ...), and which I&#39;ll let get picked up tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched The IT Crowd: Season 4: Episodes 3 and 4 (2010).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched The IT Crowd: Season 4: Episodes 5 and 6 (2010), again thanks to Dan Conderman. Moss in the court room of the last episode was hilarious. Received my new copy of The Bourne Trilogy in the mail today, and watched The Bourne Identity (2002). Worth the purchase; it&#39;s a pretty good movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Bourne Supremacy (2004) and The Bourne Ultimatum (2007).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Death Race (2008), which seemed a bit jerky with the story, but it was okay. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Movie received by Netflix and second one in my queue shipped.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Next movie shipped. Received and watched Michael Jackson: Moonwalker (1988), which I can now say I&#39;ve watched. Other than just playing clips, I liked the beginning and the first song during the credits more, but now I at least under the Moonwalker game ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Watched Fright Night (1985), which I&#39;ve seen on television before, a long time ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received next two movies, but not enough time to watch either.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Full Metal Yakuza (1997) first, which was very eh. I&#39;m going to toss the PO Box 46740 Greensboro NC 27499-3632 mailer I received it in. Watched eXistenZ (1999), which all made sense at the end. Tough call, but I&#39;ll give it 3.5, so 4 stars. Putting both in a Milwaukee (3079) mailer (which is from the latter movie).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS (that&#39;s both movies of course).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Defendor (2009), which was actually pretty good. Woody Harrelson did a really good job, and Metric closing song? That&#39;s not too bad either ... I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched National Lampoon&#39;s Animal House (1978). Eh. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Blood and Bone (2009), which had some really good action scenes, and seems quasi-early Bruce Lee/Asian in nature. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched The Royal Tenenbaums (2001) streaming on my laptop. Wes Anderson movies are unique; great music choices.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS (for Tuesday). Watched Machete (2010) at the theatre, which is the first in a long while. $15 ($12 of which was with a gift card) for an &#39;eh&#39; movie, not that I needed a reminder for why I stopped watching movies that way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Futurama: Volume 1: Episode 1 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Kiki&#39;s Delivery Service (1989), which was pretty good, even though switching over to Japanese caused the movie to skip forward dozens of minutes at a time. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Futurama: Volume 1: Episodes 2 through 4 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Futurama: Volume 1: Episode 5 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Sleep Dealer (2008), which was pretty good. Boy brings about father&#39;s death, leaves to try to make money, meets girl, and convinces father&#39;s drone-piloting killer to ease the suffering of his family. I think I&#39;ve seen the main female actress before, but ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Futurama: Season 1: Episode 6 (1999) streaming on my laptop. Watched Futurama: Season 1: Episodes 7 through 9 (1999) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Futurama: Season 1: Episodes 10 through 13 (1999) streaming on my laptop, which finishes the season.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Gone in 60 Seconds (1974), which was pretty good, although I expected him to get caught at the end. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Attack of the Killer Tomatoes (1978), which just wasn&#39;t good.&amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow when I deposit a check.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/18/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Dogtown and Z-Boys (2002) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Lost Room: Episodes 1 through 4 (2006). Really great series. Only wish I could remember why I put them in my queue ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched The Lost Room: Episodes 5 through 6 (2006). Good series, but the ending isn&#39;t very good. Far too many loose ends ... I&#39;ll let it get picked up today in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched The Virgin Spring (1960) streaming on my laptop. All-in-all, I like Bergman&#39;s works, especially when they feature Max von Sydow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial thoughts on Playstation 3 instant streaming</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Initial-thoughts-on-Playstation-3-instant-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 16:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Initial-thoughts-on-Playstation-3-instant-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received my instant streaming disc for the Playstation 3 from Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having now moved around and watched a video, here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I&#39;ve watched Netflix streaming videos on my PC as well as on my Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted, currently the streaming capabilities require a &lt;strong&gt;disc&lt;/strong&gt;. While this could perhaps be a download (and will be in the future), I don&#39;t believe it&#39;s too terrible that it requires a disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;disc&lt;/strong&gt; itself isn&#39;t too shabby. The sleeve is the standard Netflix sleeve, although it seems a little stronger, and in red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Netflix Instant Streaming Disc for Playstation 3&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/misc/NetflixPlaystation3Disc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Netflix Instant Streaming Disc for Playstation 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few moments the software was loaded and I was prompted to enter an &lt;strong&gt;activation code&lt;/strong&gt; online. At only six characters, it was pretty simple. While they say it&#39;ll take up to 3 minutes, it took around 30 seconds. There was a similar activation for the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re first presented with your instant queue, and can move around by pressing a &lt;strong&gt;direction&lt;/strong&gt;. Up will move you to the tabs where you can move between your instant queue, recently watched, and various categories. Unfortunately you can&#39;t hold down in a direction to move quickly through the queue, but instead must press the direction you want to move each time. However, I am able to move from the last movie to the first, which can&#39;t be done on the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Netflix disc interface on Playstation 3&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/misc/NetflixPlaystation3Interface.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Netflix disc interface on Playstation 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after I had watched my first movie I started playing around; &lt;strong&gt;L2 and R2&lt;/strong&gt; will move you 7 movies in whatever direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote that this seems to benefit from the &lt;strong&gt;Playstation 3 remote&lt;/strong&gt;, but I don&#39;t recall why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;added a new movie&lt;/strong&gt; to my instant queue&amp;nbsp;on my PC&amp;nbsp;and while it did not immediately show up (we&#39;re talking in seconds), by moving to a different tab and back the new movie appeared. Id est, it seems the times it goes out and grabs the listing is much more transparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie watching experience itself was okay. While Select on the remote displays the &lt;strong&gt;current/total times&lt;/strong&gt; for standard movies, you actually had to pause the movie to see it here. There is a way to have it appear on the Xbox 360, without pausing, but I don&#39;t recall the button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I don&#39;t have to do on my Xbox 360 is switch my &lt;strong&gt;TV mode&lt;/strong&gt; to Full screen. I believe this is a configuration issue on my end. Everything but regular DVDs and watching instant streaming videos (the interface is fine) requires that I change my TV mode so that the movie takes up all the space. Otherwise it believes my&amp;nbsp;TV is square. Again, I believe it to a TV setting on my Sony Bravia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating&lt;/strong&gt; the movie is &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; easier on the Playstation 3. While the Xbox 360 requires you to cycle from 3 stars to 5 to 1 to 3 again, you are able to move the &#39;cursor&#39; on the Playstation 3 and &#39;lock in&#39; your rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;removed the movie&lt;/strong&gt; from my queue on my PC and unlike on the Xbox 360, it&amp;nbsp;was not immediately removed from my queue on my Playstation 3. Switching to another tab&amp;nbsp;and back (letting the other tab load first) worked again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reordering&amp;nbsp;items&lt;/strong&gt; on my PC also didn&#39;t immediately take effect, without switching to another tab. Not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two tabs I currently have are &lt;strong&gt;&#34;Like: ___&#34;&lt;/strong&gt; which are the two movies I currently have in my recently watched listing. Haven&#39;t seen this on the Xbox 360 interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current feelings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like it. Yes, it&#39;s an extra disc to keep about, but that&#39;s a big deal. Yes, there&#39;s the issue with moving through the queue (not so bad after I found the L2/R2 trick). But that&#39;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll update with additional thoughts, as&amp;nbsp;I continue to watch more movies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 4 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 10:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Year four with Netflix begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This covers shipping and receiving from September 26, 2009 to approximately March 25, 2010. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;year 3, part 2, with Netflix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MRNOS = Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (S) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su)&amp;nbsp;- Watched Don&#39;t Tell Mom the Babysitter&#39;s Dead (1991), which I didn&#39;t want to watch when she got her job, but I remembered how it ended. I&#39;ll drop off today or tomorrow morning, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/30/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Swamp Thing (1982). An okay Wes Craven B-movie. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie. Watched first two episodes of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Watchmen (2009), which was rather good, but I believe the book was better, especially the attack at the end. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched episodes 3 and 4 of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Flight of the Conchords: Season 2: Disc 1 (2009), which contained the first six episodes. Music isn&#39;t nearly as good as the first seasons. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Flight of the Conchords: Season 2: Disc 2 (2009), including the special features. This season just wasn&#39;t as good as the first one was. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow (likely)&amp;nbsp;or Monday. (Ended up dropping off late Saturday night). Watched episode 5 of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched episode 6 of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. They believe I&#39;ll receive this on Wednesday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Children of the Corn (1984). Linda Hamilton, outside of being weak, is pretty dang good in this film. This is probably the best film of her, barring perhaps the Terminator films. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/16/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Critters (1986). The core cast wasn&#39;t that bad, and the music was catchy, but a solid B- movie.&amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll either let it get picked up tomorrow or drop it off one day this weekend, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched episode 7 of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Mailer got picked up today. Watched episode 8 of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. It was the second on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Netflix shipped the first movie on my list, in addition to having shipped the second one yesterday. Received and watched Cujo (1983), which I realized 5 minutes into I had completely watched not too long ago. Ah well. Still really good, but classic 80s suspense. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Received and watched Interstella 5555: The 5tory of the 5ecret 5tar 5ystem (2003). Not quite what I was expecting, but the hour and a half flew by. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using a spare Madison mailer, and not the Kansas City MO mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Naked Gun (1988). A few laughs, now and again. I&#39;ll drop off or&amp;nbsp;let it get picked up&amp;nbsp;tomorrow (turned out to be the latter)&amp;nbsp;using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched episode 9 of Cosmos: The Complete Collection (1980) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Jesus Camp (2006) online. Slow and scary. (And sad.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Netflix shipped another DVD, since the one they shipped yesterday was second on my list. Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched There Will Be Blood (2007). Having read the novel first, it was far better, and I kept thinking of it, rather than the movie. Otherwise I might have liked it more, had I not liked the father in the book. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched&amp;nbsp;Red Planet (2000). Another movie with an ending by Graeme Revell followed by Peter Gabriel. Anyways, realized a couple minutes in that I had in fact watched the movie before, but it was still rather good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the PO Box 2555 Bloomington IL 61702-2555 mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/30/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10/31/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Movie received by Netflix. Received and watched Once (2006), which was really quite good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Crank 2: High Voltage (2009). Let&#39;s be honest, sometimes you just need a movie filled with sex and violence. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Received my instant streaming disc for the PS3 and watched Tattooed Life (1965) on my PS3 with it. Movie seemed to jump around too much, and unfortunately the really great part was at the end. (Once Tetsu had a sword in his hand, he became another man entirely.) Watched The Yes Men (2003) streaming on my PS3. It was okay, but not what I was expecting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Tripper (2007), which had a fairly obvious ending, but it was nonetheless not too bad. I&#39;m going to drop off tonight (before 5:30) in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched 4D Man (1959) streaming on my PS3. The jazz soundtrack was&amp;nbsp;a bit weird, and the CGI was obvious, but the makeup was great.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Last Dragon (1985) streaming on my PS3. Great soundtrack, and a not too shabby story. Watched The Toxic Avenger (1985) streaming on my PS3. Orange blood and toplessness; that&#39;s about what I expected, and I got that plus a fairly good story. Still interesting that it was licensed for toys and such ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Interview&amp;nbsp;with the Vampire&amp;nbsp;(1994) streaming on my PS3. A little better than I remember it being, with a great cast.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The City Of Lost Children (1995). Amazing movie. Amazing. Will drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Class of Nuke &#39;Em High (1986) streaming on my PS3. Toxic Avenger was better, but I&#39;d watch another Troma film.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched LolliLove (2004) streaming on my PS3, which just wasn&#39;t all that good. It was probably a 3 star movie, but I gave it 2.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Harlan Ellison: Dreams with Sharp Teeth (2008), which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday (or let it be picked up since I&#39;m at training next week). It was an interesting documentary.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie, but it was fairly horribly cracked. Reported and I&#39;ll drop in the mail tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Replacement movie shipped, and cracked version received by Netflix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Rescue Me: Season 1: Disc 1: Episodes 1-4 (2004). Really great show, with a really great task. I&#39;ll &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;either let it get picked up tomorrow or&lt;/span&gt; drop it off as I go in town to sell movies, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Primer (2004) streaming on my PS3. Odd that I should add it then, by chance, see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://xkcd.com/657/&#34;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt; comic about it. Confusing, but quite good. Watched The Fly (1958) streaming on my PS3. Not much Vincent Price, but the effects were great.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa)&amp;nbsp;- Watched The Quick and the Dead (1995) streaming on my PS3. Great cast, pretty great movie. While Stiletto (2008) seemed to have editing issues at the beginning, turned out to be an interesting movie. Still left too much open. Was it trying to be Kill Bill Volume 1? Either way, Tom Sizemore.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched the worst Batman movie, Batman &amp;amp; Robin (1997) streaming on my PS3. Alicia Silverstone runs like a girl. Watched my copy of Kill Bill: Vol. 1 (2003).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched The Girlfriend Experience (2009) streaming on my PS3. Had to read IMDb on this one, although Sasha Grey did a great job acting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Rescue Me: Season 1: Disc 2: Episodes 5-8 (2004). I like the characters, and I&#39;m looking forward to the next disc. Using a Kansas City MO (Box 219788, 64121-9788) mailer instead of the Milwaukee one it came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Kiss Kiss Bang Bang (2005), which my sister&#39;s roommate brought for Thanksgiving (she too is on Netflix). Good - 4/5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Tokyo! (2008) streaming on my PS3. The end of the first one was when that got good (and this was the strongest of the three, in my opinion), the second one was confusing, and the third was okay. Watched Showdown in Little Tokyo (1991); the only good thing about this movie was Tia Carrere. Watched THX 1138: Special Edition (1971) streaming on my PS3. Wanted to stop watching not too far into it; should have.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Rescue Me: Season 1: Disc 3: Episodes 9-13 (2004). Great show, but the characters are so flawed ... I think I&#39;m going to hold off until I start getting Season 2. I&#39;m going to drop off tonight (but I think I missed the pickup) using&amp;nbsp;a Milwaukee (3079) mailer instead of the Madison one I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11/30/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W)&amp;nbsp;- Reported movie as lost, since it&#39;s been two days.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Replacement movie shipped. Watched The Mutant Chronicles (2008) streaming on my PS3. If it weren&#39;t so dark, and the action didn&#39;t jump around so much, it could have been great. Received what I believe is the missing movie; mailer was in semi-crappy shape. Watched My Name is Bruce (2006) streaming on my PS3,&amp;nbsp;which was a passable movie. Watched Tokyo Gore Police (2008) streaming on my PS3, which had a good primary actress, and an okay story, but the execution could have been better.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched House of Sand and Fog (2003), which by the end of the film was completely stripped of all happiness. &#34;House of Sand and Fog has all the happiness from the characters stripped away until their lives are as dark as the ending scene; the sadness is so think you can cut it with a knife. But it&#39;s still a really good movie.&#34;&amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, with the replacement, if I get that today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received what I believe is the replacement movie. Not sure why an extra day has been added to current ship times. Will drop in the mail, probably Monday morning, using a Milwaukee (3079) mailer instead of the Madison one it came in. Watched Operation Condor (1991) streaming on my PS3. Trying to be standard in my ratings, again, so I gave it 3 stars, since Jackie Chan was indeed good, but I don&#39;t need to watch again (I would have normally given it 4 stars).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Contract Killers (2008) streaming on my PS3. Not that bad, and 3 stars under the &#39;new&#39; system. Watched The Avengers (1998) streaming on my PS3. Thurman and Fiennes made it fairly good. Uma Thurman versus Uma Thurman = Uma Thurman.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Replacement DVD received by Netflix, so I guess that was the missing I received. Watched The Contractor (2007) streaming on my PS3. Not too shabby. Jumped around a bit, and the story was a little weak/disjointed, but the young girl was rather good, and Snipes was okay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Legend of the Red Dragon (1994) streaming on my PS3. Unfortunately, it was dubbed, and it was a horrible job. Even had it been good, the action/story was okay.&amp;nbsp;2 of 5 stars. Received and watched Sin (2003), which I think was trying to be like Heat in some ways. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Actually, they shipped the second one on my list.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Next movie shipped, since it has to come from somewhere else in the country. Estimated arrival on the 15th.&amp;nbsp;Received and watched The Idiot (1951), which was slow, but good early Toshiro Mifune. I&#39;ll drop off Sunday or Monday morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Revolver (2005) again, streaming on my PS3. Ego. Watched Following (1998) streaming on my PS3. Ran into an issue where it had to buffer, but it was due to my connection going down for a bit. Either way, very good movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/16/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next two movies. Watched Jason X (2002), which was what you&#39;d expect, but tongue-in-cheek as well. I&#39;ll hold onto until I mail the other I received today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Kill! (1969), which was really good. The trailer was completely off, however. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, in the same mailer as the other, using a Milwaukee (3079) mailer. (Actually, I think I let it get picked up instead.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Both movies received by Netflix, and third one on my list shipped for Monday. (The first had a short wait, and the second has a long wait. Done on purpose.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Interesting. First movie choice shipped today, with an estimated arrival on the 23rd. Received and watched Snakes on a Plane (2006), which really wasn&#39;t that bad. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS. Received next movie, Cardcaptor Sakura: The Movie (1999) but it froze/skipped throughout. Reported, but not getting a replacement (don&#39;t understand the story; too much missing backstory). Not rating. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, unless I have work, using Kansas City MO (PO Box 219788, 64121-9788) mailer I received it in. Watched The Legend of Drunken Master (1994) streaming on my PS3. Would have rated it a 4 before, gave it a 3 now. Pretty good action scenes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Dick Tracy (1990). Why doesn&#39;t this get a higher ranking? It&#39;s really not that bad. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow on my way north in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Damaged movie received by Netflix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched my copy of Blade II (2002). Didn&#39;t realize Del Toro directed and Ron Perlman starred in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched my copy of Blade: Trinity (2004).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Batman Forever (1995). It&#39;s amazing how bad the old Batman movies are compared to the new ones. Love the awkward ending themes on this and the other. Adult contemporary? I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12/31/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS, with excepted delivery on Saturday (no mail tomorrow).&amp;nbsp;Watched Franklyn (2008) and Joyride (1996) streaming on my PS3. Del Toro&#39;s role in the latter was pretty good, and the former was a very odd but interesting movie. Very interesting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Devil&#39;s Backbone (2001). Good, but slow. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched SNL: The Best of Chris Farley (2000) and Man, Woman and the Wall (2007) streaming on my PS3. Former brought &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; humor to the end of the day, and the latter was interesting. Asian, and interesting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W)&amp;nbsp;- Received and watched Gremlins (1984), which is suprisingly PG, with that level of violence and language. I was afraid I had, but I&#39;ve never watched the whole thing; just a little into the bank scene I think. &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;/span&gt; (Sick, so I let it be picked up.)&amp;nbsp;And it was a fairly new copy, so maybe they purchased another?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Chocolate (2008) streaming on my PS3. Great Thai action movie, with a fairly okay story. Great choreography.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watche The Eye (2007), which was rather good. I like the Blade Trinity Parker Posey more than The Eye one, however. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday (probably the latter, although I think I may need groceries).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Phoenix (1998), which did in fact have a great cast, and was a pretty good movie. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/16/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Lower Depths (1957). I seem to only be able to watch 2 hour plus movies if they&#39;re good foreign movies. Also watched my copy of Paprika (2007). I forget how good Blu-ray quality is until I see it; too bad the subtitles are hard to read at times. I&#39;ll drop the Netflix movie off Monday morning, using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Godzilla: Final Wars (2004) and The Last Boy Scout (1991) streaming on my PS3. Started doing bad MST3K bits in the last half of the former. The latter wasn&#39;t too shabby. Three stars for both.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Unstoppable (2004) which was a pretty good Wesley Snipes movie. Not quite as much action as I expected, but a fast pacing and still quite a bit of action. I&#39;ll drop off on my way to work tomorrow. Watched episodes 1 and&amp;nbsp;2 of Saturday Night Live: Season 1 (1975) streaming on my PS3. Lot of misses, but some hits.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/25/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Infernal Affairs (2004) which was a pretty good movie overall. Ended differently than the western version, but not in an altogether bad way. Great ending music, and the clip used a couple times during was pretty good as well. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched The Painted Veil (2006), which was&amp;nbsp;a chick-flick basically, but is nonetheless rather good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using an old Lansing MI (30320) mailer instead of the Madison one I received it in. (I want to play some Mass Effect 2.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/30/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Visited my mom and we rented two movies from Family Video (first time in a rental place in a long while). Watched Public Enemies (2009), which seemed to jump around quite a bit. Overall not too bad though.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01/31/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched 9 (2009). Not too bad, but I liked Wall-E better.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/01/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received next movie. Stayed up late and I&#39;m off tomorrow, so ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Drag Me to Hell (2009). I was hoping she was going to get out of it okay, but that didn&#39;t happen. I&#39;ll drop off&amp;nbsp;before noon&amp;nbsp;on my way to the grocery store.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/04/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Didn&#39;t realized Winona Ryder was in Star Trek (2009), which I received today. It was pretty good, but not quite what I was expecting with the time paradox. I&#39;ll drop off on my way to work tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched The Triplets of Belleville (2003), which had a very interesting art style and music, but the basically silent-film aspect of it was a little difficult, as well as the odd pacing. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched In the Mouth of Madness (1995), which was a pretty good John Carpenter movie. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Should receive Tuesday (no postal service on Monday).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received next movie, but didn&#39;t get home until late.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched The Thin Man (1934), which I have watched before, but which I still enjoy. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa)&amp;nbsp;- Received and watched After the Thin Man (1936), which I hadn&#39;t seen, and enjoyed. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/21/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Howard the Duck (1986) streaming on my PS3. Okay. Lea Thompson was pretty dang good in it. And she even sang. A lot of fairly big names starred&amp;nbsp;too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched A Nightmare on Elm Street (1984) streaming on my laptop. Unlike when I tried to watch it on my PS3, this time it had sound. Based on the later movies, I&#39;m not sure the ending makes the most sense?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched I&#39;m Gonna Git You Sucka (1988), which had a number of fairly funny scenes. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/26/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/27/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Another Thin Man (1939), which was yet another great movie. I&#39;ll drop off Monday morning in Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched MythBusters: Collection 1: Episodes 1 and 2 (2007) and MythBusters: Big Blasts Collection: Episode 7 (2008)&amp;nbsp;streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02/28/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Wild Things (1998) on my laptop. Holy sh*t, that was&amp;nbsp;a pretty great movie. 45 minutes in there&#39;s a bombshell, then another 30 minutes later, then nothing but switches. Nice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/02/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/03/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Ultraviolet (2006), which wasn&#39;t horrible, but which wasn&#39;t all that wonderful. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/05/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/06/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/07/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Suspicion (1941), which I don&#39;t think had&amp;nbsp;a very good ending ... (he acted too much like a murderer). Joan Fontaine looked an awful lot like Natalie Wood (as&amp;nbsp;well as a brunette instead of a blonde)&amp;nbsp;during this as well. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow. Watched MyBusters: Collection 1: Episode 9 (2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/08/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - I thought Trancers (1985), which I watched streaming on my PS3, was going to be a bad (or maybe B-movie)&amp;nbsp;Blade Runner knock-off, but it turned out to be just a bad movie. A young Helen Hunt and some musical pieces happened to be the only good thing about it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/09/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/10/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Avalon (2001). Was much more of a thinking film than the action one I thought it was going to be. Main actress was stunning, opening/closing credit music was superb, movie itself was&amp;nbsp;a tad confusing. Splash of color in the last bit of time was striking. Not sure about the use of the dog; kept thinking of Ghost in the Shell: Innocence. (And now I know why; Mamoru Oshii played a part in both GitS movies.) Reality ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/11/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Killer Klowns From Outer Space (1988) streaming on my laptop. What a bad movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/12/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/13/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/14/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Scandal (1950). I was expecting them to admit their love at the end, but of course this being Japanese, they don&#39;t. I&#39;ll drop off today or tomorrow morning, depending upon whether I go out. Watched MythBusters: Collection 1: Episode 12 (2007) streaming on my laptop. Watched MythBusters: Collection 4: Episode 3 (2008) streaming on my laptop. Watched Birthday Girl (2001) streaming on my laptop. It was fairly good; suspenseful. Kidman looked fairly young in this. Watched MythBusters: Collection 2: Episode 4 (2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/15/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched MythBusters: Collection 3: Episode 8 (2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/17/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Predator (1987), which was pretty good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/19/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched MythBusters: Collection 3: Episode 8 (2007) streaming on my laptop, which was a much older episode.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/20/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Doomsday (2008), which was fairly okay, but had some issues around the 1 hour 10 minute mark. Issue reported, and I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday morning, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched SNL: The Best of John Belushi (2005) and&amp;nbsp;Return of the Living Dead Part II (1988) both streaming on my PS3, and they were both pretty bad movies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/22/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched MythBusters: Collection 3: Episodes 7 and 11&amp;nbsp;(2007) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/23/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Watched Episodes 6 and 5 of MythBusters: Big Blasts Collection (2008) streaming on my laptop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/24/2010&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched District 9 (2009), which was really quite good. Sad, but good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 3 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 18:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 1 of year 3 with Netflix&amp;nbsp;is covered elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;. Here lies part 2 of year 3 with Netflix, from March 26 2009, to September 26, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plan changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been no changes at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. (Henceforth, MRNOS.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Quantum of Solace (2008), which actually means I probably was the second person to have this disc. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow or Monday, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. That&#39;s a lot of Milwaukee mailers in a row.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/31/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/01/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched most of the first episode of Firefly: The Complete Series: Disc 1 (2002).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched the rest of episode 1, and all of episodes 2 and 3, of Firefly: The Complete Series: Disc 1 (2002). I&#39;ll use a Milwaukee (3079) mailer instead of the Madison mailer I received it in, when I drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched all four episodes on Firefly: Disc 2 (2002), which I&#39;ll drop off in the mail tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. This is the disc that started me really getting into this series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F)&amp;nbsp;- Received and watched all four episodes of Firefly: Disc 3 (2002). I&#39;ll keep the Madison mailer I received it in, and use a Milwaukee (3079) mailer instead. I&#39;ll let the postal employee pick it up today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Eraserhead (1977) on my Xbox. Huh? Falling asleep during the movie = 2 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Firefly: Disc 4 (2002). I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. This is probably a &#39;buy&#39; series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/16/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS. Watched Super High Me (2007) on my Xbox. It was okay; the end with the DEA was depressing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Spirit (2008), which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee mailer (3079) I received it in. It was okay, but the story was all over the place. (I let the mail person pick it up Saturday morning.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Fargo (1996), which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow. I&#39;m glad I watched this after I had watched their other films (that I&#39;ve seen).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Life Aquatic with Steve Zissou (2004). It was on the high end of okay. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. (Forgot, and didn&#39;t mail it off until Monday.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04/30/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Death Note (2006). Long, but pretty good. Good guy becomes another bad guy. But who&#39;s worse? Guess that means I should watch the anime on Adult Swim, eh? Dropped it off in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in, tonight (which means tomorrow pickup).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/01/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Serenity (2005) on the Xbox. Magnificent. Watched Heavy Metal (1981) again on the Xbox. It&#39;s a solid 3 star movie, with a cool opening clip, and insight into the Blue Oyster Cult album, but a solid 3 stars.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T)&amp;nbsp;- Received and watched Death Note II: The Last Name (2006). It didn&#39;t end how I expected, but I really liked it. 4.5 stars, but unable to do that, I gave it four. Really rather good. Mailing using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer that I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Sting (1973), which was still good, even though I knew how it was going to end. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, using Madison mailer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Trafic (1971). Slow, but laugh-out-loud moments; the accident, of course, and when he pulled down the ivy come to mind. I&#39;m ignoring the Milwaukee mailer I received it in, and putting it in a spare Madison one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched He Loves Me, He Loves Me Not (2002). Shown from both sides, this one was slow, but extremely good. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Machine Girl (2008). The cast was enjoyable, but the effects and etcetera per pretty awful. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Friday the 13th (1980). I gave it three stars, only because it&#39;s tame by today&#39;s standards. However, the end was pretty nice. (Not the end-end, but the near-end.) I&#39;ll drop it off or let it be picked up tomorrow, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Before the Devil Knows You&#39;re Dead (2007) online. Should have watched it earlier. Watched WALL-E (2008) online. Another that I should have watched earlier.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Foxy Brown (1974) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie, but I was out of town until Friday, so ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Belle de Jour (1967). Eh. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow (finally got a Madison mailer too).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05/31/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Going to Pieces: The Rise and Fall of the Slasher Film (2006) online. It seemed to jump around a bit, but it was pretty darn good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/01/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched 36th Chamber of Shaolin (1983). An honestly great movie. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Day of the Dead (1985). Sara(h) sure looks familar ... Anywho, first zombie movie where one has used a gun, with such skill. I&#39;ll drop it off or let it be picked up tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Mimic (1997) online. Wow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Pan&#39;s Labyrinth (2006) online. Watched King Corn (2007) online. Watched episodes 1 and 2 of Red Dwarf: Season 1 (1988) online. Eh.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received next movie. Watched Iron Man (2008) again with my sister.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched 5 Centimeters Per Second (2007) in the morning. Beautiful movie, but the singing in the last part was jarring. I&#39;ll drop it off on my way to work, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Halloween (1978). I thought I had watched it before, but it seemed new to me ... I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched all six episodes of The IT Crowd: Season 1&amp;nbsp;(2006) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched Let the Right One In (2008) online. The &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; film I&#39;ve seen in a while. Wow. Wow. Wow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/16/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Once Upon a Time in Mexico (2003), which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Mulholland Drive (2001). Yowsa. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Up (2009) in the theatres with my sister. The villian is more classic Disney-like then Wall-E&#39;s, and wasn&#39;t too shabby of a movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS. Watched The Wrestler (2008), courtesy of one of my sister&#39;s friends. Very good movie. The first 45 minutes seem slow, but the last hour just flys by.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Branded to Kill (1967) which was just too disjointed for me. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079)&amp;nbsp;mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched 28 Weeks Later (2007). Should have killed the mother/kid. Sorry. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06/30/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Watched Liam Neeson takes Paris, also known as Taken (2008). Very good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Should have received next movie, but since I wasn&#39;t around ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched From Hell (2001), which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday morning, in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Child&#39;s Play 2: Chucky&#39;s Back (1990), which was surprisingly memorable (I could remember much of it) and good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched all six episodes of The IT Crowd: Season 2 (2007) online. Episode 1 = so funny I was crying. The rest were good, but it seemed to get lost as the season ended.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Master of the Flying Guillotine (1975). Eh. Okay, but not the best film I&#39;ve seen.&amp;nbsp;I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the Madison mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Screamers (1996). Actually, outside of the &#39;eh&#39; CG effects, it&#39;s not that bad, and it&#39;s definitely better than Imposter. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T)&amp;nbsp;- MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Do the Right Thing (1989). Great cast, and great climax, but the ending left me confused. Lee&#39;s character knew it was wrong, but did it. And him and Aiello seem okay afterwards (Aiello knew he had to do it). I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Great Race (1965). I thought I had seen it before based on the beginning, but as the movie progressed, I realized I was wrong (or had only seen some of the very beginning). I&#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday morning, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Demetri Martin. Person. (2007) which wasn&#39;t near as good as I hoped. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched The Machinist (2007). Messed up, but very good. Like Memento, I guess, of a sorts. Will drop off tomorrow using the Madison mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Coraline (2008). Five-star. Animation is better than Nightmare Before Christmas (although I have watched that a number of times, and this was the first I saw this). Perfect. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07/31/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/01/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Battle Royale (2001), which I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Tokyo Zombie (2005) online, which wasn&#39;t very good, and was dubbed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched That Obscure Object of Desire (1977). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Suicide Club (2002). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow or Monday morning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Suspect Zero (2004) with my sister. Will drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched episodes 1-4 of Little Britain: Series 1 (2003). Dan Conderman made it seem a lot funnier. Received and watched The Fast and the Furious (2001). Actually, honestly, really good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, on my way up north.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Ichi the Killer: Special Edition (2001). What a messed up movie. I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, using a Madison mailer, and not the Milwaukee mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. No idea why it took so long for them to receive this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched American Psycho: Uncut Version (2000), which I unfortunately found boring. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched He Was a Quiet Man (2007). I&#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08/31/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched Ghost of Mae Nak (2005). Actually pretty good. Ended about how I thought it would, although I was kind of expecting just a Ring knock-off (ending still left you semi-guessing). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Received and watched Vampires (1998), which I haven&#39;t watched in a while. Pretty good. I&#39;ll let it get picked up tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in, since I&#39;m off tomorrow, and don&#39;t feel like driving.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - MRNOS. Monday is a holiday, so I should get it Tuesday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Watched Spy Hard (1996) online. Not too bad; funnier than I was expecting. Re-watched Episode 1 of The IT Crowd: Season 2 (2007), this time without disruptions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched The Chronicles of Riddick: Unrated Director&#39;s Cut (2004), which was like Dune (in that they seemed to make it too complex of a story) but was rather good (and I was able to finish it, unlike Dune). I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Went home sick, so to kill some time, watched Welcome to Macintosh (2008) online. Wasn&#39;t that good only because it didn&#39;t go to the detail I would have liked. Jumped around&amp;nbsp;a lot as well. Watched Dead Leaves (2004) online, which I thought might be okay, but it was almost completely a waste of time. Re-watched Parasite Dolls (2004) online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Resident Evil: Apocalypse (2004), which was rather good, IMO. Will need to find out if they had another after this (I seem to think that they did). Will let it be picked up tomorrow, or will otherwise drop it off (tomorrow), using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched X-Men Origins: Wolverine (2008), the same day it released. Nice. Anywho, good movie. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow using Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix, but the second one on my&amp;nbsp;list was sent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Netflix shipped another movie out, since it wasn&#39;t available right away, meaning that I&#39;ll get one today and one in a couple of days. Very cool. Received next movie. Watched The IT Crowd: Season 3 (2008) online. All the episodes this time had something to them, which is better than the second season, which seemed to die out fast.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Oldboy (2003) again, since I saw a mention of it a while back, and wanted to verify it&#39;s a 5-star movie. It is. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using a Milwaukee (3079) mailer instead of the Madison one it came in, since I still have another movie coming.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Received and watched The One-Armed Swordsman (1967), which was not only a good example of the genre, but has a good ending. After some debating, I&#39;ll use the Minneapolis MN (PO Box 9473 - 55440-8543) mailer when I put it in the mail tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS. Honestly, surprised they didn&#39;t wait until they received both.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Movie received by Netflix. Received and watched Jumanji (1995), which I haven&#39;t watched probably since it came out or first showed up on network television, but which is still really good. I&#39;ll drop off tomorrow in the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-4-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;See year 4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix charges more for Blu-ray? No more Blu-ray I guess</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-charges-more-for-Blu-ray-No-more-Blu-ray-I-guess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 15:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-charges-more-for-Blu-ray-No-more-Blu-ray-I-guess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Granted, it&amp;#39;s only a dollar more, but in this economy ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Dear James,
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    As you may know, Blu-ray movies are more expensive than standard definition movies. As a result, we&amp;#39;re going to start charging $1 a month (plus applicable taxes), in addition to your monthly membership charge, for unlimited access to Blu-ray movies.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    The additional charge for unlimited Blu-ray access will be automatically added to your next billing statement on or after November 5th, 2008 and will be referenced in your Membership Terms and Details. If you wish to continue getting Blu-ray movies for $1 a month more, you don&amp;#39;t need to do anything. If not, you can remove Blu-ray access anytime by visiting Your Account at the Netflix website.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    If you have questions about this change or need any assistance, please call us anytime at 1-888-638-3549.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    -The Netflix Team
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I could stick with it and drop it before November 5, but so that I don&amp;#39;t forget, it&amp;#39;s gone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I wonder if this is $1 for all plans, or if it is based upon your plan.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunate that I have to drop it, but ...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix shipping, for Madison WI - Year 3 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 21:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
And so begins year three with Netflix. I covered &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI.aspx&#34;&gt;year one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-2.aspx&#34;&gt;year two&lt;/a&gt;, of what was shipped to me, when, and when I shipped them back, previously. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since last year got a bit long, I&amp;#39;m going to break it up a bit. So, this post covers shipping from September 26, 2008, to about halfway through (I&amp;#39;m not there yet, so ...). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plan changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On 12/10/2008 I moved from the two-unlimited to the one-unlimited plan. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The times&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;09/26/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movies received by Netflix and next two shipped. Watched Purple Rain (1984) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;09/27/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next two movies. Watched Tokyo Story (1953), which was rather long ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;09/28/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched 3:10 to Yuma (2007), which I had no idea was based on an Elmore Leonard short story ... I&amp;#39;ll drop this and the other off in the mail tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;09/30/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movies received by Netflix and next ones shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/01/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next two movies. Watched The Terminal (2004), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/02/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Inside Man (2006), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/03/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Crash (2005), which my mom rented, and&amp;nbsp;which was okay. Near the end reminded me of Magnolia, near the end.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/04/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie. Watched Yojimbo (1961), which I&amp;nbsp;picked up a copy of, a while ago.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/05/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The 400 Blows (1959), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/06/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Videodrome (1983) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/07/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Received and started watching Ray Bradbury Theater: Vol 1 (1985+). Watched &amp;quot;The Crowd&amp;quot; (which I recognized right&amp;nbsp;away),&amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;Marionettes, Inc.,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Playground,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Town Where No One Got Off&amp;quot; (very good), &amp;quot;Banshee,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Coffin,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Gotcha!.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/08/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched the rest of Ray Bradbury Theater: Vol 1 (1985+); &amp;quot;The Screaming Woman,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Emissary,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Man Upstairs,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;The Small Assassin,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;On the Orient, North,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;The Fruit at the Bottom of the Bowl.&amp;quot; I&amp;#39;ll drop it off today. Received and watched Buffy: The Vampire Slayer (1992). Oddly, I didn&amp;#39;t forget anything about the movie, but actually&amp;nbsp;thought there were more scenes ...&amp;nbsp;I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/09/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/10/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Burn After Reading (2008), which was actually rather good. Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/11/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Revolver (2006), which I believe is a psychological Jason Statham movie. Huh? I&amp;#39;ll drop it off Sunday or Monday (no mail delivery on Monday), although I might watch it again before I do so ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/13/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Expected delivery on Wednesday.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/14/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Dropped movie off in the mail. Received (early it seems) and watched Scream (1996). I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/15/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/16/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Received and watched Transylvania 6-5000 (1985), which was actually rather funny, but an abrupt end. Why do they do that to themselves? I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/17/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/18/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Novocaine: Special Edition (2001), which was very good. I&amp;#39;ll try to drop off today, before lunch. Watched The Big One (1998) online. Watched Big Trouble in Little China (1986) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/19/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Film Crew: Killers from Space (2007). Pretty bad when the most interesting part of the movie takes place in a flashback ... and definitely not MST3K commentary. Watched No Country for Old Men (2007) online. Watched Cashback (2006) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/20/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movies received by Netflix and next two shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/21/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received next two movies. Watched Firestarter (1984). I haven&amp;#39;t read the book for over a decade, but I think I liked it better. But, who else could star but Barrymore? I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/22/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Running Scared (2006), which was extremely good. I&amp;#39;ll either drop off or let it be picked up tomorrow (I&amp;#39;m on vacation, and I ended up being sick, so I won&amp;#39;t drop it off until Saturday, or Friday night through my sister).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/23/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Rob Lumley&amp;#39;s copy of JFK: Director&amp;#39;s Cut (1991). Good, but long. Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched 30 Days of Night (2007) online. Watched 2 Days in the Valley (1996) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/24/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Return of the Living Dead (1985), which is truly a cult film at its best. I&amp;#39;ll mail in the Milwaukee mailer tomorrow (unless my sister takes this and the other and drops them off - I ended up dropping them off late).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/25/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Heavy Metal (1981) online. Eh.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/27/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movies received by Netflix and next two shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/28/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received next two movies. Watched Hostage (2005), which proves again how great Bruce Willis is. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/30/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Ali (2001), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10/31/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Better Off Dead (1985). No Joan Cusack? At least there&amp;#39;s a cute French girl ... I&amp;#39;ll drop it off Monday morning. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/01/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Started November off right, with the feel good flick License to Drive (1988) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/02/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Once Upon a Time in China (1991), which had a very good opening/closing song. Netflix is right; definitely a good example of the genre.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/03/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/04/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/05/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Transporter 2 (2005), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/06/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched L&amp;#39;Avventura (1960), which was good, but long. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/07/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Double Team (1997) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/09/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Drunken Master (1978) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/10/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped, for Wednesday. Received and watched Confessions of a Dangerous Mind (2002). Okay, but long. I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/12/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Last House on the Left: Special Edition (1972), which was fine, and which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/13/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/14/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Received and watched the first 6 episodes from Curb Your Enthusiasm: Season 1: Vol. 1 (2000). I&amp;#39;ll either drop it off or put it in the mail tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/15/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched episodes 7 through 10 (id est, the rest) of Curb Your Enthusiasm: Season 1: Vol. 2 (2000) and the one-hour special feature. I&amp;#39;ll drop off Sunday or Monday morning. Overall, good, but painful; how many episodes can you get yourself into a hole?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/16/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Legend: The Director&amp;#39;s Cut (1986) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/17/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched my copy of Appleseed Ex Machina (2007).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/18/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Received and watched Starship Troopers (1997), which wasn&amp;#39;t half bad. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/19/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Flight of the Conchords: Season 1: Disc 1 (2007), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow. Funny moments, but they&amp;#39;re spread out a bit ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/20/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/21/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Received and watched The Last King of Scotland (2006). Great performances. I&amp;#39;ll try to put it in the mail tomorrow, otherwise Monday morning. (It was picked up Saturday.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/22/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Flight of the Conchords: Season 1: Disc 2 (2007), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off Sunday or Monday morning (probably the latter). I just wish I got half the music references ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/24/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix. Watched Natural Born Killers (1994) online, which I hadn&amp;#39;t watched in quite some time. Still don&amp;#39;t really care for it. Natural born, but here&amp;#39;s the environment that made them the way that they are. Umm ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/25/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and two new ones shipped, one from NM.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/26/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next movie, but it was damaged. Reported it as such, but I won&amp;#39;t get the replacement until Monday. Grief.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/27/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched my copies of Jurassic Park (1993), The Lost World: Jurassic Park (1997), and Alien (1979).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/28/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Kingdom Hospital: Disc 1 (2004), which had episodes 1 to 3. Very good. I&amp;#39;ll let it be picked up tomorrow and guess I will use the New Mexico (PO Box 27823, Albuquerque, NM 87125-9740) mailer, since they won&amp;#39;t get it until Monday, at the earliest,&amp;nbsp;anyways.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;11/30/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Tank Girl (1995) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/01/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Both movies received by Netflix and next two shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/02/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T)&amp;nbsp;- Received two new movies, but didn&amp;#39;t have time for either.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/03/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Mission Impossible (1996) which wasn&amp;#39;t too bad, even if I did know basically what was going to happen (even though I haven&amp;#39;t watched it before). I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/05/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Still haven&amp;#39;t had time for the other dvd.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/06/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa)&amp;nbsp;- Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/07/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Kingdom Hospital: Disc 2 (2004), which had episodes 4-7. Still, very good. Watched London, which was extremely different than I thought (but still good), due to Jason Statham having a full head of hair. I&amp;#39;ll put both of these in one mailer and mail them tomorrow. Hopefully they&amp;#39;ll ship out two dvds to replace, but ... we&amp;#39;ll see.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/09/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T)&amp;nbsp;- Both movies received by Netflix and, surprisingly, next two shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/10/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received next two movies. Watched Footloose (1984), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow. The Milwaukee mailer was destoryed, so sending off to Madison.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/11/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Kingdom Hospital: The Complete Series: Disc 3 (2004), which contained episodes 8-11. Weirder this time around ... I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/12/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/13/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Strange Brew (1983) online, on my Xbox 360.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/14/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Hudson Hawk (1991) online, on my Xbox 360.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/15/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Groundhog Day (1993) online, on my Xbox 360.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/16/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Wasabi (2001). Great movie, although the ending was a bit too quick; they should have just let it run for 30 more minutes. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/18/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/19/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched Kingdom Hospital: The Complete Series: Disc 4 (and all the special features). I&amp;#39;ll either let it be picked up tomorrow, drop it off tomorrow, or drop it off for Monday (it was Saturday). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/20/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Sukiyaki Western Django (2007) online, on my Xbox 360. That&amp;#39;s four versions of Yojimbo&amp;#39;s story&amp;nbsp;that I&amp;#39;ve seen now.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/22/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/23/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Casino Royale (2006). Wow. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. Might try to watch the next in theatres (still at one, with limited show times).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/25/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Invasion of the Body Snatchers (1978) and Cleopatra Jones (1973) online, on my Xbox 360.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/26/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Survey emailed on how Cleopatra Jones&amp;#39; quality was; interesting. Watched The Core (2003) online on my Xbox.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/27/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched the double-feature The Oblong Box and Scream and Scream Again (1969) on my Xbox. Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/28/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched High Plains Drifter (1973) on my Xbox. Watched West Side Story (1961), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/30/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;12/31/2008&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Pale Rider (1985) on my Xbox. Not his best, but good nonetheless. Received next movie. Watched Boiling Point (1993) on my Xbox.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/01/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Tropic Thunder (2008), which should be picked up today (otherwise I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow). (Dropped off Friday as there was no mail pick-up Thursday.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/02/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Watched Eraser (1996) on my Xbox.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - For some reason, they&amp;#39;re shipping another movie (that I won&amp;#39;t get until Friday), but I still have to send both back to get another. WTF? Received and watched Dead Space: Downfall (2008). Eh. Not bad, but not all that great, mainly due to the animation; looks like Fox Saturday morning cartoons. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow (but not in the Milwaukee mailer). Watched the semi-philosophical The Man From Earth (2007) on my Xbox, but I&amp;#39;m not quite sure what to think of it, entirely ... Very interesting idea though; I&amp;#39;ll have to look into Jerome Bixby&amp;#39;s works ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Watched Happenstance (2000) on my Xbox. Slow, but how things weave together is interesting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Contrary to what they said, movie recieved by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Paris, Je T&amp;#39;aime (2006) on my Xbox. Shouldn&amp;#39;t watch two French films in a row again. 4 1/2 stars, but I&amp;#39;ll give it 5 because it&amp;#39;s so odd ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/09/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Grateful Dead Movie (1977) and Unleashed: Lords of Dogtown (2005). The former wasn&amp;#39;t as good as The Band doc I watched a while back (empty promises), and the latter was pretty darn good. I&amp;#39;ll mail off to PO Box 49021, Sane Jose, CA 95161-9959 tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/12/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movies received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Dead Alive (1992). Certainly was a blood-drenched zombie buffet at the end. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/16/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Watched Amelie (2001), which I&amp;#39;ll mail today for PO Box 3079, Milwaukee WI 53201-9683&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/19/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Red Beard (1965). Long, but very good storytelling, as usual from Kurosawa. I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/23/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received and watched The Naked City (1948). The first commentary was very good (I feel asleep afterwards ...), talking about this being the first noir, and the importance of cogs. I&amp;#39;ll let it be picked up tomorrow, using the mailer to PO Box 079, Milwaukee WI 53201-9683, which I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Prince of Darkness (1987) on my Xbox 360. Rather good.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/26/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (M) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Received and watched Django (1966), an okay copy of the true Sergio. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow. (I actually let it be picked up.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/29/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01/30/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Received next movie, but I&amp;#39;m gone this weekend ...&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/01/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched El Mariachi/Desperado (1995) double-pack, which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the mailer I received it in (PO Box 3079, Milwaukee WI 53201-9683).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. Watched Angel-A (2007) online. Luc Besson could be a god. Crying and smiling.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Big Lebowski (1998), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using a spare Madison mailer (instead of Milwaukee).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/05/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (R) - Watched Meet Bill (2007) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Black Sheep (2006), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (PO Box 3079) mailer I received it in. Watched Pee-Wee&amp;#39;s Big Adventure (1985) on my Xbox.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched the superb The Fog (1980). Will let it get picked up tomorrow, as I&amp;#39;m off.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Jumper (2008). I&amp;#39;ll drop this off Sunday or Monday morning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched Get Carter (1971), which certainly seems quite different than what I recall the later version being. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Hidden Fortress (1958), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off today or tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (PO Box 3079) mailer I received it in. (Ended up mailing it Sunday.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The New Kids (1985), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/27/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - Movie received by Netflix and next one shipped. (&lt;em&gt;Henceforth, MRNOS.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;02/28/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received and watched Spawn (1997), since I couldn&amp;#39;t recall it. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow (probably) or Monday. (Dropped off Sunday.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/03/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/04/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Man Who Knew Too Little (1997); I haven&amp;#39;t laughed that hard in a while. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/06/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/07/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/08/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched The Eel (1997), for the second time; the first being when I lived downtown for the first time. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off today or tomorrow morning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/10/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/11/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Exterminating Angel (1962), which is probably one of the best films I&amp;#39;ve seen in a while. A definite &amp;#39;buy.&amp;#39; I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/13/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/14/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa)&amp;nbsp;- Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/15/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Body of Lies (2008), which I&amp;#39;ll drop off tomorrow. Watched I Still Know What You Did Last Summer (1998) online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/17/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/18/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Discreet Charm of the Bourgeoisie (1972). Didn&amp;#39;t like this as much as his other film (from 3/11). I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/20/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (F) - MRNOS. Watched Miracle Mile (1988) on my Xbox. Tangerine Dream provided the soundtrack.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/21/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Sa) - Received next movie.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/22/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (Su) - Watched Masculin Feminin (1966). I&amp;#39;ll drop it off tomorrow, using the Milwaukee (PO Box 3079) mailer I received it in.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/24/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (T) - MRNOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;03/25/2009&lt;/strong&gt; (W) - Received and watched The Phantom of Liberty (1974). 4 stars, but tempting to purchase. I&amp;#39;ll drop it off using the Milwaukee (3079) mailer I received it in. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Netflix-shipping-for-Madison-WI-Year-3-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;Part two of year three&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;continues.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display parts of the Waking Life Transcript on your site</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Display-parts-of-the-Waking-Life-Transcript-on-your-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 11:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Display-parts-of-the-Waking-Life-Transcript-on-your-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A lot of people like to pull full passages from &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/waking-life-transcript-with-revisions/&#34;&gt;Waking Life&lt;/a&gt;, as it&amp;#39;s a very quotable movie. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, the problem with that is that if things change there&amp;#39;s a whole lot of sites that are out-of-date. And, sometimes people forget to add attribution ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about ways to make this easier, and believe I&amp;#39;ve come up with an idea. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strike&gt;Looking at the numbers, I&amp;#39;m working from the most popular to the least popular chapters, with the goal of having all available.&lt;/strike&gt; The full chapters are available, at least. I&amp;#39;ll be adding chapter parts as time permits / demand warrants.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To display passages from Waking Life on your site, using the following piece(s) of HTML, depending upon what you want to display: 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 1: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script01_1-2.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 2: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script01_2-2.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script01.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script02.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 1: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script03_1-3.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 2: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script03_2-3.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 3:&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script03_3-3.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script03.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script04.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 1: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script05_1-2.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 2: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script05_2-2.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script05.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 1: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script06_1-4.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 2: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script06_2-4.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 3: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script06_3-4.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part 4: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script06_4-4.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter:&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script06.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 7:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script07.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script08.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script09.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 10:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script10.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 11:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script11.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 12:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script12.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 13:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script13.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 14:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script14.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 15:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script15.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 16:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script16.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 17:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script17.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 18:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script18.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 19:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script19.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 20:&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Full chapter: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://strivinglife.com/WakingLife/Script20.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Minimal styling has been applied, so you&amp;#39;re free to make the content fit within your site rather easily. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Questions? Comments? For assistance, please feel free to contact me or leave a comment below. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix suggestion (7/19/2008)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-suggestion-%287192008%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 19:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-suggestion-%287192008%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I don&amp;#39;t know if this is a suggestion, or if the information is already available.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;d really like to be able to see a complete listing of movies that I&amp;#39;ve rated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A complete listing of movies I&amp;#39;ve rated and that are in my queue is buried in the privacy tab, and I can page through movies that I&amp;#39;ve rated, but there&amp;#39;s no way to get all the movies I&amp;#39;ve rated on one page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Or is there?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(What I&amp;#39;d really like to do, and what I&amp;#39;m sure others would like to do, is be able to list these on my site; here&amp;#39;s the movies I&amp;#39;ve rated at Netflix. This helps me and Netflix, I&amp;#39;d think.)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost in the Shell - Scene 15: Closing Credits</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ghost-in-the-Shell---Scene-15-Closing-Credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 17:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ghost-in-the-Shell---Scene-15-Closing-Credits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[15 Closing Credits]&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Kusanagi stares out across the city.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Fade to black. Credits roll.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/14/&#34;&gt;previous chapter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/&#34;&gt;Ghost in the Shell - Script&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;tip&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For the sake of version control and in the interest of not having multiple versions floating about the Internet, please &lt;strong&gt;link&lt;/strong&gt; to the pages on this site instead of copying the script elsewhere. Using short blurbs of a sentence or two is perfectly fine. Thank you :)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Permanent link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/15/&#34;&gt;http://strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/15/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost in the Shell - Scene 14: Reincarnation</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ghost-in-the-Shell---Scene-14-Reincarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Ghost-in-the-Shell---Scene-14-Reincarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;[14 Reincarnation]&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(A room comes into view. We slowly zoom in to a mirror showing a girl sitting in a chair.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Batou:) You&amp;#39;re awake.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Status report, please. And maybe an explanation about this body.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I was in a hurry. It was all I could get on the black market. Not my taste, really. Section 9 arrived with help right after it happened. They took two cyborg bodies and a slightly beat-up Batou back home. That was about 20 hours ago. For diplomatic reasons, the whole case has been covered up. Section 9 reported it as a terrorist attack. In return, the Foreign Minister has resigned. Nakamura&amp;#39;s being questioned. The whole thing ends in a draw. Only the whereabouts of the Major&amp;#39;s brain shell remains a mystery. Okay with you?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I like the decorating. This your safe house?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My very own. You&amp;#39;re the first person I ever brought here. If you want to&amp;hellip; You can stay as long as you like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks, but I&amp;#39;d better go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hey. What did you and he talk about? Is he still there, inside of you?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Batou, do you remember the voice we heard on the boat that night? Before those words we heard come these ones: &amp;quot;When I was a child, I spake as a child. I understood as a child, I thought as a child. But when I became a man, I put away childish things.&amp;quot; Here before you is neither the program called the Puppet Master nor the woman that was called the Major.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;ll find a car key in the left pocket of that dress. Take one you like. The code on it is&amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;hellip;2501? Let&amp;#39;s make that our password, for when we meet again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Kusanagi is outside Batou&amp;#39;s.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And where shall I go now? The net is vast and limitless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/13/&#34;&gt;previous chapter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/15/&#34;&gt;next chapter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/&#34;&gt;Ghost in the Shell - Script&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;tip&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For the sake of version control and in the interest of not having multiple versions floating about the Internet, please &lt;strong&gt;link&lt;/strong&gt; to the pages on this site instead of copying the script elsewhere. Using short blurbs of a sentence or two is perfectly fine. Thank you :)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Permanent link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/14/&#34;&gt;http://strivinglife.com/ghost-in-the-shell-script/14/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>