<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perfect Blue on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/perfect-blue/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perfect Blue on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 22:04:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/perfect-blue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Blue; 4 of 5 stars ... unfortunately</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Perfect-Blue3B-4-of-5-stars-unfortunately/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 22:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Perfect-Blue3B-4-of-5-stars-unfortunately/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I just finished watching Perfect Blue online (via Netflix). Believing that they do influence what movies are recommended, in a good way, I had to give it four stars, out of five. In Netflix terms, that&amp;#39;s the difference between a &amp;quot;Really Liked It&amp;quot; and a &amp;quot;Loved It.&amp;quot; However, I really wanted to give it a five stars ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All-in-all, it&amp;#39;s probably one of the most interesting films I&amp;#39;ve seen. The animation quality, with the exception of the environments and select main characters, was fairly plain, for a film produced around 1997. For example, Royal Space Force - Wings of Honneamise, was created back in the late 80s, but characters in this movie are quite visually more appealing.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, on the other hand, the style of the characters actually suggests something of their character. At the beginning of the film, for example, we are introduced to a character that adores the main character of the film. Later, he gets creepier and creepier, and we see that he is no &amp;#39;hunchback&amp;#39;, but rather truly monstrous.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;BEGIN SPOILERS&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In fact, the main character&amp;#39;s friend, who we believe to be good-hearted, is also drawn fairly bad, but by the end of the movie we find that she is not quite what she seems.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;END SPOILERS&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, the animation doesn&amp;#39;t really impact the movie too much, or at least it shouldn&amp;#39;t.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps the only thing that really holds this film back, after watching it, is the amount of violence. However, whether or not it&amp;#39;s truly as violent as other films of it&amp;#39;s genre (psychological thriller) is debatable. Perhaps it is it&amp;#39;s animated nature that makes one believe that is more violent than it really is ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, that&amp;#39;s why it gets four stars instead of five. Again, I thought the movie was great, but I would be unable to tell most of the people I know that they should watch this film. Of course, the film is hard to find, so perhaps it&amp;#39;s best left to those few of us anyways ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
===
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As an aside, I&amp;#39;m a bit upset that Netflix never told me that I could watch movies online, and that I had to find out while watching a commercial for their service. Perhaps I don&amp;#39;t watch enough television, but I would have liked to have known before May was up ... if you know what I mean.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>