<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rpg on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/rpg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rpg on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 12:25:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/rpg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Dragon Age Origins: Ultimate Edition (2010)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Dragon-Age-Origins-Ultimate-Edition-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 12:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Dragon-Age-Origins-Ultimate-Edition-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0045ZIEPY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Dragon Age Origins: Ultimate Edition&lt;/a&gt; (2010) for the PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Amazing value, for a great RPG&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while ago a friend lent me his copy of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0045ZIENQ?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Dragon Age Origins for the Xbox 360&lt;/a&gt;. While I enjoyed the game, I had a number of other games that I was playing, and I returned it without finishing it. With the price drops of the Ultimate Edition, I decided to finally pick up a copy, for the PS3, but it sat unused until a short time ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection comes with the original game as well as all the DLC. You&amp;rsquo;ll still be prompted about a new DLC when you&amp;rsquo;re on the start screen, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually telling you about one that collected two of the DLC together, which I think is just an oversight on their end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DLC display as a second disc when you put the game in (there&amp;rsquo;s only one physical disc) and require that you install each separately. I have an idea of why they did this, but it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that you have to install each, as you can&amp;rsquo;t just start the process, walk away to do something else, and then come back to have them all installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the game itself, I wanted this because of the RPG elements, and that I had played games of this type on PC many years ago. While initially people were worried that PC gameplay wouldn&amp;rsquo;t cross over to the consoles, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was really necessary for this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are times when I wish I had a mouse so I could better control which enemies my character attacks, but over the course of my many hours this only came up a handful of times, and in all but a few cases it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story for this game is actually quite good, with a nice variety depending upon your actions. There are different origins for each character type (with race, birth, and class all determining who you start as), and whether you care about the trophies/achievements or not, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend playing through them all, especially since you&amp;rsquo;ll meet a number of the characters later, no matter your origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into one glitch where a battle never ended, but at this point there&amp;rsquo;s enough information about the game to know what to do to prevent it. I also found the initial loading screen to take a heck of a long time. I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is related to the number of saves I had, and my network connection is fairly quick, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t care enough to actually research it too deeply, so I can&amp;rsquo;t complain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my 10th platinum trophy, so I obviously enjoyed the base game enough to play the heck out of it (although the base trophies are more time consuming, depending upon what you do, than hard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly have a hard time finding any faults with the game. Is &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0045ZIEPY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Dragon Age Origins: Ultimate Edition&lt;/a&gt; really a five-star game? I could certainly see myself finishing the DLC that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get through (including Awakening, which was once a game sold by itself), and have basically gone through all the main story options, so &amp;hellip; I supppose it is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Parasite Eve</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Parasite-Eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Parasite-Eve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000038ABO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Parasite Eve&lt;/a&gt;, for the Sony PlayStation (1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost six years ago, back in 2005, I found and picked up a copy of Parasite Eve. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the exact circumstances on why I picked it up, but I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that seeing &amp;lsquo;Squaresoft&amp;rsquo; on the jewel case had more than a little to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0045U4U52?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The 3rd Birthday&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s U.S. launch fast approaching, I put the first Parasite Eve back on my list, having not played it since a short time after I bought it, and even then not having finished the game. Thanks to a YouTube user&amp;rsquo;s help, I started playing the game again, from the start, and finished it one very late night a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parasite Eve is our first experience with New York copy Aya Brea, who over the course of 6 days battles against forces unleashed upon New York, before they expand to the entire world. Overall a pretty solid story, although bits of the quasi-science&amp;nbsp;are laughable. An initial play will take from 9 to 13 hours, although seasoned hands can finish the game in around 7 hours. (I completed the game in around 11 hours and 45 minutes, doing everything that I could in my first play through.) Once the game has been completed an EX game is unlocked, which allows you to replay the game, keeping some amount of your character&amp;rsquo;s goods, and possibly unlock an additional ending. As noted above I actually finished the game late one night (early one morning), since I felt compelled to see the game to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&amp;nbsp;game is an action RPG, involving leveling of your character and her weapons/equipment, with battle portions allowing you to move around while your action gauge fills. So, a sort of cross between Secret of Mana and Final Fantasy VII. Overall, I personally found it to be rather enjoyable, once I got into the hang of how the battles play out. The camera is stuck in place, much like the first Resident Evil games, but generally has little effect on battles. (You will have to watch for chests.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully the game does not feature tank controls (which I can&amp;rsquo;t stand), and was part of that group of PlayStation games that allowed analog controls (but at the price&amp;nbsp;of being able to use the d-pad). I played the game on my 80 gig PlayStation 3, and experienced no issues, outside of one of my controllers seemingly having the analog stick stuck &amp;lsquo;up&amp;rsquo; at times. (Swapping out another controller resolved the issue.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s obvious what generation the game is from because of the CG, and the normal graphics are flat, but despite that the game has held up &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; well. Of course, that may be because I found the battle system so enjoyable, and because the graphic quality fits with the darker atmosphere of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game does have a Mature rating, but what I assume gave it the rating is a character model later in the game that could be compared to Shiva&amp;rsquo;s model in the Final Fantasy series. There&amp;rsquo;s some talk about sexual themes as well, but nothing that a teenager doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about from school. (The EX game&amp;rsquo;s ending may feature content that pushed this game into the M rating.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is an amazing game, and I look forward to doing an EX game run very soon, and perhaps even moving on to Parasite Eve 2. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Kingdom Hearts: Birth by Sleep</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Kingdom-Hearts-Birth-by-Sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 08:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Kingdom-Hearts-Birth-by-Sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002I0GZ5Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kingdom Hearts: Birth by Sleep&lt;/a&gt;, for the Sony PlayStation Portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played Kingdom Hearts 1 and 2 years ago, I skipped most of the other iterations of the Kingdom Hearts series either because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the console (DS) or because the games just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have the same appeal (Chain of Memories).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly before picking up my PSP I heard a lot of really great things about this game, with most reviews saying it had a good story, graphics, and an improved combat system, but a quirky camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having put almost 43 hours into the game, over the course of 10 days (having completed it yesterday), I can honestly say this game has been one of the most enjoyable I&amp;rsquo;ve played in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game features a combat system similar to the first two Kingdom Hearts games, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Crisis-Core-Final-Fantasy-VII.aspx&#34;&gt;Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII&lt;/a&gt;. The story, while a little confusing because we follow three (playable) characters, is pretty good. I only wish I had remembered more about the first Kingdom Hearts, since it&amp;rsquo;s a prequel to the events that take place there (although if you haven&amp;rsquo;t played the other games in the series you&amp;rsquo;ll still do fine). I&amp;rsquo;m once again a little embarrassed that I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying a game featuring Disney characters, but Square once again merges the different characters together very nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voice acting for all characters is decent to great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, I&amp;rsquo;ve put at least 42 hours into the game, completing each character&amp;rsquo;s stories, and the final episode, but could easily put a dozen hours more into the game getting further completion and in the arena (which is still enjoyable, even though I don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone else with a PSP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all, I give this game 5 stars across the board. Square and Disney have really hit the mark with this game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Crisis-Core-Final-Fantasy-VII/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 15:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Crisis-Core-Final-Fantasy-VII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a review of the Sony PlayStation Portable game &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0014X7SQ6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy VII was the game that made me want a PlayStation 1. I played Final Fantasy VII briefly after it was initially released at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house, then my own copies later in college on both the PC and PlayStation 1. So when&amp;nbsp;I ordered a PlayStation Portable (PSP)&amp;nbsp;recently&amp;nbsp;it seemed like a no-brainer to pick up a copy of Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII as one of my first games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having previously played and enjoyed the Kingdom Hearts games for the PlayStation 2, this game was the perfect choice for my first PSP game, and is the major reason I&amp;rsquo;m extremely glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up a PSPgo, and will continue to keep my PSP-3000 for as long as it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crisis Core tells the events that lead up to Final Fantasy VII (in fact ending&amp;nbsp;with the opening of FF7), and I&amp;rsquo;ll admit the story is pretty moving (Lost Odyssey was the last game to make me tear-up, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t cry during FF7). The gameplay will be quite familar if you&amp;rsquo;ve played the PlayStation 2 Kingdom Hearts games, featuring a mix of real-time battles with RPG elements. Depending upon your preference for such things, it offers various simplified elements, such as the shop and leveling, which I think works fairly well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game plays great on the PSP, offering fairly tight controls (movement via either the d-pad or stick), with great sound and video (as usual with Square (Enix), the CG videos&amp;nbsp;are top-notch and they look great on the PSP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is UMD-only, and there seem to be no plans to make it available electronically. Compared to the other UMD game I&amp;rsquo;ve thus far played, Star Ocean: First Departure, the UMD seems to be&amp;nbsp;read from&amp;nbsp;fairly frequently, but loading times are fairly quick, and it&amp;rsquo;s something that you can easily ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To completion, with a number of optional missions finished, I put in a little over 27 hours into the game, and will definitely be putting more hours in to get near 100% on the optional missions, and perhaps even another playthrough (via new game plus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the default difficulty I died once or twice (excluding those times a Phoenix Down kept me going), and those were more from stupidity then anything else. Generally, I&amp;rsquo;d say the game is fairly easy, with some fights a little more difficult than others. Unlike Final Fantasy VII it seems to be a little easier to be a completionist in this game, but since the main area is pretty spread out, those of this type might get a little bored walking back and forth (unless they&amp;rsquo;re following a guide).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give the game 5 stars of 5, as I found the game to be extremely enjoyable, and the amount of time put into it currently, and in the future, is vastly more than the price of entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended for fans of Final Fantasy VII, as well as those who enjoyed Kingdom Hearts on the PlayStation 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
