<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pdf on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/pdf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pdf on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2005 16:06:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/pdf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with PDFs</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Experiments-with-PDFs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2005 16:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Experiments-with-PDFs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I like PDFs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While a number of individuals will attack PDFs with blanket statements, PDFs are a great way to allow users to print documents from the Internet as intended.&amp;nbsp; So, instead of printing off a Web page and losing 10 to 20 characters from the right-side, you can print off a document formatted specifically for printers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, if you use them as the sole content delivery method, you may run into issues.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For StrivingLife.net, PDFs make sense, since I assume people will be printing these documents off for future reference.&amp;nbsp; Why?&amp;nbsp; Because I have scholarly and technical information, for the most part.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Additionally, in today&amp;#39;s world, problems with PDFs are fairly uncommon, as long the PDF is created correctly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To create the PDFs on my site, I first created the article in Microsoft Word.&amp;nbsp; Next, I converted the file to PDF using Adobe Acrobat Professional&amp;#39;s PDF conversion plug-in.&amp;nbsp; From there, a quick &amp;#39;Save as&amp;#39;, to verify that the file size is as small as possible, and it&amp;#39;s ready for publication.&amp;nbsp; I haven&amp;#39;t placed security on my files before, and don&amp;#39;t really feel that there&amp;#39;s much need to for my public files.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Today I tried a couple of new methods to create PDFs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, OpenOffice - OpenOffice.org - allows you to create PDFs with their office suite, without the purchase or use of a third-party utility.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Second, Macromedia&amp;#39;s FlashPaper 2 allows you to create PDFs from Microsoft Office programs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Testing these two alternatives, I found that the PDFs they create are far too bulky for my purposes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, I created a PDF from Microsoft Word, using the Adobe Acrobat 6.0 PDFMaker.&amp;nbsp; This resulted in a 27 KB PDF.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Next, I created a PDF from OpenOffice Writer, using PDF conversion.&amp;nbsp; This resulted in a 82 KB PDF.&amp;nbsp; Printing to Distiller resulted in a 20 KB file.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Finally, I created a PDF using Microsoft Word and Macromedia FlashPaper 2, which resulted in a 88 KB file.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Needless to say, I&amp;#39;ll be sticking with Microsoft Word and Adobe Acrobat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will be experimenting with Macromedia FlashPaper&amp;#39;s ability to create Flash conversions of documents.&amp;nbsp; This allows the viewing and printing of a document via the Flash plug-in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
File sizes for both conversion from Microsoft Word, as well as from the PDF, are about 70 KB (converting from PDF is slightly larger).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ll be doing my testing on &lt;a href=&#34;http://DoNotDenyMyUnicorn.com/&#34;&gt;http://DoNotDenyMyUnicorn.com/&lt;/a&gt;, so head over there if you&amp;#39;d like to test these methods out.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
