<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Playstation 2 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/playstation-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Playstation 2 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 14:19:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/playstation-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Devil Kings (2005)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-Devil-Kings-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 14:19:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-Devil-Kings-2005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B000A8NXCO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Devil Kings&lt;/a&gt;, released in 2005 for the PlayStation 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Perfectly acceptable example of the genre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s something satisfying about games of this particular genre. You play a kind of super-powered individual, able to wade your way through groups of the enemies armies, fighting your way to their lord(s), and taking them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can certainly be repetitive, yet despite that ... the simple controls, basic story lines, multiple characters, and excited announcer, drives you play each character, and at increasing levels of difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re not a fan of the genre, or are a fan of the Sengoku Basara series, you won&#39;t find anything here that will win you over. I knew enough about the &#39;universe&#39; after playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002X9KYFW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Sengoku Basara Samurai Heroes&lt;/a&gt; to know a bit more about each of the characters, but names have been changed, and the historical background has been almost completely removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you like Dynasty Warriors, or enjoyed Sengoku Basara Samurai Heroes and want to play as some of those characters again, you can probably find this game cheap, and will have an enjoyable time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing through all 12 characters I got somewhere over 15 hours of play. However, I still have many weapons and items to find, and still have a ways to go before my characters reach level 20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cutscenes look pretty dang good (as expected from the PlayStation 2). The camera ends up being a little tight on your character, especially with &#39;Iron OX,&#39; and the map always in the corner, but you&#39;ll stop noticing it after a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I enjoy the genre I&#39;m pretty average when playing it, so I did feel as though I had to start at easy, but leveling up some items (which carryover to all your characters) certainly gives your other characters a better start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to be able to back out to the menu after getting into Conquest mode, without having to start the mission and then exit out, but it&#39;s not horribly inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimate I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B000A8NXCO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Devil Kings&lt;/a&gt; 4 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On why I purchased another PlayStation 2</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/On-why-I-purchased-another-PlayStation-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 20:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/On-why-I-purchased-another-PlayStation-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon I picked up a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000TLU67W/?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;PlayStation 2 slim model&lt;/a&gt; from Best Buy. I&#39;ve already got a fat PS2, from way back in 2004 (after a bit of research, it looks like January, and that I paid about $200 for it), that still works pretty darn good, although the controllers are a bit ... discouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PlayStation 3 is also backwards compatible, so between the two I should be able to play my 52 PlayStation 2 (plus those I purchase in the future, as purchase I will)&amp;nbsp;games for many years into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet for some reason a couple of months ago I promised myself that when I next received a check from Google I&#39;d use that $100 to purchase a new PlayStation 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PS2 continues to sell extremely well, despite being a last generation system. In fact, Amazon currently has it listed as number 140 in their &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/bestsellers/videogames/ref=pd_dp_ts_vg_1?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;list of bestselling video games&lt;/a&gt;. The original Xbox that I found on Amazon was listed as number 899, with used or collectible options, both starting under $100. The Gamecube is available for under $70 (new) and is listed as number 779.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of right now, the PS2 has sold, worldwide, the most number of units, with the Nintendo DS about 2.5 million units away, according to &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.vgchartz.com/hardware_totals.php&#34;&gt;VGChartz&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(and with new versions coming out, still under the DS name, it&#39;ll certainly gain the number 1 spot). (The top half of the chart is all Sony and Nintendo products, interestingly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was shocked that PS2s were still selling a number of months ago, but now, after purchasing a slim (which is &lt;em&gt;amazingly&lt;/em&gt; small and light), it doesn&#39;t seem that shocking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played it for a couple of hours, it somewhat reminds me of when I picked up my &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Retro-Twin-Video-System-Nintendo-DS/dp/B001VDZN3O/?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Retro Duo&lt;/a&gt;, so I could play Earthbound and the other SNES titles I enjoyed. There&#39;s just something about playing games for the really great systems ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Odin Sphere</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-Odin-Sphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-Odin-Sphere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000IONGU4?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Odin Sphere&lt;/a&gt;, for the Playstation 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the ads for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001HB7K6I?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Muramasa: The Demon Blade&lt;/a&gt;, since the game looked so very beautiful, and the game looked rather enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought it a few days after it came out and enjoyed it immensely. After some research I found that they had previously done this game, Odin Sphere, and thought it would be worth a play. However, for whatever reason I kept putting off the purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I finally spent the money. At first I was expecting Muramasa&amp;rsquo;s combat, so I got my butt kicked. However, once I realized that Odin Sphere requires tactics, I had a much easier and enjoyable time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is spread out between 5 characters, with varying degrees of overlap. However, you start out with one character, and after finishing their story, unlock the next, until all five are unlocked. This is, quite honestly, a bit disappointing, but to some extent makes sense within the scope of the larger story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the last character is finished a final level is playable, which allows for two different endings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can replay any character&amp;rsquo;s story, but you can&amp;rsquo;t pick a specific chapter to play. So once you&amp;rsquo;ve finished the first character, you can play their story again but must start at the beginning. You can switch to any other unlocked character at any time, but if you start playing the first again, you pick up where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 of 5 stars only because I played Muramasa: The Demon Blade first, and how they perfected this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playstation 3 note: I played this on my 80 GB Playstation 3 and experienced no excessive lag at all, which is supposedly present when playing on a Playstation 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams data</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Onimusha-Dawn-of-Dreams-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 20:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Onimusha-Dawn-of-Dreams-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the archives, I&#39;ve created an &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xsd/2010/09/03/OnimushaDawnOfDreams.xsd&#34;&gt;XML Schema&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/OnimushaDawnOfDreams.xml&#34;&gt;XML data file for Onimusha: Dawn of Dreams&lt;/a&gt;, for the Playstation 2. Currently the data only includes armor leveling information, from level 1 to 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data comes from an OpenDocument Spreadsheet (OnimushaDawnofDreams.ods) from way back in May of 2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My characters and core weapons being completely maxed (not to mention souls), I may decide to replay the game to track this information as well, or just upgrade weapons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odin Sphere: Character data file</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Odin-Sphere-Character-data-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Odin-Sphere-Character-data-file/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Similar to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Resonance-of-Fate-General-data-file.aspx&#34;&gt;Resonance of Fate data file&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Muramasa-The-Demon-Blade-Complete-weapon-listing.aspx&#34;&gt;Muramasa demon blade listing&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;ve begun work on converting a notepad file&#39;s data to XML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is still raw, but ... I plan on completing it as much as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external download&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/files/OdinSphere.xml&#34;&gt;View/download the Odin Sphere data file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted in the file, data is licensed under the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
