<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steam on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/steam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Steam on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 13:59:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/steam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Shadowrun Returns (2013)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Shadowrun-Returns-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 13:59:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Shadowrun-Returns-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Shadowrun Returns (2013), available for PC on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Enjoyable story and gameplay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having the game for a little over 9 months, I&#39;ve finally beaten the main campaign, Dead Man&#39;s Switch, of &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/234650/&#34;&gt;Shadowrun Returns&lt;/a&gt; (2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn&#39;t take this long to beat it because the game wasn&#39;t enjoyable, but rather because the machine I had until a few months ago wasn&#39;t ideal for gaming, so it wasn&#39;t until the last three months that I really got into this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game itself has a robust story, as one would hope from a Shadowrun game. The game isn&#39;t particularly difficult, as I found myself only losing two characters over the course of the ~11 hours of time I put in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a robust editor and community, I expect I&#39;ll be able to come back to Shadowrun Returns again and again over the years, for continued enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/234650/&#34;&gt;Shadowrun Returns&lt;/a&gt;, and give it a 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Still Life (2005)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Still-Life-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 19:14:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Still-Life-2005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/46480/&#34;&gt;Still Life&lt;/a&gt; (2005), available for PC on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Great story, interesting puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having liked &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/46500/&#34;&gt;Syberia&lt;/a&gt; (you have to like a game if you&#39;ve bought multiple copies over the years), when I saw the Still Life trilogy in a bundle (Post Mortem, Still Life, Still Life 2) a few months ago I decided to pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it&#39;s taken me a while to get to this game (not thinking, I played the second in the series first), I&#39;m glad I finally did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still Life eventually ends up following the lives of two characters, with the real focus on one, Victoria. While at times she seemed like a bit of a teenager (attitude), I actually enjoyed her character pretty dang well. The other character is also interesting, and ... well, spoiler, look forward to playing as him when I get around to Post Mortem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the puzzles are rather challenging, and I&#39;ll readily admit that I opted to just look at a guide as time went on; I&#39;m not as smart as I once was, and really I was just digging the story. I have no shame in admitting that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to playing the rest of the games in this series. Honestly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/46480/&#34;&gt;Still Life&lt;/a&gt; gets 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Fearless Fantasy (2014)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Fearless-Fantasy-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 10:27:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Fearless-Fantasy-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://steamcommunity.com/app/282100&#34;&gt;Fearless Fantasy&lt;/a&gt; (2014), available for PC on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Enjoyable, but controls are a bit iffy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Fearless Fantasy isn&#39;t long (there&#39;s only 13 sections), it&#39;s nonetheless an interesting game. The combat mechanic is probably more suited for touch-based devices (I found windowed mode makes the game a little easier, than playing full screen in 1920x1080), it still keeps combat interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the mechanic, I did find myself having to grind earlier levels for experience, and ended the game with level 17 characters. But, I still recommend it as a fun little RPG, especially if you can get it cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely enjoyed the cutscene style as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: To the Moon (2011)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-To-the-Moon-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 07:09:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-To-the-Moon-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/206440&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;To the Moon&lt;/a&gt; (2011), available for PC on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Good story, but iffy controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the reviews of this game I was expecting a short game with a good story. And having now beat the game in a little over 3 and a half hours (having only looked up if I needed to get off the horse to exit the stage; we&#39;ll get to that in a bit), that&#39;s exactly what I got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the Moon did make me start to tear up at one point, as the game progresses from a man&#39;s old age to his youth, and you see what happened to bring him to where he was. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The art is good, the music is fantastic, but the controls leave a bit to be desired. I ended up playing the game with part mouse and part keyboard for movement, and quite frankly I still don&#39;t know which was better. Perhaps using a controller would have helped (if I even could; I didn&#39;t look). As mentioned above, the movement controls, and sometimes even the mouse selection, can be iffy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I understand it&#39;s built on top of an RPG Maker version, there&#39;s no real RPG elements, just point and click and minor puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite the minor issues, the game is recommended. 4 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Hexcells Plus (2014)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Hexcells-Plus-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 17:15:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Hexcells-Plus-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Hexcells Plus (2014), played on the PC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;More of the same, with a bit more complexity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having gone through the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/265890&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Hexcells&lt;/a&gt; rather quickly, I just as quickly started playing the standalone &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/271900/&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Hexcells Plus&lt;/a&gt;. While this game contains the same number of puzzles as the original, it adds additional gameplay dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I finished the first in less than 2 hours, Steam reports that I put in 8 hours on this version. I think I ended up letting the game run, as I don&#39;t think it required anywhere near that amount of time. However, the puzzles in this version are a bit more complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed the first Hexcells, you&#39;ll like this one. Since I did, and do, this game is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Hexcells (2014)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Hexcells-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 17:02:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Hexcells-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Hexcells (2014), played on the PC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A short, but enjoyable, puzzle game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/265890&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Hexcells&lt;/a&gt;, especially for the price I paid ($1.25 with the standalone expansion), as I got a around 110 minutes of play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a pretty basic puzzle game, with some extra dynamics added in as you progress. I do wish that the puzzles were a little more complex, but I also tend to enjoy this type of game, so the general idea wasn&#39;t new to me. Still, as I said, enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>