<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 08:27:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Grand Design</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-The-Grand-Design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 08:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-The-Grand-Design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553805371?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Grand Design&lt;/a&gt;, written by Stephen Hawking and Leonard Mlodinow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;s the audience?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While interesting, the lack of a defined audience makes this book an extremely difficult read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having read &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0553380168?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Time&lt;/a&gt; I was looking for something with a similar feel to it. Instead the book starts out geared towards anyone with the desire to really read and understand it, then seems to leave most of that audience towards the wayside - seemingly right around when the science gets a little iffy - and then finishes geared back towards the larger audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps the audience isn&amp;rsquo;t as large as I&amp;rsquo;ve thought. But why then, in one of these &amp;lsquo;higher level&amp;rsquo; sections do we see jokes added within the text?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the authors realized that the theory they state within is too complex for most people, and this is their way of making it bearable for us, until things start getting more understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, while I generally enjoyed the book, and found many noteworthy passages, the ideas expressed within still need some work to be generally accessible. While I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly re-read a Stephen Hawking book, it is unlikely that it will be this one, so I give it 3 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postulate: Given the present, the future can be known, but the past only guessed</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Postulate-Given-the-present-the-future-can-be-known-but-the-past-only-guessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 08:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Postulate-Given-the-present-the-future-can-be-known-but-the-past-only-guessed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I submit the following as a postulate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given knowledge of the present state of affairs, we can know the future, but not the past. Of the latter we can only make guesses and assumptions, albeit educated ones, but cannot know with certainity that they were the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that two vehicles are heading towards each other at speed, and neither will be able to stop in time, we can know that they will hit each other and cause a certain amount of damage, knowing the speeds they&#39;re going, the integrity of the vehicles, and etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we can only guess, assuming we did not know the state of affairs at the key points in the past, as to why they&#39;re headed towards each other. If a child is standing in the road, where one of the vehicles would otherwise be, or would have been, we could assume that the vehicle swerved to avoid striking the child. But given a &#39;snapshot&#39; of the present referred to above, we cannot know that to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why this is important&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolute knowledge of the current state of affairs is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; sufficient to&amp;nbsp;absolute knowledge of the past, even assuming cause and effect reigns supreme (which it seemingly must). Given a present, there are many pasts, but only one future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanded Table of Contents for The World as Will and Representation: Volume I (Dover Edition)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Expanded-Table-of-Contents-for-The-World-as-Will-and-Representation-Volume-I-Dover-Edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 08:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Expanded-Table-of-Contents-for-The-World-as-Will-and-Representation-Volume-I-Dover-Edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dover Edition of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0486217612?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The World as Will and Representation: Volume I&lt;/a&gt;, translated by E.F.J. Payne, suffers from a sparse table of contents, covering only the starting pages of the four books and the appendix (the index being contained in the second volume).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remedy this, I&amp;rsquo;ve presented below an expanded table of contents for this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expanded Table of Contents for Volume I&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Translator&amp;rsquo;s Introduction (v - xi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preface to the First Edition (xii - xvii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preface to the Second Edition (xviii - xxvii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preface to the Third Edition (xxviii)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selected Bibliography (xxix - xxx)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contents, Volume I (xxxi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Book: The World as Representation. First Aspect (1 - 92)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;1 (3 - 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;2 (5 - 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;3 (6 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;4 (8 - 13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;5 (13 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;6 (19 - 25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;7 (25 - 35)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;8 (35 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;9 (39 - 50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;10 (50 - 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;11 (51 - 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;12 (53 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;13 (58 - 61)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;14 (61 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;15 (69 - 83)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;16 (83 - 91)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Book: THe World as Will. First Aspect (93 - 166)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;17 (95 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;18 (99 - 103)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;19 (103 - 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;20 (106 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;21 (109 - 110)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;22 (110 - 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;23 (112 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;24 (119 - 127)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;25 (127 - 130)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;26 (130 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;27 (139 - 152)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;28 (153 - 161)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;29 (162 - 5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third Book: The World as Representation. Second Aspect (167 - 268)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;30 (169)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;31 (170 - 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;32 (174 - 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;33 (176 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;34 (178 - 181)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;35 (181 - 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;36 (184 - 194)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;37 (194 - 5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;38 (195 - 200)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;39 (200 - 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;40 (207 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;41 (208 - 212)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;42 (212 - 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;43 (213 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;44 (218 - 220)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;45 (220 - 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;46 (226 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;47 (229)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;48 (230 - 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;49 (233 - 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;50 (237 - 242)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;51 (242 - 255)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;52 (255 - 267)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fourth Book: The World as Will: Second Aspect (269 - 412)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;53 (271 - 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;54 (274 - 286)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;55 (286 - 307)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;56 (307 - 310)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;57 (311 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;58 (319 - 323)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;59 (323 - 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;60 (326 - 331)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;61 (331 - 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;62 (334 - 350)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;63 (350 - 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;64 (357 - 9)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;65 (359 - 367)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;66 (367 - 374)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;67 (375 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;68 (378 - 398)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;69 (398 - 402)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;70 (402 - 8)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;sect;71 (408 - 412)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix: Criticism of the Kantian Philosophy (413 - 534)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Thought on Time Travel</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/A-Brief-Thought-on-Time-Travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 21:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/A-Brief-Thought-on-Time-Travel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To those who cannot travel outside the normal flow of time, it matters not whether time travel is possible, for they would be unable to determine if the past had changed (assuming it even possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thought came to me a moment ago, as I was about to watch the eighth episode of Cosmos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on objects and their underlying structure</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-objects-and-their-underlying-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 07:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-objects-and-their-underlying-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Image for a moment two sheets of paper. On the first we have a design of a Web page. On the second we have the code (all of it) needed to generate that page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we were to overlap the sheets of paper, so that the design covered the code, let us imagine that the overlapping sheet&#39;s background&amp;nbsp;would turn transparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, we could overlap the two sheets of paper equally, with the right side of the design&#39;s sheet overlapping the left side of the code&#39;s sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now really, these two have absolutely no physical dimensions at all, in particular, no thickness; they&#39;re just a stream of bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while before, when we&amp;nbsp;imagined/saw them as sheets with a thickness of 0.5mm, they have a thickness of 0. This also means that by overlapping the two we no longer have 0.5 *2, but 0 + 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the two overlap in how we perceive them (due to the transparency), they seem to become one, which, again, because they have no dimension, 1 + 1 = 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, is it really that we can remove the left side of the equation and simply say 1?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent the two are different and separate. Yet, looking at it from another perspective, they are the same; it&#39;s merely our perspective that changes. Or perhaps the depth at which we know/understand the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the exception of abstract methods (and not even then), I find that I tend to think with both perspectives in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since they say that the gods can look at a thing and know everything about it, this seems to be a good place to be, even if it&#39;s only with code, and not physical objects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Self Control</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Self-Control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 20:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Self-Control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a difference between self control and killing something off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self control is when you hunger for something, but say no. Killing something off is when you no longer hunger for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former is a near-constant struggle, depending upon how often the hunger makes itself known, while the latter is, once the desire is killed, relatively easy, except perhaps during moments of rememberence. Trying to remember what it was like to have a hunger/desire of a particular sort, can be, at times, more painful than the desire itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s not to say that the hunger can&#39;t be temporarily killed off. While attempting to satisfy the hunger it can die off. One either continues through the motions, stops, or tries to determine why the desire has disappeared. Which is worse, in such a case, must depend upon the particular circumstances at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Ayn Rand&#39;s The Fountainhead: Part 4</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following article will contain spoilers of Ayn Rand&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452273331?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt;. If you wish to read the book without my bias, do so before reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the previous parts, it seems that Ayn Rand has written the final part of The Fountainhead with two people as the focus of the part. Howard Roark is associated with this part, but Gail Wynand is obviously the secondary character. Yet, Ellsworth&amp;rsquo;s speech to Keating, which gives us a glimpse into what Ayn Rand fears, clarifies his character for us. If we didn&amp;rsquo;t learn so much about Wynand, and what makes him the same, yet different than Roark, Ellsworth could be seen as the secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, I was upset with the speech that Roark gave. Not because of what he said, but rather that he said it at all. Throughout the book Roark has been the same in one particular way. His speech, while correctly what he (and Rand) thinks, is out of character. Could Rand have made her philosophy as obvious, but without manipulating Roark?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see also that Keating has become a mere shell of a man - he has become nothing - while Roark has finally become himself. The world, it appears, has finally (been forced to) accept(ed) him. (I&amp;rsquo;m posting this 2 days later. Originally I had the following after this line. &amp;ldquo;(I)f we were to suppose that this is what Roark is, and not Rand&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;puppet&amp;rsquo; (being crude for a moment).&amp;rdquo; The feeling still stands - I was truly disappointed that she had to make Roark give a speech - but is quiet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this, I&amp;rsquo;d say that one could perhaps read Ellsworth&amp;rsquo;s and Roark&amp;rsquo;s speeches and understand the book/Rand completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a very long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve read a book that I had such a hard time putting down. Many nights I would stop reading, set it down, and then look at the time and/or how many pages I had to read until the next chapter. I would usually toss my head about and pick up the book, only to read another chapter. I&amp;rsquo;ve begun Atlas Shrugged immediately (in part because I was in Chicago and that was the only other book I packed) and finished a tenth of it in one day. It seems I&amp;rsquo;ll fly through that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philosophically, I have to leave my thoughts on that until another time. Generally, I think she seems to lean to far to an extreme. Yet, with Roark, such as when he helps Keating, we see a bit of middle-ground. Didn&amp;rsquo;t Roark know that Keating would fail? If he really didn&amp;rsquo;t, then what about his planning? Again, that would seem to be against his character, especially based on what he did before that, with the other project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Ayn Rand&#39;s The Fountainhead: Part 3</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 20:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following article will contain spoilers of Ayn Rand&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452273331?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt;. If you wish to read the book without my bias, do so before reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having finished Part 3 of The Fountainhead in less than a day, the whole should be fairly fresh in my memory. Yet, I have a hard time putting a second name to this part, to go along with Gail Wynand&amp;rsquo;s, and as I did for &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;my thoughts on part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent we could put Dominque&amp;rsquo;s again. After all, next to Wynand she is covered the most in this part, from her marriage to Keating to her marriage to Wynand, which continues the trend from the beginning of part 2. Ellsworth might belong as well, since he becomes a bit more clearer in this part, yet is it as clear as Dominque has become? Or have we instead seen her weakness exploited by someone who may not have even wanted to, and has certainly not completely realized that he has?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the previous parts, it seems that Wynand is still an enigma. This could certainly be due to the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s played such a minor role up to now. Looking at the four parts, and their respective names, one almost thinks that Dominque should have been named here, as Keating, Roark, Dominque, and Ellsworth are the four characters one would think of first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet perhaps that he remains an enigma is why he belongs here. To some extent, continuing the idea in my last article that Keating and Roark are on two ends of a (vertical) line, Wynand seems to belong in the middle of that line. He does what the masses want, because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t want them to spoil that which is truly beautiful. Take for instance the subtle point of his gallery, and his obvious remarks about the play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part four, having the name of Roark associated to it, suggests that we will move once again into the life of Roark. Armed with the full knowledge of what has happened to Keating, and a glimpse at Wynand, where will Roark take us? As we might expect, or in another direction?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Ayn Rand&#39;s The Fountainhead: Part 2</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 20:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part 1 of this series I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;the first part of Ayn Rand&#39;s The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt;. Having now finished part 2, I can write on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following will contain spoilers. I highly recommend you do not continue if you wish to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452273331?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt; with fresh eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of The Fountainhead is devoted to Ellsworth M. Toohey, as the subtitle suggests. This further introduces a character we had met in part one, but gives us the chance to get to know him further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toohey is a sort of hybrid of&amp;nbsp;Keating and Roark. Like Roark he seems to understand that one should strive after their own ideals, but like Keating tries to make the situation work in his best interests. This is most apparent when he speaks with Dominque and Catherine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the former he speaks bluntly and honestly, showing his greed and contempt for man. With the latter he shows his dual-nature, saying one thing while believing the opposite. Yet he holds contempt for those, like Stoddard, who have the basic idea in mind, but fail in their execution. Toohey appreciates those who can trick others into believing what they say, not what they mean, or using their words to say multiple things at once. Dominque&#39;s time at the witness stand, and earlier her article on Roark&#39;s building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also read exactly what&#39;s been going on in Dominque&#39;s mind this whole time, near the end of this part. It&#39;s hard to remember, but the beginning of this part involved the first meeting of Dominque and Roark, and their conquests over each other. If Rand had done it so for her other parts, Dominque&#39;s name could have appeared below Toohey&#39;s, as we learn so much more about her, making Ellsworth and Dominque the two main characters of this part (Keating and Roark being part one&#39;s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While our feelings of Ellsworth may have been further cemented in place, Dominque has changed from one without a purpose, to&amp;nbsp;an individual&amp;nbsp;driven by one. In a way, a sort of change from Keating into Roark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along these same lines, the beginning of the part is not without it&#39;s share of Roark. While we (I) may not have liked either one, I now understand that Roark and Keating are not on two ends of a horizontal line, but rather two ends of a vertical one, Keating being at the bottom. Roark ends up with nothing, but has grown stronger, while Peter now has everything he wanted before, but fears it. See for example the outburst with Guy at the end, the same end that was driving him in part one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part three awaits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update 5/25/2009: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-3.aspx&#34;&gt;Read part three of this series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Ayn Rand&#39;s The Fountainhead: Part 1</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 22:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve known of Ayn Rand for quite a number of years. The first time I can remember her being talked about was by a fellow philosophy student, approximately one year ahead of me, who was a rather big fan of her work. At least one professor got into arguments with this student, as she&#39;d&amp;nbsp;bring up&amp;nbsp;Rand&#39;s approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2002 and 2003 I read We the Living and Anthem, and enjoyed them well enough. Other than a scene in which red blood is on white snow, I can&#39;t say I remember all that much about them, but We the Living seemed to be very 1984 ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I picked up &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452273331?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452011876?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Atlas Shrugged&lt;/a&gt;, at some point, but never went about reading them. Reading about BioShock 2, having enjoyed the first, made me pick look at The Fountainhead and Atlas Shrugged, and after some research on which to begin with, I started on the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having just finished Part 1: Peter Keating, I can begin making some notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started the book I realized that I didn&#39;t care for either of the main characters, at the time being Peter Keating and Howard Roark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howard, being the main character, has ideals on what he believes a building should be.&amp;nbsp;From my uneducated perspective, I think he&#39;s right. The form of a building should follow it&#39;s function. While certain things were necessary in the past, just because they were used does not mean that they still need to be used. Yet, on the other hand, a certain amount of trim isn&#39;t too horrid, as long as it&#39;s not excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howard is fairly self-sufficient, but to a fault; he doesn&#39;t need most people, so he doesn&#39;t bother with them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the opposite end we have Peter Keating. Peter uses a number of people throughout part one to get to where he wants. Yet, as we know, he doesn&#39;t really care that he&#39;s in the profession that he&#39;s in, just that people, especially his mother, care about his accomplishments. He sees other people as serving a purpose to himself, and sees himself serving others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part one concludes, Howard and Peter are moving even further apart. While I still don&#39;t care for Peter, I do feel bad for him. He does only what he thinks will please others. Howard, on the other hand, has moved in my eyes from one who only cares about himself, to one who cares about the ideals that he has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the perspective that Ayn Rand is coming from, in that she seems to believe that the many should not control the one, but the one should not care only about itself. After all, one of the greatest things about man is that we can communicate with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll see what Part&amp;nbsp;2 brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update 5/24/2009: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Thoughts-on-Ayn-Rands-The-Fountainhead-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;Read part two of this series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countries that come to mind ...</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Countries-that-come-to-mind-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 23:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Countries-that-come-to-mind-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
When I think of Europe I think of the U.K., France, then Germany. What about Spain though?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Moving east, Japan and China, followed by North Korea. I realize that India should be on the list, but it&amp;#39;s not one that immediately comes to mind.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Africa, as a whole, is not on the list; only bad things come to mind (AIDs and spammers/scammers).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Same with Israel; isn&amp;#39;t it bad that&amp;nbsp;I think not of religiousness, but rather of constant war?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Is the above because of the media?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On &#34;Shafty&#34;</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Shafty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 20:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Shafty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    the terrible thing about hell&lt;br /&gt;
    is that when you&amp;#39;re there you can&amp;#39;t even tell&lt;br /&gt;
    as you move through this life you love so&lt;br /&gt;
    you could be there and not even know
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    but you say so what I&amp;#39;m doing just fine&lt;br /&gt;
    the irony is that it&amp;#39;s all in your mind&lt;br /&gt;
    and that&amp;#39;s why hell is so vicious and cruel&lt;br /&gt;
    but you&amp;#39;ll just go on an oblivious fool
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    (Phish/Marshall. &amp;quot;Shafty.&amp;quot; Lyrics. &lt;u&gt;The Story of the Ghost&lt;/u&gt;. 1998.)
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When you really think about it, I think it&amp;#39;s pretty obvious that life is striving, with small parts of boredom thrown in. This is obvious, I think, because everything we do is towards some goal, or end. Yet, once the goal is met, we find another goal to work towards.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, they say that Heaven is not like this; that instead, we have everything we need and want. This suggests that we must either be bored, continually striving towards new goals, which are immediately attained, and/or in some other state that we can&amp;#39;t even know, being a part of the world we live in (which is, &amp;#39;through-and-through will,&amp;#39; striving).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To some extent, the fact that we can never attain a goal that does not open us up to seeking, or finding without seeking, another, suggests that we may perhaps be in a sort of hell, not unlike what Phish suggests in &amp;quot;Shafty.&amp;quot;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yet, by the same token, we may already be in paradise. True, we&amp;nbsp;have before us an unlimited&amp;nbsp;number of goals to strive towards, from birth to death; every moment of our life is striving, or the briefest of moments between those periods (save for those very few who have attained a life without striving).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Along these lines I can recall a story I read many years ago (it may have been in &lt;em&gt;Dangerous Visions&lt;/em&gt; &amp;hellip;). In that story the main character commits suicide, thinking that there&amp;#39;s a better life (or something to that effect). Instead, after death, he finds that this was in fact a paradise, or rather, a vacation from his time elsewhere, which was in fact a kind of hell, in that it demanded so much of him.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Billy Joel once sang that he&amp;#39;d &amp;#39;rather laugh with the sinners, than cry with the saints.&amp;#39;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Too we must remember the Twilight Zone episode in which a man can never lose at pool. Yet, while that would make most happy for a while, the inability to lose would itself drive one crazy. No competition means the victory is flat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In my opinion, I would almost rather hope that Leibniz is correct, that this is the &amp;#39;best of all possible worlds,&amp;#39; and further, that we can live (in any sense of the world) in just this one.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You either did or didn&#39;t waste your time playing the video game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/You-either-did-or-didnt-waste-your-time-playing-the-video-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 21:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/You-either-did-or-didnt-waste-your-time-playing-the-video-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
You know what grinds my gears?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When people say that they wasted time playing a video game.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For example, &amp;#39;I was playing Fallout 3 and it began freezing at this certain point, twenty hours in; since I can&amp;#39;t proceed, I&amp;#39;ve wasted twenty hours of my life.&amp;#39;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hello? What do you get for finishing the game? Not the hours that you spent playing it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Or did you? If you spend 80 hours and beat a game, how is that really different? You beat it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But isn&amp;#39;t stopping after 20 hours because of a bug different than stopping because you got tired of the game? Sure it is. For the latter the game wasn&amp;#39;t any fun; there&amp;#39;s no point in wasting any more time. But for the former, the game &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; fun, and you want to spend more time with it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But you can&amp;#39;t. So suddenly the entire 20 hours becomes wasted time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But then they fix the issue and you&amp;#39;re able to continue. Yay.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But since you wasted 20 hours, why waste any more? Or did you really not waste those 20 hours? (Or did you, and wasting 20 hours wasn&amp;#39;t a bad thing?)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tagged &lt;strong&gt;xbox 360&lt;/strong&gt; since a video on Fallout 3 freezes was the reason for this post.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on sacrifice and religion</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-sacrifice-and-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 19:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-sacrifice-and-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The following is a reply to a co-worker on Facebook regarding a particular topic. Since it&amp;#39;s on Facebook, I probably can&amp;#39;t link to it, but since I don&amp;#39;t want to lose my response &amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;m afraid I can&amp;#39;t be as eloquent as everyone else; I&amp;#39;m a little mentally drained on nights.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That said, Obama called for all American&amp;#39;s to be ready to make sacrifices. There is little doubt that greed (part of the great motivator) is what brought this country to the knee it now rests on.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Maybe I&amp;#39;m wrong, but with that in mind, I&amp;#39;m not sure we should be focusing on any possible worlds outside of this one. It&amp;#39;s been quite a while, but I seem to recall that the focus of scripture is not on the next world, but the one that we live in.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We ought to do &amp;#39;good&amp;#39; now, in his world.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, it&amp;#39;s rather simple to do so, as it can be contained in just a few words. Love, for example. Or, Compassion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, the task that Obama has asked of us is more than compassion. I can show compassion but still keep what I have. To sacrifice, however, is to give up. To some extent, to act agressively against our striving/will.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You&amp;#39;re right that when we focus on this world we focus on the &amp;#39;now.&amp;#39; Heck, in a couple of months that which drove so many people yesterday will be a distant memory.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And of course it&amp;#39;s easy to talk of sacrifice. But, again, this existence is the only one that we know.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If a man was lying on the street bleeding to his death, what would Christ do? Would he talk to him of God and the eternal? Or would he instead help him to live?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yes, this life is transitory, but does that make it any less real?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don&#39;t Care For Ethics: 9 people on a boat</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Why-I-Dont-Care-For-Ethics-9-people-on-a-boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 16:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Why-I-Dont-Care-For-Ethics-9-people-on-a-boat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Since college I have disliked ethics. However, I couldn&amp;#39;t explain why.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On December 10, 2008, at approximately 10:04 PM, I turned on the lamp next to my bed and wrote the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    9 people on a boat that can only hold 8. What do you do? 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Even then I knew the answer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Morally, I think the answer is you (me) jump off the boat. 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Maybe I was reading too much Schopenhauer, but this seems like the only answer you can give.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Even if you were given information about the 8 other people, you can&amp;#39;t make a decision about why anyone else should jump or be thrown from the boat. But, here&amp;#39;s some other arguments that one might give. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Arguments&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the oldest. After all, they&amp;#39;re the nearest to death.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the youngest.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the one who isn&amp;#39;t married and doesn&amp;#39;t have children.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the one who can&amp;#39;t have children. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the atheist.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the christian.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the republican.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the democrat.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Vote on who should be thrown off.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Pick straws.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Throw off the stupidest. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Despite all these options, there is truly only one that can be picked, and may in fact lead to another because of it; allow the first to jump off to stay off. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Am I wrong? Is there any other way to solve this dilemma?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If it is the only way, can it be used to solve all other questions? What if you&amp;#39;re the only doctor? Or the only one who has survived in such a situation before? Or the only one strong enough to get the survivors back?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And this is why I don&amp;#39;t care for, and even dislike, ethics. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>