<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Birthday on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/birthday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Birthday on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2006 09:24:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/birthday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays and birthdays</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Holidays-and-birthdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2006 09:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Holidays-and-birthdays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
My birthday happens to be today, and when I started checking my email this morning, I was presented with 4 different birthday greetings, from 4 different forums.  I&amp;#39;m aware that forums have been doing this for a long time, so what struck me is the forums I signed up for, but don&amp;#39;t remember doing so :D  (That&amp;#39;s also a little security-scary&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;link1&#34; name=&#34;link1&#34; href=&#34;#note1&#34; title=&#34;link1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I know I&amp;#39;m signed up with many more that don&amp;#39;t appear to be sending birthday greetings.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about the worth of a good deal of holidays, especially when it comes to gifts.  This year, we&amp;#39;re going to spend little - hopefully nothing - on Christmas, and more on birthdays.  We&amp;#39;re doing this for a number of reasons.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, Christmas time is a usually the worst time to be shopping, since it&amp;#39;s so busy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Second, after doing all of that shopping, there&amp;#39;s no time to enjoy either the season or the gifts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On the other hand, not every family can get together for every birthday - it&amp;#39;s easier to get together for just one day, even if it is the busiest day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Third, birthdays mean more.  We&amp;#39;re not a religious family - they believe in some God, and I&amp;#39;m a Schopenhauerian&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;link2&#34; name=&#34;link2&#34; href=&#34;#note2&#34; title=&#34;link2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - so Christmas for us, and for a vast majority of the American people (no matter what faith they may say they believe in) is just another day we&amp;#39;re off from work, and one that tradition says must be filled with good food and gifts - like Thanksgiving.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
===
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Back to the emails I received today, this was a great feature of the board&amp;#39;s software.  Not only do a get a generic birthday greeting, but more importantly, I get a reminder of my involvement in the board.  Some of these four I&amp;#39;m not going to be checking up on, but at least 2 I will be, since my interest has grown in said areas (they are more techie boards).  It&amp;#39;s been a while, and I&amp;#39;d like to see just how they&amp;#39;ve grown.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What I checked into was a Wordpress plugin for this as well.  However, Wordpress users don&amp;#39;t currently enter a birthday.  So, it would involve creating another field for the user, and then creating a notification if it&amp;#39;s the user&amp;#39;s birthday.  It could be totally optional, but may just bring readers closer to a site, or at least give them a reminder on a good day to do so.  After all, there are few days as personal as the day of one&amp;#39;s birth (which, thereby, could be number four for the list above).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
===
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a id=&#34;note1&#34; name=&#34;note1&#34; href=&#34;#link1&#34; title=&#34;note1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;: Security-scary simply because it&amp;#39;s another way to find out personal information about me.  Of course, these days Google will give you everything you need to know about a person - and I don&amp;#39;t mind.  I want people to be able to do a search for me and find out how to contact me.  You never know ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a id=&#34;note2&#34; name=&#34;note2&#34; href=&#34;#link2&#34; title=&#34;note2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;: As in, I find Arthur Schopenhauer to have a good stand on life.  Whether that requires a God is questionable indeed, since, in a way, the Will is a kind of standard god (lowercase intentional).  I&amp;#39;m not sure whether Schopenhauerian is the correct term or not ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Update: May 14, 2006 @ 9:32 am&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One note that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it into this is that Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day and Father&amp;rsquo;s Day appear to be more Hallmark Days than anything, much like Secretary&amp;rsquo;s Day, and etcetera. These &amp;lsquo;Day&amp;rsquo;s are only necessary because we forget that these people should be thanked on a regular basis, not for doing their &amp;lsquo;job&amp;rsquo;, but also for just being who they are - someone close to us, or someone who provides some assistance to us.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, as with Christmas, having a specific day helps draw attention, on a large/national scale. So, there&amp;rsquo;s some benefit to it, however, too much consumerism is a bad thing - is it better to show how much you appreciate the Secretary by buying her a gift, or do you thank her in other ways?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Of course, now that the day exists, the Secretary, if smart, will want that material aspect to it, perhaps in the form of a bonus, or better in my opinion, a raise.)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
