<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flex on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/flex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flex on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 20:38:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/flex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreamweaver 8 as a MXML IDE?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Dreamweaver-8-as-a-MXML-IDE/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 20:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Dreamweaver-8-as-a-MXML-IDE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve spent the last couple of hours trying to get Dreamweaver 8 to begin to function as a MXML IDE. Unfortunately, while I can get every &amp;lt;mx: tag added to the code hints, I&amp;#39;m having a heck of a time getting the actual code hints to function.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The small tutorial that Macromedia (and truly it was Macromedia at the time) provided isn&amp;#39;t very helpful at all. CodeSnipers.com (link below) has some information on using Dreamweaver 8 a Ruby IDE, but since Ruby appears to be so function based ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My open call is this; can anyone point me to a good tutorial that focuses on setting up CodeHints.xml, TagChooser.xml, and TagLibraries.vtm? Or, just CodeHints.xml?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
===
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note: Title borrowed from &lt;a href=&#34;http://codesnipers.com/?q=node/175&#34;&gt;Dreamweaver 8 as a Ruby IDE&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling Flex applications with Dreamweaver</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Compiling-Flex-applications-with-Dreamweaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 18:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Compiling-Flex-applications-with-Dreamweaver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Tom Lee wrote a post in July detailing how to compile and run Flex applications using Dreamweaver.  Since Flex 2 is making me very excited, I felt it was post worthy (especially since I won&amp;#39;t have to do a Google search to get back to his post now).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tom-lee.blogspot.com/2006/07/edit-and-compile-flex-apps-in.html&#34;&gt;Edit and Compile Flex Apps in Dreamweaver&lt;/a&gt; details how to not only install Flex, but also how to easily, with the press of a button, compile Flex files using Dreamweaver and a couple of files.  Very cool stuff.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since I&amp;#39;m having a heck of a time getting Flex 1.5 so I can setup Eclipse to create/edit Flex, I&amp;#39;m glad I found this post.  If only Adobe would link to this post as well.  I can see why they want to push Flex Builder to developers, since they&amp;#39;re providing the Flex SDK free of charge, but still, the nice thing to do would point out that you can still get limited functionality with Dreamweaver ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As for Flex, I need to goof off with creating some of the sample apps before I do what I want to do - namely switch some of my downloadable programs into Flex apps :D
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>