<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wii on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/wii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wii on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 21:20:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/wii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kinect is selling really well; but is that good for gamers?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Kinect-is-selling-really-well-but-is-that-good-for-gamers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 21:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Kinect-is-selling-really-well-but-is-that-good-for-gamers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Techmeme had a couple of interesting titles this evening. &#34;&lt;a rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/kinect_is_selling_2x_as_fast_as_the_ipad.php&#34;&gt;Kinect is Selling 2X as Fast as the iPad&lt;/a&gt;&#34; and &#34;&lt;a rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://blogs.barrons.com/techtraderdaily/2010/11/29/microsoft-over-25m-kinect-sold/&#34;&gt;Microsoft: Over 2.5M Kinect Sold&lt;/a&gt;.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I thought I had the space for it (I&#39;d have to move furniture every time I wanted to play it in my current apartment) I still wouldn&#39;t pick up the Kinect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First there&#39;s the price. At $150 you might as well buy a PSP (which I did) or a Nintendo DSi. Either of which would solve the second issue, which is a lack of good games for that $150 you threw down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there&#39;s a couple of reasons it&#39;s done so well. First, it&#39;s fairly unique as a gaming device. Second, they&#39;ve marketed it to almost no end (I wonder how many devices they just gave away during their blitz?). Third, it&#39;s fast approaching the holiday season, which means parents buying gifts for kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also have those who are using the device for purposes other than those intended, but that&#39;s admitedly a very small chunk of that number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what&#39;s unfortunate is that it&#39;s doing so well, when there&#39;s so few games, which makes me afraid that the price on the device will drop rapidly, simply because it&#39;s become a niche device with no games developed for it, and those that are in line with what you can get on the Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, games that the older &#39;style&#39; of gamer won&#39;t want to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sony&#39;s Move seems like a better technology, as it builds upon the success (and science, if you will) of the Wii&#39;s controller, but moves it to a platform that can deliver much better graphically. Unfortunately, it too suffers from too few launch titles, although seemingly offers more in the next year. And of course a number of existing games have already been updated to now offer Move support (such as Heavy Rain). But, it hasn&#39;t been marketed anywhere near as much as the Kinect has, and it doesn&#39;t draw a big audience because it&#39;s too similar to the Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wii, which suffers from a large number of shovelware titles, made only to take advantage of the uniqueness of the console&#39;s controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps history won&#39;t repeat itself ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragile Dreams: Farewell Ruins of the Moon (Wii) - leveling and initial thoughts</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Fragile-Dreams-Farewell-Ruins-of-the-Moon-Wii-leveling-and-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 21:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Fragile-Dreams-Farewell-Ruins-of-the-Moon-Wii-leveling-and-initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little over an hour into &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002E6XY6U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Fragile Dreams: Farewell Ruins of the Moon&lt;/a&gt; I have three levels of information, and some preliminary thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Leveling information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll put this into an XML file at some point, I&#39;m sure, but here are the first three levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level - HP - Base Attack - Experience to next level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 - 100 - 4 - 1000&lt;br /&gt;2 - 120 - 6 - 3000&lt;br /&gt;3 - 140 - 8 - 6775&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve died once so far, when the third enemy I ran into (see also below) &#39;snuck&#39; up on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue ghosts give 100 points of experience, and seem to come back very frequently, so I was tempted to grind out a couple of levels on them. Just left the Subway, and it sounds like I&#39;ll probably be going back there soon, so perhaps I will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I have a basic Wii remote, so a newer model may work better. But what I&#39;ve found is that the pointer frequently gets lost, resulting in camera spin and disorientation. Since it was third-person, I thought I wouldn&#39;t be impacted by the game, but my stomach and head haven&#39;t been feeling too hot (although I do think I&#39;m still fighting something off, and the darkness of the game and weakness of the intial flashlight doesn&#39;t help).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third enemy you run into (the small blue ghosts being what I consider the second) are pretty freaky, reminding me of something I&#39;d see in Persona, or a SMT game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s early, but the story already seems&amp;nbsp;a little odd. You follow someone into a Subway and while you can&#39;t find them, there&#39;s also no way they could have gone anywhere, since every exit but the one you came in is locked ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s much too early, though, for any real decisions about the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published by XSEED Games, though, and something I was looking forward to when it was still questionable whether it was coming over to the States, so ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix on the Wii - my experience</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-on-the-Wii-my-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 21:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Netflix-on-the-Wii-my-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After receiving my instant streaming disc for the Wii a long while back, I finally popped it in my Wii and gave it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this experiment I watched three episodes of 30 Rock: Season 1. I wasn&#39;t expecting much for quality, and each episode isn&#39;t very long, so I thought I was giving the Wii a very good chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I was extremely impressed in the entire experience, and definitely think Nintendo&#39;s own video channels can learn a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike on the PS3 and Xbox 360, most of the functionality to browse and watch videos is available right from the control, with on-screen cues. For example, to start watching a video, press &#39;1.&#39; However, I didn&#39;t pause the videos, and am not exactly sure how that would be done (but assume the A button).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of the videos was much better than I expected, with TV-quality picture and sound. I do have a widescreen television (Sony Bravia) and while most content on the Wii displays in a standard-sized box, I had to manually switch to widescreen to view the video as expected, but since I have to do that for everything but the Xbox Netflix experience, I was expecting that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, since the Wii&#39;s control is the only console that I have that doesn&#39;t offer a rechargeable solution, I probably will not watch another Netflix streaming video on it. If it was my own choice to watch Netflix streaming videos on my television, however, I absolutely would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice job Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video games I&#39;m looking forward to in 2010</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Video-games-Im-looking-forward-to-in-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 11:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Video-games-Im-looking-forward-to-in-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In no particular order, here are the video games I&#39;m currently looking forward to playing in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that some games may have been released earlier. Consoles that games can be released for are the PS2/PS3, Xbox 360, or Wii (which therefore includes GameCube games). Since I will probably not be getting an Xbox Live Gold subscription this coming January, and am going to go back to playing RPGs on PS systems only, when possible, PS3&amp;nbsp;versions of multi-console releases&amp;nbsp;will be higher on my list. Of course, FFXIII on PS3 is a no-brainer, even if I was hard-core Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bioshock 2 (Feb 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tales of Vesperia (release for the PS3 w/ unknown date)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (Feb 2010 for PS3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy XIII (Mar 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resonance of Fate (May 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mass Effect 2 (Jan 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demon&#39;s Souls (Oct &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, once it drops in price a bit more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Borderlands.aspx&#34;&gt;Borderlands&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, once it drops in price a bit more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BioShock (for the PS3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the games that all signs point to interest being high, but that I&#39;m not interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assassin&#39;s Creed&amp;nbsp;II - Disappointed by the first one, and combat on this one looks pretty boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragon Age: Origins - Looks as though it would be good on the PC, but doubtfully so on consoles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Muramasa: The Demon Blade</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Muramasa-The-Demon-Blade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 20:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Muramasa-The-Demon-Blade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001HB7K6I?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Muramasa: The Demon Blade&lt;/a&gt;, for the Nintendo Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get it out of the way; Muramasa: The Demon Blade is the game that finally made my purchase of the Wii worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muramasa is in some ways similar to Super Metroid in that you progress around the game by moving from screen to screen, with enemy battles occuring randomly, as you move towards the act&amp;rsquo;s boss. Many paths are locked, only becoming accessible after you defeated set bosses, leading to some level of back-and-forth (especially for the male character Kisuke). Enemy lairs can also be unlocked in the same way, allowing your character to fight in multi-stage battles against set enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all, this results in an linear path from boss to boss, as each act takes place, with the random battles and (typically) multiple paths to objectives adding in a good level of diversity. Normal enemies level with you, so outside of mastering combat, no battle will seem boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featuring two characters, each with their own story line and bosses, you can play the game from each character&amp;rsquo;s perspective in any way you want, adding another layer of diversity to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game also features a robust weapon crafting system, with a total of 108 weapons (all swords) that can be unlocked, but which feature level-based requirements. For those that don&amp;rsquo;t want this experience, however, each boss unlocks a weapon (again, unique for each character), allowing players to switch to these new weapons as the game progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical to games of this genre, a leveling component increases character health, strength, and vitality, which impacts what blades you can equip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based solely on my own gameplay, each character&amp;rsquo;s story lasts around 9 hours, allowing for a fair amount of exploration and forging of new blades. For the most part, grinding for levels is unnecessary, especially considering that dying carries almost no penalty at all, during boss and lair fights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post-game allows you to unlock the remaining blades, as a handful of these can only be acquired after you have beaten the game with each character. Additional, alternate, endings are also available, again for each character. In total, this resulted in over 25 hours of gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest draw of the game, coming up in almost any discussion, and which I&amp;rsquo;ve therefore left for the last, is the art and story style. The art of the game is simply beautiful, with the power of the Wii stretch to the breaking point. It would have been something to see this game on the Xbox 360 or Playstation 3, where areas would have loaded faster the pixel borders would have been near-invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spoken language throughout the game is Japanese, with English subtitles, and no way to each either of these. While this may distract some, it leads to a much more &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I must give this game a full 5 stars. There are few drawbacks to the game, with the only semi-semi-major ones being from what I believe to be hardware-related issues (the few second loading from screen to screen and the visibly square pixels), and the art, music, and forging element adding considerable value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that the fast nature of battles (many standard battles will last seconds, while some boss battles may last dozens of minutes or more) allows for a very high level of replayability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you consider yourself a gamer and your Wii has a coat of dust, go check out some gameplay videos. If it looks good, go buy this game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muramasa: The Demon Blade - Complete weapon listing</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Muramasa-The-Demon-Blade-Complete-weapon-listing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 22:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Muramasa-The-Demon-Blade-Complete-weapon-listing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There aren&#39;t too many good gamer&#39;s games on the Nintendo Wii, so when Muramasa: The Demon Blade started getting advertised, I started getting really excited. Finally,&amp;nbsp;a reason to dust off the Wii and play something other than Virtual Console games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 108 blades available, Muramasa is also a completionist&#39;s dream. With the interest of making it a little easier to determine what weapons are available, I&#39;ve crafted the following file, listing all the blades with their type, attack, secret arts, and effects, as well as which of the two character&#39;s trees it belongs to (those shared blades are noted as such, however some I still need to set).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still want to complete the requirements, as well as make it sortable and a little more robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/files/MuramasaBlades.xml&#34;&gt;Muramasa: The Demon Blade&amp;nbsp;weapon database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to pick semi-easy-on-the-eyes colors, to help break out the listing a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments are of course welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wii for gamers</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Wii-for-gamers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 08:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Wii-for-gamers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    &amp;quot;Seriously considering purchasing a Wii (and only playing virtual console games)&amp;quot; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/strivinglife/status/1147123347&#34;&gt;James Skemp&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the February 2009 edition of GameInformer, they have an article titled &amp;quot;Hardcore Gamer&amp;#39;s Guide to the Wii.&amp;quot; In that same issue, on the ratings page, there is one Wii game with an 8.5. The next highest is 8.25, followed by a number of 7.75s.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since GameInformer is a magazine for gamers, I therefore make the claim that the article should have been titled &amp;quot;Gamer&amp;#39;s Guide to the Wii&amp;quot; (note the missing word).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Clearly, when I spoke earlier, I wasn&amp;#39;t joking; why would a gamer purchase a Wii, other than for the Virtual Console?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nintendo.com/wii/virtualconsole/games&#34;&gt;the list of games&lt;/a&gt;, I can find a number that make me recall my old systems (one of which was taken from me all too soon):
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Donkey Kong Country
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Secret of Mana
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Super Mario Bros. (1, 2, 3, and lost levels, which we had as one, but they&amp;#39;ve done separately)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Super Mario RPG
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Super Mario World
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Super Metroid
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then there&amp;#39;s other games which I&amp;#39;ve heard are good, or which I wouldn&amp;#39;t mind playing again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sadly, some games are missing (Earthbound comes to mind immediately), but I can see a little over 15,000 Wii points waiting to be spent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, these are Virtual Console games, hence somewhat geared more towards older gamers, who grew up on these games. (Who else remembers Wal-Mart having a SNES with Super Mario World? How far along had someone gotten yours? Ours was to the last boss, but I don&amp;#39;t think Star World was done. Heck, I just re-found my old game guide the other weekend for this game and a bunch of others.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Is WiiWare the answer? Perhaps &amp;hellip; but it remains to be seen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>