<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 08:53:33 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Cash N Guns Second Edition</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Cash-N-Guns-Second-Edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 08:53:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Cash-N-Guns-Second-Edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Cash N Guns Second Edition, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fun with a good group&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When initially reading over the instructions for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KU10OUU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Cash N Guns&lt;/a&gt; I wasn&#39;t sure how it would actually play. The idea of robbers trying to split the loot from a heist is pretty easy to understand, but would it play out fairly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now played the game in a group of five I think it went fairly well. With the exception of one person (who had played before and knew the rules), everyone else had either known each other for a few months, or in the case of two people, for quite a while. While those two did end up going back and forth, it ultimately didn&#39;t have much of an impact upon the group as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to bring this to my normal group, but one individual has an issue with the inclusion of the foam guns, and would have skipped out had we played. Something to keep in mind depending upon the group, as the game does involve pointing a foam gun at another player, and either shooting them, or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the set&#39;s pieces, I found them to be of a very high quality, and they seem they&#39;ll hold up against abuse as any other game would. However, I did find that the drawings at the bottom of the box, while nice, kept throwing me off; I kept expecting them to be pieces of the game, and not part of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KU10OUU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Cash N Guns&lt;/a&gt; 4 stars of 5. The game is simple enough to play in about 30 minutes, but the number of required players (to make it fair and fun) and the fact that my group can&#39;t play it because of the guns/shooting is unfortunate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Gray Matter (2010)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Gray-Matter-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 15:35:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Gray-Matter-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/260570/&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Gray Matter&lt;/a&gt; (2010), available for the PC on Steam and on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004NNVE8M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;An enjoyable story, with minor puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find point and click adventures to be generally enjoyable, but the older I get the more interest I have in the story they tell than the puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I finally started playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/260570/&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Gray Matter&lt;/a&gt;, which I received for very cheap as part of a bundle, my main focus was on the story. Having now put almost 12 hours into it (having let the game run a bit, it was probably closer to 11), I have to say I ultimately enjoyed the game, and might seek out more of Jane Jensen&#39;s works (a writer on the game).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game follows Sam/Samantha as she interacts with David and the other characters we meet. As she is a magician, the puzzles mostly involve her performing tricks or solving puzzles as she gets closer to her goal of becoming a master magician. However, the focus of the game is not on the tricks, but rather the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some interesting twists as the story progresses, and it had me shivering in a few spots. I definitely recommend this game if you&#39;re looking for an interesting story, and have at least a passing enjoyment of point and click adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/260570/&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Gray Matter&lt;/a&gt; gets 4 of 5 stars, only because of very slight control issues in a handful of scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>