<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Playstation on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/playstation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Playstation on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 20:49:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/playstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite Final Fantasy mini-game</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/My-favorite-Final-Fantasy-mini-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 20:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/My-favorite-Final-Fantasy-mini-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0000296O5?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Final Fantasy VIII&lt;/a&gt; for many years, but have never finished it. In fact, I&#39;ve never gotten through the first disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, having recently started it up once again, after picking up an electronic copy on the PSN (I still have the original, but this is the only legit way to play it on my PSP), I have to say that Final Fantasy VIII contains my favorite mini-game of the series, and perhaps one of my top favorites of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triple Triad is a card game in which you go up against one other player. You each start with five cards from your collection. Depending upon the active rules you may see your opponents cards (and vice versa) or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically you each take turns laying down a single card on a three-by-three grid. Each card has a set of four numbers, for each side, and possibly an element type (which I&#39;ve never gotten far enough to use). The objective is to have more cards than your opponent, where you take cards by laying a card next to one of theirs that beats the corresponding number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not in English, but &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K1r68IAjP9E&amp;amp;feature=related&#34;&gt;this video on YouTube shows one game&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course there&#39;s the addicting music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&#39;s because I&#39;ve played this part at least 3 or 4 times, but there&#39;s nothing like the first time you go up against this particular player and win the Quistis card. My deck usually seems to be Ifrit, Caterchipillar, and the rest Bomb, until you get either Quistis or Wedge, Biggs, or Iron Giant. Once you have one or two of those last three you can easily win every game against this particular player, and provides some nice downtime if you don&#39;t want to move on to the next mission quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Parasite Eve</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Parasite-Eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 11:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Parasite-Eve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000038ABO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Parasite Eve&lt;/a&gt;, for the Sony PlayStation (1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost six years ago, back in 2005, I found and picked up a copy of Parasite Eve. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall the exact circumstances on why I picked it up, but I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet that seeing &amp;lsquo;Squaresoft&amp;rsquo; on the jewel case had more than a little to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0045U4U52?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The 3rd Birthday&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s U.S. launch fast approaching, I put the first Parasite Eve back on my list, having not played it since a short time after I bought it, and even then not having finished the game. Thanks to a YouTube user&amp;rsquo;s help, I started playing the game again, from the start, and finished it one very late night a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parasite Eve is our first experience with New York copy Aya Brea, who over the course of 6 days battles against forces unleashed upon New York, before they expand to the entire world. Overall a pretty solid story, although bits of the quasi-science&amp;nbsp;are laughable. An initial play will take from 9 to 13 hours, although seasoned hands can finish the game in around 7 hours. (I completed the game in around 11 hours and 45 minutes, doing everything that I could in my first play through.) Once the game has been completed an EX game is unlocked, which allows you to replay the game, keeping some amount of your character&amp;rsquo;s goods, and possibly unlock an additional ending. As noted above I actually finished the game late one night (early one morning), since I felt compelled to see the game to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&amp;nbsp;game is an action RPG, involving leveling of your character and her weapons/equipment, with battle portions allowing you to move around while your action gauge fills. So, a sort of cross between Secret of Mana and Final Fantasy VII. Overall, I personally found it to be rather enjoyable, once I got into the hang of how the battles play out. The camera is stuck in place, much like the first Resident Evil games, but generally has little effect on battles. (You will have to watch for chests.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully the game does not feature tank controls (which I can&amp;rsquo;t stand), and was part of that group of PlayStation games that allowed analog controls (but at the price&amp;nbsp;of being able to use the d-pad). I played the game on my 80 gig PlayStation 3, and experienced no issues, outside of one of my controllers seemingly having the analog stick stuck &amp;lsquo;up&amp;rsquo; at times. (Swapping out another controller resolved the issue.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s obvious what generation the game is from because of the CG, and the normal graphics are flat, but despite that the game has held up &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; well. Of course, that may be because I found the battle system so enjoyable, and because the graphic quality fits with the darker atmosphere of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game does have a Mature rating, but what I assume gave it the rating is a character model later in the game that could be compared to Shiva&amp;rsquo;s model in the Final Fantasy series. There&amp;rsquo;s some talk about sexual themes as well, but nothing that a teenager doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about from school. (The EX game&amp;rsquo;s ending may feature content that pushed this game into the M rating.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is an amazing game, and I look forward to doing an EX game run very soon, and perhaps even moving on to Parasite Eve 2. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Hearts: Covenant leveling information</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Shadow-Hearts-Covenant-leveling-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 10:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Shadow-Hearts-Covenant-leveling-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I continue to look through my old files I found leveling information for Shadow Hearts: Covenant, from December 2005 to January (1st)&amp;nbsp;2006.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve converted it from an ODS file to XML, and am making it available. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/ShadowHeartsCovenant.xml&#34;&gt;Shadow Hearts: Covenant leveling guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/ShadowHeartsFromTheNewWorld.xml&#34;&gt;leveling guide for Shadow Hearts: From the New World&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Shadow-Hearts-From-the-New-World-leveling-information.aspx&#34;&gt;previously written about&lt;/a&gt;), it almost makes sense to go back and play the original Shadow Hearts to get information for that game as well. I&#39;ve been meaning to replay it, so ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Achievements and Trophies</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/On-Achievements-and-Trophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/On-Achievements-and-Trophies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To a very large extent, I consider myself to be a gamer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time the NES came out, my family picked up an Atari 2600, used. I don&#39;t know who sold it to us, but I can remember going with my dad to pick it up at my school&#39;s playground (that was the meeting place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a later point we picked up an NES, via my dad, and then my mom bought us a SNES. Nintendo 64 came after that, followed by the Playstation, Playstation 2, and Playstation 3, all of which I purchased. (I can&#39;t recall the N64 purchase, but I think that was a family purchase.) Finally the Xbox 360 and Wii. At some point there was a Game Gear as well, which our dad picked up for us at a Circuit City, if I remember correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, with that kind of history, I&#39;ve been playing games over over half my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before when you wanted to play with someone you had to invite them over. Now you can play with people all over the world. Boasting about beating a game, or getting a certain score, is as timeless as games themselves, and there were (are?) books that even kept track of this information. But with Microsoft&#39;s Xbox came achievements, which, although possible to cheat, allows you to show anyone (with a Live account) just what kind of gamer you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, or maybe the month before, I surpassed the second person I personally knew in Achievements on Xbox Live. I also surpassed the one person I personally know in Trophies shortly after they were launched, although being relatively new to the PS3, that wasn&#39;t very hard to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Xbox, one of those individuals (the first I passed) purchased their Xbox around December 2006, while the second purchased their&#39;s around January 2006. (I didn&#39;t dig into their information very deeply, and they don&#39;t track it as much as I do, so ... these are estimates.) I purchased my Xbox in December 2008. And in five months and change I&#39;m approaching 9900 points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now some people might consider me an achievement &#39;whore,&#39; in that I gained so many points so fast. However, I think it&#39;s important to look further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I have played 22 games on Xbox 360. Those games allow for 18775 gamerscore, if I were to get every point. (Although that&#39;s actually high, since they track points for games in which you can&#39;t get all the points yet, such as for Halo 3.) I have 9830, which is 52.36%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those 22 games, I don&#39;t own 2 of them, having instead borrowed them. Those two games gave me 205 of 2250, and since I felt extremely ill after playing those games, I will probably be unable to pick them up again. Removing those &#39;bad decisions&#39; would result in 58.25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two games that I own that I don&#39;t play, one of which came with another, and one of which I can&#39;t get the control scheme down. Subtracting the 120 of 2000 would result in 65.44%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the 18 games remaining, I have beat (meaning the main story line) 12 of them. I am close to completing&amp;nbsp;2 others, and 4 I would consider endless (I consider Rez HD to have a story line).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play games, and I beat &#39;em.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trophies on the Playstation 3 are a little different. I have trophies listed for 12 games on the PS3 (although 1 additional game should be listed, and is not). Having four different types of trophies, I have 101 bronze and 18 silver, with no gold or platnium trophies. I have beat the story on four of those games (since I purchased Eden Encore, I&#39;m missing those gardens, so that game is now &#39;unfinished&#39;), and have not on 6. Two others I would consider endless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since they use a percentage of completion, doing the math gives a 23.8% completion rate across those games with trophies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Metal Gear Solid 4, which has no trophies, was finished twice by me. Uncharted got beat three times, and the third time was for the trophies. And that&#39;s not to mention all the other games I&#39;ve finished on the PS3 and PS2, before trophies (and for the latter, achievements) were about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I go for achievements? Yeah, sometimes I&#39;ll do something and then re-load a save to continue with a game. Is that because the achievement is silly? Yeah. But if they feel it necessary to give an arbitrary value to something silly, I&#39;ll go with the designers on that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I play the game to play the game. And if it&#39;s horrid, I won&#39;t play it. (But I will let the achievements keep me going, when I would otherwise give up - I&#39;ve tried three times to finish disc 1/2 of FFXIII, and I just can&#39;t do it.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve been up to (Feb &#39;09 edition)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/What-Ive-been-up-to-Feb-09-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 20:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/What-Ive-been-up-to-Feb-09-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
As my last post may have suggested ... I&amp;#39;ve been playing games. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s a small taste of the games currently on my plate. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Playstation 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Hearts: From the New World&lt;/strong&gt; was close to completion .. before I bought an Xbox 360. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Persona 3: Fes&lt;/strong&gt; still remains to be started, and&amp;nbsp;ditto for &lt;strong&gt;Persona 4&lt;/strong&gt; ... Yes, I didn&amp;#39;t even start Persona 4. Yes, I know how good reviews said it is. (I did pre-order it, after all.) 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Disgaea&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be &amp;#39;finished,&amp;#39; and &lt;strong&gt;Disgaea 2&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be started. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I didn&amp;#39;t finish the first, I pre-ordered &lt;em&gt;Devil Summoner 2&lt;/em&gt; ... How could I not? If it&amp;#39;s great, I&amp;#39;d never be able to get a copy again. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Playstation 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I just picked up &lt;strong&gt;Flower&lt;/strong&gt; the other day, and really enjoyed it. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Disgaea 3&lt;/em&gt; has been out for a while, and they&amp;#39;re releasing questionable character packs, but ... it&amp;#39;s still supposedly a solid game. Need to pick up a copy ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Xbox 360&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lost Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt; is my current game of choice. Maybe a week more for that to be finished. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I should get further in &lt;strong&gt;Skate&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;#39;s certainly not Tony Hawk ... This might be a rainy day game. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Blue Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Infinite Undiscovery&lt;/strong&gt; need to be started. Probably once I finished Lost Odyssey I&amp;#39;ll do so. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fallout 3&lt;/strong&gt; seemingly still has a couple of major bugs. This the only reason I haven&amp;#39;t been playing it as much as I&amp;#39;d like; it&amp;#39;s really a pretty awesome game. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fable 2&lt;/em&gt;, also seemingly had bugs, but they may be fixed? If so, this sounds like a definite buy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Others that I missed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After writing this, I realized I missed a couple.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Valkyria Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; (Playstation 3) has been getting very good reviews, and the demo I played wasn&amp;#39;t too shabby.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I played the demo for &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: The Force Unleashed&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the Playstation 3,&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;was tempted. All things being equal, this is probably something I&amp;#39;ll pick up for the Xbox 360&amp;nbsp;at some point. (For the power aspect, not the Star Wars/George Lucas aspect.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tales of Vesperia&lt;/em&gt; (Xbox 360) has gotten &amp;#39;eh&amp;#39; reviews, but I starred it for some reason ... probably a video review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lost Planet&lt;/em&gt; (Xbox 360) and &lt;em&gt;The Last Remnant&lt;/em&gt; (Xbox 360) are for picking up when they&amp;#39;re cheap, since the last is supposedly pretty &amp;#39;eh,&amp;#39; while the second has graphics issues, and needs a patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Even though life is merely striving, it&amp;#39;s good to know that I won&amp;#39;t suffer from boredom on account of not having enough video games to enjoy ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Hearts: From the New World leveling information</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Shadow-Hearts-From-the-New-World-leveling-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 22:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Shadow-Hearts-From-the-New-World-leveling-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A leveling &amp;#39;guide&amp;#39; for Shadow Hearts: From the New World is now available; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/ShadowHeartsFromTheNewWorld.xml&#34;&gt;Shadow Hearts: From the New World leveling&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not only should it have been written up and posted a while ago, it gave me a good chance to use XSD (XML Schema Definition). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I tried creating one for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/vehicle_gas.xml&#34;&gt;tracking my vehicles&amp;#39; gas usage&lt;/a&gt;, but failed. Having worked through the issues on this one, I think I now know what I did wrong. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Next step is to work on an XSLT (XSL Transformation) for the file. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anywho, this covers the experience between levels, and the HP, MP, and SP for characters, per level. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playstation Home Beta: First impressions</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Playstation-Home-Beta-First-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 19:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Playstation-Home-Beta-First-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Eh.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think it looks really good, but I&amp;#39;m not sure a 3d world is what really drives me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That&amp;#39;s about all I&amp;#39;ve got to say at the moment. Definitely looks good, but ... if you don&amp;#39;t want to meet people, what&amp;#39;s the point?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Side-note: Couldn&amp;#39;t find the themed environments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a good video game great?</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/What-makes-a-good-video-game-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 23:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/What-makes-a-good-video-game-great/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A while ago I was reading a thread asking individuals what games they had last played multiple times.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, I actually have a hard time coming up with more than a couple, even though I&amp;#39;m sure I must have played games all the way through when I had more time (id est, in college).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only two I could think of were Uncharted: Drake&amp;#39;s Fortune and Metal Gear Solid 4: Guns of the Patriots.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I played Uncharted, from beginning to end, three times.&amp;nbsp;The third time was because trophy support had been added in, and I wanted the trophies for what I&amp;#39;d already been able to accomplish before.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Metal Gear Solid 4 I did an initial play, doing whatever I felt like (and eventually what the game finally beat into me as how I shoiuld play if I wanted to finish it), and one more with zero kills.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I believe I played through Final Fantasy VII twice, as I first purchased and played the PC version, and then the Playstation version. While I think I finished the PC version, I can&amp;#39;t recall for certain (but I&amp;#39;m almost positive I did).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I started a second playthrough of Final Fantasy X-2, but I only got a little way in before I got wrapped up with other things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve tried to play FF8 and FF9 a number of times, but never stuck with it long enough, which could also be said for a handful of other games.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ultimately, it was the story that really drove me on in both Uncharted and MGS4; I played them and didn&amp;#39;t get sick of them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now there&amp;#39;s other games that I&amp;#39;ve picked back up, after &amp;#39;beating&amp;#39; them, such as FFXII, Katamari Damacy and We Love Katamari (although not so much the latter), LittleBigPlanet, and way back when, Super Mario World and Mario 64. (And I&amp;#39;m very tempted to play through the first Shadow Hearts again, because I remember loving it when I first played it, because of the story and gameplay.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ultimately, then, it is the story that really makes a game worth it to me, in that I want to go through the game again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I was lent Bioshock, and I think that may take another spot in this short list (although whether it&amp;#39;s the 360 or PS3 version that takes it, depends upon time).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My only hope is that Uncharted 2 and Bioshock 2, not to mention some game among all those other games that will be out between now and the former, will be a part of this list as well ...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persona 4 pre-order goody = wow</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Persona-4-pre-order-goody-equals-wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 19:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Persona-4-pre-order-goody-equals-wow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Mustn&amp;#39;t ... look ... too ... closely ... (already ruined one surprise)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Atlus certainly out-did themselves this time, with the Persona 4 pre-order goody. While I was expecting the &amp;quot;Visual Data&amp;quot; bonus to be large enough to fit behind the game&amp;#39;s case, like the Persona 3 bonus, this one is actually graphic novel sized. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Very nice Atlus, very nice. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And, with reviews like this, looks like we can expect a Persona 5 in the near future. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now it&amp;#39;s just a question of what the soundtrack is like ... but I&amp;#39;m too hesitant to pop that in before I start playing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1+ hours of text and video before gameplay, here I come! (As soon as the guide gets here, of course :D) (Unless I really &lt;em&gt;won&amp;#39;t&lt;/em&gt; get it until next Monday. Come Saturday evening, I&amp;#39;m popping it in.)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I own an Xbox 360</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/I-own-an-Xbox-360/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 21:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/I-own-an-Xbox-360/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
So I did it. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Back on November 17 2007 &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/10-random-reasons-why-I-bought-a-Playstation-3.aspx&#34;&gt;I purchased a Playstation 3&lt;/a&gt;. I had debated, back and forth, the purchase of that versus the Xbox 360. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the time the Xbox was having quite a few issues, including overheating, power block malfunctions, and the wonderful RROD. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, as time has gone by, the number of complaints has gone down. Some say that the issues are basically resolved, and you just need to find newer systems. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What I can tell you is I spent the $39.99 for the extended warranty from Best Buy, and I only purchased the Pro &amp;#39;edition&amp;#39; (while I really wanted the black one, I couldn&amp;#39;t justify the extra $100). I realize that I&amp;#39;ll probably have issues with it at some point, but the Playstation 3 just isn&amp;#39;t pumping out the good games as fast as it can. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, I&amp;#39;m back to a state that I haven&amp;#39;t been in since the N64 was still about; I&amp;#39;m a two console man. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s a couple of things that I don&amp;#39;t know that I care for with the Xbox 360. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Everything seems really large. There&amp;#39;s a huge power brick, there&amp;#39;s huge plugs. The controller seems excessive ... WTF? 
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Batteries for the controller? Really? I&amp;#39;m spoiled by my Playstation 3 in this regard; plug it into the machine using a standard USB cable to charge it and that&amp;#39;s it. 
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    The fan is loud. However, it runs pretty cool (to the touch, that is). 
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Loud disc reads. Could be because it&amp;#39;s vertical, but it just seems kind of loud. 
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    30 minutes to start playing (on initial setup). I also kind of wanted to hold off on activating the Gold membership trial until this weekend, but, whatever, I guess it&amp;#39;s okay. 
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Otherwise, I&amp;#39;m pretty happy thus far. Still getting used to the controller, but ... a good purchase. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I am glad I purchased my PS3 first, however. Besides, now when my system has to go in for repair I can still game. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As before, I&amp;#39;m still updating &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/video_games.xml&#34;&gt;my XML file with my game purchases&lt;/a&gt;. Although I&amp;#39;ll probably work on moving it to an ASP.NET page eventually ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update 12/07/2008&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://live.xbox.com/member/strivinglife&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;My official profile&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of LittleBigPlanet: BradyGames Signature Series Guide</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-of-LittleBigPlanet-BradyGames-Signature-Series-Guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 20:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-of-LittleBigPlanet-BradyGames-Signature-Series-Guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rated 5 stars.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/review/R30R783N0UIOZX/ref=cm_cr_rdp_perm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rate this review on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Purchase this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0744010446?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001IVXI7C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;game&lt;/a&gt; through Amazon.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First of all, this is a beautiful guide. Every time I pick up one of the Brady Games guides I&amp;#39;m impressed with the quality of the actual item. Nice smooth pages, great colors, etcetera.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
About 66% of this guide deals with the story mode. This involves a checklist of items for each level, as well as hints and tips on completing them successfully.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The remainder handles the level creation tools, which is really where the replay value of LittleBigPlanet is going to be. Once you&amp;#39;ve read this, you&amp;#39;ll be able to create your own level with relative ease.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, LittleBigPlanet itself has tutorials for most of the items you can use to build levels, but having it in one place for future review is timeless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, all-in-all, a very solid book.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The minor issues I mentioned in my review title are solely that:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
a) There&amp;#39;s no overview map of the story levels. Granted, these levels are rather large, but I&amp;#39;d still like to see a couple of pages near the beginning, with the full maps.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
b) A comprehensive checklist of items. In other words, here&amp;#39;s all of the stickers, and where you can find them. Etcetera.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I&amp;#39;m also not seeing a listing of items you receive after doing the tutorials.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I can&amp;#39;t remove an entire star because of these two minor issues, so 4.5 stars is rounded to 5.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;You&amp;#39;ll use most of the guide for 100% completion in story mode, once, and refer to the rest for as long as the level creation functionality keeps your interest.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LittleBigPlanet - First day, first thoughts</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/LittleBigPlanet-First-day-first-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 20:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/LittleBigPlanet-First-day-first-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Right or wrong, GameStop was in stock and selling pre-orders of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001IVXI7C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LittleBigPlanet&lt;/a&gt; today, so I was able to pick up my copy, along with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0744010446?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;official guide&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thus far I&amp;#39;ve gone through four complete areas, and picked up the trophies accordingly. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On only the first level did I actually get a 100% (but not the Ace award), and with the later levels, I had to retry a number of times. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It seems also that there are some issues with movement, in particular from the foreground to background, and vice versa. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I haven&amp;#39;t played much with the creation functionality, since I want to go through the game once (and then pick up the missing items as time goes by), but I did go through the tutorials, and the Brady guide should otherwise help. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specialists guide/listing for Disgaea: Hour of Darkness (Playstation 2 Greatest Hits)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Specialists-guidelisting-for-Disgaea-Hour-of-Darkness-Playstation-2-Greatest-Hits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 17:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Specialists-guidelisting-for-Disgaea-Hour-of-Darkness-Playstation-2-Greatest-Hits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A brief &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/files/DisgaeaHourOfDarkness.xml&#34;&gt;guide/listing of specialists for Disgaea: Hour of Darkness (Playstation 2 Greatest Hits)&lt;/a&gt; is now available.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While there are other guides available, I didn&amp;#39;t find one that I could easily print out and make note of which character had which specialists. Now I&amp;#39;ve got one.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Comments appreciated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LittleBigPlanet - New site and available for pre-order</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/LittleBigPlanet-New-site-and-available-for-pre-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 23:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/LittleBigPlanet-New-site-and-available-for-pre-order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Got a notice of &lt;a href=&#34;http://littlebigplanet.us.playstation.com/&#34;&gt;http://littlebigplanet.us.playstation.com/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in my Gmail account a few moments ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was unaware that LittleBigPlanet was already available for pre-order. I looked at Amazon, but, quite frankly, I want it rather quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BestBuy.com doesn&amp;rsquo;t have it listed, but Gamestop.com does, so &amp;hellip; my first online purchase through that site. Store pick-up selected, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I don&amp;rsquo;t care for is that there will supposedly be different items available for pre-ordering, depending upon where you do so. For instance, a sticker book? Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho,&amp;nbsp;we&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens. If anything, I suppose I can just cancel the pre-order, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing Game Stop will get either the Brady guide, or one of the figures. Brady guide also makes sense&amp;nbsp;for Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sticker book? That must be some sticker book &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related links:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.us.playstation.com/2008/08/05/littlebigplanet-pre-order-goodness/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LittleBigPlanet: Pre-order Goodness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ZKA0JG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Order through Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on PixelJunk Eden</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Thoughts-on-PixelJunk-Eden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 22:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Thoughts-on-PixelJunk-Eden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This morning Charter fixed whatever issues they were having, so I was able to purchase and download the full version of PixelJunk Eden.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I played 30 minutes this morning, and many hours this afternoon/evening. (When I&amp;nbsp;shut down for the last time, my&amp;nbsp;rank was 1013 - I&amp;#39;m sure it&amp;#39;s already changed though.)&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As the demo suggested, this game is the closest thing to a masterpiece I&amp;#39;ve seen in a very long time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While it may not have the quantity, the Playstation Network is certainly attracting a number of quality, unique, games.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hopefully we can luck forward to many more gardens in the future, that we can grow/explore (although I suppose that would make one of their trophies incorrect, so an upgrade would have to resolve that issue).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
