<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bruce Springsteen on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/bruce-springsteen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bruce Springsteen on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 08:07:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/bruce-springsteen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What The Boss means to me; an open letter to Bruce Springsteen</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-The-Boss-means-to-me-an-open-letter-to-Bruce-Springsteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 08:07:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-The-Boss-means-to-me-an-open-letter-to-Bruce-Springsteen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Mr. Bruce Springsteen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I can&amp;#39;t remember the exact date, or even the year, it was shortly after my parents had divorced, and my father moved out into the country, that I first listened to &lt;u&gt;Born in the U.S.A.&lt;/u&gt;; it was one of my father&amp;#39;s old tapes. Now, I really wonder that I didn&amp;#39;t wear that old tape out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I was pre-teen, and living in northern Wisconsin, and raised Catholic,&amp;nbsp;so not all of the lyrics made sense (not that I really thought about them all that much outside of remembering the exact order, so I could sing the songs by heart), so in that sense, I certainly was lacking an understanding of what they really meant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, they sounded really great, and I was old and smart enough to realize the few that were applicable at the time, being in &amp;#39;love,&amp;#39; and, for the first time in that state, also having the one I really liked (for that&amp;#39;s what it was), like me as well. They were all great songs, but some really stuck with me; &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m On Fire,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Downbound Train,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Cover Me,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Glory Days,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Dancing In The Dark,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;My Hometown&amp;quot; (which I would think of many times in my near future).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Later, I would ask for, and receive, one of my first CDs, getting not &lt;u&gt;Born in the U.S.A.&lt;/u&gt; as I asked for, but instead &lt;u&gt;Greatest Hits&lt;/u&gt;. While it had many of the songs I had enjoyed previously, it wasn&amp;#39;t &lt;u&gt;Born in the U.S.A.&lt;/u&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I can&amp;#39;t recall if &amp;quot;The River&amp;quot; struck me the first time that I heard it, but it would become, and continues to be, one of my favorite songs; period. Too I was introduced to your harder side via &amp;quot;Murder Incorporated,&amp;quot; and your political side (still being in the dark about &amp;quot;Born in the U.S.A.&amp;quot;&amp;#39;s meaning) via &amp;quot;Streets Of Philadelphia.&amp;quot;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As time progressed, I continued to pick up more and more of your music, as I found it. During that time, it was &lt;u&gt;Live 1975-1985&lt;/u&gt; that absolutely made &amp;quot;The River&amp;quot; the song that it is to me today, and perhaps also when I began to &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; your music (although perhaps I could argue against that, based on the above listing of songs from &lt;u&gt;Born in the U.S.A.&lt;/u&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As of today, I can look at the listing of albums on your official site and, with the exception of the DVDs, of which I have only one (not listed; your music videos), I can honestly say I have every one. Of all the other artists I enjoy, I can say that of none other.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As I purchase your new music, I realize that while&amp;nbsp;I may not like all of it, that comes more from a lack of understanding, or experience, of what you sing about. While there are some songs that I believe instantly impart their meaning (most of those listed above, &amp;quot;The Fever,&amp;quot; etcetera), there are others that require more thought and experience (&amp;quot;The Ghost of Tom Joad,&amp;quot; etcetera). And through the years, I&amp;#39;ve found that little extra work to be well worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I&amp;#39;m young enough to have not lived through the beginning of music&amp;#39;s greatest periods of change, I&amp;#39;m grateful I was at least able to live during the times of one of the greatest legends of music.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Very sincerely,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
James Skemp
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I began listening to Bruce Springsteen</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/How-I-began-listening-to-Bruce-Springsteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 00:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/How-I-began-listening-to-Bruce-Springsteen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Years and years ago I was young. My father had moved out of his parent&amp;#39;s house by this time (meaning the time I&amp;#39;m recollecting on), and had possibly lived at at least one other place.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyways, he ended up living at my Uncle Pat&amp;#39;s place. I don&amp;#39;t recall the first couple of visits to the place, but I remember the place well enough. Recollections of the place itself will have to wait, though, since that&amp;#39;s not what I wanted to speak about.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, my sister and I ended up spending a deal of time at that old place. I recall the first couple of times I didn&amp;#39;t like the room I had got because of a feature of my closet. My sister had a very large closet in her room - one time me and the neighbors hung out in there, trying to hide from a brother, and possibly a sister. My closet, in addition to being pretty empty, had a small rectangular hole in it. From an early age I had read &amp;#39;scary&amp;#39; stories, stories of UFOs, and aliens, and mosters, detective stories, mysteries, and the like. I was always afraid someone was going to crawl through the hole, even though I knew no normal person could.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(One time, at the first house I remember, I had built a very large LEGO city. One night I either had a dream, or not,&amp;nbsp;that something was trying to get me. I don&amp;#39;t know what &amp;#39;get&amp;#39; means anymore, but I know it was bad&amp;nbsp;- life and death almost. Anyways, I had to touch the LEGO city before&amp;nbsp;whatever it was did. And it had to be constant; if it touched it, the bad thing was going to happen.&amp;nbsp;Picture an &amp;#39;0&amp;#39;, or a square&amp;nbsp;zero. Now imagine that the&amp;nbsp;points that make up the zero are empty space, while the rest is filled. If you were in one corner, you couldn&amp;#39;t see the opposite, but you could see the two opposing. Now, you&amp;nbsp;have to get to the opposite corner. However, there&amp;#39;s someone else that needs to do the same thing, and they&amp;#39;re in the opposite corner. In other, words you&amp;nbsp;have to switch positions. But, whoever gets to their&amp;nbsp;position last &amp;#39;loses&amp;#39;. And, if&amp;nbsp;one person&amp;nbsp;is in their corner and sees the other, they can&amp;nbsp;force the other person to&amp;nbsp;&amp;#39;lose&amp;#39;. But, you can&amp;#39;t stay in your corner the whole time, you have to move, even if it&amp;#39;s just a little bit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What do you do? Stay in&amp;nbsp;your corner?&amp;nbsp;When do you&amp;nbsp;sleep?)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyways, it so happened that my father had a number of tapes at his house, as well as an AM/FM radio/alarm/cassette player. I don&amp;#39;t recall all of the tapes, but The Police&amp;#39;s Synchronicity and Bruce Springsteen&amp;#39;s Born in the U.S.A. were two of them. I liked Sting, but I really liked Bruce. Before he had moved out, I knew the words to every song on that tape.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, I was young, and didn&amp;#39;t necessarily understand the lyrics, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://brucespringsteen.net/albums/bornintheusa.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a number of songs&lt;/a&gt; had a place in my heart. Downbound Train, I&amp;#39;m On Fire, Glory Days, Dancing In The Dark, and My Hometown.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When you like an artist, there&amp;#39;s a reason for it, just as there&amp;#39;s a reason for almost everything people do. For me, music has some relation to my life, in particular memories of what I was doing at some time; memories of my life. This in turn shapes how you hear, or in the case of physical works, how you see, the artist&amp;#39;s works.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For example, the first time I heard Touch of Grey, I saw it on MTV. My dad was trying to sell a truck, or some vehicle, and it was fairly late at night (at least, the sun had gone down and the stars were in the sky). My sister must have been asleep, and my mom at work. He was in the kitchen, and I was in the living room (I don&amp;#39;t think my bedroom was in the basement at that time).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For me, Springsteen is about times lost, and coming to gripes with that lose. For some of his songs, we look back with sadness, some with happyness.&amp;nbsp; For the former, those memories are more than we can successfully handle, while for the latter, we&amp;#39;ve learned to move on with our life, using those past experiences to make our future life that much better.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Enough said on this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Love - Thoughts from others - Bruce Springsteen</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Love-Thoughts-from-others-Bruce-Springsteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 19:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Love-Thoughts-from-others-Bruce-Springsteen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve been a fan of Bruce Springsteen since I first listened to the album Born in the USA (on cassette), way back, many, many years ago. Most of the music/songs that I enjoy are because of women, but Bruce Springsteen is one of the few artists that I enjoy because of a man. In this case, my father had the tape, but it was women who gave the music true meaning.&amp;nbsp; Anywho ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Probably one of his most interesting songs I heard was many years later, when I bought a copy of 18 Tracks.&amp;nbsp; The text of that song follows. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    When I get home from my job I turn on my T.V.&lt;br /&gt;
    But I can&amp;#39;t keep my mind on the show&lt;br /&gt;
    When I lay down at night, oh I can&amp;#39;t get no sleep&lt;br /&gt;
    So I turn on my radio&lt;br /&gt;
    But the only sound I hear is you whisperin&amp;#39; in my ear&lt;br /&gt;
    The words that you used to say&lt;br /&gt;
    Now my days grow longer&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;#39;Cause my love grows stronger&lt;br /&gt;
    And the fever gets worse&lt;br /&gt;
    And I&amp;#39;ve got the fever for this girl&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    CHORUS&lt;br /&gt;
    Got the fever, oh I&amp;#39;ve got the fever&lt;br /&gt;
    Nothing that a po&amp;#39; boy can do&lt;br /&gt;
    When he&amp;#39;s got the fever for this girl&lt;br /&gt;
    Got the fever, oh I&amp;#39;ve got the fever&lt;br /&gt;
    Left this little boy blue&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    I can remember comin&amp;#39; home&lt;br /&gt;
    See you standin&amp;#39; at the stove&lt;br /&gt;
    With the dishes on the table&lt;br /&gt;
    Dinner ready to go&lt;br /&gt;
    We&amp;#39;ll maybe go out to a movie show&lt;br /&gt;
    Something that you like to see&lt;br /&gt;
    Well now you are my sun in the morning&lt;br /&gt;
    And my moon at night&lt;br /&gt;
    I think about you baby&lt;br /&gt;
    I feel alright&lt;br /&gt;
    Now my days grow longer&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;#39;Cause my love grows stronger&lt;br /&gt;
    And the fever gets worse&lt;br /&gt;
    And I&amp;#39;ve got the fever for this girl&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    CHORUS 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From Bruce Springsteen&amp;#39;s The Fever (1973).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The next, from The River, I first heard on the old Live/1975-85 three-disc set. It&amp;#39;s probably best heard with his live text, where he actually talks about waht the song means to him. Nonetheless, a very great song.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    I come from down in the valley&lt;br /&gt;
    where mister when you&amp;#39;re young&lt;br /&gt;
    They bring you up to do like your daddy done&lt;br /&gt;
    Me and Mary we met in high school&lt;br /&gt;
    when she was just seventeen&lt;br /&gt;
    We&amp;#39;d ride out of that valley down to where the fields were green&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    We&amp;#39;d go down to the river&lt;br /&gt;
    And into the river we&amp;#39;d dive&lt;br /&gt;
    Oh down to the river we&amp;#39;d ride&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Then I got Mary pregnant&lt;br /&gt;
    and man that was all she wrote&lt;br /&gt;
    And for my nineteenth birthday I got a union card and a wedding coat&lt;br /&gt;
    We went down to the courthouse&lt;br /&gt;
    and the judge put it all to rest&lt;br /&gt;
    No wedding day smiles no walk down the aisle&lt;br /&gt;
    No flowers no wedding dress&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    That night we went down to the river&lt;br /&gt;
    And into the river we&amp;#39;d dive&lt;br /&gt;
    Oh down to the river we did ride&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    I got a job working construction for the Johnstown Company&lt;br /&gt;
    But lately there ain&amp;#39;t been much work on account of the economy&lt;br /&gt;
    Now all them things that seemed so important&lt;br /&gt;
    Well mister they vanished right into the air&lt;br /&gt;
    Now I just act like I don&amp;#39;t remember&lt;br /&gt;
    Mary acts like she don&amp;#39;t care&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    But I remember us riding in my brother&amp;#39;s car&lt;br /&gt;
    Her body tan and wet down at the reservoir&lt;br /&gt;
    At night on them banks I&amp;#39;d lie awake&lt;br /&gt;
    And pull her close just to feel each breath she&amp;#39;d take&lt;br /&gt;
    Now those memories come back to haunt me&lt;br /&gt;
    they haunt me like a curse&lt;br /&gt;
    Is a dream a lie if it don&amp;#39;t come true&lt;br /&gt;
    Or is it something worse&lt;br /&gt;
    that sends me down to the river&lt;br /&gt;
    though I know the river is dry&lt;br /&gt;
    That sends me down to the river tonight&lt;br /&gt;
    Down to the river&lt;br /&gt;
    my baby and I&lt;br /&gt;
    Oh down to the river we ride 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From Bruce Springsteen&amp;#39;s The River (1980).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Many times I listened to this song on those summer nights of old ...&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Hey little girl is your daddy home&lt;br /&gt;
    Did he go away and leave you all alone&lt;br /&gt;
    I got a bad desire&lt;br /&gt;
    I&amp;#39;m on fire&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Tell me now baby is he good to you&lt;br /&gt;
    Can he do to you the things that I do&lt;br /&gt;
    I can take you higher&lt;br /&gt;
    I&amp;#39;m on fire&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Sometimes it&amp;#39;s like someone took a knife baby&lt;br /&gt;
    edgy and dull and cut a six-inch valley&lt;br /&gt;
    through the middle of my soul&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    At night I wake up with the sheets soaking wet&lt;br /&gt;
    and a freight train running through the&lt;br /&gt;
    middle of my head&lt;br /&gt;
    Only you can cool my desire&lt;br /&gt;
    I&amp;#39;m on fire
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From Bruce Springsteen&amp;#39;s I&amp;#39;m On Fire (1984).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Springsteen released two albums, around the same time, and while 57 Channels (And Nothin&amp;#39; On) was the song that I really enjoy from this, but this song sheds much on our subject. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    You and me we were the pretenders&lt;br /&gt;
    We let it all slip away&lt;br /&gt;
    In the end what you don&amp;#39;t surrender&lt;br /&gt;
    Well the world just strips away&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Girl, ain&amp;#39;t no kindness in the face of strangers&lt;br /&gt;
    Ain&amp;#39;t gonna find no miracles here&lt;br /&gt;
    Well you can wait on your blesses my darlin&amp;#39;&lt;br /&gt;
    But I got a deal for you right here&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    I ain&amp;#39;t lookin&amp;#39; for praise or pity&lt;br /&gt;
    I ain&amp;#39;t comin&amp;#39; &amp;#39;round searchin&amp;#39; for a crutch&lt;br /&gt;
    I just want someone to talk to&lt;br /&gt;
    And a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    Just a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Ain&amp;#39;t no mercy on the streets of this town&lt;br /&gt;
    Ain&amp;#39;t no bread from heavenly skies&lt;br /&gt;
    Ain&amp;#39;t nobody drawin&amp;#39; wine from this blood&lt;br /&gt;
    It&amp;#39;s just you and me tonight&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Tell me, in a world without pity&lt;br /&gt;
    Do you think what I&amp;#39;m askin&amp;#39;s too much&lt;br /&gt;
    I just want something to hold on to&lt;br /&gt;
    And a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    Just a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Oh girl that feeling of safety you prize&lt;br /&gt;
    Well it comes at a hard hard price&lt;br /&gt;
    You can&amp;#39;t shut off the risk and the pain&lt;br /&gt;
    Without losin&amp;#39; the love that remains&lt;br /&gt;
    We&amp;#39;re all riders on this train&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    So you&amp;#39;ve been broken and you&amp;#39;ve been hurt&lt;br /&gt;
    Show me somebody who ain&amp;#39;t&lt;br /&gt;
    Yeah, I know I ain&amp;#39;t nobody&amp;#39;s bargain&lt;br /&gt;
    But, hell, a little touchup&lt;br /&gt;
    and a little paint...&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    You might need somethin&amp;#39; to hold on to&lt;br /&gt;
    When all the answers, they don&amp;#39;t amount to much&lt;br /&gt;
    Somebody that you could just to talk to&lt;br /&gt;
    And a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
    Baby, in a world without pity&lt;br /&gt;
    Do you think what I&amp;#39;m askin&amp;#39;s too much&lt;br /&gt;
    I just want to feel you in my arms&lt;br /&gt;
    Share a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    Feel a little of that Human Touch&lt;br /&gt;
    Give me a little of that Human Touch
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From Bruce Springsteen&amp;#39;s Human Touch (1992).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>