<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 21:52:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Example batch file to dump Subversion repositories</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Example-batch-file-to-dump-Subversion-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 21:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Example-batch-file-to-dump-Subversion-repositories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a large collection of repositories, and until now ran a single batch file that had to be updated each time I created a new repository, to add the new directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To combat that, I did some research and created a new batch file that does all the heavy lifting for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To save others time, I present it below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;SET timeVar=%date:~10,4%%date:~4,2%%date:~7,2%
SET repoDumpDir=..\repos_dump
FOR /D %%G IN (*) DO svnadmin dump %%G &amp;gt; %repoDumpDir%%%G%timeVar%.dump

PAUSE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key items are the repoDumpDir variable, which you&#39;ll want to set accordingly. (Save and run this batch file in the directory you store your repositories.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each directory it finds, it assumes it&#39;s a repository and attempts to do an &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://svnbook.red-bean.com/nightly/en/svn.ref.svnadmin.c.dump.html&#34;&gt;svnadmin dump&lt;/a&gt;, so we can restore if needed. It&amp;nbsp;adds today&#39;s date (YYYYMMDD) to the end of the repository (directory) name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steps to setting up a Windows Server 2003 Web Server on VirtualBox</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Steps-to-setting-up-a-Windows-Server-2003-Web-Server-on-VirtualBox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Steps-to-setting-up-a-Windows-Server-2003-Web-Server-on-VirtualBox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following goes through the steps needed to setup&amp;nbsp;Windows Server 2003, with Web server capabilities (IIS 6 in this instance), on a Sun VirtualBox virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Windows Server 2003 when Server 2008 is out and available? Because a large number of hosts (mine included) haven&#39;t made the switch yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;Sun VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;. We want this in particular for the great networking functionality, but other apps, like Microsoft Virtual PC, will work fine as well. I used version 3.0.8 r53138 on Windows 7 Home Premium&amp;nbsp;64-bit for this guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A copy of Windows Server 2003. In my case, I picked up a copy of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WM3L3O?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Visual Studio 2008 Professional with MSDN Professional&lt;/a&gt;, which gives access to a large number of Windows Operating Systems and tools. Microsoft offers a number of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/subscriptions/subscriptionschart.aspx&#34;&gt;subscription options&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer that with a good amount of RAM and processor. The machine I used for this guide has 4 GB of RAM and a 2.20 GHz processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VirtualBox setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install VirtualBox, making sure that you install any network adapters VirtualBox may need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new virtual machine.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the virtual machine a good name, such as &lt;em&gt;Windows Server 2003 - Web Server 1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Microsoft Windows - Windows 2003 as the operating system and version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to bump up the base memory size, but if looking to mimic an external server, try to use it&#39;s specs. I typically stick to the default of 256 MB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new hard disk, of the type Dynamically expanding storage; this allows you to create a large disk, but only have it take up the space it needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the disk a good amount of space; I generally change from the default of 20 GB to 50 GB, since it&#39;s not easy to increase this later, but you&#39;ll typically never go above 10 GB anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the Network Adapter from the default of NAT to Bridged Adapter. This will allow you to reach both the Internet and your internal network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the machine setup, you&#39;ll want to verify that your Windows Server 2003 installation media is available. If using MSDN, that means adding your downloaded ISO to the Virtual Media Manager (FIle &amp;gt; Virtual Media Manager)&amp;nbsp;under CD/DVD Images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start the machine, attaching the ISO when prompted.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generally the defaults are acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;General Windows Server 2003 setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once Windows Server 2003 is installed, install the guest additions (Devices &amp;gt; Install Guest Additions); it&#39;ll save you a deal of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Windows Server 2003 as needed.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In particular, I like to download the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://smallestdotnet.com/&#34;&gt;current version of ASP.NET&lt;/a&gt; and install IE 8 (although I do the latter as a separate update; I&#39;ve had issues otherwise).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point I like to exit out of the machine and clone the hard drive. I&#39;ll have activated the license and have a nice hard drive, with the current updates. If I want to create another Window Server 2003 instance, it&#39;s easier to just use a base drive and customize as needed. Your decision. (The VirtualBox (VBoxManage) command is clonehd.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Specific Windows Server 2003 setups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a base install ready, we can go in various ways with our installation. By default, almost no services will be up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this particular instance, we just want to run IIS 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you&#39;re in the Manage Your Server application. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/server2003Roles_01.jpg&#34;&gt;See this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default it will start automatically (a good thing) or you can find it at Start &amp;gt; All Programs &amp;gt; Administrative Tools &amp;gt; Manage Your Server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the options, select &lt;strong&gt;Add or remove a role&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We want a &lt;strong&gt;Custom configuration&lt;/strong&gt;, since we just want a Web server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For our needs, we want our&amp;nbsp;server to be an&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Application server (IIS, ASP.NET)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We only want to enable &lt;strong&gt;ASP.NET&lt;/strong&gt;, not FrontPage Server Extensions (unless you particularly know you want that).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our summary reads something like the following. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/server2003Roles_02.jpg&#34;&gt;See this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Internet Information Services (IIS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable COM+ for remote transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable Microsoft Distrubuted Transaction Coordinator (DTC) for remote access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable ASP.NET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may be prompted to insert a CD, at which point you&#39;ll want to mount CD 1 of the R2 discs, and not CD 2. You can play around with this as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shortly, you see that &#34;This server is Now an Application server.&#34; Included on this page is a link to view additional steps to secure the server. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/server2003Roles_03.jpg&#34;&gt;See this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should now see that the Application Server role is now available to be managed. &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/windowsServer2003/server2003Roles_04.jpg&#34;&gt;See this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opening a browser and calling &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/&lt;/a&gt; should now display the standard Under Construction page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to Windows Update and install any needed updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assuming you&#39;ve setup a Bridged Adapter in Network for the virtual machine, you should now be able to browse to the virtual instance in your host machine. You can use both the IP as well as the server name. For example, &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://james-wins03ws1/&#34;&gt;http://james-wins03ws1/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://192.168.1.106/&#34;&gt;http://192.168.1.106/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This can be found by opening a command prompt (cmd) and running &lt;strong&gt;ipconfig /all&lt;/strong&gt; and finding the IP Address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point you&#39;ve successfully setup IIS running on Windows Server 2003, in a virtual machine, and are able to connect to it from your host machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now mimic a real machine as much as you&#39;d like, for example by setting up FTP (&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://filezilla-project.org/&#34;&gt;FileZilla Server&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;nbsp;to move files between the machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend just using VirtualBox to move files between the two; Devices &amp;gt; Shared Folders will let you setup temporary and permanent folders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions, comments, and suggestions are appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications I have to install on my core development machine</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Applications-I-have-to-install-on-my-core-development-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 21:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Applications-I-have-to-install-on-my-core-development-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a listing of applications, as I run into them, that need to be installed on my core development machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TortoiseSVN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oxygen Xml Editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CollabNet Subversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FileZilla FTP client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun VirtualBox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serious Samurize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7-Zip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon MP3 Downloader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why bother creating this list? Because at the moment I&#39;ve just upgraded to Windows 7 and need to reinstall my programs. Above is the order I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notepad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every computer I touch for more than 15 minutes, I always add Notepad to the Send to menu. But where is it on Windows 7?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Windows Explorer, type the following to immediately go to the SendTo folder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;shell:sendto&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s easy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing iTunes data with C#</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Parsing-iTunes-data-with-C/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2009 22:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Parsing-iTunes-data-with-C/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This application has since been updated. &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/apps/iTunesPlaylists2Xml/&#34;&gt;Read about the current version of iTunes Playlists to Xml.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For better or worse, when I began setting up my iPod I opted to manually organize my iPod. In large part, this was because at the time I had a machine with a pretty small hard drive, and couldn&amp;#39;t keep all of my music on it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, with a new HP, I was able to store all my music on that computer, as well as back it up to a USB drive.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, that means that my playlists, ratings, play counts, etcetera, are stored solely on my iPod. Not a good situation to be in. If we could export our iPod library using iTunes, like we can for the library on our computer, it might not be so bad. However, that&amp;#39;s not the case.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve tried manually rating my music on my computer, every once in a while, but it&amp;#39;s ended up a disaster.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I was digging into the iTunesDB, I found a post on how to use a custom library to query this file using C#. Further digging revealed that once you install iTunes you can use C# (etcetera) to access a COM, thereby getting results directly out of iTunes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, it seems to be very resource intensive to query iTunes and pull information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve created a test application (called &lt;strong&gt;iTunes Application&lt;/strong&gt;) that queries iTunes and outputs the following information;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    sources of the kind library or iPod
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    playlist names and kinds&amp;nbsp;on those sources
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    the first 10 songs, with the number of stars, on any &amp;quot;Music&amp;quot; playlists
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Because of the way it operates, if iTunes isn&amp;#39;t started, it will be when the application begins. Outside of writing to a text box and label, no writing occurs, so the application should be pretty safe. Tested on Windows Vista Ultimate and Windows XP Home, with iTunes 8.0.2.20. .NET is required (probably 3.5).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What I&amp;#39;d like to do is have it allow you to pull the songs/ratings for any playlist, on any device. Then I can do a compare to determine what songs are different.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/applications/iTunesApplication.zip&#34; title=&#34;iTunes Application pre-alpha&#34;&gt;Download iTunes Application pre-alpha&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting drives in Windows Vista</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Formatting-drives-in-Windows-Vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 20:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Formatting-drives-in-Windows-Vista/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
So Disk Management can&amp;#39;t be found using the Vista Start Search. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, you can&amp;nbsp;type in&amp;nbsp;Computer Management, and get to Disk Management from there. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From what I was reading online, as long as the BIOS sees the drive, Windows should have popped up a message asking about formatting it. Too bad you have to go through this extra step - it would have been nice to have at least seen a small pop-up regarding this. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now I&amp;#39;ve just got to let the 750 GB hard drive format ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing TortoiseSVN to Windows Vista</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-TortoiseSVN-to-Windows-Vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-TortoiseSVN-to-Windows-Vista/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous article, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Subversion-and-TortoiseSVN-to-a-Windows-XP-Home-Edition-SP2-local-machine-with-Dreamweaver-8.aspx&#34;&gt;installed Subversion and TortoiseSVN to a Windows XP Home Edition machine&lt;/a&gt;. Later, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Upgrading-Subversion-and-TortoiseSVN-on-Windows-(140-to-142).aspx&#34;&gt;upgraded the installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just recently I covered &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Subversion-to-Windows-Vista.aspx&#34;&gt;installing Subversion 1.4.6 to Windows Vista&lt;/a&gt;. This time I&#39;ll be installing TortoiseSVN on that same machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system I&#39;m using is a HP Pavilion a6360t, with 4GB install RAM, 2.20 GHz, with two cores, running Windows Vista Ultimate SP1, 32-bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloading TortoiseSVN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since TortoiseSVN is for Windows, it makes it even easier to&amp;nbsp;find the version to download. Right on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tortoisesvn.tigris.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;nbsp;see a link for the download page, where we can get a copy of the most current version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing that&#39;s version 1.4.8, built against version 1.4.6 of Subversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be downloading the file TortoiseSVN-1.4.8.12137-win32-svn-1.4.6.msi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing TortoiseSVN&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the program, you&#39;ll work your way through a number of installation screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Install screens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width: 513px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 1&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/tortoisesvn/tortoisesvn_1.4.8_install_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 1&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 509px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 2&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/tortoisesvn/tortoisesvn_1.4.8_install_02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 2&#34; width=&#34;509&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 509px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 3&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/tortoisesvn/tortoisesvn_1.4.8_install_03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 3&#34; width=&#34;509&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 509px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 4&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/tortoisesvn/tortoisesvn_1.4.8_install_04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 4&#34; width=&#34;509&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 509px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 5&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/tortoisesvn/tortoisesvn_1.4.8_install_05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 5&#34; width=&#34;509&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 376px; height: 176px;&#34; title=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 6&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/tortoisesvn/tortoisesvn_1.4.8_install_06.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TortoiseSVN Setup Screen 6&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;176&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Post-Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With TortoiseSVN installed, we can now interact with Subversion in a Windows-friendly way, instead of relying upon the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a later article, we&#39;ll actually use Subversion and TortoiseSVN to put a Web site under source control, as well as a Windows application (based upon the .NET Framework).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&#39;ve covered &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Subversion-and-TortoiseSVN-to-a-Windows-XP-Home-Edition-SP2-local-machine-with-Dreamweaver-8.aspx&#34;&gt;Dreamweaver&lt;/a&gt; in the past, I&#39;ll be looking at using Subversion with Visual Studio, to see if it&#39;s indeed possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Subversion to Windows Vista</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-Subversion-to-Windows-Vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2008 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-Subversion-to-Windows-Vista/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous article, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Subversion-and-TortoiseSVN-to-a-Windows-XP-Home-Edition-SP2-local-machine-with-Dreamweaver-8.aspx&#34;&gt;installed Subversion and TortoiseSVN to a Windows XP Home Edition machine&lt;/a&gt;. Later, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Upgrading-Subversion-and-TortoiseSVN-on-Windows-(140-to-142).aspx&#34;&gt;upgraded the installation&lt;/a&gt;. This time I&#39;ll be installing Subversion on a Windows Vista Ultimate SP1 machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system I&#39;m using is a HP Pavilion a6360t, with 4GB install RAM, 2.20 GHz, with two cores, running Windows Vista Ultimate SP1, 32-bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m already running IIS 7, so I won&#39;t be installing Apache to run Subversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloading Subversion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://subversion.tigris.org/&#34;&gt;official Subversion site&lt;/a&gt;, downloads can be found under Getting&amp;nbsp;Subversion &amp;gt; Downloads. I went for the &#34;friendly Installer program&#34; link, and downloaded the file svn-1.4.6-setup.exe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing Subversion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you&#39;ve turned it off, trying to run the installer will prompt you if you want to allow access to your computer. You do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue through the installer screens, setting up Subversion as you&#39;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opted to install in the default directory of C:\Program Files\Subversion\ but without the desktop or quick launch icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Install screens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the screens from the installer for Subversion 1.4.6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width: 398px; height: 169px;&#34; title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 1&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 1&#34; width=&#34;398&#34; height=&#34;169&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 513px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 2&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 2&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 513px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 3&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 3&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 513px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 4&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 4&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;width: 513px; height: 396px;&#34; title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 5&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 5&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 6&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_06.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 6&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_07.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 8&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_08.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 8&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt; &lt;img title=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 9&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/subversion/subversion_1.4.6_install_09.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Subversion Setup Screen 9&#34; width=&#34;513&#34; height=&#34;396&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Post-Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run the following command at a prompt, you can&amp;nbsp;verify that your installation is complete. To run a command, select the Run command from the Start menu, or use the Start Search&amp;nbsp;and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;svnadmin ?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you see a listing of available subcommands, you should be set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I&#39;ve covered what I need to for installing Subversion to Windows Vista.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time I&#39;ll be covering TortoiseSVN, which will allow direct integration with Windows Explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to quickly hide all of the Windows Vista Ultimate language packs</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/How-to-quickly-hide-all-of-the-Windows-Vista-Ultimate-language-packs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 22:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/How-to-quickly-hide-all-of-the-Windows-Vista-Ultimate-language-packs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
While there&amp;#39;s no way to hide them all at once,&amp;nbsp;you can make it a short chore to hide the Windows Vista Ultimate language packs that you don&amp;#39;t use. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1) Right-click, H. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
2) Allow admin privileges. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
3) Right-click, H. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
4) Repeat step 3 for each language pack. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It takes less than a minute. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining which IIS 6.0 Application Pool belongs to which application</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Determining-which-IIS-60-Application-Pool-belongs-to-which-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 22:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Determining-which-IIS-60-Application-Pool-belongs-to-which-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In IIS 6.0, you can setup Application Pools for each of your sites. My knowledge of the exact benefits of this is somewhat lacking, but what I do understand is that these help applications (Web sites) stay within their own bounds, and prevent them from having a bad effect upon each other. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For example, if one application is preforming poorly, as long as it&amp;#39;s not a server-wide issue, the other sites on the server will be impacted minimally. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Matching an Application Pool to a process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you check the Windows Task Manager, and verify that you&amp;#39;re looking showing processes from all users, you&amp;#39;ll see&amp;nbsp;one w3wp.exe for each running process, along with Memory Usage.&amp;nbsp; PID (Process ID) isn&amp;#39;t shown by default, but once you add that, you&amp;#39;re on your way to discovering which process belongs to which Application Pool. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Select Start &amp;gt; Run ... and enter &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;. From the command line, if you&amp;#39;re not in the &lt;em&gt;systemroot&lt;/em&gt;\system32 directory, cd to it. For example, &lt;strong&gt;cd c:\windows\system32&lt;/strong&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, either enter iisapp.vbs or cscript iisapp.vbs to display the running Application Pools, along with a Process ID and the ID of the Pool. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once you can match an Application Pool with a process, you can see just how much memory is being used. If you find that an application is using a deal of memory, then that may mean that you need to Recyle the Pool more regularly. You may also need to look at the code you&amp;#39;re running to see if you have instances of leaks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From my, albeit limited, experience, w3wp.exe starts with about 8 MB of memory usage, after a Recycle. However, how fast it climbs is up to the individual usage of the Application Pool.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Remember to check into your Performance logs, or enable logging for a set amount of time, to see if memory usage is getting too high too fast. For most business applications, there is generally a slow period, or two, where you can have the Application Pool Recycle. Of course, there&amp;#39;s no real reason to Recycle too often, if you don&amp;#39;t need it. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s an article on TechRepublic from Brien M. Posey (MCSE) with more information about Application Pools: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://articles.techrepublic.com.com/5100-6345_11-5170149.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SolutionBase: Stabilize Web servers by using application pools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to ensure that performance counters continue after a restart</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/How%20to%20ensure%20that%20performance%20counters%20continue%20after%20a%20restart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 21:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/How%20to%20ensure%20that%20performance%20counters%20continue%20after%20a%20restart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A few days ago my server was restarted in the early morning hours. I had been logging network and processor usage using Windows built-in performance monitoring, but when the server restarted, the logs did not. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A bit of research later, it appears that there is a way to have Windows restart the logging after a system restart. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To enable this, it seems you just need to have the log stop after a certain amount of time (for example, after x hours, or x days). Then, check the box stating that &amp;quot;When a log file closes,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Start a new log file.&amp;quot; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This has the added benefit of keeping your log files manageable in size. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Information to log&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, I haven&amp;#39;t found much in the way of information regarding what counters should be logged. I believe I read a Microsoft article that suggested Bytes Total/sec for the Network Interface, and Processor(_Total)\% Processor Time. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I was doing this for a couple of weeks, but have decided to try out the following instead, for a couple of weeks. Once I&amp;#39;ve got a baseline (looking at the old numbers and the new), I&amp;#39;ll disable the logging for a bit, or decrease the polling time, and then start it back up to see if that baseline remains. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Memory\Available MBytes&lt;br /&gt;
    Network Interface(x)\Bytes Received/Sec&lt;br /&gt;
    Network Interface(x)\Bytes Sent/sec&lt;br /&gt;
    Processor(_Total)\% Processor Time 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Some information removed, to protect the innocent.) 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once you have these logging, it&amp;#39;s easy to use LogParser and avg(), min(), max() to generate some meaningful information. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example SQL query&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
See the below example (some data replaced with &amp;#39;xxx&amp;#39;). Modify to taste, and save as a sql file, running it through Log Parser with &amp;#39;file&amp;#39;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    /* 2007.09.19&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; J.Skemp&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Created query. */&lt;br /&gt;
    SELECT count(*) AS TotalCounters,&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; -- Get the initial and final datetime&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; min([(pdh-csv 4.0) (eastern daylight time)(240)]) as DateFirst,&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; max([(pdh-csv 4.0) (eastern daylight time)(240)]) as DateLast,&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; -- Processor information&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; avg(to_real([\\xxx\Processor(_Total)\% Processor Time])) as ProcAvg(%),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; min(to_real([\\xxx\Processor(_Total)\% Processor Time])) as ProcMin(%),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; max(to_real([\\xxx\Processor(_Total)\% Processor Time])) as ProcMax(%),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; -- Memory information&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; avg(to_int([\\xxx\Memory\Available MBytes])) as MemAvailAvg(MB),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; min(to_int([\\xxx\Memory\Available MBytes])) as MemAvailMin(MB),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; max(to_int([\\xxx\Memory\Available MBytes])) as MemAvailMax(MB),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; -- Network (in) information&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; avg(div(to_real([\\xxx\Network Interface(xxx)\Bytes Received/Sec]),1024)) as NetRecAvg(K),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; min(div(to_real([\\xxx\Network Interface(xxx)\Bytes Received/Sec]),1024)) as NetRecMin(K),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; max(div(to_real([\\xxx\Network Interface(xxx)\Bytes Received/Sec]),1024)) as NetRecMax(K),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; -- Network (out) information&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; avg(div(to_real([\\xxx\Network Interface(xxx)\Bytes Sent/sec]),1024)) as NetSentAvg(K),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; min(div(to_real([\\xxx\Network Interface(xxx)\Bytes Sent/sec]),1024)) as NetSentMin(K),&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; max(div(to_real([\\xxx\Network Interface(xxx)\Bytes Sent/sec]),1024)) as NetSentMax(K)&lt;br /&gt;
    -- Change file names accordingly&lt;br /&gt;
    INTO temp_report.txt&lt;br /&gt;
    FROM ServerInfo_*.csv 
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Add/remove as necessary, for your logs. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image thumbnails - blindingly fast on Ubuntu (vs. Windows)?</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Image-thumbnails-blindingly-fast-on-Ubuntu-%28vs-Windows%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 10:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Image-thumbnails-blindingly-fast-on-Ubuntu-%28vs-Windows%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;m at work, just finishing up my lunch period, and I&amp;#39;m really wishing I had access to my Ubuntu machine right now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The reason? I just put in a CD of 200 images - one of my backup CDs - and was hoping to get a quick glance at what images were contained on the CD.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, Windows was crawling through the thumbnail generation. Adobe Bridge isn&amp;#39;t much faster (but is what I ended up going with).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Grr ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Disk Investigator to Regain Files</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Using-Disk-Investigator-to-Regain-Files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2003 01:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Using-Disk-Investigator-to-Regain-Files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve already discussed Disk Investigator in some detail (see &lt;em&gt;Overview of Disk Investigator&lt;/em&gt;). However, what I really want to have is an example of the great use Disk Investigator is. In order to do this, I&amp;#39;m going to set up an example - an example of a situation that is not too uncommon - in order to show just how powerful it is. I urge you to follow along, with my example, on your own computer. Please note that for this article I am using Disk Investigator v1.3. I am also using Windows 98, Second Edition (but I have tested this program personally on Windows XP Home, SP1).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first thing we are going to do is create a folder directly within the hard drive of your computer. Most computers designate this drive by &amp;#39;C&amp;#39;. On the desktop, click on &amp;#39;My Computer&amp;#39;, then on &amp;#39;C:&amp;#39;. When you are in the &amp;#39;C&amp;#39; folder, right click in a blank area, and select &amp;#39;New&amp;#39;, and then &amp;#39;Folder&amp;#39;. This will create an empty folder on your hard drive. Let&amp;#39;s name the folder something like &amp;#39;diskinvest&amp;#39;, or &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39;. I&amp;#39;ll be using &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39; for this exercise, so please just replace &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39; with the name that you gave this new folder to follow along.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let&amp;#39;s open this folder (&amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39; - &amp;#39;C:\empty1&amp;#39;). Now, let&amp;#39;s create a new text file, by right clicking in an empty area, and selecting &amp;#39;New&amp;#39;, and then &amp;#39;Text Document&amp;#39;. Let&amp;#39;s name this something like &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39; (&amp;#39;empty2.txt&amp;#39;). Now we have created a file, called &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39;, residing within a created folder, &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39;. The full path of this new file is something like &amp;#39;C:\empty1\empty2.txt&amp;#39;. Now, let&amp;#39;s open up the text file and type some gibberish. For my file, I typed &amp;quot;This file is going to be saved by Disk Investigator&amp;quot;. For this exercise, you may want to copy and paste the above (without the quotes) into the text file, so that we get the same results.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let&amp;#39;s open Disk Investigator now, and find our file. Disk Investigator will start by &amp;quot;Reading Disk Information . . .&amp;quot;, which may take a while on larger hard drives. I&amp;#39;ve included an image of where you&amp;#39;ll want to end up below. If you&amp;#39;ve used Windows before, you&amp;#39;ll have no problem getting to where I am at. If you need clarification on this, please send me an email (I&amp;#39;m not sure if people need to know this, so I&amp;#39;m not going to add it in this edition, however, I will if even one person asks).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/files/images/diskinvest01.jpg&#34; onclick=&#34;window.open(this.href);return false;&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width: 475px; height: 235px&#34; src=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/files/images/diskinvest01t.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Disk Investigator&#34; title=&#34;Disk Investigator&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here we see where our file is located on the computer, it&amp;#39;s DOS name, it&amp;#39;s size, it&amp;#39;s modified date, and it&amp;#39;s creation date. Right now, nothing else really matters.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, click on one of the other folders, on the right side of Disk Investigator (such as &amp;#39;C&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;Desktop&amp;#39;). Then, flip back to Windows Explorer, or, on the desktop, go &amp;#39;My Computer&amp;#39; -&amp;gt; &amp;#39;C&amp;#39; -&amp;gt; &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39;. Now, select our created text file (&amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39;) and delete it (with the Delete key for example). Now, either navigate to the &amp;#39;Recycle Bin&amp;#39;, or close the current window (not Disk Investigator) and open the &amp;#39;Recycle Bin&amp;#39;. You&amp;#39;ll notice that &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39; is located in the bin. Empty the recycle bin, or delete &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39; again to remove it from your bin, and therefore from your computer (...). Close this window.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, switch back to Disk Investigator, and go back like we were before (see the above image). This time, you&amp;#39;ll notice that &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39; is no longer black, but is rather red. In the bottom left hand corner of Disk Investigator we see that red files are deleted files. If we navigate to &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39; again, we&amp;#39;ll notice that the folder is quite empty.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, click on &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39; and press the &amp;#39;View&amp;#39; button. A window will pop up which will have the text files contents contained in it. If you switch back to looking at &amp;#39;empty1&amp;#39;, you&amp;#39;ll still notice that the file is gone. Press &amp;#39;OK&amp;#39; to dismiss the window. Now, making sure that &amp;#39;empty2&amp;#39; is still selected, press &amp;#39;Undelete&amp;#39;. Disk Investigator will now ask you where you want the file restored to. I choose the C drive, even though you may not normally want to do this, because I have nothing to lose :) Disk Investigator will popup a window telling you were it restored the file to (in my case, &amp;#39;C:\Recovered_10_09_03&amp;#39;). If we navigate to this file we&amp;#39;ll see that we have recovered our information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, while the way above will work, I often (if it is a text file, or a document file with text contained in it) just open up the file and copy/paste the information/text that I need. Sometimes, if you have other processes going, you&amp;#39;ll notice that the information may not be restored correctly. This is because your hard drive saves data on it until it is overwritten - just because you delete something doesn&amp;#39;t mean that it&amp;#39;s completely gone. For example, imagine that your computer is like a sheet of carbon copy paper. If you write something on the top sheet, a copy is created on the carbon copy. Now, if you delete/erase the top copies information, that doesn&amp;#39;t mean that the carbon copy information is erased. Rather, you have to write over it to &amp;#39;get rid&amp;#39; of it (by writing over it, in both cases).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I hope that this has helped in using Disk Investigator. It should be noted that you can&amp;#39;t recover information within deleted folders, using Disk Investigator, so, please keep that in mind. However, if Word happens to incorrectly save your document, causing corruption, be happy in the fact that you can still go grab an older copy (with luck) :)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please feel free to email me with any questions you may have regarding the topics covered on this page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Modified:&lt;/strong&gt; January 6th 2004; January 25th 2004&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt; See also my paper titled &lt;em&gt;Overview of Disk Investigator&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>