<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Playstation 3 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/playstation-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Playstation 3 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 19:43:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/playstation-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: PlayStation 3 EX-02 Next Gen Bluetooth Headset with Faceplates</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-PlayStation-3-EX-02-Next-Gen-Bluetooth-Headset-with-Faceplates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 19:43:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-PlayStation-3-EX-02-Next-Gen-Bluetooth-Headset-with-Faceplates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004ASOLLM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;PlayStation 3 EX-02 Next Gen Bluetooth Headset with Faceplates&lt;/a&gt;, which I received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;External speaker is key&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve tried two different microphones before this headset: the one that came with Warhawk and the PlayStation 3 camera, and since I rarely play multiplayer games, and PlayStation players are less likely to have microphones that Xbox 360 players, both were just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004ASOLLM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;EX-02&lt;/a&gt; available on Amazon Vine, and had just started a Borderlands 2 campaign with 3 other people (I was planning on, and had used for one session already, my PS camera), it seemed like fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve now used this in three 3 to 4 hour sessions and I&#39;m completely sold. Unlike Warhawk&#39;s headset this one features a very nice external speaker. This means that instead of resting inside my ear a bit, it sits completely outside of it, resting against the ear. This is by far the best feature of this headset. Maybe others include this, but since it&#39;s new to me, it&#39;s an eye-opener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The piece that wraps around the ear is also fixed, which I initially thought was going to be an issue, but actually works rather well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mute button is easy to trigger, and emits a pleasant tone when it&#39;s activated. I&#39;m not sure what I think about the volume buttons yet, since touching them seems a little off, but it&#39;s not a big issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had to turn up the volume of the microphone on my PlayStation 3 itself as it was mentioned I was a little quiet. However, I&#39;m generally that way in real-life, so that&#39;s probably me, and not a big deal since it only had to be set once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of different headsets is rather nice, but I haven&#39;t felt the need to change the one it already had on. Overall, I&#39;m completely sold with my almost 4 weeks of use, and would definitely recommend the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004ASOLLM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;PlayStation 3 EX-02 Next Gen Bluetooth Headset&lt;/a&gt; to anyone that needs one for the PlayStation 3. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Mafia II (2010)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Mafia-II-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 20:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Mafia-II-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mafia-II-Playstation-3/dp/B00198PO5I?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Mafia II&lt;/a&gt; (2010), for the PlayStation 3 and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mafia-II-Xbox-360/dp/B000ZK698C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Xbox 360&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you enjoyed The Saboteur, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was playing Mafia II I was constantly reminded of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Saboteur-Playstation-3/dp/B00149ILDO?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The Saboteur&lt;/a&gt; (2009), and since I enjoyed that game, I would consider that a good thing.&amp;nbsp;The game features much of the same, with gun and hand fights (the latter of which plays an important part in the story) and driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experienced no technical issues while playing the game, and the hard difficulty featured some cheap kills, but after a bit of practice everything worked out just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came into this game without knowing having played the first Mafia game (and I honestly have looked into whether there&amp;rsquo;s any tie-ins), and found the story to be fairly good and engaging. I certainly felt as though the main character was understandable, but I do wonder how much pressure they may have gotten to make the ending what it is. I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily believe it was forced, but &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having finished it on hard, I may pick up some of the trophies I still need, however I don&amp;rsquo;t believe I&amp;rsquo;ll platinum this (due to one collectibles trophy that seems like a pain, and a couple others), and don&amp;rsquo;t see myself replaying the story again. It was good, but now that I know it there&amp;rsquo;s nothing deep to get me to go through it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m on the fence about it, but after some thought have decided to give it 3 of 5 stars (I&amp;rsquo;d give it 3.5 if I could). It&amp;rsquo;s a fun game, but I&amp;rsquo;ll probably trade this in before too long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nier weapon data in XML (and LINQ sample query)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Nier-weapon-data-in-XML-and-LINQ-sample-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 21:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Nier-weapon-data-in-XML-and-LINQ-sample-query/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going through the game &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Nier-2010-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3.aspx&#34;&gt;Nier&lt;/a&gt; yet again, I wanted an easier way to track what weapon levels I had already upgraded to, and what items I still needed to unlock weapon items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase one towards that goal is creating an XML file with weapon upgrade information which is available online: &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/NierWeapons.xml&#34;&gt;Nier weapon data&lt;/a&gt;. An XML schema document for this information is also available: &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xsd/2011/10/NierWeapons.xsd&#34;&gt;Nier weapon XSD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sample LINQ query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following query can be run from LINQPAD, and will either display all items with their counts, or a grouped listing of items with the total quantity needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;csharp&#34;&gt;XDocument weaponsXml = XDocument.Load(@&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/NierWeapons.xml&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/NierWeapons.xml&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;var items = weaponsXml
    .Descendants()
    .Elements(&amp;ldquo;Item&amp;rdquo;)
    .Select(i =&amp;gt; new WeaponItem { Name = i.Attribute(&amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo;).Value, Quantity = i.Attribute(&amp;ldquo;Quantity&amp;rdquo;) != null ? int.Parse(i.Attribute(&amp;ldquo;Quantity&amp;rdquo;).Value) : 1 })
    .OrderBy(i =&amp;gt; i.Name).ThenBy(i =&amp;gt; i.Quantity)
    ;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;var itemsGrouped = items.GroupBy(i =&amp;gt; i.Name).Select(g =&amp;gt; new WeaponItem { Name = g.Key, Quantity = g.Sum(i =&amp;gt; i.Quantity) });&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//items.Dump();
itemsGrouped.Dump();&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}
public class WeaponItem {
    public string Name {get;set;}
    public int Quantity {get;set;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Yakuza 4 (2011) (PlayStation 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Yakuza-4-2011-PlayStation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 11:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Yakuza-4-2011-PlayStation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003QX4F7C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Yakuza 4&lt;/a&gt; for the PlayStation 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A masterpiece&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up Yakuza 4 without having played any of the previous iterations of the game. After looking at reviews online I thought it might have a pretty good story, and provide a good amount of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After playing a little under an hour of the game I was quite impressed what I had seen. Used copies of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0030GBSUC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Yakuza 3&lt;/a&gt; were available locally, at a pretty decent price, so I decided to pick up a copy of Yakuza 3 and play that first (since Yakuza 1 and 2 were a little harder to find, and more importantly on the PlayStation 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/review/R29P6M00THJR9D/ref=cm_cr_rdp_perm?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;my review of Yakuza 3&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save you the effort - I found it to be one of the best games I&amp;rsquo;ve played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I started Yakuza 4 back up I had high expectations for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of sticking with one character in this game, like you do in the others of the series, you play through the stories of 4 different characters who then combine forces for a final act. Each characters has their own distinctive style which can honestly be a little frustrating at first (especially with the second character, when you get thrust in a very difficult battle early on). However, their styles match their character, and by the time you finish their distinct acts you&amp;rsquo;ll be in complete control of their style. Otherwise combat hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed much. For newcomers, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly short range attacks. You can get away with button &amp;lsquo;mashing&amp;rsquo; for many of the average battles, but bosses may require actual planning and thought. With a few exceptions, I found combat to be easier in this iteration than in Yakuza 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game mostly takes place in one area, but instead of being restricted to the streets like last time you can now travel on the roofs and in underground areas. For the most part, however, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself on the streets and use the others for either main or sub-story activities. Chase segments have also decreased, and I believe become easier. There was one of these that kicked my butt in Yakuza 3, but this time my three losses were from one particuarly difficult battle (already mentioned above).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is the best part of the game, and one might argue it surpasses the story of Yakuza 3. As the story goes on each of the four characters acts through certain events, with each coming to the realization at the end that their paths are tied together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of characters from previous iterations make an appearance, but even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t played the previous games you&amp;rsquo;ll still have an understanding of what&amp;rsquo;s going on (you just might not feel the full impact).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With combat being what it is, and the story a masterpiece the game already has 5 of 5 stars from me. However, for the U.S. release of Yakuza 4 they kept in many of the mini-games that were in the original release. While the virtual fighter makes an appearance again, and is a pain in the butt this time, I found the other mini-games (that I played) to be rather fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I finished the main story, and finishing almost all the sub-stories I could, as well as all the fighter trainings (optional) and one of the hostess trainings (optional) I was at 59 hours and 43 minutes, with 51.13% completion. While playing Yakuza 3 I had decided that I liked the game and story so much that I would pick up the first two in the series. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve finished some of the other games in my catalog I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be going through Yakuza 1 and 2, and then re-playing 3 and 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a near-perfect story and all-around great experience, I give Yakuza 4 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yakuza 4: Tanimura Hostess Guide</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Yakuza-4-Tanimura-Hostess-Guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2011 21:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Yakuza-4-Tanimura-Hostess-Guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a very rough guide for the hostesses for Tanimura for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003QX4F7C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Yakuza 4&lt;/a&gt;. This only includes the questions/answers I needed to complete his hostesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chihiro (Jewel)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Italian Scarf +.25 - never wore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Orange Juice +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Fruit Platter +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was twenty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I wasn&#39;t interested in love yet. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;It&#39;s nothing, really. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think of a girl who can&#39;t drink?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;It&#39;s cute. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something interesting? Well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Ameba Pigg. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had acting lessons (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You could try looking at other performances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spa (8 hearts): Chest +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hang out &amp;gt; Karaoke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===10 hearts to 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Well, at least it was a good experience. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He would never do that kind of thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I&#39;m sorry. Being a cop makes me suspicious. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most attractive feature (14 hearts): Eyes +? (at least .25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know any good ways to get rid of stress?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;There&#39;s nothing better than karaoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green tea (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&#34;I&#39;m kind of picky about Chinese tea.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(date)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===15 hears to 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something interesting? Well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;777 Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I know this is your big chance, but... +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s all thanks to your advice. I really appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;It&#39;s a too bad, though. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you keep talking like that, I&#39;m gonna get all choked up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Call me any time you feel lonely. +? (at least .25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karaoke (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&#34;Let&#39;s have a sing off.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Himeka (Shine)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popularity Bracelet +.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini Skirt Dress (Pink) +.5 (worn after 2nd date)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orange Juice -.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicken Basket +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my pet, Mr. Meowy! Pretty cute, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I&#39;m more of a dog person. +2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure it does. I&#39;d do anything to be taller!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I could give you a ride on my shoulders. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously?! I had no idea! I&#39;d love to go! You really know a lot about this city, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Have fun. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 hearts+: Massage &amp;gt; Legs +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ended up dumping me... He said he couldn&#39;t stand eating with me anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;He was being a jerk. +? (at least .75)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You think someone like me could ever get married?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You just have to find a man who can cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I just love a man who can make me laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(Try telling a joke.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowboarding (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I&#39;m good at snowboarding, too. +.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(date) &amp;gt; Hot Springs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I can&#39;t stand those people, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===10 to 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He comes in almost every day now. It makes me depressed to think about tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Why don&#39;t you just wait and see what happens? +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should quit blogging altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;That&#39;s just running away form the problem. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You okay with me asking you for advice? I don&#39;t know if I can keep working here without your support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Maybe you should quit being a hostess. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14+: Wash &amp;gt; Face +? (at least .25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drink responsibly! (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;That&#39;s because you beg for drinks so much. +.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(date) &amp;gt; Karoake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===15 to 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something interesting? Well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;The footbaths at Yunosono Hot Springs. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Phone calls) Hmm...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Leave this to me. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think I should do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Wouldn&#39;t you regret it if you left now? +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where should I go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;If you&#39;ve never been, I&#39;d go to Korea. +? (at least .75)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um... Do you think I could ever be your wife?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Let&#39;s just worry about Kashiwabara for now. +?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So jealous! (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Do you want to go on a trip with me sometime?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nanami (Elise)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***intro***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really? You&#39;re a policeman?! Are you one of the higher ups, by any chance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Unfortunately, no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All right. My fee is that you request me whenever you come here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You don&#39;t beat around the bush, do you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fruit Platter +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charismatic Ring +.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popularity Bracelet +.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. Can you guess what it was?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You&#39;re looking for an eligible man? +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could never do that. You should really try to apply yourself to your work or you&#39;ll never be anything but a loser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Ouch... +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have any plans for your future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I&#39;d like to walk a beat in a small town. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for choosing me (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&#34;You&#39;re a really interesting girl.&#34; +.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You didn&#39;t think I was writing to you personally, did you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You shouldn&#39;t play that kind of trick on a cop. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think you measure up in that department?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I&#39;ve always been good at solving puzzles. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8+ hearts - what do you first notice? &amp;gt; Hands +.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it as a chance to talk and drink with girls. Otherwise, you&#39;re probably just wasting your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;No, I&#39;m going to find a girlfriend this way. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers like that are more common than you might think. I don&#39;t care how much they pay, I can&#39;t stand them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;So what kind of things are okay to talk about? +? (at least .25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep! How much money do you have saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;A good amount. +?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of things do you like to talk about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;I&#39;m interested in social issues. +?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This... (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&#34;I look forward to seeing you again.&#34; +.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(date)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Watami &amp;gt; Iron Skillet Potstickers +0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===10 to 15 hearts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You can be happy without money, you know. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about chaning my hairstyle. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Sounds like a good idea to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No that&#39;s no the case. He would never do that to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;You almost sound like his mother. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14+ hearts - What do you think I should learn? &amp;gt; Mouth +? (at least .75)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be inspired by the latest trends in Kamurocho hostess clubs and make them available nationwide. I think it could be really popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Sounds like a good idea. +?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High price to pay (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&#34;I hate it when people cancel on me suddenly.&#34; +.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(date)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Watami &amp;gt; Sashimi Platter +?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;===15 to 20 hearts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something interesting, eh? Well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;777 Town. +.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes... Apparently my brother was so intent on making money for the club that he forced some customers to order things they couldn&#39;t afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Sounds familiar. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&#39;ve been thinking about quitting my job at the cosmetics company so I can focus on my business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;What about your job at the club? +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you wouldn&#39;t be my customer anymore. It would be a little strange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Maybe it&#39;s our chance for love. +1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stressed out (email)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&#34;Champagne is asking a little too much...&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Last Rebellion (2010) (PlayStation 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Last-Rebellion-2010-PlayStation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Last-Rebellion-2010-PlayStation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DC8GRC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Last Rebellion&lt;/a&gt; for the PlayStation 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how badly this game is generally rated, yet I didn&amp;rsquo;t find the approximately 12 hours I put into the game all that horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure the graphics don&amp;rsquo;t push the limits of the PlayStation 3, and the game could certainly have been released for the PlayStation 2, but given the current pricing of the game I&amp;rsquo;d argue it&amp;rsquo;s worth a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story isn&amp;rsquo;t all that bad. There&amp;rsquo;s a couple parts where it seems we&amp;rsquo;re missing something, and the ending isn&amp;rsquo;t all that satisfying, but the story is certainly passable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game has an interesting aspect where you need to know what order to attack enemies body parts. Each enemy has a different number of these, and a different order, with some battles resulting in the order changing (but otherwise all instances of an enemy can be attacked with the same order). There&amp;rsquo;s a number of guides online that have already mapped this ordering out for you, if you choose to go that route, but it adds a certain flair if you try to determine these yourself. But getting the order right consistently results in more experience per battle, which means you level that much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially important because combat is otherwise fairly easy once you determine the order, and once you surpass enemy levels you get almost no experience at all. On the other hand, you can &amp;lsquo;seal&amp;rsquo; (defeat) the enemies immediately at this point, instead of having to knock them down to 0 HP first. But, for the most part I found myself just attacking enemies, and very rarely needing to buff, until the optional, secret enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like RPGs and you can get it for around $20, I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s worth it for the approximately 12+ hours of play and 19 fairly easy trophies. For these reasons I give &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DC8GRC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Last Rebellion&lt;/a&gt; 3 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Yakuza 3 (2010) (PlayStation 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Yakuza-3-2010-PlayStation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 14:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Yakuza-3-2010-PlayStation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0030GBSUC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Yakuza 3&lt;/a&gt;, for the PlayStation 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time Yakuza 4 was being released I began hearing about the game, although after further research I do remember hearing about those who had asked actual Yakuza to play a Yakuza game (the 3rd specifically). Either way, everything I had heard about 4 suggested I would like it, especially when I heard it had a great story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I picked up &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003QX4F7C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Yakuza 4&lt;/a&gt; and after less than an hour of play decided I liked what I had seen and played. Since the series is basically one big story I decided to hunt down another game in the series, which was this one, Yakuza 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of about a week I put almost 33 hours into the game and finished it on the normal difficulty. Having done so I promptly went out a picked up a copy of Yakuza 2 and ordered a copy of the first Yakuza. Obviously, that means I&amp;rsquo;m giving this game a high rating, and here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I have not yet played the first two games in the series I was able to get some idea of what happened thanks to the inclusion of story overviews, presented in video format, in both the main menu as well as when the game begins. This allowed me to get some idea of what happened, despite not having as close a relationship with the characters as someone who played the previous games in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story itself is rather robust, and ties together rather nicely in the end (although I&amp;rsquo;m on the fence about how the ending worked out). The main character doesn&amp;rsquo;t always tie things together as quickly as I&amp;rsquo;d expect, but I suppose he does have to play dumb a little so the slower players can catch on. I&amp;rsquo;d argue that the story is on par with Metal Gear Solid 4 (although not so difficult to understand, especially if you didn&amp;rsquo;t play the other games in the series like I) and Lost Odyssey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characters within the game are all very life-like, making it extremely easy to like, or at least understand, them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audio is almost entirely Japanese, save when an American speaks in English, and the entire game (with the exception of bits spoken during battles) is subtitled. I like watching movies in their original language with subtitles, so I liked this presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve only put 33 hours into the game I only touched upon the amount of content within. From what I can tell I did less than 40% of the optional substories and played only a handful of the games within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game also features a rather robust new game plus system where you can start a new game with some amount of stuff, but with substories and other completion lists reset. You can also continue playing after the game has ended to complete items beforehand, as you can create new clear saves in this extended play as well. This is actually the first game I&amp;rsquo;ve played where you can do that (normally clear saves are created only when you finish the last boss, if at all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One might argue that combat is repetitive, but it was only near the very end of the game, when I was tracking down locker keys and unlocking secret menu items, that I started running away from fights. At least on the normal difficulty the majority of the fights are not that difficult. In fact, I had to continue more during segments that required I chase someone down or escape than during fights. You can use normal or strong attacks, block and dodge, or use a variety of special attacks, as well as use items within the environment. As you walk around you&amp;rsquo;ll be challenged by various people. One could argue that this is what gets repetitive, but, again, I had no difficulty making this enjoyable by changing up what I did to defeat these enemies. Defeating enemies also allows you level up your character&amp;rsquo;s abilities, which makes for more variety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already noted above Yakuza 4 is actually why I picked up this game, and I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased the first two in the series, so I&amp;rsquo;ll undoubtedly be playing this game again. For these reasons I give &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0030GBSUC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Yakuza 3&lt;/a&gt; a 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Eat Them! (2010) (PlayStation 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Eat-Them%21-2010-PlayStation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 09:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Eat-Them%21-2010-PlayStation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Eat Them!, for the PlayStation 3, and released on the PlayStation Network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just recently picked up a copy of Eat Them!, for the PlayStation 3, as it was on sale for PlayStation Plus members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to some Eat Them! is a Rampage-like game, where you control a monster that lays waste to an area of a city. Indeed, this an extremely apt description, as playing this game brought to my mind fond memories of putting quarters/tokens into the Rampage machine, and later playing it, and later releases (such as for the Nintendo 64) to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where this game really shines is the monster creation aspect. Each level has three goal levels. Obtaining a bronze allows you to move on, while silver and gold unlock one new monster part each (with medals stacking, so completing a level the first time with a gold unlocks two parts). The game also features a fairly robust coloring system where you can color each part separately (by default you merely select three colors for the entire monster, from a rather large array).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera is above and behind the monster, and never caused issues, since you can rotate it at will. Some of the later parts result in a truly epic monster, allowing you to quickly destory the area you&amp;rsquo;ve been unleashed upon. The areas are different enough that I never found them tedious, although some are used in different mission types. Unfortunately, there does seem to be one map that is only used for a bonus mission (or I just got gold on it the first time through and haven&amp;rsquo;t gone back to it yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of chapters (signified by comic books in the menu), containing either missions of destruction of particular objects, destruction amounting to a certain dollar amount, racing through a map, and occassionally bonus missions like eating a number of people or returning a number of animals back to the zoo. (The last might not sound like fun, but you basically grab and fling the animals, so it&amp;rsquo;s rather enjoyable.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difficulty does increase as you get near the end, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need to plan accordingly, and update your monsters to deal with the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three downsides to the game seem to be that you can&amp;rsquo;t delete a monster you&amp;rsquo;ve created (although you can edit it) and you are not told what a particular monster part will do when added, instead you have to just try it out. Finally the menu navigation can seem a little clunky at first, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get used to it. These are minor points, however, and don&amp;rsquo;t detract from the actual game play experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the game, 100%, over the course of 4 days, and had an absolute blast doing so. I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly be keeping the game on my PS3 for those moments when I just want to wreck havoc upon a city. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kinect is selling really well; but is that good for gamers?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Kinect-is-selling-really-well-but-is-that-good-for-gamers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 21:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Kinect-is-selling-really-well-but-is-that-good-for-gamers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Techmeme had a couple of interesting titles this evening. &#34;&lt;a rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/kinect_is_selling_2x_as_fast_as_the_ipad.php&#34;&gt;Kinect is Selling 2X as Fast as the iPad&lt;/a&gt;&#34; and &#34;&lt;a rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://blogs.barrons.com/techtraderdaily/2010/11/29/microsoft-over-25m-kinect-sold/&#34;&gt;Microsoft: Over 2.5M Kinect Sold&lt;/a&gt;.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I thought I had the space for it (I&#39;d have to move furniture every time I wanted to play it in my current apartment) I still wouldn&#39;t pick up the Kinect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First there&#39;s the price. At $150 you might as well buy a PSP (which I did) or a Nintendo DSi. Either of which would solve the second issue, which is a lack of good games for that $150 you threw down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there&#39;s a couple of reasons it&#39;s done so well. First, it&#39;s fairly unique as a gaming device. Second, they&#39;ve marketed it to almost no end (I wonder how many devices they just gave away during their blitz?). Third, it&#39;s fast approaching the holiday season, which means parents buying gifts for kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also have those who are using the device for purposes other than those intended, but that&#39;s admitedly a very small chunk of that number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what&#39;s unfortunate is that it&#39;s doing so well, when there&#39;s so few games, which makes me afraid that the price on the device will drop rapidly, simply because it&#39;s become a niche device with no games developed for it, and those that are in line with what you can get on the Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, games that the older &#39;style&#39; of gamer won&#39;t want to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sony&#39;s Move seems like a better technology, as it builds upon the success (and science, if you will) of the Wii&#39;s controller, but moves it to a platform that can deliver much better graphically. Unfortunately, it too suffers from too few launch titles, although seemingly offers more in the next year. And of course a number of existing games have already been updated to now offer Move support (such as Heavy Rain). But, it hasn&#39;t been marketed anywhere near as much as the Kinect has, and it doesn&#39;t draw a big audience because it&#39;s too similar to the Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wii, which suffers from a large number of shovelware titles, made only to take advantage of the uniqueness of the console&#39;s controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps history won&#39;t repeat itself ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Kinect and Playstation Move</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-the-Kinect-and-Playstation-Move/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-the-Kinect-and-Playstation-Move/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laying aside the question of whether these are merely in response to the amount of money being made by the Wii, and whether the technology will be as lasting as history suggests 3D televisions will be, I&#39;ve been thinking about the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002BSA298?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kinect&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002I0J4NE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Move&lt;/a&gt; recently. Here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How well will they work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest question. Ever since they were first shown on television there&#39;s been the question of what environments will support the Kinect. For the Move, with it&#39;s big glowing ball, there hasn&#39;t been much of a question, since everything suggests that it&#39;ll be easier to track (especially after learning that the ball consists of LEDs which can change based on the environment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this regard, unless I can see Kinect working in a Best Buy or GameStop, or at someone&#39;s house, there&#39;s almost no reason I&#39;d pick one of these up. The last thing I need after paying $150 is to find out that it won&#39;t work in my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hardware pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Price doesn&#39;t just mean how much you pay out of the gate, but also what you get for hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002BSA298?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kinect&lt;/a&gt; you currently pay $150 for the sensor and a game, with no other costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002I0J4NE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Playstation Move&lt;/a&gt; costs $100 for a Playstation Eye, main move controller, and game. The navigation controller costs $30, but a Playstation 3 controller can be used instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the Kinect wins out is that with the one sensor you can seemingly support up to two people, while to do the same with the Move you have to purchase another $50 &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002I0J51U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Move controller&lt;/a&gt;. (At that price it might be easier to purchase another Starter Bundle and sell the game and Eye.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you already have an Eye and don&#39;t care about the starter game you can just purchase the Move controller. Which of course suggests another benefit, in that the Playstation Eye is hardly new technology, and is already used by a handful of existing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity of the Microsoft solution is also a little disarming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For software we have a couple aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less obvious at first is the pricing of the games. Sony seems to be sticking to a lower price of $40 for their games, while Microsoft is sticking to a higher $50 price. Both are less than the $60 games normally go for, and since Wii game prices range from $40 to $50, are on par with Wii games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft seems to be going more for a playful look with their avatars, in line with the Wii, while Sony is sticking with their hardware abilities and leaning towards realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a larger number of Move games being announced for release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Launch date&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Playstation Move is set to release in the middle of September, with the Kinect launching in the beginning of November. Necessarily we have to think about holiday sales. I personally think Microsoft is cutting it a little close in case issues come up. On the other hand, if the Move has issues out of the gate it may result in sales of the Kinect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I can&#39;t help but think that the Kinect won&#39;t be able to outsell the Playstation Move now, for more than a month or two at a time, because of that month and a half delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Company support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As was recently pointed out to me, the Playstation Move doesn&#39;t seem to be the main focus of Sony marketing, while the same cannot be said on the Microsoft front, who seem to be betting fairly heavy. With Microsoft generally seen as more hardcore/shooter focused, getting a chunk of the casual players would move a good deal of hardware, and a $300 price for their Kinect+console bundle certainly isn&#39;t that bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Sony is stressing the games, with really only the Move controller the truly new hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How they both trump the Wii&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the Kinect and Playstation Move trump the Wii, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both consoles support better graphics, but more importantly, both do away with the waste of having to purchase batteries to power the controller. This is obvious for the Kinect, and in the case of the Playstation Move, like their other controllers, it can be charged via USB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to pick one I&#39;d pick the Playstation Move, without a doubt, because of the above. And if no other reason than that Heavy Rain looks pretty playable with Move controllers, I may actually do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: AmazonBasics USB 2.0 A-Male to Mini-B Cable (6 Feet / 1.8 Meters)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-AmazonBasics-USB-20-A-Male-to-Mini-B-Cable-6-Feet-18-Meters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-AmazonBasics-USB-20-A-Male-to-Mini-B-Cable-6-Feet-18-Meters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001TH7GUK?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;AmazonBasics USB 2.0 A-Male to Mini-B Cable (6 Feet / 1.8 Meters)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased this for an additional (and longer) cable for a Playstation 3 controller. It works perfectly (although I realize now I would have preferred a few feet longer - oh well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that it comes in Amazon&amp;rsquo;s hassle free packaging is another definite plus, although since the box was rather large, when I received my package in the mail, I thought perhaps it was the Blu-ray movies I&amp;rsquo;d purchased shaking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first AmazonBasics product purchase, but it will definitely not be my last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonance of Fate: General data file</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Resonance-of-Fate-General-data-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 12:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Resonance-of-Fate-General-data-file/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Resonance of Fate, available for the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002BRYHY0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Playstation 3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002BRWUA8?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Xbox 360&lt;/a&gt; (I purchased for the former), has a vast amount of data associated with it, as RPGs usually do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I usually do, I started keeping track of levels and etcetera for the game, which is available as an XML data file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is currently raw (and as of this post need to finish adding data that I&#39;ve got on paper and on another computer), without styling, but I&#39;ve been sitting on the information for far too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external download&#34; href=&#34;http://jamesrskemp.com/files/ResonanceOfFate.xml&#34;&gt;View/download the Resonance of Fate data file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted in the file, data is licensed under the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Resonance of Fate? You can see &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=42BbXtjs4UM&amp;amp;feature=PlayList&amp;amp;p=B1008E533685C01A&amp;amp;playnext_from=PL&amp;amp;index=0&#34;&gt;my video &#39;walkthrough&#39; of the Dakota Vein on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Borderlands</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Borderlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 20:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Borderlands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WMEEBM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Borderlands&lt;/a&gt;, available for the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360. I specifically played the Playstation 3 version, but my review should be applicable to the Xbox 360 version as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I was expecting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all the hype and reviews I was expecting a ripe-off, albeit a&amp;nbsp;fairly good&amp;nbsp;one, of Fallout 3. Of course, Diablo II with it&amp;rsquo;s randomly generated baddies and weapons (and drops in general) was also mentioned. Seeing as how I played Diablo II and its expansion quite a bit when they were released, and absolutely enjoyed Fallout 3 (purchasing all of the DLC and even getting into the double-digit levels for a second evil/neutral player), this sounded like something I would enjoy. One thing I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about was the first-person aspect, having a generally weak stomach for &amp;lsquo;twitch&amp;rsquo; games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this I decided to hold off until the price dropped, after a handful of months. But as I had a coupon that I wanted to use towards a game (since I was in one of those moods where I just needed something new to play) I decided to pick this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I got&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pleasant surprise. Having just beaten the game after playing for around 2 weeks (with two batches of the flu in there) this is probably one of my favorite games of the last year; definitely in the top 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;RPG elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borderlands has a fairly robust skill tree, for each of the four character classes, similar to Diablo II versus Fallout 3; the former having a small set of skills, within a couple of skill trees, that&amp;nbsp;you can increase in skill, and the latter having a wide variety of skills, without too much in the way of skills requiring other skills. This makes it extremely simple, ignoring the decisions you have to make when gaining new skill points, to work with this element. In fact, the decision making process is fairly flexible, as you can always reset your skill points (without losing any) to try a different style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played a game with a skill implemention like this, I&amp;rsquo;ll honestly have a slightly harder time going back to games that don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to reset (although within the story this element makes sense).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of story, it&amp;rsquo;s actually much better than what I thought it would be, after the various reviews. The ending seems a bit abrupt, but everything is tied together, so it may be more an issue with the open-endness of the game. Which brings us to mission&amp;nbsp;structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are seemingly well over a hundred missions, only a small quantity of which are required to advance the story. The rest serve to help increase your level (more on this later) to what is required for the story missions. Generally they tie into the story enough that it makes sense to just do them, especially for the rewards (whether you&amp;rsquo;re going to just sell them or not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back-tracking, an essential element of RPGs, is present in this game, but isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad once you gain access to an &amp;lsquo;instant-travel network.&amp;rsquo; With enemy respawns being fairly quick (approximately two in-game days, which seems to be less than an hour) and vehicles available for most large areas, the travel isn&amp;rsquo;t tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shooter elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borderlands is&amp;nbsp;a fairly standard FPS, made interesting by the art style it uses and the plethora of weapon choices. While there are a handful of weapon types, most weapons are randomly generated, making it fairly hard in the beginning and middle of the game to choose just four weapons (the most you can have equipped). Generally you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have at least one or two kept in your backpack to swap in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This randomization and weapon type scope is what really makes this aspect of the game interesting, in my opinion. But when you add in class-specific skills, you end up with something completely more. In fact, I think it&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy to miss out on the importance of your core skills, often forgetting to use them. I personally didn&amp;rsquo;t use my character&amp;rsquo;s skill all that often until near the end of the game, and having played with others online, that seems to be fairly common for lower-level first-timers. Perhaps that just serves to show the deepness of this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already mentioend, I have a hard time with FPS games usually, if they&amp;rsquo;re twitch. While Borderlands can be, generally you survey the area and come up with some kind of plan; rushing straight at enemies at or above your level is suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to the level aspect. Each enemy has a set level, excluding one-off mission-related enemies, which is consistent throughout the game. Higher level enemies give great rewards, but are also more difficult. This is the same with the quests/missions. Thankfully there&amp;rsquo;s almost no grinding required (although I should note that I did all optional missions in addition to the story-related ones). Experience also changes based on this, so targeting lower level enemies eventually becomes near useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is interesting in this, allowing you to get a &amp;lsquo;second wind&amp;rsquo; if you kill an enemy before you bleed out. Failing that, a certain amount of money is deducted and you are resurrected at the nearest &amp;lsquo;station&amp;rsquo; (saying no more in case of minor spoilers) ready to go back up against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multiplayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borderlands offers on- and offline cooperative play. Offline coop is okay, with the split screen (side-by-side) a little hard to use. Online multiplayer (using Playstation Network) was fairly quick and without issue. You can choose what game you join, making it fairly easy to find a group at your level (or higher/lower if you so choose). (Unlike on Xbox, Playstation owners typically don&amp;rsquo;t have mics, so I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on communication.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having let my Xbox Live Gold subscription lapse a few weeks ago, online multiplayer was actually the reason I picked this up for the Playstation 3; surprising since I usually don&amp;rsquo;t care too much about online play with games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Replayability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new game plus mode (keep everything, replay the story again with enemy levels increased) and four classes, as well as the online multiplayer and two currently DLC (with one more in the works), replayability is pretty high. Once&amp;nbsp;I finish the DLC and a few&amp;nbsp;upcoming games - Mass Effect 2, BioShock 2, and probably Heavy Rain - I&amp;rsquo;ll be back on Pandora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Borderlands is, again, one of the top 5 games I&amp;rsquo;ve played in the last year (in no particular order, Fallout 3, Muramasa: The Demon Blade, Uncharted 2: Among Thieves, and Lost Odyssey, with Batman: Arkham Asylum getting bumped). A good, long, game, with an&amp;nbsp;interesting&amp;nbsp;story, and high replayability means I give Borderlands 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video games I&#39;m looking forward to in 2010</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Video-games-Im-looking-forward-to-in-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 11:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Video-games-Im-looking-forward-to-in-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In no particular order, here are the video games I&#39;m currently looking forward to playing in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that some games may have been released earlier. Consoles that games can be released for are the PS2/PS3, Xbox 360, or Wii (which therefore includes GameCube games). Since I will probably not be getting an Xbox Live Gold subscription this coming January, and am going to go back to playing RPGs on PS systems only, when possible, PS3&amp;nbsp;versions of multi-console releases&amp;nbsp;will be higher on my list. Of course, FFXIII on PS3 is a no-brainer, even if I was hard-core Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bioshock 2 (Feb 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tales of Vesperia (release for the PS3 w/ unknown date)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (Feb 2010 for PS3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy XIII (Mar 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resonance of Fate (May 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mass Effect 2 (Jan 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demon&#39;s Souls (Oct &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, once it drops in price a bit more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Borderlands.aspx&#34;&gt;Borderlands&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, once it drops in price a bit more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BioShock (for the PS3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the games that all signs point to interest being high, but that I&#39;m not interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assassin&#39;s Creed&amp;nbsp;II - Disappointed by the first one, and combat on this one looks pretty boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragon Age: Origins - Looks as though it would be good on the PC, but doubtfully so on consoles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial thoughts on Playstation 3 instant streaming</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Initial-thoughts-on-Playstation-3-instant-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 16:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Initial-thoughts-on-Playstation-3-instant-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received my instant streaming disc for the Playstation 3 from Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having now moved around and watched a video, here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I&#39;ve watched Netflix streaming videos on my PC as well as on my Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted, currently the streaming capabilities require a &lt;strong&gt;disc&lt;/strong&gt;. While this could perhaps be a download (and will be in the future), I don&#39;t believe it&#39;s too terrible that it requires a disc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;disc&lt;/strong&gt; itself isn&#39;t too shabby. The sleeve is the standard Netflix sleeve, although it seems a little stronger, and in red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Netflix Instant Streaming Disc for Playstation 3&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/misc/NetflixPlaystation3Disc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Netflix Instant Streaming Disc for Playstation 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few moments the software was loaded and I was prompted to enter an &lt;strong&gt;activation code&lt;/strong&gt; online. At only six characters, it was pretty simple. While they say it&#39;ll take up to 3 minutes, it took around 30 seconds. There was a similar activation for the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re first presented with your instant queue, and can move around by pressing a &lt;strong&gt;direction&lt;/strong&gt;. Up will move you to the tabs where you can move between your instant queue, recently watched, and various categories. Unfortunately you can&#39;t hold down in a direction to move quickly through the queue, but instead must press the direction you want to move each time. However, I am able to move from the last movie to the first, which can&#39;t be done on the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Netflix disc interface on Playstation 3&#34; src=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/graphics/misc/NetflixPlaystation3Interface.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Netflix disc interface on Playstation 3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after I had watched my first movie I started playing around; &lt;strong&gt;L2 and R2&lt;/strong&gt; will move you 7 movies in whatever direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote that this seems to benefit from the &lt;strong&gt;Playstation 3 remote&lt;/strong&gt;, but I don&#39;t recall why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;added a new movie&lt;/strong&gt; to my instant queue&amp;nbsp;on my PC&amp;nbsp;and while it did not immediately show up (we&#39;re talking in seconds), by moving to a different tab and back the new movie appeared. Id est, it seems the times it goes out and grabs the listing is much more transparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie watching experience itself was okay. While Select on the remote displays the &lt;strong&gt;current/total times&lt;/strong&gt; for standard movies, you actually had to pause the movie to see it here. There is a way to have it appear on the Xbox 360, without pausing, but I don&#39;t recall the button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I don&#39;t have to do on my Xbox 360 is switch my &lt;strong&gt;TV mode&lt;/strong&gt; to Full screen. I believe this is a configuration issue on my end. Everything but regular DVDs and watching instant streaming videos (the interface is fine) requires that I change my TV mode so that the movie takes up all the space. Otherwise it believes my&amp;nbsp;TV is square. Again, I believe it to a TV setting on my Sony Bravia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating&lt;/strong&gt; the movie is &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; easier on the Playstation 3. While the Xbox 360 requires you to cycle from 3 stars to 5 to 1 to 3 again, you are able to move the &#39;cursor&#39; on the Playstation 3 and &#39;lock in&#39; your rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;removed the movie&lt;/strong&gt; from my queue on my PC and unlike on the Xbox 360, it&amp;nbsp;was not immediately removed from my queue on my Playstation 3. Switching to another tab&amp;nbsp;and back (letting the other tab load first) worked again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reordering&amp;nbsp;items&lt;/strong&gt; on my PC also didn&#39;t immediately take effect, without switching to another tab. Not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two tabs I currently have are &lt;strong&gt;&#34;Like: ___&#34;&lt;/strong&gt; which are the two movies I currently have in my recently watched listing. Haven&#39;t seen this on the Xbox 360 interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current feelings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like it. Yes, it&#39;s an extra disc to keep about, but that&#39;s a big deal. Yes, there&#39;s the issue with moving through the queue (not so bad after I found the L2/R2 trick). But that&#39;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll update with additional thoughts, as&amp;nbsp;I continue to watch more movies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>