<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opera on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/opera/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opera on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 14:30:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/opera/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Current, major, browsers</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Current-major-browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 14:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Current-major-browsers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Do users know that they&amp;#39;re not using the current version of their browser? While many browsers will check for updated versions (Firefox, for example), some do not. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anywho, I&amp;#39;ve decided, looking at the numbers, that I would start adding a check on my sites to alert users if there browser is out of date, and tell them where they can get an updated version. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that I refer to the desktop version of these browsers, and mention only the major browsers. From personal experience, I highly recommend Opera&amp;#39;s mobile browser(s). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recBrowserIE&#34;&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current version:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous version:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upcoming version:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/internet-explorer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Find out more and download&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update 12/21/2008:&lt;/strong&gt; After looking through my logs, I found a couple of instances where the MSIE 6 and MSIE 7 instances show up in the user-agent, as well as MSIE&amp;nbsp;6 and 8. This seems to be with users who have installed standalone versions of Internet Explorer. If you&amp;#39;re using a newer version of IE, but are seeing a message about using an older version, that may be the issue. See &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://techpatterns.com/forums/about1028.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt; for more information. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recBrowserFF&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current version:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous version:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.0 (supported through mid-December 2008)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upcoming version:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getfirefox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Find out more and download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Safari&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current version:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.2&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous version:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upcoming version:&lt;/strong&gt; unknown&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/safari/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Find out more and download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recBrowserC&#34;&gt;Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current version:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous version:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.4&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upcoming version:&lt;/strong&gt; unknown&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/chrome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Find out more and download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recBrowserO&#34;&gt;Opera&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current version:&lt;/strong&gt; 9.6&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous version:&lt;/strong&gt; 9.5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upcoming version:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;unknown &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opera.com/browser/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Find out more and download&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other browsers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Netscape&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For quite a while Netscape (Navigator)&amp;nbsp;was an extremely popular browser. However, it is no longer actively supported. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you continue to use Netscape most people will recommend that you upgrade to Firefox. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser environments for testing</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Browser-environments-for-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 22:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Browser-environments-for-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/How-to-really-compact-Virtual-PC-hard-drives.aspx&#34;&gt;a previous post&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned using virtual machines for testing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s the three virtual machines that I feel cover the most options for browser testing (on Windows):&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current versions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Looking at the top 10 browsers for this site, using data from Google Analytics, we have; Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Chrome, Mozilla, Opera, Playstation 3, Konqueror, SeaMonkey, and Camino.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of those, Internet Explorer and Firefox, obviously, account for the largest amount of traffic, at about 86% of all visits. Safari is a respectable 6.6%, Chrome at about 2.7%, Mozilla at 2.1%, and Opera at 1.8%.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some&amp;nbsp;may think&amp;nbsp;I&amp;#39;m a bit&amp;nbsp;off, but I&amp;nbsp;consider Opera a fairly good browser, while Mozilla doesn&amp;#39;t much concern me. So, that gives us our top five browsers, all of which&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;be installed on Windows.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, any&amp;nbsp;test&amp;nbsp;environment for current versions of browsers (on Windows), should include the following (in order of importance).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Internet Explorer 7
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Firefox 3
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Safari 3
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Chrome 0
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Opera 9
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s talk that Chrome may replace Firefox, if Google stops supporting Mozilla, so while Chrome may have low usage numbers, it&amp;#39;s fairly standards-compliant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is also why I feel that not including Opera would be a very big mistake.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This rounds out our first virtual machine to 5 unique browsers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Previous versions&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While it would be great if it wasn&amp;#39;t the case, you&amp;#39;ll always need to support older versions of popular browsers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Again, looking at Google Analytics for this site, almost 25% of Internet Explorer users are using version 6. Firefox, which supposedly has some issues in version 3, that are keeping users back in version 2, is about the same, with 75% of users on version 3.0.3 or 3.0.4 (I suppose there may be some overlap there).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Most other browsers don&amp;#39;t actively support so many previous versions, which means that a virtual environment for past versions of browsers can stick with the following.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Internet Explorer 6
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Firefox 2
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Upcoming versions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This virtual machine is really focused on browsers currently in beta, or that may otherwise not be in the top listing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Primarily, that means the following should almost certainly be included.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    Internet Explorer 8
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That&amp;#39;s right, Internet Explorer 8. That&amp;#39;s all I&amp;#39;d absolutely need, especially looking at stats.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, to a great extent, Chrome, like most of Google&amp;#39;s other &lt;strike&gt;products&lt;/strike&gt; applications is truly a beta browser (and one that I&amp;#39;ve had numerous issues with, probably due to that fact) and that might suggest that it should truly be installed in this environment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What about Linux and Mac?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The top browsers for Linux, again according to this site, are Firefox and Mozilla, which should&amp;nbsp;function the same as they are on Windows (and, again, I consider Firefox and Mozilla to be basically the same). It&amp;#39;s extremely easy, and free, to get started with any number of Linux environments, but I just don&amp;#39;t know that it makes all that much sense. (Keep reading for the clarification of this statement.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For Mac&amp;nbsp;we have Safari and Firefox. The latter should be very similar to the Windows version.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For Safari Apple was kind enough to give Windows users this browser. As to whether it&amp;#39;s the same as the Mac version, well, it looks very similar. But, unless you&amp;#39;re willing to pay the Apple premium, the Windows version should suffice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For these reasons, basic Web development doesn&amp;#39;t need to dive too deep into Linux and Mac environments.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mobile browsers?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But what about browsers on mobile devices?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Both Safari, Opera, and Internet Explorer have mobile versions available (in the case of Opera, they have two), which will definitely change the output of your site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To some extent &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/lynx/&#34;&gt;Lynx&lt;/a&gt; fills this hole by providing a text version of your site, and therefore might make sense installed on a virtual machine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The standard Opera browser also provides a mobile-like &amp;#39;emulator&amp;#39; for your site, by way of the Small View functionality.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, for the mobile version of Internet Explorer (which won&amp;#39;t be tracked by Analytics, as it doesn&amp;#39;t support JavaScript (speaking of Windows Mobile 6)) accessing an emulator is not quite as easy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As to the solution, I can&amp;#39;t say I can provide one, but as we move more and more towards mobile devices, perhaps we&amp;#39;ll be virtualization for these environments much more readily available.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Above I&amp;#39;ve suggested three virtual environments, for Web site development. For the majority of projects, I think having current versions of the top three browsers - Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari - would be quite enough.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What do you think? What do you develop for?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1. Of course, I realize that if you were going to create&amp;nbsp;a Flash or Silverlight application, you&amp;#39;d naturally want to test on both Mac and Linux (or if your app becomes popular, you&amp;#39;ll get some backlash on Slashdot). At that point what you&amp;#39;re really testing is the environment, and not just the browser. But, for the &amp;#39;majority&amp;#39; of Web sites, I personally feel that virtual Mac and Linux environments are unnecessary. Compare this to my feelings a number of years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Four-working-browsers-(at-least).aspx&#34;&gt;before Safari was available for Windows&lt;/a&gt;, and you&amp;#39;d see a different view.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
2. I also recommended Lynx and Netscape in that post, but no longer see that as necessary, entirely.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four working browsers (at least)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Four-working-browsers-%28at-least%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 21:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Four-working-browsers-%28at-least%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s just something about having four different browsers on your computer, to say the least.  I do believe I&amp;#39;ve Lynx installed as well, but it&amp;#39;s hardly used these days ... for better or worse.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Firefox 1.5.0.6&lt;br /&gt;
Internet Explorer 7.0.5450.4 (i.e., 7.0 Beta 3)&lt;br /&gt;
Opera 9.01-8552&lt;br /&gt;
Netscape 8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Best of all?  My site displays great in all four.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are other browsers to test, of course, but the question is whether it&amp;#39;s really necessary to do so.  Both Flock and Mozilla seem like a waste to install, since they (like Netscape) are so much fluff.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Lynx is actually a pretty good browser for a developer, and what do you know, I do have a version from 10/2005 on my computer (2.8.5rel1).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Want a copy?  Download it from &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/lynx/&#34;&gt;http://strivinglife.net/lynx/&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If I had a Mac, I&amp;#39;d test my site with Safari, but alas I do not.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If I had a Linux machine that connected to the Internet (perhaps fairly soon ...) then I would test Konqueror and the like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The lessons are two-fold.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1) If you&amp;#39;re working on a site, test it in multiple browsers.  Honestly, with today&amp;#39;s world, there&amp;#39;s no reason people shouldn&amp;#39;t upgrade to the newest version of their preferred browser.  Not only do you get better security, but you also get a better browsing experience.  I recommend Firefox, but no matter which browser you choose, if it&amp;#39;s up-to-date, and still being supported (i.e., it&amp;#39;s not a dead browser, but patched to the latest version), it&amp;#39;s okay in my book (some are just better than others).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
2) Keep your browser up-to-date.  You don&amp;#39;t need to have the bleeding edge beta releases (in fact, you probably don&amp;#39;t want to either), but at least keep your browser fully patched.  Don&amp;#39;t like how they upgraded the browser in a future release?  It&amp;#39;s not only selfish to keep using that old version, but also dangerous.  And you can always switch to a browser that allows more customization (like Firefox).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>