<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Card Game on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/card-game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Card Game on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 19:11:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/card-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Just Desserts</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Just-Desserts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 19:11:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Just-Desserts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Looney Labs&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00U05Y830?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Just Desserts&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Just Delicious&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having played the game with three different groups, consisting of 2, 4, and 5 people, I can honestly say that every group I&#39;ve played it with has had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t go into the actual rules, other than to say that they&#39;re relatively simple to learn and pick up. Depending upon the group, however, you may need to keep handy the possible turn options, as in one game a few players kept needing to be reminded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the first game, where I thought new customers were only flipped over to replace the initial three (whoops!), we were able to play, and generally finish, two games in the span of an hour. During the second session we had run low enough on customers, however, that two people were effectively out of the game, and two others were fighting for the last card to complete a run of five different suits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are a number of different types of desserts, generally I think it played fine as-is, as otherwise the games may have ended sooner, as every player ended up looking for one or two types of desserts for the customers available at least a couple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I really like the artwork on the cards. People would comment that some of the customers looked like their names, but I think I was the only one of the eight different people I played with that commented on the desserts. The card quality is also pretty nice, consistent with other Looney Lab games, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this game will be part of my standard game lunch rotation, I have to give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00U05Y830?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Just Desserts&lt;/a&gt; five of five stars. Easy to learn, and pretty fair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Karma Card Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Karma-Card-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 11:30:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Karma-Card-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IZ7FH1M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Karma Card Game&lt;/a&gt;, provided to me by the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Simple enough for kids, but fun for all&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of years ago I was introduced to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00000IV34?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Card Game&lt;/a&gt; by a former co-worker. SET is fairly basic game that requires a deal of thinking, and is something I really enjoyed playing. So when I saw the SET name on the box for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IZ7FH1M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Karma Card Game&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to request a copy. Having now played a few games of it, I&#39;m glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karma is a pretty basic game, similar to the game Shithead, but with additional cards. Basically you and up to 5 other players take a set of cards, some of which are in front of you face down, some of which are face up, and some of which are in your hand. Each turn you either need to lay a card higher than the last card played, or pick up the stack. If you do play a card and have less than a certain number of cards, you draw a replacement card(s), with the goal to have no remaining cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve played one of the other variants you&#39;ll find the inclusion of the Karma cards to be a nice variant. These can be played against any card and have effects ranging from requiring a card below a certain value to be played, a card higher in value than the bottom card, or for someone to pick up the entire stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play initially starts slow as you run through the main desk, especially since unlike other variants there&#39;s not really a good way to clear the play pile (a variant I play has a set of 4 cards in a row clear the pile). Because of this game length varied from 25 to 35 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did generally agree that the game would be great for playing with kids, although the number of cards you need to manage when you pick up a large play pile can be a bit overwhelming. Since there&#39;s nothing more than a small stack of cards required, it&#39;s also very portable (I played a couple games waiting for food at a restaurant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price is a little unfortunate, as when I told people how much it was (list price $13, Amazon for a little over $10) they were expecting something around $7 or $8 instead, especially since this could easily fit into a smaller package. With the exception of the Karma cards, you can also play one of the standard variants with a normal pack of playing cards. The numbering these cards use, however, does seem like it would be better for younger players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately it&#39;s still a very fun game, and is highly recommended. However, I have to give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IZ7FH1M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Karma Card Game&lt;/a&gt; only 4 of 5 stars, since while fun, a normal pack of cards would be fine for most older players.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>