<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hp Compaq Presario Cq60 615dx on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/hp-compaq-presario-cq60-615dx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hp Compaq Presario Cq60 615dx on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 13:11:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/hp-compaq-presario-cq60-615dx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: HP Compaq Presario CQ60-615DX</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-HP-Compaq-Presario-CQ60-615DX/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 13:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-HP-Compaq-Presario-CQ60-615DX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 16 of this year I purchased a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0033KELCM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;HP Compaq Presario&amp;nbsp;CQ60-615DX&lt;/a&gt; laptop. Almost&amp;nbsp;4 and a half months later I regret nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point during my college career -&amp;nbsp;either my Sophmore or Junior year, which means 2000 or 2001 - I purchased my first laptop, a Dell. I used it for a number of years, but one day it just wouldn&#39;t start back up. Ever since then I&#39;ve purchased HP desktop computers, and while I&#39;ve helped others purchase laptops, and have thought about buying one, the price for the machine I wanted to build just wasn&#39;t in line with what I wanted to pay. So instead I&#39;d purchase a nicely built desktop, for a fraction of the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After goofing around with some other portable PC options, and debating whether to buy an iPod Touch, I finally settled on picking up this laptop. I trust HP to&amp;nbsp;put together well-built, and dependable machines;&amp;nbsp;three desktops of varying ages, still all working today. I wasn&#39;t sure about their Compaq line, but at the beginning of this month, based on this laptop, I picked up a low-cost Compaq desktop, and would do it again in the future. And a&amp;nbsp;co-worker purchased this same computer a few months earlier, and when asked, said he still found it to be a good buy (and this is actually what pushed me over the edge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t speak too much about what the machine contains, since that&#39;s well covered in the specs. Instead, I&#39;ll tell you how I use it and what I&#39;ve done to it, with notes as needed for what I&#39;ve found to be issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s not too much junk installed on the machine, so no issues there; maybe 3 or 4 hours to get those uninstalled, backup discs made, and Windows Updates applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the 2 GB of RAM is okay, since this is a 64-bit machine I purchased 2 2GB sticks (from Crucial) for around $120, with shipping. It&#39;s unfortunate that it&amp;nbsp;comes with&amp;nbsp;two 1 GB sticks, but ... I did this 2 and a half months after I purchased the machine, so clearly it&#39;s more of a personal choice (I do Web development and wanted to be able to run various systems on VirtualBox).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve debated following the advice of another reviewer and swapping in a more powerful video card (Windows experience is 3.3 because of it, although Windows 7 starts up and runs fine), but with the Web surfing (handles Flash-heavy sites fine, as well as Netflix streaming) and development (mostly in Visual Studio 2010; have run Windows XP and Windows Server 2008 on VirtualBox)&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;I do on the machine, I haven&#39;t felt the need. (Office 2010 also handles well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireless (B/G/N)&amp;nbsp;has worked great, although I&#39;ve had to manually turn it off and back on twice after it lost my signal, which is amazingly simple. (A third time I ended up powercycling my router, so I assume there were larger issues.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left mouse button does seem a little unresponsive at times (3 or 4 times), but if nothing else, there&#39;s always USB mice, which I&#39;ve taken to using when I&#39;m at home, which is where this computer gets most of it&#39;s use, as I&#39;ve shut down one of my desktop machines that I always had up and running for surfing and etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every day I lug the machine to work and pull it out during lunch to work on one thing or another. I purchased an &lt;span id=&#34;btAsinTitle&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B000LTKLT0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;HP EZ141AA Nylon Value Case&lt;/a&gt;, and while at first it seemed like it was going to be too small, it actually works really well. I highly recommend this bag, but if want to lug a number of other items within it, you&amp;nbsp;probably want to look for something larger.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Overall, I give this computer 5 of 5 stars and recommend it highly (and have to my sister and another co-worker).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
