<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sony Bravia on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/sony-bravia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sony Bravia on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2007 22:15:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/sony-bravia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Bravia KDL-32M3000 comments: 2 weeks later</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Sony-Bravia-KDL-32M3000-comments-2-weeks-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2007 22:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Sony-Bravia-KDL-32M3000-comments-2-weeks-later/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of this month, &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/My-new-television-the-Sony-Bravia.aspx&#34;&gt;I purchased a 32&#34; Sony Bravia&lt;/a&gt;. In the two weeks that I&#39;ve had the television, I&#39;ve run into a couple of things that I would like the television to offer. In no particular order, they are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Better volume detection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&#39;s because the speakers are better on this tv than my old one, but there&#39;s definitely an issue with commercial versus programming volumes. Commercials are &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; louder than they need to be, compared to the show that I really want to watch. Since I&#39;m watching more digital channels (via an antenna), this may be an issue with those channels. Nonetheless, it would be great to have the ability to set a volume level, and let the tv dynamically control the level outputted. I want to hear the same level of noise, no matter what I&#39;m watching. Otherwise, I have to keep changing the volume during/after commercials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Better picture-in-picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, you can only have picture-in-picture if you&#39;re hooked into a PC. Why not let me put something else down there? Let me play a video game, have the sound off on that, and then listen to a tv show or dvd?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Better input switching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought some really nice component av cables for my Playstation 2, so I no longer have to use the standard av cables. However, I&#39;m using av cables for my DVD player (or at least, I was until I decided to use the PS2 for my DVDs, finally; but that&#39;s another story). If I want to switch from TV to DVD to Playstation, I&#39;ve got to move through a number of inactive components. Why not let me hide components that I&#39;m not using, like I can do for channels? I can name my components, so it doesn&#39;t seem like this would be too difficult ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Better guide functionality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bravia has a pretty good Guide, which allows you to move through all available channels to determine what&#39;s on where. However, unlike what you&#39;d think, it&#39;s basically no different than switching the channel with display on. Why not let me stay what channel I&#39;m on, and just get the information about what else is on, so I can keep watching what I am? (Added November 18, 2007.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new television, the Sony Bravia</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/My-new-television-the-Sony-Bravia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2007 17:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/My-new-television-the-Sony-Bravia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Today I purchased a new television, to replace my tried-and-true Philips 20&amp;quot;. After a couple of months of research, and etcetera, I decided to go with a Sony Bravia. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since my previous television was a 20&amp;quot;, purchased back during my sophmore or junior year of college, and still using &amp;#39;tube&amp;#39; technology, I figured it was time to upgrade, especially since I&amp;#39;ve been watching more movies via Netflix, and am planning on purchasing one of the current next-gen video game systems (P3 or 360). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For me, there was no question between plasma, projection, and LCD. I also definitely had to have widescreen (not that you can&amp;#39;t get much of anything else with LCD). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had to choose between the 26&amp;quot; and the 32&amp;quot;, and because the price difference was only $100 - $700 versus $800, at least at Best Buy this week&amp;nbsp;- I went with the 32&amp;quot; (the KDL-32M3000). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I purchased an RCA antenna back in 2005, when I was living downtown, and have been using it with my televisions since. After plugging it into my new tv, I was able to get both standard analog channels, as well as a number of digital channels. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, I did have to spend some time messing with the antenna to get both Fox 47 and NBC 15 at the &amp;#39;same&amp;#39; time (id est, with the same settings). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ll post more about this television as I use it, but I&amp;#39;m pretty happy after a couple of hours of use. My first movie on the television? Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s. My first full show? That 70s Show, interestingly enough (not much else on at 5 on a Saturday afternoon).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Follow ups:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Sony-Bravia-KDL-32M3000-comments-2-weeks-later.aspx&#34;&gt;Two weeks later&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(comments)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>