<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web 2.0 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/tags/web-2/index.0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web 2.0 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 10:30:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/tags/web-2.0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;d like to see in 201X in regard to browsers</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/What-Id-like-to-see-in-201X-in-regard-to-browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 10:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/What-Id-like-to-see-in-201X-in-regard-to-browsers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Situation 1: WebKit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft drops all active development on Internet Explorer 9. Instead, they throw their full support (development team)&amp;nbsp;behind WebKit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple, with Safari, and Google, with Chrome, are already behind WebKit. Apple&amp;rsquo;s implementation on Windows, via Safari for Windows, is shoddy at best, and Google&amp;rsquo;s Chrome is a completely slimmed down version. By getting Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s support behind the engine you have an experienced team that has already developed for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also have three operating systems covered (Microsoft = Windows, Apple = Mac, and Google ~= Linux), suggesting that users of these systems will have a great experience with the WebKit implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leaves Mozilla Firefox and Opera out of the mix, but Opera&amp;rsquo;s team has the mobile browser understood, and could bring that to the table, while Mozilla would have extension experience (not that the experience is all that great, but &amp;hellip;). Either way, the only thing that seems to tie Mozilla together is Google&amp;rsquo;s money, and if Google were to withdraw that support, and WebKit were to support extensions as Firefox does, Mozilla/Firefox may experience a peaceful end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Situtation 2: Standards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, perhaps this decade we can see standards being agreed upon, in particular as the HTML 5 &amp;lsquo;release&amp;rsquo; approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they&amp;rsquo;re at it, they may as well join together on the common cause of making the Web a safer place, and together build safe browsers (even if they each have their own).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What will really happen?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, while I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful enough to have these &amp;hellip; hopes, a decade just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem long enough for either of these situations to actually occur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of the Web - A Trailer</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/The-State-of-the-Web-A-Trailer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2007 22:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/The-State-of-the-Web-A-Trailer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;#39;s true that I have some of my best thoughts at night ... or at least, so they then seem.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Web 2.0 promises to bring us a unified Web, a Web joined together under the collective banner of Collaboration.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But the new paradigm is just the old with new voices. The new Web has it&amp;#39;s collaborators, but that hasn&amp;#39;t changed the number of kingdoms.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Come to us and help us build the best ___! However, you must share your knowledge to benefit the whole.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Did we really sign up for the rehashing of the same old content on site after site, all because of collaboration? Are the crowds better or worse than the individual? And, at what cost the unified crowd? Have we lost the power of the individual within the common man?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It may be that the crowd is wise, but with so many crowds, which are we to believe when they speak the opposite?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;d rather have the smart, the average, and the dumb working alone or in clumps than unified under one banner, for that way leads to naught but stupidity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Kill the krowd and save MAN!&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Create your content, but keep it as your&amp;#39;s; don&amp;#39;t let them take it from you and divide it to the common denominator.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Teach men to fish. Teach men to think.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;If you expect us to believe your promise of unification, then you must begin by unifying the movement itself.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Can man perceive the world without his own senses? Can he act without being active?  No.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms or human judgement?  Give me logic</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Algorithms-or-human-judgement-Give-me-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 23:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Algorithms-or-human-judgement-Give-me-logic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Earlier today, it was noted in the news that Wikipedia founder Jimmy Wales is working with Amazon on a search engine.&amp;nbsp; This new engine supposedly will use human judgement to weight results.&amp;nbsp; Naturally, sources are saying that this engine&amp;#39;s competition is Google.&amp;nbsp; While Web 2.0 has some good things going for it, this is one of the silliest ideas I&amp;#39;ve heard of in a long time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, DMOZ anyone?&amp;nbsp; Want your site to show up high in the DMOZ directory? Bribe a DMOZ editor.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;#39;s not hard.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Want your site or service to be posted on Digg?&amp;nbsp; No, your money &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; good with Digg posters.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Maybe people are intrinsically good (I like to think that they are neither good nor evil/bad in their original state/position), but thousands and thousands or years of evolution and humanity has resulted in man being less than perfect.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With people already trying to cheat the mathematical algorithms that the best SEs (Search Engines) use, how is a human-based search engine going to do any better?&amp;nbsp; What we really are talking about, when we talk about human judged search results is a &lt;strong&gt;directory&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Putting aside the cheating and lying, the Wikipedia is a great example of this - probably one of the best out there (that I know of - comment if you know of anything potentially better).&amp;nbsp; The content, taken with a grain of salt, includes links to external sources.&amp;nbsp; For technical/Web-based items, you bet I&amp;#39;ll hit the Wiki, as there&amp;#39;s probably going to be at least one link on any article that points to the essentials (id est, the essential information).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anything more than this and you have to account for man&amp;#39;s selfishness, pride, and greed.&amp;nbsp; As with the Wiki, it will be essential for individuals to have &amp;#39;super&amp;#39; powers, the ability to lock items down, as well as the need to educate users that the service should be taken with a grain of salt.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, you have to do that with search engines now, for black-hat SEOs and the rest are interested in few things as much as the green, but ... when it comes to billions of sites, give me an algorithm-based search engine any day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After all, how else are we to find the sites for our directory in the first place?&amp;nbsp; User submission?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;On a related note ...&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One thing that I would like to see in future versions of search engines is the ability to have some control over how my sites are listed.&amp;nbsp; Using sitemaps, I can already tell Google that I own such-and-such domains, but it would be nice to give my results some credibility.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;quot;This site&amp;#39;s Webmaster has registered with us, and here&amp;#39;s their information.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp; (Information could be basic contact information, a Web page address, or what-have-you.)&amp;nbsp; I don&amp;#39;t know, but it seems like a semi-good idea.&amp;nbsp; If the site is &amp;#39;trouble&amp;#39;, then the search engine could be notified of this.&amp;nbsp; You could potentially tie this into user reviews of the site as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Of course, there&amp;#39;s a number of sites out there that do this, but that&amp;#39;s the problem - there&amp;#39;s a &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; of sites that do this.&amp;nbsp; (Again, why trust people in general when there&amp;#39;s at least half-a-dozen sites for every possible idea out there?&amp;nbsp; Why not consolidate, and allow branching that&amp;#39;s linked to the original site/group?)&amp;nbsp; Why build another site when, given sufficient numbers, you can make an existing site better?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A unicorn, perhaps.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status update on logging into my Root /Vault</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Status-update-on-logging-into-my-Root-Vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2006 21:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Status-update-on-logging-into-my-Root-Vault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Thanks to some great support, I&amp;#39;m now able to log in to my Vault.&amp;nbsp; Now that I&amp;#39;m in, I&amp;#39;ll be bouncing around items a bit more.&amp;nbsp; There&amp;#39;s also some great articles that I&amp;#39;d like to comment on, that revolve around the project, so that&amp;#39;ll end up meaning new philosophy-related posts (instead of just the porting-over of old ones.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hooray!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention: Where do you put it?</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Attention-Where-do-you-put-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2006 19:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Attention-Where-do-you-put-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In some way, I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.AttentionTrust.org/&#34;&gt;AttentionTrust.org&lt;/a&gt;.  Basically, AttentionTrust operates under the principle that your attention is both yours, and of worth.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What really brought me in has an article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.attentiontrust.org/node/153&#34;&gt;Attention as a Backup Identity&lt;/a&gt;.  Reading this, I&amp;#39;m struck by a number of things.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1) Web 2.0 advocates are a lot like philosophers - they both can reference science fiction as the future.  There are, from what I&amp;#39;ve seen, no groups of individuals online that reference science fiction more.  Of course, the Internet is extremely connected with science fiction, in that it allows the almost instantaneous sharing of information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
2) &amp;quot;That which we own ends up owning us.&amp;quot;  All too often, especially with the youth, but certainly not limited to them, there&amp;#39;s a problem with the connection between their Internet personality and their real personality.  MySpace is a great example, where not only do you live in a community, you can die into one as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &amp;quot;As we establish multiple online identities and avatars, we increasingly run the risk of suffering a catastrophic loss of identity.&amp;quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Errr ... kinda, depending upon how we read this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The only loss of identity we have is that we&amp;#39;re creating multiple identities online, and often a different personality online.  Like some games, we become so focused on who are in relation to the game, or within the game, that we are no longer anything outside of the game.  In short, remove that which we have connected, or focused, upon, and we cannot determine what we are anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We exist not only as a part of the communities we are a part of, but individually outside of them.  It&amp;#39;s important to remember this.  Just because an online community disappears, doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily mean that I disappear.  Likewise, just because you leave a community, doesn&amp;#39;t necessarily mean that the community disappears.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyways, I downloaded the Attention Recorder extension for Firefox, and signed up at Root Vaults to host my data.  However, I&amp;#39;ve yet to find any information on when this data is uploaded ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyways, once again, it sounds both interesting and promising.  More on this as things progress.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0 and overload</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Web-20-and-overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2005 13:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Web-20-and-overload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve been reading a good deal today, before and after my excursion around Madison (on Homecoming game-day, even).  There are three that really stick out:&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, we have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/oreilly/tim/news/2005/09/30/what-is-web-20.html&#34;&gt;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/oreilly/tim/news/2005/09/30/what-is-web-20.html&lt;/a&gt;, which is an article by Tim O&amp;#39;Reilly on Web 2.0.  If you&amp;#39;ve heard of it, or if you haven&amp;#39;t, it&amp;#39;s worth a read.  Since I&amp;#39;ve only skimmed the first two pages, I&amp;#39;m not sure about lasting worth, but ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Then we have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.collisiondetection.net/mt/archives/2005/09/_for_a_few_year_1.html&#34;&gt;http://www.collisiondetection.net/mt/archives/2005/09/_for_a_few_year_1.html&lt;/a&gt;, on the snobbery of iPods.  Make sure you read the comments ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Which leads into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rootburn.com/2004/12/too-much-of-good-thing.html&#34;&gt;http://www.rootburn.com/2004/12/too-much-of-good-thing.html&lt;/a&gt;, on too much of a good thing.  Specifically photos, but I think it&amp;#39;s applicable to the whole Web 2.0 &amp;#39;movement&amp;#39;, thereby bringing us back to link one.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
~Jk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
