<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movie on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/movie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movie on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 10:42:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/movie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sin City / color in movies</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Sin-City-color-in-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 10:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Sin-City-color-in-movies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A thread from Facebook that I don&#39;t want to lose. To be updated as more responses come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial post&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, color in movies. Like the bar scene - &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sbl2LxNZ2eY&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sbl2LxNZ2eY&lt;/a&gt; - in Sin City and near the end of Avalon - &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P28-PPzCI3k&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P28-PPzCI3k&lt;/a&gt; - and the obvious ones in the Wizard of Oz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any other good examples?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Response from &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://rmlumley.com&#34;&gt;Rob Lumley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You seem to be mentioning when a particular color stands out. Another obvious one is the end of Schindler&#39;s List.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color in general in movies is interesting. I&#39;m always intrigued with the palette of colors a DIrector chooses. For example, Michael Mann&#39;s Heat uses a lot of blues/grays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My response&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I debated putting Wizard of Oz on there, and after more thought, shouldn&#39;t have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Avalon I think it&#39;s the shock factor. The entire movie, up until then, is in a sepia-like tone. But when she (spoilers) opens the door into the &#39;highest level&#39; and color fills the screen, you realize that the entire movie *is* in color. Of course, I&#39;m sure there&#39;s more to it than just that, but I&#39;ve yet to re-watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Sin City it&#39;s far deeper than that. The movie is mostly in black and white, excluding certain aspects of some people. Marv&#39;s story seems to feature more purely black and white moments, like when he&#39;s in his parole officer&#39;s apartment, where the white of the bandages really seem to pop off the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the above scene, however, you first see color start to bleed into the world. It makes sense a few scenes later when he admits that he loves her. While her love for him may be more hero/savior worship, you know his love transcends that. I think the clearest evidence of that is this scene where we see his world view, of Basin City, change. Color seeps in until he realizes that he&#39;s just put her life at risk. With this the color fades quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Avalon, Sin City isn&#39;t *shot* in a particular hue, for the characters, the world really is that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically don&#39;t follow individual directors, but Mann is one that I do. (It&#39;s too bad the Miami Vice movie was such a disappointment.) Heat&#39;s a *long* movie, but one that features very little filler. I guess I didn&#39;t pay that much importance to the palette choice (although certainly, based on the Miami Vice series, I knew that was one of the things he uses), just because I find his characters much more interesting. Like Collateral. Features perhaps a bit more filler than it could, but the characters, I think, make up for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t watch Schindler&#39;s List in school, so while it&#39;s on my list, I can&#39;t comment on that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
