<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linksys on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/linksys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linksys on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 16:42:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/linksys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Linksys WRT 8-Port Gigabit Switch (SE4008-FFP)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Linksys-WRT-8-Port-Gigabit-Switch-SE4008-FFP/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 16:42:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Linksys-WRT-8-Port-Gigabit-Switch-SE4008-FFP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00NQ19E5M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Linksys WRT 8-Port Gigabit Switch (SE4008-FFP)&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A great basic switch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been many years since I&#39;ve used a network switch, as wireless has become fast and prevalent enough that most devices are just wireless now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since I&#39;m running into an issue where wired computers weren&#39;t on the same subnet due to the usage of a router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00NQ19E5M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Linksys SE4008&lt;/a&gt; in my network for a number of weeks now I&#39;ve found it to be extremely performant. It has very basic functionality, so it&#39;s not too surprising, but I&#39;ve had no reason to restart it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of functionality, there&#39;s no web interface for the switch. So if you&#39;re hoping to setup any sort of advanced functionality, such as quality of service (does seemingly support router configuration of this), port forwarding, or MAC address-based static IPs, you&#39;ll have to look elsewhere. Initially I tried putting the switch between my modem and wireless router, to prevent some issues I&#39;m having with sessions in the router, but because of these restrictions had to keep the switch connected through the router. Not a big issue there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to the hardware, this features 8 ports, which, again, in our world should be more than enough for the majority of home networks, even if you&#39;re plugging multiple next-generation consoles into it. The front LEDs showing activity can be switched on or off, which is something I haven&#39;t seen on many modems or routers, and definitely not on switches from years ago. Given the various places these devices can be placed in, this is quite nice to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to network speed, the speeds I saw using this device were on-par with speeds I noticed using my current router setups. Outside of filling every port with a device and having them all hit the network as hard as possible, you shouldn&#39;t experience any issues because of this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, while I don&#39;t have a Linksys router that supports it, I do like the stacking ability that they promote in their marketing for this. It&#39;s a nice idea, but your mileage may vary, given how many quality products are being released by a variety of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a basic switch, this works just as I&#39;d expect. Individuals looking for something with additional functionality, or the ability to install firmware on it, will need to look elsewhere. For these reasons I give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00NQ19E5M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Linksys WRT 8-Port Gigabit Switch (SE4008-FFP)&lt;/a&gt; 4 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Linksys AC1200 Wi-Fi Wireless Dual-Band&#43; Router with Gigabit &amp; USB Ports (EA6350)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Linksys-AC1200-Wi-Fi-Wireless-Dual-Band-Router-with-Gigabit-USB-Ports-EA6350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 19:49:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-Linksys-AC1200-Wi-Fi-Wireless-Dual-Band-Router-with-Gigabit-USB-Ports-EA6350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00JZWQW4C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Linksys AC1200 Wi-Fi Wireless Dual-Band+ Router with Gigabit &amp;amp; USB Ports (EA6350)&lt;/a&gt;, which I received as part of the Amazone Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Runs hot, but nice interface and speeds&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a couple routers around the house, but I&#39;ve always been a fan of Linksys, so when I saw the opportunity to review the Linksys AC1200+ I snapped it up. Unfortunately, while it has a number of good points, I&#39;ll ultimately be unplugging it and using an existing device instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the good. The setup (ignoring the Smart Wi-Fi application for a moment) was pretty painless. Once the router came back up I was able to connect to both bands of the device without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B009V00K3W?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;D-Link&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0044YU60M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Medialink&lt;/a&gt; router, as well as past Linksys models (WRT54G/L), I actually rather liked the web interface that they provided. The single light on the top of the device isn&#39;t ultra-bright, so I didn&#39;t have to keep the light in mind for placement. Speeds and signal strength seemed comparable to my other routers, which is to say perfectly sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the Smart Wi-Fi functionality, I ultimately have no need for such an application, but it was easy enough to skip during the setup. It also has functionality to check for updates automatically, but since I don&#39;t trust devices not to brick themselves during an auto-update, I opted to turn this off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the bad. This thing runs extremely hot. Within a few minutes. That combined with the size of the box requires a certain amount of planning on where the device can be placed. Having a number of other devices, this is by far the hottest one I have. And yes, I mean hot, not warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00JZWQW4C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Linksys AC1200 Wi-Fi Wireless Dual-Band+ Router with Gigabit &amp;amp; USB Ports (EA6350)&lt;/a&gt; worth the more than $100 it&#39;s currently selling at? I&#39;m not sure. My &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B009V00K3W?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;D-Link dual-band router (DIR-855L)&lt;/a&gt; has served me extremely well, with a smaller footprint and heat signature. I really like the interface, but realistically I&#39;ll use it about once a year or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ultimately I&#39;d say it&#39;s four of five stars. If you&#39;re okay with the price, it does what it says it&#39;s going to do, but you&#39;ll need to make room for the device. If you&#39;re not okay with the price, then you can find alternatives without compromising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
