<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sony Psp on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/sony-psp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sony Psp on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 19:50:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/sony-psp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Ys Seven (PSP)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Ys-Seven-PSP/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 19:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Ys-Seven-PSP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003O21OWY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ys Seven&lt;/a&gt;, for the Sony PlayStation Portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003O21OWY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ys Seven&lt;/a&gt;, the first Ys game I&amp;rsquo;ve played, was recommended to me a number of times before I finally picked up a copy. Since XSEED had some hand in the game, I was expecting a fairly good game, and found an excellent one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ys Seven is a sort of action RPG, with combat taking place on the field, and consisting of standard attacks, dodges, skills, and special attacks. Up to three characters can be in the party at any one time, and switching between them is easy as pressing a button. This provides for extremely fast battles, although, depending upon your level, battles due require more than just simple button mashing (although at higher levels you can generally clear the field doing just this), as some enemies will guard against certain character&amp;rsquo;s attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience is gained each time an enemy is defeated, as well as for each use of a skill. Each character has a base class of weapon, with additional, learnable skills attached, two equipment slots, and slot for an accessory that provides some sort of bonus.&amp;nbsp;So there&amp;rsquo;s a very simple skill tree within the game, for each character, although since skills cannot unlock new skills, it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty skinny tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music is one of the first things you&amp;rsquo;ll notice about the game, as it successfully fades into the background, or grabs your attention, whenever necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is fairly good. At the end of the game things are tied up rather nicely, in a rather satisfying manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game itself generally takes between 20 to 30 hours to complete. While it&amp;rsquo;s not recorded, I ended up doing all of the optional missions, created the ultimate weapons (and armors), learned all skills, and I believe picked up most, if not all, of the various treasures, leading me to believe I had near 99% completion. This brought me up to approximately 31 hours of gameplay. There is new game plus, and if you wish to continue after defeating the final boss, you need to reload an existing save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is avaliable in physical and electronic formats - I purchased and played the latter, which requires approximately 450 MB of space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give the same 5 of 5 stars, since I was able to get a pretty solid number of hours out of the game, I enjoyed almost every minute I played, and could potentially pick up the game to play it again, whether that means using my final saves or starting again (although I probably would just do the former).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video review: PSP Super Travel Case With Pockets</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-PSP-Super-Travel-Case-With-Pockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 07:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-PSP-Super-Travel-Case-With-Pockets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ASBKHE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;PSP Super Travel Case With Pockects&lt;/a&gt;, produced by CTA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was looking at purchasing my &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001KMRN0M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Sony PSP (3000)&lt;/a&gt;, I knew I had to get some kind of case to keep it safe. After looking around, I decided upon this travel case, released by CTA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve&amp;nbsp;create a video review of the product, which I&amp;rsquo;ll let handle the specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;390&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/a5CK-gb1dvE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Kingdom Hearts: Birth by Sleep</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Kingdom-Hearts-Birth-by-Sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 08:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Kingdom-Hearts-Birth-by-Sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002I0GZ5Y?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kingdom Hearts: Birth by Sleep&lt;/a&gt;, for the Sony PlayStation Portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played Kingdom Hearts 1 and 2 years ago, I skipped most of the other iterations of the Kingdom Hearts series either because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the console (DS) or because the games just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have the same appeal (Chain of Memories).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly before picking up my PSP I heard a lot of really great things about this game, with most reviews saying it had a good story, graphics, and an improved combat system, but a quirky camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having put almost 43 hours into the game, over the course of 10 days (having completed it yesterday), I can honestly say this game has been one of the most enjoyable I&amp;rsquo;ve played in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game features a combat system similar to the first two Kingdom Hearts games, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Crisis-Core-Final-Fantasy-VII.aspx&#34;&gt;Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII&lt;/a&gt;. The story, while a little confusing because we follow three (playable) characters, is pretty good. I only wish I had remembered more about the first Kingdom Hearts, since it&amp;rsquo;s a prequel to the events that take place there (although if you haven&amp;rsquo;t played the other games in the series you&amp;rsquo;ll still do fine). I&amp;rsquo;m once again a little embarrassed that I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying a game featuring Disney characters, but Square once again merges the different characters together very nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voice acting for all characters is decent to great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, I&amp;rsquo;ve put at least 42 hours into the game, completing each character&amp;rsquo;s stories, and the final episode, but could easily put a dozen hours more into the game getting further completion and in the arena (which is still enjoyable, even though I don&amp;rsquo;t know anyone else with a PSP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all, I give this game 5 stars across the board. Square and Disney have really hit the mark with this game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Crisis-Core-Final-Fantasy-VII/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 15:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Crisis-Core-Final-Fantasy-VII/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a review of the Sony PlayStation Portable game &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0014X7SQ6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy VII was the game that made me want a PlayStation 1. I played Final Fantasy VII briefly after it was initially released at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house, then my own copies later in college on both the PC and PlayStation 1. So when&amp;nbsp;I ordered a PlayStation Portable (PSP)&amp;nbsp;recently&amp;nbsp;it seemed like a no-brainer to pick up a copy of Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII as one of my first games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having previously played and enjoyed the Kingdom Hearts games for the PlayStation 2, this game was the perfect choice for my first PSP game, and is the major reason I&amp;rsquo;m extremely glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up a PSPgo, and will continue to keep my PSP-3000 for as long as it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crisis Core tells the events that lead up to Final Fantasy VII (in fact ending&amp;nbsp;with the opening of FF7), and I&amp;rsquo;ll admit the story is pretty moving (Lost Odyssey was the last game to make me tear-up, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t cry during FF7). The gameplay will be quite familar if you&amp;rsquo;ve played the PlayStation 2 Kingdom Hearts games, featuring a mix of real-time battles with RPG elements. Depending upon your preference for such things, it offers various simplified elements, such as the shop and leveling, which I think works fairly well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game plays great on the PSP, offering fairly tight controls (movement via either the d-pad or stick), with great sound and video (as usual with Square (Enix), the CG videos&amp;nbsp;are top-notch and they look great on the PSP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is UMD-only, and there seem to be no plans to make it available electronically. Compared to the other UMD game I&amp;rsquo;ve thus far played, Star Ocean: First Departure, the UMD seems to be&amp;nbsp;read from&amp;nbsp;fairly frequently, but loading times are fairly quick, and it&amp;rsquo;s something that you can easily ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To completion, with a number of optional missions finished, I put in a little over 27 hours into the game, and will definitely be putting more hours in to get near 100% on the optional missions, and perhaps even another playthrough (via new game plus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the default difficulty I died once or twice (excluding those times a Phoenix Down kept me going), and those were more from stupidity then anything else. Generally, I&amp;rsquo;d say the game is fairly easy, with some fights a little more difficult than others. Unlike Final Fantasy VII it seems to be a little easier to be a completionist in this game, but since the main area is pretty spread out, those of this type might get a little bored walking back and forth (unless they&amp;rsquo;re following a guide).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give the game 5 stars of 5, as I found the game to be extremely enjoyable, and the amount of time put into it currently, and in the future, is vastly more than the price of entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended for fans of Final Fantasy VII, as well as those who enjoyed Kingdom Hearts on the PlayStation 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23&#43; hours with the PlayStation Portable: Initial thoughts</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/23-plus-hours-with-the-PlayStation-Portable-Initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 22:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/23-plus-hours-with-the-PlayStation-Portable-Initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the first of the month I purchased a Sony PlayStation Portable, which was delivered to me on the 4th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I&#39;ve used it, mostly for play, for approximately 24 hours. Approximately 23 hours and 12 minutes of that was with my first game, Crisis Core; Final Fantasy VII, and the rest (which was probably over an hour) was initial setups, as well as the playing of a handful of demos, and Castlevania: Symphony of the Night, which I had purchased for play on my PS3 a long while ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are my thoughts on my purchase, after approximately 24 hours, over the course of approximately 12 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The initial debate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Oh-why-cant-I-find-a-reason-to-buy-a-current-gen-portable-console.aspx&#34;&gt;I had debated getting a Nintendo DSi or a Sony PlayStation Portable&lt;/a&gt; (henceworth PSP). Granted, I had discussed possibly getting an Apple product as well, but the games for their systems are far too casual for my tastes, and the cost of entry is far too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was down to a DSi, which would be replaced in a handful of months by the Nintendo 3DS, or a PSP, with its questionably-sized U.S. selection. Of course there&#39;s also the PSPgo, which has been getting a bit of slack, but UMDs cannot be used in the device, and not all games are available for download. The PSP 2 seems to have&amp;nbsp;a similar fate, so since the &#39;regular&#39; PSP can play both &#39;types&#39; of games now, the future doesn&#39;t matter as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The winner seems clear ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So given that the 3DS was the product to purchase, if any Nintendo portable device, and the current PSP-3000 device was the Sony product to purchase, you would think the winner would be obvious. Yet, the question then becomes whether the cost to purchase is too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cost of entry (for the PSP)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Metal Gear Solid bundle looked good, at it&#39;s $200 price with a game, memory stick, and free movie included, the big question was whether I&#39;d be able to play the game, or if I&#39;d just end up selling it. I&#39;d also be getting a green PSP, when I&#39;d much rather have a black machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were bundles as well, but based on how the game was included - a non-standard case - I decided that if anything I&#39;d get the standalone version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to play games I&#39;d need to purchase a memory card/stick, and since the PSP doesn&#39;t close in on itself, I&#39;d need some kind of case to protect it during travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it could play the handful of games I currently purchased (PSOne Classics) on the PlayStation Network, I&#39;d probably want to pick up a game or two, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that gives us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001KMRN0M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;PSP 3000 Core Pack&lt;/a&gt; = $169.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013AX2JM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;4 GB Memory Stick PRO Duo&lt;/a&gt; = $15.87&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ASBKHE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;PSP Travel Case&lt;/a&gt; = $8.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0014X7SQ6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Crisis Core: Final Fantasy VII&lt;/a&gt; = $9.96&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000R39IKI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Brave Story: New Traveler&lt;/a&gt; = $19.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first game was an obvious choice, while the second was supposedly one of the best of its kind on the system. Before shipping was included, the total cost was $224.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001T8W2LW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;DSi&lt;/a&gt; would have started at $150, and I wouldn&#39;t have needed memory (already had a spare card) nor a case. I would have purchased &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002I0EH6I?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Dragon Quest IX&lt;/a&gt;, at approximately $35, and would have had enough to purchase an older game, like &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00136MBHA?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;The World Ends With You&lt;/a&gt;, or an Atlus offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again, the DSi isn&#39;t an option, so it was more on whether the $225 would be an okay cost. Since I had recently made over $250 selling some of my old possessions, I certainly had the money to spend. So I finally did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Additional purchases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my initial purchases I of course decided that I had to pick up a couple more things. The first was an &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002L2X958?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;8 GB Pro Duo&lt;/a&gt; memory stick, as the number of games on the PlayStation Network that I decided I may be interested in totals far more than 4 GB of space. With Sony&#39;s Media Go application it would be relatively easy to transfer files between my laptop/network and my PSP, but I may not always been in a situtation where that&#39;s an option. (Although, as I&#39;ll possibly note later, the battery life of the PSP isn&#39;t all that wonderful, so it may be rather likely after all.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also purchased &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001CM62UM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Star Ocean: First Departure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001CM0PJ6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Star Ocean: Second Evolution&lt;/a&gt;, since both received good reviews. I was tempted to pick up one of the Personas instead, but ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I&#39;ve blown my budget, so this will probably be it until late December or January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus far I&#39;ve been extremely happy with the PSP experience. The device itself is beautiful, and after my first day of play (a couple of hours) my hands were a bit sore from how I was holding the device, but I&#39;ve since gotten used to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sound is great, and thus far I haven&#39;t missed the second, right, analog stick. In fact, I&#39;ve been staying away from the only analog stick, as much as I can. A couple of demos have required the use of it, but since I&#39;ve been playing mostly Crisis Core, which allows for either, it hasn&#39;t got much use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s also a little strange not to have additional buttons on the top of the console/controller, but again, I have yet to play any games that required an L2 or R2 button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been shutting of the console &#39;incorrectly,&#39; due to not completely reading the manual all the way through. Instead of holding the power button up for 3 seconds I was pushing it up briefly, as you do when you turn it on. I haven&#39;t quite played every day, but haven&#39;t noticed any issue with the battery life because of it. (Supposedly it still takes some charge from the battery.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve also noticed that it&#39;s extremely difficult to tell how much battery is left, unless you exit out of your current game entirely and view the system menu. I&#39;ve only had the console &#39;die&#39; on me once, and that was graceful, in that after plugging it in I was able to continue my game right where I had left off. In fact, that&#39;s actually the really cool thing about the console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Past portable console experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I should probably point out that I wanted a GameBoy, and my cousins had one, but we ended up purchasing a Game Gear. As you may be aware, it was much like a PSP, except the batteries didn&#39;t come with the device, probably weren&#39;t rechargeable (not until later were mine), and the battery life sucked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I think I ended up tossing the device and the battery pack we had ended up purchasing for it. And I don&#39;t really feel that bad about losing it. (The power pack had bent prongs, if I remember correctly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, that&#39;s my experience. I was tempted to purchase one of the Nintendo devices before, but after the 64 (another console I didn&#39;t feel that bad about selling), I just haven&#39;t been a big fan of Nintendo&#39;s consoles. Sure, I bought a Wii, but only after I had purchased a PlayStation 3 and an Xbox 360, and really just for the hardcore games (No More Heroes) and especially the virtual console. (Yes, I could just play the games on my PC, but like music, I want to support the people that made the games possible, whenever I can. That means let me spend my money on it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The experience, continued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really, the battery hasn&#39;t been that bad for more casual play, and I&#39;m sure Crisis Core is taxing the system more than a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen quality is great, as is the video, but I have already got fingerprints on the screen around the main buttons, and my lens cloth doesn&#39;t seem to have done much in the way of cleaning this. I&#39;m also still trying to get the hang of the best place to hold the console so that I can get the best sound (it&#39;s pretty obvious where that sweet spot is) and screen quality, without tiring my arms. (Yeah, that does sound a bit wimpy, but I&#39;ll be the first to admit I don&#39;t lift much in my daily affairs.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My PlayStation 1 library&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last point worth mentioning is that when&amp;nbsp;I had researched the device I had read that custom firmware exists to allow people the ability to play, for example, SNES games on the PSP. In fact, the device is something of a hacker&#39;s playground, with piracy on the device rather high, and a number of publishers sticking with UMDs because of that. Supposedly the PSP 2 will offer more protection in that regard, but ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I was really interested in was whether I&#39;d be able to potentially play games in my PlayStation 1 library on the device. From what I can tell it is possible, but it requires custom firmware. It&#39;s truly unfortunate that I can&#39;t play games that I had previously purchased on the device, unless I go custom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, I like to support creators whenever I can, but if I can&#39;t re-purchased Xenogears, or Parasite Eve 1/2, or Tony Hawk, then I&#39;m extremely tempted to hack my device. And even games that can be purchased, that I already own, like the Final Fantasy series, are difficult for me to justify purchasing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, based on my experience with Castlevania: SotN, the PSP may just not be the best console to re-play those games after all, so it may not even make all that much sense to go through the trouble, especially since it&#39;s difficult to know exactly what each custom firmware offering offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trophy support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one other thing worth mentioning is the PSP&#39;s trophies. Or rather, the lack thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I was a little disappointed that these weren&#39;t available, but having now put in almost 23 and a half hours with Crisis Core, and having enjoyed every minute of it, I&#39;ve got to admit that I miss not having trophies in games. As I used to do, I&#39;m trying to get close to 100% in the game for the sole reason that I want to, not that I&#39;ll get a trophy or achievement for it. Sadly I have started reading a walkthrough (which I&#39;m going to stop, although at this point I&#39;m pretty close to the end anyways, so hurrah at least for not looking at one for ~85% of the time currently invested), but I did that during my second playthrough of Final Fantasy VII, and I don&#39;t believe there&#39;s any problem with using one to get the full experience out of a game (as opposed to missing one stupid thing and getting upset, like in Final Fantasy X and others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current conclusion?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&#39;m extremely happy with my decision to purchase a Sony PSP 3000, and given everything would have done it again (perhaps only purchasing&amp;nbsp;two 8 GB cards instead of one 4 GB and one 8 GB). And given that the games I&#39;m really interested in are yet to come (like The Third Birthday), and it&#39;s unlikely the the 3000 will drop in price (excluding possibly around the holidays), I feel this was the perfect time to make my purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh why can&#39;t I find a reason to buy a current gen portable console?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Oh-why-cant-I-find-a-reason-to-buy-a-current-gen-portable-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2010 17:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Oh-why-cant-I-find-a-reason-to-buy-a-current-gen-portable-console/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spent a great portion of the day researching current gen portable consoles; the Nintendo DS(i) and Sony PSP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MLB for the latter was disappointing (I&#39;m not much of a sports fan, so no surprise), but the Pokemon (I&#39;m ashamed to admit) game was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of the stores in Madison actually carried the Metal Gear PSP bundle I would have purchased it, even though I logically have a difficult time justifying it. I think PSOne Classics and 3rd Birthday (which isn&#39;t even out until 2011) are the only things I keep consistently coming back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For variety the DS seems to be the winner, but with the 3DS coming out next year, reviewers say to hold off until then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there&#39;s no reason to purchase an iTouch when my iPod is working just fine, and I could purchase a DS and a PSP for the price I&#39;d end up paying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the talk of classic Gameboy titles coming out for electronic download/purchase for the 3DS is true, as well as backwards support for DS games, I&#39;ll surely pick one of those up at some point next year, but otherwise ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>