<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video Games on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/video-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video Games on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:20:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/video-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Informer&#39;s The 30 Characters Who Defined A Decade is an excellent read</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Game-Informers-The-30-Characters-Who-Defined-A-Decade-is-an-excellent-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 17:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Game-Informers-The-30-Characters-Who-Defined-A-Decade-is-an-excellent-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having just received this month&#39;s issue of Game Informer I was pleasantly suprised by the article &#39;The 30 Characters Who Defined A Decade,&#39; contained on pages 46 to 69.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was particularly surprised to see Elena Fisher on the list, since Nathan Drake was already present, but feel that was an excellent choice. Lost Odyssey doesn&#39;t show up as much as I feel it should, so it was great to see Kaim Argonar showing up on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the&amp;nbsp;King of All Cosmos was baffling, but welcome at number 30. I was unaware that Auron from Final Fantasy X was such a deep character, and the same for Jade from Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Andrew Ryan down all the way at number 8 was rather odd, in my opinion. I feel that had John Marston not been a more recent development, Ryan would have been further up, and Marston further down (although I haven&#39;t played Red Dead since I crossed into Mexico a few weeks, or maybe a month, ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I tend to recycle the magazines a short time after I get them, I think I&#39;ll definitely be holding onto this one for a little while ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, the article is not available online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>