<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Departed on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/the-departed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Departed on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 17:43:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/the-departed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie review: The Departed (2006)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Movie-review-The-Departed-%282006%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 17:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Movie-review-The-Departed-%282006%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Since I&amp;#39;m not going to be able to write the article(s) that I wanted to tonight (since one is going to require research, and the other is going to involve thought) I figure I&amp;#39;ll write up a quick review on The Departed, which I had the pleasure of seeing today.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    The Departed is quite easily the best film of 2006 that I&amp;#39;ve seen. Take that however you wish. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://framingbusiness.net/&#34;&gt;Gavin Schmitt&lt;/a&gt;, via email, October 20 2006)
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don&amp;#39;t think Gavin thought I was going to quote him, but, I think we both know that anything we say via email is fair game (with a few exceptions). Anyways, I think Gavin hit it on the nose.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first thing I have to comment on is the audience that was with me. It&amp;#39;s been a while since I&amp;#39;ve seen a movie in a theatre so close to when it was first released. Usually, I see movies a month or so after they&amp;#39;ve been out (id est, a week or so before they leave the theatre). I&amp;#39;ve been waiting for The Departed since I first saw the trailer on tv, so I didn&amp;#39;t want to wait that long this time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the theatre, there were initially a lot of women. Now, keep in mind that I saw the movie on Sunday, at the 1 pm showing. This means that not only was the movie $4, it&amp;#39;s early Sunday morning. After a while, couples started filtering in, followed by a rather large group of obnoxious teen/college students, who thankfully shut the _ up (&amp;#39;cause I was certainly going to shush them in an aggressive tone if they had not when the movie started).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, overall, an audience that I was not expecting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Moving on, the cast. There&amp;#39;s a whole lot of A-list talent in this movie, and it shows. Overall, I don&amp;#39;t think anyone did less than their best in this film. Not only that, but they&amp;#39;ve picked exactly the right people for &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; part. Sometimes you think about what an actor has done before, what parts they&amp;#39;ve played, and it changes how you think about the character that they&amp;#39;re playing. Yet, in this movie, the few times I thought about, which was mainly after the fact, it seemed that they were being conditioned to play their part in this movie.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not only is this a &amp;#39;watch in the theatre&amp;#39; movie, this is also a &amp;#39;buy it when it comes out on DVD&amp;#39; flick. Your mileage may vary, but I completely enjoyed the movie - with absolutely no exceptions. The movie is violent, but before you know it it&amp;#39;s over - there&amp;#39;s little sustained violence during this movie.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
R&lt;br /&gt;
152 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
2006
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>