<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Playstation 4 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/playstation-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Playstation 4 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 10:00:10 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/playstation-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Contrast (2013)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-Contrast-%282013%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 10:00:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/posts/Review-Contrast-%282013%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Contrast, released in 2013, for the PlayStation 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Charming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Watch Dogs was delayed, I&#39;ve been thinking about what game would be my first PlayStation 4 experience. Between Contrast, Flower, and Resogun, I ultimately decided upon Contrast, since while I had played flOw first on my PlayStation 3, I had already played (and enjoyed) Flower on the PS3, and wanted something slightly different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast is free for PlayStation Plus subscribers, of which I am one of. So my review might have a slight bias since I paid nothing for the game, which would otherwise cost $14.99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I beat the game and unlocked all trophies within 4 hours of play. But despite that, this game was a worthwhile experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is primarily a platformer that plays in both two and three dimensions. You normally walk around in a three dimensional world, but spend a good portion of the puzzles in light and shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a few of the puzzles were a little frustrating for a moment or two, they were generally quite simple and obvious. The controls are relatively tight, although I did find that switching into the plane, which is done by the R2 button, seemed a little ... off. Perhaps there was a bit of delay in the command registering, I wasn&#39;t close enough to the wall, or I just need to get used to the controller. Either way, the minor frustration this caused didn&#39;t take away too much from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found myself stuck in objects, normally while shifting, that required two restarts from the last save. Again, annoying, but nothing horrible, and it only required a minute to get back to where I was in both places (in part due to the ease of the puzzles once you&#39;ve figured them out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t mentioned the story yet, but it&#39;s one of the things that I found most charming about the game. The medium used to tell the story is ... rather interesting, and the ending, while a bit ambiguous, seems fitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, while I haven&#39;t played Resogun or Flower on the PS4 yet, I&#39;m glad this was my first experience with my PlayStation 4, and that this was free for PlayStation Plus members, so I would experience it right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the game&#39;s length, most people may want to wait until it drops to $9.99 to pick it up, and I&#39;ll admit I would have fallen under that camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll knock it a star for the length and easy puzzles, but ultimately the purpose of the game seems to be more to tell a story in a unique way, which it does well. 4 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
