<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elmah on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/elmah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elmah on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 13:44:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/elmah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2010 complaints about ELMAH on a 64-bit machine - fixed</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Visual-Studio-2010-complaints-about-ELMAH-on-a-64-bit-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 13:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Visual-Studio-2010-complaints-about-ELMAH-on-a-64-bit-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My laptop has quickly become my development machine for smaller projects, especially after I purchased a low-end desktop to host the Subversion repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently added ELMAH support to one of my sites, but since I run 64-bit, and have been using the built-in&amp;nbsp;Cassini for quick development, I started getting a message in Visual Studio 2010 saying &#34;ASP.NET runtime error: Could not load file or assembly &#39;System.Data.SQLite&#39; or one of its dependencies. An attempt was made to load a program with an incorrect format.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While my low-end desktop has Server 2008 R2 installed on it for research and development purposes (thank you MSDN subscription), having a laptop means I won&#39;t always have this resource available. So, since &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1278929/could-not-load-file-or-assembly-system-data-sqlite&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; states that this is an issue with Cassini, and I&#39;m running Windows 7 Home Premium, it was time to install IIS 7 on the machine. After a minimal click in the Control Panel and with the hep of Microsoft Web Platform Installer, my IIS instance was setup correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that requires that Visual Studio 2010 run as administrator (I was afraid I was going to have to update each of my pinned solutions; thankfully you need to (and can only) update this on the main application shortcut), and my MVC 2 project was failing horribly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to debug this further I kept searching and found another post on &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2814101/unwanted-sqlite-inserted-in-bin&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;. After updating my&amp;nbsp;&#39;shared&#39; directory to contain a folder with all of the&amp;nbsp;ELMAH files and&amp;nbsp;another with just the necessary ones, I&#39;m happy to report the errors (warnings)&amp;nbsp;are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one site is still a mash of the old and new, so I had to manually remove the items from the Bin directory to verify, but things seem just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>