<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/categories/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 09:24:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/categories/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Fury of Dracula Third Edition Board Game</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Fury-of-Dracula-Third-Edition-Board-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 09:24:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Fury-of-Dracula-Third-Edition-Board-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OkfQMt&#34;&gt;Fury of Dracula Third Edition Board Game&lt;/a&gt;, which I received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So many pieces, but easy after a week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t played any of the previous editions of Fury of Dracula, so I can&#39;t speak to the changes made in this third edition. However, as I understand it, the game has changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This supports 2 to 5 players, with one player controlling Dracula and the others controlling one or more of the hunters. This does mean that in a two player game one person is controlling all four hunters, which is how I played it for the purposes of this review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game has an approximate run time of 2 to 3 hours, which is why I&#39;m reviewing it from a 2-player perspective; it was difficult to find others to invest that much time, with the perceived difficulty, given the amount of pieces in the box. However, to some extent the difficult is lessened since certain cards that one would think are different, are actually the same. For example, while there are hunter and Dracula event cards, these are combined into a single pile during play. After playing a week of rounds in the game, we had it down pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&#39;ve seen them played, I haven&#39;t played a hidden movement game like this before. I rather enjoyed how it worked, with location cards being used to track where Dracula has moved, instead of using some sort of sheet and writing locations down. It also lessens the ability for Dracula to move backwards (although he can still be tricky to locate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game works with the hunters playing once during the day and then once at night, with Dracula then going at night. This cycle repeats for each day of the week, until either Dracula is defeated, or he wins. However, if the game doesn&#39;t end after a few weeks Dracula starts gaining influence (his way of winning) at a very steady rate. So the game does have some maximum number of turns, based upon how the players do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game itself seemed relatively balanced, which I understand wasn&#39;t the case in earlier editions, with Dracula having a slight advantage. At first I found this to be slightly interesting since Dracula has a number of disadvantages, having less turns and allowing the players to find where he&#39;s been, since Dracula&#39;s last six locations can (generally) be discovered. He also can&#39;t backtrack, since the last six locations aren&#39;t part of the location deck he uses to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as was evident when Dracula was discovered to have moved into Italy, it&#39;s still possible for him to evade capture, as he did when he traveled by sea for three turns, opening up the number of possible locations he could have landed at. He can also leave behind encounters at locations he visited, which may either cause immediate harm, or if left as-is, help him slow down the hunters or finish the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last note is that unlike some games, in Fury of Dracula no player is completely out of the game. While hunters can be defeated, they eventually recover health and can continue on the quest. Each hunter has their own advantages and disadvantages, so no one hunter necessarily dominates over the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the board components themselves are of quite nice quality. The game includes five figures, which are of nice quality (and could potentially be painted), a nice quality board and cardboard pieces, and nice cards. The artwork is of note since it matches the style of the game relatively well. We did find that two of the figures were easy to mistake at a quick glance, which unfortunately did lead to combat happening with a character that should not have been in combat. However, with three or more players, closer attention, or perhaps a paint job, this wouldn&#39;t be an issue. It also only happened once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the only downside I found was the amount of time it took, which was closer to four hours, but was also our first time. Otherwise, when I can find people that will play it, much like Betrayal at House on the Hill and BioShock, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OkfQMt&#34;&gt;Fury of Dracula, Third Edition&lt;/a&gt; will be a game I&#39;ll recommend we try. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Nightmares from the Deep: The Cursed Heart (2012)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Nightmares-from-the-Deep-The-Cursed-Heart-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 12:14:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Nightmares-from-the-Deep-The-Cursed-Heart-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/259740/&#34;&gt;Nightmares from the Deep: The Cursed Heart&lt;/a&gt; (2012), available on Steam and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1WbKptb&#34;&gt;for physical purchase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A good way to get into the genre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I played the Steam version of this game, and this review is based upon that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first real hidden object game I played, thanks to a kind Reddit user who gifted me a key. It was actually quite good, with great artwork. The animated bits suffer from a bit of pixelation, but it doesn&#39;t detract too much from the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The puzzles are relatively easy, but the hint option is there if you need it (just make sure you don&#39;t accidentally hit it while walking about :( ). It took me about four and a half hours to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/259740/&#34;&gt;Nightmares from the Deep: The Cursed Heart&lt;/a&gt; gets four of five stars, and seems to be a good way to get into the genre.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous Base Set</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Pathfinder-Adventure-Card-Game-Wrath-of-the-Righteous-Base-Set/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 17:52:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Pathfinder-Adventure-Card-Game-Wrath-of-the-Righteous-Base-Set/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1FLqFDn&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous Base Set&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Too soon to tell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw the Pathfinder Adventure Card Game available from Amazon Vine I jumped on the chance to give it a try. Unfortunately the complexities of the game currently result in this partial review. This review will be updated in the coming days and weeks as we further play the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason the Pathfinder Adventure Card Game jumped out at me is because the idea of a tabletop RPG has appealed to me for a very long time, but I don&#39;t have the group of friends that (I thought) would be interested in it. It seems you need someone who&#39;s interested in DMing or GMing, and I just don&#39;t know anyone like that anymore. The premise behind the card game version of Pathfinder is that you don&#39;t need a gamemaster (GM), as each player is, to some extent, that role. See also the Sentinels card game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The box itself contains another room for the base set and the eventual expansions. I think I would have liked it to be a bit more like Dominion, where you could see where the cards went without consulting the rules, and so that the various expansions could be slipped in without keeping their original packaging. However, it works for what it is, and I think it&#39;s fine in the sense of each player keeping a consistent character over the course of the game. I have no fear about the components getting mixed up when the box is closed (although one corner or another tended to stick a bit every time I tried to close it), and it tends to sit on it&#39;s side when not in use. It&#39;s a big box though, so lugging it back and forth resulted in me giving up and just leaving it at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules are pretty dense, and while I had read them before hand we ended up reading them as a group before starting as well. You can also expect the initial setup to take at least 30 minutes, so plan accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards themselves seem to be of a good stock, and feature some really fantastic artwork. In a way it almost made me recall decades ago when I played Magic: The Gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ... that&#39;s sadly all I can really say at this point, since we realized we were playing wrong and restarted our adventure. But from what I&#39;ve seen thus far, the quality of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1FLqFDn&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Pathfinder Adventure Card Game: Wrath of the Righteous Base Set&lt;/a&gt; gives it a current 4 star rating. Updates will be woven into the review, and noted at the bottom of this review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Dimension: The Spherical Stackable Fast Paced Puzzle Game</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Dimension-The-Spherical-Stackable-Fast-Paced-Puzzle-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 18:20:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Dimension-The-Spherical-Stackable-Fast-Paced-Puzzle-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Y5qoXn&#34;&gt;Dimension: The Spherical Stackable Fast Paced Puzzle Game&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fun, but I don&#39;t think it&#39;ll turn into a staple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Normally I&#39;d work this into my review, but it&#39;s a little harder this time. As noted above this is a review of a product I received for free, through Amazon. I try very hard to not let that impact my rating.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lauge Luchau, the creator of Dimension, was once an architect. After first opening the game, reading the instructions, and after playing it, I can definitely see that&#39;s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dimension is a fairly simple game. You&#39;re given a total of 15 balls - three of five different colors - and a board to use to stack them into a pyramid. Each other player (1-4 players can play at a time) has the same setup. A set of six cards are flipped up, which determines the rules of the first round of play, and then each player has a set amount of time to create a pyramid of balls that follow those rules. Rules might include that the number of green balls need to be higher than the number of orange ones. Or every black ball must touch a blue ball (and vice versa).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can break some of the rules, and lose a few points, but sometimes you have to to get one or two more points (or end up balancing out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a relatively simple idea, but it can lead to some rather different structures. When it does. Unfortunately sometimes the random selection of rules is pretty clear-cut, and the &#39;smartest&#39; people will end up with the same score, with others falling a few points behind because they ran out of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The build quality of the pieces is extremely high. The balls appear to be very high quality, and should last through years of play. The boards are simple, and as long as they&#39;re treated well, should also last (they&#39;re a fairly heavy stock, with a nice thickness). The cards are on the smaller size, so shuffling for an adult isn&#39;t the easiest, but they work fine enough (just don&#39;t expect the first half dozen rounds to be very diverse :) ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately the question I have about games is whether they&#39;ll become a gaming staple. And sadly, I&#39;m not sure Dimension will be. I kind of think of it like &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1LuVY7k&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Mad City&lt;/a&gt;, which involves building a 3 x 3 city from square tiles. One of my co-workers really enjoyed the game, but the rest of the group would tend to gravitate toward something a little more complex, or ... strategic. Yet, Dimension does have a complexity to it, but more &#39;scientific,&#39; in a way. I unfortunately don&#39;t have access to any, but part of me wonders if children might like the game more, as I think it would be a fairly good way to really get them thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with all that said I bounce between whether this is a 4 or 3 star game. On the one hand it features a high build quality and is fairly fun to play. On the other hand, it, as others have mentioned, is a little niche, and probably outside of what I&#39;d generally go for. You can have high build quality in a crap game (and this isn&#39;t a crap game), so that has to be tempered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ultimately I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Y5qoXn&#34;&gt;Dimension: The Spherical Stackable Fast Paced Puzzle Game&lt;/a&gt; a high three of five stars. If I had kids, and they enjoyed this, I think my rating might be a little higher, but personally it&#39;s not going to be in my top half dozen choices for a game I&#39;m going to grab to play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Batman Fluxx</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Batman-Fluxx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 06:41:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Batman-Fluxx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onhv54&#34;&gt;Batman Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Not just a minor tweak of Fluxx&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was introduced to Fluxx well over a year ago (I think it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onh4aI&#34;&gt;Oz Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;) I&#39;ve been interested in the game. Thus far I&#39;ve played &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onh4aI&#34;&gt;Oz Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OnhfCY&#34;&gt;Zombie Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1g3jrnl&#34;&gt;Pirate Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1EIvoLe&#34;&gt;Cthulhu Fluxx&lt;/a&gt;, having purchased the latter in July 2014. When I saw that a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onhv54&#34;&gt;Batman Fluxx&lt;/a&gt; was up for review I wondered how the game would play compared to the others, and requested a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now played Batman Fluxx in our lunch gaming group I can honestly say it plays quite well, and will definitely keep it in my bag for future lunches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick and dirty about Fluxx is that the game starts with the rule of draw one card and play one card (starting with three cards in your hand), with no win condition. However, as play proceeds new rules can be played, such as draw 3 or play 4, as well as win conditions, such as having four villains. Ever-changing rules and goals (win conditions) lead to a very interesting game, where one person might think they&#39;ll win in a particular way, but conditions change before they can (such as a hand limit 3 getting played).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each variant of Fluxx adds something to the game, and for Batman Fluxx I would say it adds tools and ways to deal with villains (creepers, which either prevent you from winning or satisfy win conditions). The tools include ways to increase your draw, play count, and hand size, as well as ways to steal keepers (cards that satisfy win conditions) and handle creepers. The action cards are pretty standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the cards each variant of Fluxx seems to have a general play time. Cthulhu Fluxx, for example, can tend toward shorter play times, as it can have multiple goals in play (goals and ungoals) and no one can win. Zombie Fluxx, from what we could remember, tends to have longer play times. Thus far I&#39;d say Batman Fluxx tends toward longer sessions as well. A number of rules allow for a variety of free actions, so depending upon which are selected, and what keeper free actions there are in play, each person&#39;s turn can go longer than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the artwork is based upon the cartoon version of Batman. It looks good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Onhv54&#34;&gt;Batman Fluxx&lt;/a&gt; is a good deal of fun, and is different enough from the other variants that it&#39;s worth a pickup even if you have a different variant already. If you&#39;ve never played Fluxx, but it sounds interesting, and you like Batman, give this game a try. I&#39;m sure you can find a reason to say &#34;I&#39;m Batman,&#34; in a deep growl, while playing it. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the above reasons I give Batman Fluxx a full five of five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Live the Queen: Attempt 4 (Blind)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-4-Blind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 19:12:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-4-Blind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: We&#39;re almost home. Your room is just the way you left it.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I know it&#39;s hard to leave your school and all your friends, but I&#39;ve arranged the best possible tutors for every subject.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll have to work hard this year to prepare yourself before your fifteenth birthday, but I know you can do it.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll learn quickly and you&#39;ll make a wonderful queen. It&#39;s what your mother would have wanted.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is not what Mother would have wanted!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wouldn&#39;t have wanted to die and leave me.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No. She wouldn&#39;t. But sometimes bad things happen. We have to pick up and carry on.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: All of Nova depends on us. On you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: *sigh*&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I will be here to guide you until your coronation, but the decisions you make are ultimately up to you.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Come. Your maids are waiting.&lt;br/&gt; Welcome to &lt;b&gt;Long Live The Queen!&lt;/b&gt; If this is your first time playing, you should read this brief introduction to how the game works.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Tell me more] [I&#39;ve played this before] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I&#39;ve played this before&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 1&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s all that noise outside? Who&#39;s here?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! It&#39;s my cousins! And my aunt and uncle.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: Darling. We were so terribly sorry to hear about your mother Fidelia.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br/&gt;Laurent, Duke of Merva: You look well, niece.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Hi, &#39;Lodie!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Hi, Lottie. I haven&#39;t seen you in ages! Will you be staying long?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Yup! Mummy said we&#39;d be here all month.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Maybe we&#39;ll have some time to talk later.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: I love this room! It&#39;s so much bigger than mine back home.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You should visit more often. It&#39;s awful that the only time I get to see you is...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ... something like this.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I know your brother and sister are still too young, but why haven&#39;t you come to school?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: My mother worries about me. She doesn&#39;t think anywhere but home is safe.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I understand. I&#39;m probably not going to be allowed to leave this castle until my birthday.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But at least we can have fun together here!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 2&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s that commotion outside? Father? What&#39;s going on?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I have come to pay my respects in honor of your mother.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You have no respect or honor. It&#39;s because of you and your powers that my wife is dead!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?!?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I am a Lumen, as was she, and like every Lumen I am willing to give my life if necessary to protect our domain. &lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Your line has been traitors for two hundred years. I won&#39;t have you corrupting my daughter.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: That is for the Crown Princess to decide.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Elodie, your mother trusted me, and I have much to teach you.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Send her away] [Arrest her] [Let her stay] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Send her away&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You heard my father - get out! Leave and don&#39;t come back!&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: As you wish. I will return to my duchy, until you call for me.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: She won&#39;t.&lt;br/&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 3&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt; You may now play Sports on the weekends.&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: He loves me, he loves me not...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Lottie, do you have a boyfriend?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Not really. I just like to play with the flowers.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Me too.&lt;br/&gt; You gather your skirts and prepare to sit down, when all of a sudden, a hissing noise alerts you to a hidden danger - a snake!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Charlotte, don&#39;t move!&lt;br/&gt; With your quick reflexes, you grab a forked stick and manage to flip the snake away from you and your cousin.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: EEEEEK!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Get away, you horrible thing!&lt;br/&gt; You stomp loudly on the ground, and the snake slithers off into the distance.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: What is going on out here?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Mummy, there was a snake!&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: What was a snake doing in the royal gardens? This is completely unacceptable. You could have been killed!&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Elodie scared it off.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: That&#39;s not good enough. I can&#39;t have my daughter remaining in such a dangerous place! We are returning home to Merva at once.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Awww....&lt;br/&gt; You creep through the castle dungeons, catching glimpses here and there of the fate that awaits troublemakers in this kingdom. Even nobles can end up here, sometimes. It&#39;s a good reminder to stay on the straight and narrow.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 4&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Dance in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: The castle seems quieter with Charlotte and Emry and Zahra and their parents gone.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s certainly not empty, though. It seems like we get more servants every day.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Dad? What really happened to Mom?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: She was a Lumen, a magic-user. It was meant to be in reserve, to defend our domain, but she insisted on...&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: ... you don&#39;t need to hear that.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: She used magic. It drained her strength. She thought it was harmless, and it wasn&#39;t. Eventually, her heart just... stopped.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: That&#39;s why I don&#39;t want you involved with it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 5&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; One of the maids approaches for your attention.&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, couriers have arrived from the Duke of Sedna.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We have a Duke of Sedna?&lt;br/&gt;Alice: ... No, my Lady. The duchy of Sedna is in Talasse.&lt;br/&gt;Alice: They have brought you a letter, and a gift.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &#39;Condolences on the death of&#39;, &#39;deeply regret&#39;, &#39;best wishes&#39;...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! What a beautiful necklace!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It might not be appropriate for me to wear a man&#39;s gift in public, though. People would think it meant something.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Wear it] [Don&#39;t wear it] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Don&#39;t wear it&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s important to maintain the proper image.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 6&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: Your Royal Highness. I would speak with you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What is it?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: There are questions you have not yet thought to ask. You know that the powers of a Lumen should be yours. Why have you not sought your crystal?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: My father said I shouldn&#39;t get involved in magic.&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: If you don&#39;t, who will defend your domain if the krakens rise again?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: I have seen signs of the future. Danger is coming. I can teach you to control your powers, but first, you must seize your birthright and become a Lumen.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [I won&#39;t do it] [I will do it] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I will do it&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: How do I do that?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: You must find the royal crystal. Speak to your father - he will know where it is.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Dad, what happened to Mom&#39;s Lumen crystal?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: It&#39;s in a safe place.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Can I have it?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But it&#39;s mine!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Meddling with magic killed your mother. I don&#39;t want that to happen to you.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Once you&#39;re crowned Queen, I can&#39;t stop you from doing anything you want, but for now you are still a child.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 7&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; As you are walking up the stairs, a maid comes running down holding a towering pile of linen.&lt;br/&gt; You swiftly step aside and let her pass.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: My father says I can&#39;t have the crystal until I&#39;m Queen. He&#39;s hiding it somewhere. What do I do?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: I will search for it.&lt;br/&gt; She brings out a black bowl filled with water and stares into its depths. You look as well, but you see nothing but your own reflection.&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: The crystal is kept in the treasury, under guard. They have been ordered to keep you out. You must find a way past this obstacle.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Like what?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: Use your skills to convince them to stand aside, or else dispose of them.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: Their lives are a small price to pay for the safety of your domain. You must have that crystal.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Is she serious? She wants me to kill my own guards?)&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: Try to reach the crystal. If you fail, speak to me again and I will help you to do what needs to be done.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 8&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Accounting in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a man here to see you. He wishes Crown funding for a project of his.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember, the treasury is not unlimited. If you choose to invest, you will have less money to work with later.&lt;br/&gt;Man: Your Royal Highness, I have a plan to print books using metal letters which can be moved and reused.&lt;br/&gt;Man: I need to borrow 875 lassi to assemble the metal and a factory to mold and cast the type.&lt;br/&gt;Man: With this system, we will be able to create new books in a fraction of the time it takes now, and make copies to send all over the world.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know much about factories or trade. Would that really be worthwhile?)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 9&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Presence in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, my sympathies for your loss. Even after all these years I sometimes forget that my own mother will never be coming back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: However, I must call for your aid. The Ixionite occupation of the county of Imbrium has gone on for too long. Now is the time to push back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I know there&#39;s been some problems with Ixion, but I don&#39;t know the details. I guess they&#39;re occupying southern Maree.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know anything about the military. I don&#39;t want to fight.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There must be a peaceful way to settle this. I will send for diplomats from Ixion and try to come to some arrangement.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Thank you, Your Highness.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: If I might say so, you are looking particularly lovely this day. I hope you will think fondly of me.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Is he flirting with me? He&#39;s almost as old as my father!)&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 10&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt; Your skill in Novan History is now 50.  You may not increase this skill until your other History skills are 25 or higher.&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The representative from Ixion is here. Be careful - no one wants to give up prizes that they have won.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: You have the full support of my sister and myself, Your Highness.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: Hmph. Let&#39;s get this over with.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Hellas and Maree are neighboring duchies. Together, the siblings Brin and Banion govern most of Southern Nova.)&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Your Royal Highness, thank you for granting me this audience. I am sure we can come to an amicable agreement.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Let bygones be bygones, no? We will forget about your unprovoked attacks on us, and you will transfer the rights to this little province.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: We can be good neighbors again, without any lives being lost.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Surrender Province] [Offer him money if Ixion withdraws] [Bluff / Intimidate] [Execute him] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Bluff / Intimidate&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You are trespassing on our lands. You will withdraw your troops at once. Only then will we have peace.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Threaten to attack] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Threaten to attack&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: My soldiers are poised to destroy you. Withdraw now.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Then I&#39;m very sorry we were not able to come to an agreement.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I guess now we have to fight.)&lt;br/&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 11&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You receive a report on the outcome of the battle against the Ixionites.&lt;br/&gt; You succeeded in driving them out of Maree, but it cost you almost a full battalion of soldiers and a great deal of materiel.&lt;br/&gt; You lost 1032 soldiers.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: The Duke of Maree will be happy, but we could have done better!&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 12&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a woman here to see you. She wishes Crown funding for a project.&lt;br/&gt;Woman: Thank you for seeing me, Your Royal Highness. I... I come to you on behalf of the people.&lt;br/&gt;Woman: I wish to build a hospital where any citizen afflicted with disease can be brought for treatment.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Putting all the sick people together? Wouldn&#39;t that make them die even faster?)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 13&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You are requested to stand in judgement. A woman has been convicted of attempted murder and requests the mercy of the Crown.&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Your Highness! This slattern dares to beg pardon, when she &lt;b&gt;admits&lt;/b&gt; that she tried to poison my sister under her own roof!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Which sister?&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Corisande, the Duchess of Mead.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (His other full-sister is the wife of the Duke of Kigal, and his mother is the Duchess of Lillah. Family ties are complicated.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Is she all right?&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: She is unharmed. We caught the culprit in the kitchens before anyone could eat her foul spew.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Well, what do you have to say for yourself?&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: It&#39;s justice, it is! Them devils killed me brother, and broke me mam&#39;s heart.&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: Lied to her, they did, when she went to see why he&#39;d not come back. Said he&#39;d gone for a soldier, when he never would!&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: He weren&#39;t the only one neither. I waited ten years for my chance to get my own back. That&#39;s justice!&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: You see? She&#39;s completely unrepentant! Hang her and be done with it.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know what this is all about. Either way, murder is a serious crime, but...)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Put her to work] [Imprison her] [Execute her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Put her to work&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This woman failed in her goals. She harmed no one. I do not require her life.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: If she is kept far away from your sister&#39;s court, she will no longer be a threat.&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: You&#39;re going to &lt;b&gt;forgive&lt;/b&gt; her?!?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I&#39;m indenturing her, not pardoning her. She will serve as a heavy laborer in northern Ursul.&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: She should be made an example of! She should be drawn and quartered in a public square!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I have spoken!&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: Gods bless you, miss!&lt;br/&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the history outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 14&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Dance in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; As you are walking one day in the gardens, you hear a strange sound and look up to see an owl flying overhead. A single dry leaf flutters in its talons.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s funny, I thought owls were nocturnal. I guess I was wrong.)&lt;br/&gt; When you return to the castle, your father is waiting for you.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There are reports that a keythong has been sighted leaving the Old Forest.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s a keythong?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: A beast with the body of an enormous golden cat, a sharp beak, and spikes on its back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Eek!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Several disappearances in southern Caloris are already thought to be the work of this creature.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do we do? Should we send hunters?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The traditional policy on stray beasts is to hope that they return to the forest and stay there.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Hunters are no match for such creatures. You would only make it angry and waste more lives.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: So... we just let it eat people?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Everyone dies in the end.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br/&gt; A walk in the fresh air helps you forget the burdens on your shoulders.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 15&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Dance in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Flattery in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember that the Festival of the Good Lady is approaching.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There will be public celebrations for the commoners, followed by a grand gala for the nobility.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A grand ball... There will be dancing.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As Queen, you would be expected to lead the procession and take part in the ceremonial planting, possibly give a speech.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: However, since you are not yet crowned, it is not required, and it may not be safe to expose you to the public.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you mean, not safe?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Outside of the castle, you are less well protected. If anyone means you harm... Think on it now, decide later.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a letter for you as well.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s from Briony! I went to school with her, but she&#39;s a couple years older than me. Her mother is the Duchess of Mead.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s complaining that her mother still won&#39;t let her come home for the holidays.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Apparently her uncle Kevan is absolutely furious about that woman&#39;s trial.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s bored and looking for an adventure. Well, I don&#39;t have any to suggest to her!)&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 16&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Flexibility in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Today is the procession and planting for the Festival of the Good Lady. Will you be leading the parade?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: If you have any concerns about your safety, please, stay here.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The people will recover from disappointment; if we lose you, there is no recovery.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [I will lead the parade] [I will parade and make a speech] [I would rather not go] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I will parade and make a speech&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I&#39;m not afraid. I&#39;m going to be the best parade-leader ever!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: My little girl.&lt;br/&gt; You prepare your best gown for the occasion, then walk slowly through the town with your attendants. It would not be appropriate for you to wear a sword, but you do walk with a sturdy golden scepter that&#39;s taller than you are.&lt;br/&gt; At the end of the route, you help the priestesses turn over the earth for the new tree to be planted.&lt;br/&gt; After the blessings are read, you hold up your hands and call for silence so that you can speak.&lt;br/&gt; Unfortunately, all the words you had planned go out of your head when you&#39;re faced with the moment.&lt;br/&gt; You manage a few polite sayings about the meaning of the holidays and thank everyone for attending, then turn away, your cheeks red.&lt;br/&gt; The procession regroups to return to the castle.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 17&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Flexibility in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Are you ready for the grand ball?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: All the nobles in the domain are here to see you - to see their queen.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (gulp!)&lt;br/&gt; You finish dressing and descend the stairs to make a grand entrance.&lt;br/&gt; All around, the rich and powerful pause in their activities to gaze upon you, the ruler of them all.&lt;br/&gt; Seeing yourself reflected in so many eyes makes you want to run away and hide.&lt;br/&gt; After a moment, you force yourself to carry on, but you&#39;re sure they&#39;ve all seen you hesitate.&lt;br/&gt; Your father waits for you at the bottom of the stairs and offers you his arm.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The first dance is for us.&lt;br/&gt; He guides you gently around the dance floor, never rushing you. It&#39;s fun to dance with your father, but the look in his eyes is so sad.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: After this, you must choose your own partner. There are a number of men who hope to catch your eye.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The Duke of Kigal alone has brought three eligible sons, all near your age.&lt;br/&gt; You look around the room at all your possible partners - which is to say, everyone. No one may begin dancing until you do. You can pick whomever you want and you will not be denied.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Someone about your age] [Someone younger than you] [Someone older than you] [Someone already married] [Someone scandalous] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Someone older than you&lt;br/&gt; You look around for a likely candidate, and your eye settles on Chaine, the Earl of Mima. He&#39;s almost ten years older than you are and quite good-looking, so why not enjoy yourself?&lt;br/&gt; He smiles brightly at your approach and you begin to dance.&lt;br/&gt; Dancing with a real partner feels quite different from dancing with your father. You knew him, knew his steps like a part of you. Now every move is a mystery.&lt;br/&gt; Unfortunately, you lose track of which steps you&#39;re supposed to do when, and trip over your own feet. Oops!&lt;br/&gt; Between the dances, there is time for the guests to mingle, chat, and sample tiny bites of exquisite food.&lt;br/&gt; During a lull in the music, Banion, the duke of Maree, taps an elegant fingernail against a wineglass, letting the clear note ring out through the room.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: If I might have your attention?&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: I believe we should offer our compliments to our lovely hostess.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Her bravery and courage keep our borders defended.&lt;br/&gt; Everyone applauds politely.&lt;br/&gt; As the gala continues, you take the opportunity to observe nobles that you rarely see.&lt;br/&gt; There&#39;s Gwenelle, for instance - the Young Lady of Sudbury, only months older than you and due to finally inherit control of her duchy soon.&lt;br/&gt; Or Adele, the youngest daughter of the Duchess of Lillah and a fierce sportswoman. She was a few years ahead of you at school and the absolute terror of the ballfields.&lt;br/&gt; No Briony - she had said her parents were leaving her stuck at school this season.&lt;br/&gt; Her parents are here, dancing together - the Duke-Consort clutching his Duchess possessively tight.&lt;br/&gt; Strange that there&#39;s no sign of your cousins, though. Shouldn&#39;t they be here?&lt;br/&gt; Your aunt and uncle &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; here, of course. It would be scandalous if they hadn&#39;t come, Merva being so close by.&lt;br/&gt; It&#39;s nice to be able to enjoy time with friends and family, isn&#39;t it?&lt;br/&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the agility outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 18&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Trade in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You wander downstairs to visit your father and talk about the latest events in the domain.&lt;br/&gt; You&#39;re moving with such enthusiasm that you don&#39;t realise your father isn&#39;t alone until it&#39;s too late to avoid him and his... companion.&lt;br/&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: You are too kind, Joslyn.&lt;br/&gt; Countess Sirin. &lt;i&gt;Not&lt;/i&gt; a member of your circles - she&#39;s a bit more than a decade your senior, far too old to have ever been your friend. And yet, not at all old, as noblewomen go.&lt;br/&gt; She has two minor titles, no husband, and &lt;i&gt;your father&#39;s arm in her grasp.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt; How &lt;i&gt;dare&lt;/i&gt; she make a move on your father?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Shame her with silent scorn] [Insult her with false flattery] [Trip her as she passes] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Insult her with false flattery&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Good afternoon, Countess.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: My, what large breasts you have. Putting them on display for any particular reason?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Elodie!&lt;br/&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: Really, my dear, it&#39;s not polite to comment on a lady&#39;s attributes like that.&lt;br/&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: But you are young. You will... grow.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Ooo!&lt;br/&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: Perhaps we&#39;ll be seeing more of each other in the future.&lt;br/&gt; She gives a little wave and exits.&lt;br/&gt; Once she&#39;s gone, you raise an eyebrow at your father.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Don&#39;t give me that look, young lady. She&#39;s a nice woman, nothing more.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wants something more!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: And it&#39;s not going to happen any time soon.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You should be careful how you deal with people like Sirin. You need the goodwill of your nobles as well as your commoners.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There haven&#39;t been any problems so far.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Many dark looks were aimed your way at the gala.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As Queen, you must be aware of everything around you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Isn&#39;t that what I have agents for?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Yes, but you must give them direction. What is your greatest concern?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Noble plots] [Commoner uprisings] [Foreign threats] [Assassins] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Noble plots&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I need to know what the other nobles are up to, and whether anyone is plotting behind my back.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 19&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: It is the time of year to decide any necessary adjustments to the royal budget.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The majority of the money we receive is already spoken for, but there is always some room for discretion.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I really don&#39;t understand all of these numbers. Maybe I should leave them alone.)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Raise taxes] [Keep them the same] [Lower taxes] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Keep them the same&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I think they&#39;re fine as they are.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 20&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You are requested to stand in judgement. A man has been convicted of the murder-by-strangling of his wife.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: He does not deny the act, but requests a pardon that he might be set free.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: If you admit you killed your wife, why do you think I&#39;m going to set you free?&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Man: Save me, Your Majesty! Wasn&#39;t my fault. &lt;i&gt;Demons&lt;/i&gt; made me do it.&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Man: Everyone knows the power of magical beasties! They used me, they twisted my fingers into chains...&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Man: My wife found me screaming, she tried to shake me, and the chains wrapped around her...&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Man: I need the priestesses to bless me and make me clean again!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Demons that make you attack people? Is that even possible?)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Pardon him] [Imprison him] [Execute him] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Imprison him&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Whether there were demons or not, you still killed a woman - your &lt;i&gt;wife.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I won&#39;t forgive you for that. You will be imprisoned for the rest of your life.&lt;br/&gt; He opens his mouth to argue with you further, but then his shoulders slump.&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Man: Yes, Your Majesty.&lt;br/&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the intrigue outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 21&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You receive word that the murderer you condemned to prison has escaped. A large explosion rocked the jail he was in, destroying the walls and setting many dangerous criminals free.&lt;br/&gt; It will now fall to the Royal Treasury to repair the damage.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 22&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I regret to inform you that Fabian, the Earl of Titan and Duke-Regent of Elath, has passed away.&lt;br/&gt; This isn&#39;t really a surprise; he was pretty old. The problem is the political implications.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: With the control of Elath in doubt, it falls to the crown to make decisions.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Young Lord Adair will not reach his fifteenth birthday for over two years. He requires a regent.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: His stepmother, Arisse, the Duchess of Lillah, has petitioned that the boy be left in her care.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: This would, however, leave her in personal control of two neighboring duchies, which is generally forbidden.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Not to mention that she&#39;s closely related to the Duchess of Mead and the Duke of Kigal!)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She could control almost the entire eastern half of Nova. People already call her Nova&#39;s other queen!)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Duchess Arisse almost certainly killed her second husband after she divorced him.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Her son, the Earl of Io, apparently hates and fears her.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (But without proof, she couldn&#39;t be punished.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The boy does have a living grandfather, the Earl of Ishtar. Or you might appoint an unrelated noble to act in his stead.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The Earl of Ishtar has suggested another possibility. You and Adair are both young, not too far apart in age.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: He requests that we accept the boy as your future husband and keep him here at the castle.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Leave him with Arisse] [Send him to his grandfather] [Marry him] [Send him to your uncle] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Send him to your uncle&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What about your brother Armand? He would be a safe pair of hands to watch over Adair.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br/&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 23&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a woman here to see you. She is a musician and wishes Crown patronage.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Which means money.)&lt;br/&gt;Sabine: Your Royal Highness! If you accept me as a member of your court I will immortalise you in word and song.&lt;br/&gt;Sabine: I have dabbled in musical styles from many countries, and can entertain your guests and lighten your evenings.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Musicians are often used as secret agents and messengers. They can be useful - and dangerous.)&lt;br/&gt; The musician sings a little ditty to demonstrate her skills with the lute.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s actually pretty good.)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Accept her as Court Musician] [Reject her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Accept her as Court Musician&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Very well, you can remain as part of the court.&lt;br/&gt;Sabine: I will do my best for you!&lt;br/&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 24&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You receive a letter from Young Lord Adair.&lt;br/&gt; So far, he&#39;s enjoying himself with your uncle Armand in Mazomba. He says the trees look different, and there are a lot more frogs. He looks forward to visiting the lookout fort at Shepherd&#39;s Point.&lt;br/&gt; You also receive an update from your agents. It would seem that the Duchess of Lillah is not pleased with your actions and is putting out feelers amongst the other nobles for support.&lt;br/&gt; If she means to rebel against you, that is treason. Unfortunately, she&#39;s a long way away, in her own power base. Calling her to order may not be easy.&lt;br/&gt; Still, the longer you wait, the more dangerous she may become.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Send soldiers to arrest her] [Send assassins to kill her] [Wait for more information] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Send assassins to kill her&lt;br/&gt; You give orders for assassins to arrange for a quiet and natural-looking demise. She is not a young woman, and she&#39;s just lost her husband... it shouldn&#39;t be suspicious.&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 25&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; Staring up into the sky out your window, you notice a strange flash of light.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A falling star... Pretty!)&lt;br/&gt; You receive word that the Duchess of Lillah has passed away quietly in her sleep.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (At least, that&#39;s what everyone thinks!)&lt;br/&gt; She left her title not to the Earl of Io, but to Kiran, one of her younger sons. He&#39;s 19, and rather handsome as you recall. Everything has turned out for the best.&lt;br/&gt; A walk in the fresh air helps you forget the burdens on your shoulders.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 26&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Naval Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, there is a letter for you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Who sent this? It isn&#39;t signed...)&lt;br/&gt; It appears to be a poem, describing you in a manner that is entirely inappropriate for a Queen.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I *what*? With a *squid*?)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [That&#39;s hilarious!] [That&#39;s terrible!] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: That&#39;s hilarious!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s actually pretty funny!)&lt;br/&gt; Just then, an incredibly unlucky breeze swirls between the windows of your tower bedroom, tugging the paper out of your hands and off into the sky.&lt;br/&gt; You stick your head out the window to discover the &#39;poem&#39; caught and fluttering on the roof nearby. You can &lt;i&gt;almost&lt;/i&gt; reach it.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Climb out and grab it] [Ignore it] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Climb out and grab it&lt;br/&gt; You take a moment to look at where you&#39;ll have to climb in order to reach your target.&lt;br/&gt; It&#39;s so close! You just need to put your foot here, and your hand there, and then reach a little bit more...&lt;br/&gt; ...&lt;br/&gt; ... &lt;b&gt;OW!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt; You&#39;re lucky you didn&#39;t break your neck, but your bruises are going to make it difficult to do anything strenuous for a while.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 27&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, there are letters for you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Another letter from Briony. Why does she keep writing me? We were never even friends.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She says she&#39;s bored and lonely and she&#39;s looking forward to seeing me at Gwenelle&#39;s birthday party.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s right! Gwenelle is about to turn fifteen! She&#39;ll be Duchess of Sudbury for real now.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (This other letter must be my invitation to her birthday celebration next week.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Gwenelle and I were friends at school, and this will be a big event, but it&#39;s also a long way to travel.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A lot of things can happen on the road.)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Go to Sudbury for Gwenelle&#39;s party] [Send your regrets] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Send your regrets&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I&#39;d better stay here.)&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 28&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Naval Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: *sigh*&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (All of my friends are at Gwenelle&#39;s party and I don&#39;t get to go.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I sent Gwenelle a letter saying that I couldn&#39;t come, but it was her mother the Countess who replied.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I think she&#39;s insulted that I didn&#39;t consider the event important enough to attend.)&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the military outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 29&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Alice: The new Duke of Lillah has sent you a gift.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s this?&lt;br/&gt; It&#39;s a cushion, finely embroidered with the design of a running horse. It&#39;s well done, and clearly required hours and hours of needlework, but it&#39;s also fairly useless.&lt;br/&gt; Or is it? You did, after all, have his mother killed. Does he know? Is this cushion meant to send some sort of message? Or is it somehow trapped? Is it a &lt;i&gt;poisoned pillow?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt; You place it across the room from you, far away from your bed, so you can keep an eye on it. Tomorrow you&#39;ll have it quietly destroyed, but for tonight, you won&#39;t be sleeping well.&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt; The game will now attempt to save the log and open it in a web browser.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Continue] [Cancel] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Cancel&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 30&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Alice: The Duchess of Mead is here to see you, my lady.&lt;br/&gt;Corisande, Duchess of Mead: Hello, Elodie. I&#39;m sorry to trouble you, but - have you seen Briony?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No, not since I left school.&lt;br/&gt; She shakes her head.&lt;br/&gt;Corisande, Duchess of Mead: She&#39;s gone missing. She&#39;s not at school where she should be. I know she was unhappy, but I never expected...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wrote me a letter saying that she was bored and looking for adventure, but that&#39;s all I know.&lt;br/&gt;Corisande, Duchess of Mead: Oh, dear.&lt;br/&gt;Corisande, Duchess of Mead: I hope she hasn&#39;t done anything too foolish. My poor little lamb... I have to go look for her.&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: So. Your efforts to access the treasury have not been successful. We still require your crystal.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She said before, if I couldn&#39;t get into the treasury, she might have to kill the guards...)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Keep trying on your own] [Let Selene have her way] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Keep trying on your own&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Don&#39;t worry. I&#39;m working on it. It&#39;ll be fine.&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: As you say.&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the intrigue outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 31&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Flattery in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; As you are walking through the great hall, a freak gust of wind suddenly blows out all the candles in the room.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (An omen of war and danger...)&lt;br/&gt; There&#39;s no sign of where the danger might be coming from, so there&#39;s nothing you can do about it. Perhaps it&#39;s nothing.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the military outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 32&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Strategy in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt; You may now tour the Barracks on the weekends.&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Things have been so unsettled lately... Everyone&#39;s on edge. We need something cheerful.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You could hold a tournament.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What a good idea!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Knights, jousting, musicians... all sorts of competitions. Everyone loves a contest.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: What will you offer as prizes to the winners?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Status and praise] [Employment] [Gold] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Status and praise&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Being declared to be the &lt;i&gt;best&lt;/i&gt; in front of the entire domain should be prize enough for anyone!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Very well. I will draft the announcements.&lt;br/&gt; You leave him to his work.&lt;br/&gt; As you move through the hall, your eye falls upon a vase of flowers. Pretty, but apparently not getting enough water. The leaves on one blossom have shriveled.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A leaf killed by a secret weakness... A hidden threat.)&lt;br/&gt; You continue up the stairs to your room, where a maid is waiting for you.&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, a gift has arrived from Kigal.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: From the Duke?&lt;br/&gt;Alice: No, my lady. A merchant house, I believe. It was sent with a shipment down the Cavalla River.&lt;br/&gt; You tear open the brightly colored paper, to find:&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Chocolates!&lt;br/&gt; There is a little card with the box - &#39;With Our Compliments, The House of Kraellat&#39;.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (There&#39;s something suspicious about this.)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Eat candy now] [Save it for later] [Test for poison] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Test for poison&lt;br/&gt; You can&#39;t think of any safe way to test the chocolate, and you don&#39;t want to leave it lying around where it might present a danger to others.&lt;br/&gt; Eventually you mash the candies together into an unappetising paste and bury the box in the palace garden.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s a waste, if they weren&#39;t really poisoned... My candy...)&lt;br/&gt; You are impressed by the discipline of the Novan troops, but the responsibility for their lives weighs heavily on your shoulders.&lt;br/&gt; There are approximately nine battalions and one platoon under your direct command.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 33&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt; You have nothing more to learn about Internal Affairs.&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; This is the week of the general tournament. Nobles and commoners alike have turned out to compete against each other.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The people will be pleased if you participate in their games. However, it would expose you to danger.&lt;br/&gt; What event do you wish to take part in?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Mounted Parade] [Jousting] [Fencing] [Archery] [Music] [Falconry] [None] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: None&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I guess I&#39;ll just watch from my tower.&lt;br/&gt; The tournament goes on without you.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 34&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, your father wishes to speak with you. He says it&#39;s urgent.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Fine, I&#39;m coming.&lt;br/&gt; You find your father standing over a map of the coastline, his face grave.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Ships have been sighted on approach from Shanjia. Not tradeships - this is a warfleet.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Within a week they will be in Novan waters. Within two they could reach the capital.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Then we will fight to defend ourselves.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You can try to use the treasury funds to hire additional soldiers, but it may be difficult on short notice.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Recruit soldiers] [Don&#39;t] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Recruit soldiers&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Fine, we&#39;ll do that.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You will need to draw up a naval strategy for our ships to carry out.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; choose to act as admiral and lead the fleet in person, but the danger to you would be very great.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Unless you think your personal skills will make the difference, I would strongly advise against it.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Direct the fleet] [Stay in the capital] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Stay in the capital&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No, there&#39;s too much to do here. I can&#39;t go to sea.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Do your best, and Nova will survive.&lt;br/&gt; You are impressed by the discipline of the Novan troops, but the responsibility for their lives weighs heavily on your shoulders.&lt;br/&gt; There are approximately nine battalions, three companies, and two platoons under your direct command.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 35&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; Danger on the high seas!&lt;br/&gt; Ships close in on each other, angling into range.&lt;br/&gt; The Shanjians have half again as many troops as you do. It doesn&#39;t look promising.&lt;br/&gt; The eventual outcome...&lt;br/&gt; ... is not in your favor.&lt;br/&gt; The Novan ships are sunk or scattered, as the Shanjian forces press towards landfall.&lt;br/&gt; Many good soldiers were lost today, and Nova&#39;s troubles have not ended.&lt;br/&gt; Since you have failed to repel the invasion, the Shanjian fleet will soon land and their troops will begin to progress towards your capital city.&lt;br/&gt; Your remaining soldiers will hold them off as long as possible, of course, but the main strength of your military has been exhausted. Nova&#39;s future looks bleak.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 36&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; The invasion of Nova is proceeding. Your coastline is under Shanjian control. Soldiers have marched through villages, trampling fields and frightening citizens.&lt;br/&gt; A diplomatic delegation from Shanjia has requested access to the castle to discuss terms - most likely, for your surrender. You lack the strength to hold off their armies, and surrendering now will save many lives. It would seem that you have no choice.&lt;br/&gt; You prepare yourself as best you can to meet with the representatives from Shanjia.&lt;br/&gt; You expected diplomats and a military representative, a general or an admiral. You did not expect the handsome man decked in jewels who now stands before you - a man announced by your servants as Togami, King of Shanjia.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Is he really their King? Why would a king come all the way here?)&lt;br/&gt;Togami: My dear young lady. How difficult this must be for you. So much responsibility at such a tender age.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Don&#39;t pretend to be my friend while you&#39;re killing my people!&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Temper, temper, Princess. After all, I am here to &lt;i&gt;save&lt;/i&gt; your people.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: War benefits no one, don&#39;t you think? Such a terrible waste. Better to settle things in a civilised manner.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: A contest. A game, so to speak, with Nova as the stakes.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Should I win, then your domain will submit and accept me as Overlord with no further resistance.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Should I lose, then my army will leave your domain in peace and shed no more blood.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What sort of game?&lt;br/&gt;Togami: It is well known that Nova is ruled by Lumens. As it happens, I too possess the powers of a Lumen.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: I propose a formal duel. My powers against yours. The winner takes control of Nova, the loser... dies.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But I&#39;m not a Lumen!&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Saving it for the coronation, were you? Such a pity that you&#39;ll be unprepared.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Well, then. Go and find your crystal. Becoming a Lumen is a very simple matter. Then we can have our duel.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s the point? You know I can&#39;t win. Why don&#39;t you just kill me now?&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Because that&#39;s not the game. You want to save your people, don&#39;t you? I want to fight a Lumen.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: If you refuse, then the war will continue.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: I&#39;ll sweeten the deal. If you meet me in a formal Lumen challenge, I&#39;ll call off the invasion even if I win.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Really?&lt;br/&gt;Togami: I swear it by the gods. Nova will be free and safe.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Why take that risk? You&#39;re winning the war.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: It&#39;s not your land that I want. It&#39;s your crystal.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: To gain your power, I am willing to wager my own. Shall we begin?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t like this... But what choice do I have?)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Accept his terms] [Offer marriage alliance] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Offer marriage alliance&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What if I marry you instead? Then everything I have is yours as well!&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Silly little girl. I already told you. Your land isn&#39;t what matters to me.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: And I already have a wife - a woman far riper than you.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Accept his terms] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Accept his terms&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Then... I must.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No! Not my little girl!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You want to fight the Lumen ruler of Nova?&lt;br/&gt; Your father reaches into his pocket and pulls out a shimmering blue crystal, which he places over his heart.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: &lt;i&gt;Illuminate!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Your hair stands on end as a veil of blue sparkles settles over your father, crawling into his skin. When it&#39;s over, the jewel has been absorbed into his body without a trace.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Fight me. Leave her alone.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Well! This is not what I expected, but it will serve my purposes just as well.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Daddy?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Be quiet, Elodie. You are &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a Queen yet.&lt;br/&gt; You are forced to sit and watch as the two men work out the details of the duel and its stakes, then take their places in a carefully warded circle.&lt;br/&gt; Your father crosses his arms, summoning up a thick gray fog that swirls around him, hiding him from view. But the Shanjian king conjures a cloud of glowing butterflies which drive into the fog and blow it apart.&lt;br/&gt; Then the invader claps his hands together and chants. Fiery red lights cluster over his fingertips and merge together into a pulsing blob before erupting towards your father. He resists with a beam of blue, catching the infernal energy and pushing it back in Togami&#39;s direction.&lt;br/&gt; You knew what the outcome would be, you knew it all along. Togami is a trained Lumen eager to demonstrate his powers, and your father...&lt;br/&gt; ... was your father.&lt;br/&gt; The blue crystal reappears, lying beside your father&#39;s body like an innocently-discarded bauble - but now that blue color is colored by a faint wash of red.&lt;br/&gt; The smirking King of Shanjia sweeps the crystal off the floor and tucks it away into his robes.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: How fitting. First I end your mother&#39;s life and then your father&#39;s.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You what?&lt;br/&gt;Togami: You didn&#39;t think her death was an accident, did you? That took careful planning!&lt;br/&gt;Togami: And now the Novan power is mine, and you even get to live.&lt;br/&gt; He holds out a hand in front of him, the elegant robe dangling freely.&lt;br/&gt;Togami: Now kneel and kiss my hand.&lt;br/&gt; Never. Not in a thousand years.&lt;br/&gt; With a scream, you launch yourself at the Shanjian king, prepared to go down fighting.&lt;br/&gt; Of course, it takes only a touch of his magic to end your life.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie did not survive to reach her coronation.  Nova would have to go on without her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&#39;t have to end this way.  Make different choices, train different skills, and Elodie&#39;s star may rise again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Live the Queen: Attempt 3 (Blind)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-3-Blind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 14:32:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-3-Blind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: We&#39;re almost home. Your room is just the way you left it.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I know it&#39;s hard to leave your school and all your friends, but I&#39;ve arranged the best possible tutors for every subject.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll have to work hard this year to prepare yourself before your fifteenth birthday, but I know you can do it.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll learn quickly and you&#39;ll make a wonderful queen. It&#39;s what your mother would have wanted.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is not what Mother would have wanted!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wouldn&#39;t have wanted to die and leave me.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No. She wouldn&#39;t. But sometimes bad things happen. We have to pick up and carry on.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: All of Nova depends on us. On you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I will be here to guide you until your coronation, but the decisions you make are ultimately up to you.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Come. Your maids are waiting.&lt;br/&gt; Welcome to &lt;b&gt;Long Live The Queen!&lt;/b&gt; If this is your first time playing, you should read this brief introduction to how the game works.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Tell me more] [I&#39;ve played this before] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I&#39;ve played this before&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Week 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Studied Composure in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s all that noise outside? Who&#39;s here?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! It&#39;s my cousins! And my aunt and uncle.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: Darling. We were so terribly sorry to hear about your mother Fidelia.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br/&gt;Laurent, Duke of Merva: You look well, niece.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Hi, &#39;Lodie!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Hi, Lottie. I haven&#39;t seen you in ages! Will you be staying long?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Yup! Mummy said we&#39;d be here all month.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Maybe we&#39;ll have some time to talk later.&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 2&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Composure in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s that commotion outside? Father? What&#39;s going on?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I have come to pay my respects in honor of your mother.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You have no respect or honor. It&#39;s because of you and your powers that my wife is dead!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?!?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I am a Lumen, as was she, and like every Lumen I am willing to give my life if necessary to protect our domain. &lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Your line has been traitors for two hundred years. I won&#39;t have you corrupting my daughter.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: That is for the Crown Princess to decide.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Elodie, your mother trusted me, and I have much to teach you.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Send her away] [Arrest her] [Let her stay] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Arrest her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You are a traitor to the crown and I ought to have you executed.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: GUARDS! Arrest her!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Throw her into the castle dungeons and let her rot!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Well. I suppose she won&#39;t be a problem anymore.&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 3&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You may now play Sports on the weekends.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: He loves me, he loves me not...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Lottie, do you have a boyfriend?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Not really. I just like to play with the flowers.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Me too.&lt;br/&gt; You gather your skirts and prepare to sit down, when all of a sudden, a hissing noise alerts you to a hidden danger - a snake!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Charlotte, don&#39;t move!&lt;br/&gt; With your quick reflexes, you grab a forked stick and manage to flip the snake away from you and your cousin.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: EEEEEK!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Get away, you horrible thing!&lt;br/&gt; You stomp loudly on the ground, and the snake slithers off into the distance.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: What is going on out here?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Mummy, there was a snake!&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: What was a snake doing in the royal gardens? This is completely unacceptable. You could have been killed!&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Elodie scared it off.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: That&#39;s not good enough. I can&#39;t have my daughter remaining in such a dangerous place! We are returning home to Merva at once.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Awww....&lt;br/&gt; You venture into the depths of the castle dungeons.&lt;br/&gt; The Duchess of Ursul is there, in her cell, sitting perfectly straight on the bench against the wall and looking your direction as if she&#39;d been expecting you.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Caution is wise for one in your position. Hasty judgments can lead to trouble.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Are you ready to listen now?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Hear her out] [Taunt her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Taunt her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Having fun in here? Are the rats being good company? Because you&#39;re &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; leaving.&lt;br/&gt; You flick your fingernail against the metal bars to remind her of her place.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Eek!&lt;br/&gt; For a moment, the ground seemed to tremble. Was that an earthquake?&lt;br/&gt; You&#39;re not sure, but you think you&#39;d rather not be in the dungeons right now.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 4&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Composure in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: The castle seems quieter with Charlotte and Emry and Zahra and their parents gone.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s certainly not empty, though. It seems like we get more servants every day.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 5&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Herbs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; One of the maids approaches for your attention.&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, couriers have arrived from the Duke of Sedna.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We have a Duke of Sedna?&lt;br/&gt;Alice: ... No, my Lady. The duchy of Sedna is in Talasse.&lt;br/&gt;Alice: They have brought you a letter, and a gift.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &#39;Condolences on the death of&#39;, &#39;deeply regret&#39;, &#39;best wishes&#39;...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! What a beautiful necklace!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It might not be appropriate for me to wear a man&#39;s gift in public, though. People would think it meant something.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Wear it] [Don&#39;t wear it] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Don&#39;t wear it&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s important to maintain the proper image.&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 6&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Battlefield Medicine in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That woman, the priestess, keeps staring at me.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you want?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: Your destiny will find you, even if you run from it. You were born to wield the power of a Lumen.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you know about that?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: The power was your mother&#39;s, and the kings and queens before her. It is your right and your responsibility to defend your domain.&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: I have seen signs of the future. Danger is coming. Without that power, this land is defenseless.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Well... What am I supposed to do about it?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: The Duchess of Ursul will teach you, if you set her free.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But -&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: She never harmed your mother. They were friends. It is only because she bears the power of a Lumen so openly that your father rejects her.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [I will free her] [I won&#39;t free her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I won&#39;t free her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is all a trick to get the traitor released. I won&#39;t listen to you!&lt;br/&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 7&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; As you are walking up the stairs, a maid comes running down holding a towering pile of linen.&lt;br/&gt; You swiftly step aside and let her pass.&lt;br/&gt; You return to your rooms, but you have barely settled when someone knocks on the door.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: A visiting noble wishes to speak with you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt; Who is it?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The Duke Consort of Mead.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (If I remember right, he&#39;s the brother of the Duchess of Ursul.)&lt;br/&gt; You follow your father downstairs to greet your guest.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: Your Highness. Thank you for meeting with me in this difficult time.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: I come to you on behalf of the people of Ursul, who have been left without a protector.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: Commoners require governance and leadership, or they fall into chaos.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You want me to free your sister the Duchess?&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: I wish for Ursul to have a leader. If my sister has displeased you, then I stand willing to serve.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: If you prefer Julianna in that position, then yes, free her. It is, of course, your decision.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Free Duchess Julianna] [Give her title to Ignatius] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Give her title to Ignatius&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Fine, then. &lt;b&gt;You&lt;/b&gt; can be Duke of Ursul.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke of Ursul: On behalf of our people, I thank you for your wisdom.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Now I can leave Julianna locked up forever and no one will care!)&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 8&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a man here to see you. He wishes Crown funding for a project of his.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember, the treasury is not unlimited. If you choose to invest, you will have less money to work with later.&lt;br/&gt;Man: Your Royal Highness, I have a plan to print books using metal letters which can be moved and reused.&lt;br/&gt;Man: I need to borrow 875 lassi to assemble the metal and a factory to mold and cast the type.&lt;br/&gt;Man: With this system, we will be able to create new books in a fraction of the time it takes now, and make copies to send all over the world.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know much about factories or trade. Would that really be worthwhile?)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 9&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Herbs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Battlefield Medicine in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, my sympathies for your loss. Even after all these years I sometimes forget that my own mother will never be coming back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: However, I must call for your aid. The Ixionite occupation of the county of Imbrium has gone on for too long. Now is the time to push back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I know there&#39;s been some problems with Ixion, but I don&#39;t know the details. I guess they&#39;re occupying southern Maree.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know anything about the military. I don&#39;t want to fight.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There must be a peaceful way to settle this. I will send for diplomats from Ixion and try to come to some arrangement.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Thank you, Your Highness.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: If I might say so, you are looking particularly lovely this day. I hope you will think fondly of me.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Is he flirting with me? He&#39;s almost as old as my father!)&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 10&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The representative from Ixion is here. Be careful - no one wants to give up prizes that they have won.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: You have the full support of my sister and myself, Your Highness.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: Hmph. Let&#39;s get this over with.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Hellas and Maree are neighboring duchies. Together, the siblings Brin and Banion govern most of Southern Nova.)&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Your Royal Highness, thank you for granting me this audience. I am sure we can come to an amicable agreement.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Let bygones be bygones, no? We will forget about your unprovoked attacks on us, and you will transfer the rights to this little province.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It was the Duchess of Hellas who tried to take over part of Ixion&#39;s territory, without the support of my mother the Queen.)&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: We can be good neighbors again, without any lives being lost.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Surrender Province] [Offer him money if Ixion withdraws] [Offer to punish the Duchess of Hellas] [Bluff / Intimidate] [Execute him] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Offer to punish the Duchess of Hellas&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We appreciate that you feel wronged. One of our subjects attempted to instigate a rebellion in your territory.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: However, she did not have our approval for these actions. If you withdraw your troops, we will punish her.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: Your Highness!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is the fair solution. You have no right to invade us because of her actions.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: What manner of punishment were you considering?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Make her a commoner] [Command her to marry an Ixionite] [Execute her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Make her a commoner&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She will be stripped of her titles and forced to live as one of the common people.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, I must protest!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No one will be allowed to benefit from sneaky attempts at stealing land. Not Hellas and not Ixion. Nobody.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Very well. We will accept this apology.&lt;br/&gt;Brin: This is outrageous!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Out!&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;(Put on the history outfit.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 11&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Dance in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Herbs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There are reports that a keythong has been sighted leaving the Old Forest.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s a keythong?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: A beast with the body of an enormous golden cat, a sharp beak, and spikes on its back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Eek!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Several disappearances in southern Caloris are already thought to be the work of this creature.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do we do? Should we send hunters?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The traditional policy on stray beasts is to hope that they return to the forest and stay there.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Hunters are no match for such creatures. You would only make it angry and waste more lives.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: So... we just let it eat people?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Everyone dies in the end.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br/&gt; You go down to the dungeons to taunt Julianna with her helplessness and lack of noble status.&lt;br/&gt; However, when you approach her cell, you find her sitting cross-legged with her eyes closed, paying absolutely no attention to you.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Taunt her anyway] [Execute her] [Leave her alone.] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Execute her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You think you can ignore me?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: GUARDS!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Go in there and get your swords ready.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Cut her head off. Right now.&lt;br/&gt; Julianna&#39;s eyes snap open, staring at you. But it doesn&#39;t matter, because there&#39;s nothing she can do. She&#39;s a helpless prisoner.&lt;br/&gt; ... Right?&lt;br/&gt; What&#39;s that light heading towards you?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie did not survive to reach her coronation.  Nova would have to go on without her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&#39;t have to end this way.  Make different choices, train different skills, and Elodie&#39;s star may rise again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Live the Queen: Attempt 2 (Blind)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-2-Blind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 14:00:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-2-Blind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: We&#39;re almost home. Your room is just the way you left it.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I know it&#39;s hard to leave your school and all your friends, but I&#39;ve arranged the best possible tutors for every subject.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll have to work hard this year to prepare yourself before your fifteenth birthday, but I know you can do it.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll learn quickly and you&#39;ll make a wonderful queen. It&#39;s what your mother would have wanted.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is not what Mother would have wanted!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wouldn&#39;t have wanted to die and leave me.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No. She wouldn&#39;t. But sometimes bad things happen. We have to pick up and carry on.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: All of Nova depends on us. On you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I will be here to guide you until your coronation, but the decisions you make are ultimately up to you.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Come. Your maids are waiting.&lt;br/&gt; Welcome to &lt;b&gt;Long Live The Queen!&lt;/b&gt; If this is your first time playing, you should read this brief introduction to how the game works.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Tell me more] [I&#39;ve played this before] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I&#39;ve played this before&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Week 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Studied Novan History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s all that noise outside? Who&#39;s here?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! It&#39;s my cousins! And my aunt and uncle.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: Darling. We were so terribly sorry to hear about your mother Fidelia.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br/&gt;Laurent, Duke of Merva: You look well, niece.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Hi, &#39;Lodie!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Hi, Lottie. I haven&#39;t seen you in ages! Will you be staying long?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Yup! Mummy said we&#39;d be here all month.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Maybe we&#39;ll have some time to talk later.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Dad? Can we talk?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I&#39;m sorry. Your uncle and I have things to do. Maybe another time.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 2&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s that commotion outside? Father? What&#39;s going on?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I have come to pay my respects in honor of your mother.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You have no respect or honor. It&#39;s because of you and your powers that my wife is dead!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?!?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I am a Lumen, as was she, and like every Lumen I am willing to give my life if necessary to protect our domain. &lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Your line has been traitors for two hundred years. I won&#39;t have you corrupting my daughter.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: That is for the Crown Princess to decide.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Elodie, your mother trusted me, and I have much to teach you.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Send her away] [Arrest her] [Let her stay] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Arrest her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You are a traitor to the crown and I ought to have you executed.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: GUARDS! Arrest her!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Throw her into the castle dungeons and let her rot!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Well. I suppose she won&#39;t be a problem anymore.&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 3&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: He loves me, he loves me not...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Lottie, do you have a boyfriend?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Not really. I just like to play with the flowers.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Me too.&lt;br/&gt; You gather your skirts and prepare to sit down, when all of a sudden, a hissing noise alerts you to a hidden danger - a snake!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Charlotte, don&#39;t move!&lt;br/&gt; You grab for a stick to push the snake away, but you lack the skills to do the job properly, and poking the snake only makes it angry. Too fast to see, it lunges forward and sinks its fangs into your leg!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: OW!&lt;br/&gt; The snake slithers away, but it&#39;s too late now. A strange tingling sensation begins to spread through your flesh.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: That&#39;s a milk viper. They&#39;re poisonous!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I don&#39;t feel good.&lt;br/&gt; Your leg is going numb. You stumble and fall to the ground.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Hold on!&lt;br/&gt; Your cousin kneels beside you and presses her hands over the bite mark. The area throbs painfully, then begins to feel warm.&lt;br/&gt; After a minute, you&#39;re dizzy, but your leg isn&#39;t buzzing anymore, and even the wound has disappeared.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: How did you do that?&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: I don&#39;t know how I do it. I just can.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: I&#39;m not supposed to tell anybody. People think it&#39;s freaky. You won&#39;t tell, will you?&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Of course not. I&#39;m just lucky you were here.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: Girls? What&#39;s going on out here? I heard yelling.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Nothing!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We saw a snake, but it got away.&lt;br/&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: A snake! That&#39;s it. Charlotte, pack your things. We&#39;re going back to Merva. It&#39;s not safe here.&lt;br/&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Awww...&lt;br/&gt; You venture into the depths of the castle dungeons.&lt;br/&gt; The Duchess of Ursul is there, in her cell, sitting perfectly straight on the bench against the wall and looking your direction as if she&#39;d been expecting you.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Caution is wise for one in your position. Hasty judgments can lead to trouble.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Are you ready to listen now?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Hear her out] [Taunt her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Hear her out&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you want to say?&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: It is the responsibility of the king or queen of Nova to handle magical energies to protect the domain.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: That is what a Lumen does - what your mother did, and what I do.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: My father said it was your fault she died!&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: What he said was that she died by magic. Being a Lumen is never &lt;i&gt;safe.&lt;/i&gt; We pay a high price for our powers.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: But without a Lumen queen, this entire domain is at risk.&lt;br/&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Release me, and I will teach you what you need to know to keep your responsibilities.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Free her] [Refuse] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Refuse&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You don&#39;t tell me what to do. I&#39;m the Queen!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You can starve in here for all I care.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 4&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: The castle seems quieter with Charlotte and Emry and Zahra and their parents gone.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s certainly not empty, though. It seems like we get more servants every day.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 5&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; One of the maids approaches for your attention.&lt;br/&gt;Alice: My lady, couriers have arrived from the Duke of Sedna.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Sedna, that&#39;s in Talasse, the domain to our southeast.)&lt;br/&gt;Alice: They have brought you a letter, and a gift.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &#39;Condolences on the death of&#39;, &#39;deeply regret&#39;, &#39;best wishes&#39;...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! What a beautiful necklace!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It might not be appropriate for me to wear a man&#39;s gift in public, though. People would think it meant something.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Wear it] [Don&#39;t wear it] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Don&#39;t wear it&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s important to maintain the proper image.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Dad? What really happened to Mom?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: She was a Lumen, a magic-user. It was meant to be in reserve, to defend our domain, but she insisted on...&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: ... you don&#39;t need to hear that.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: She used magic. It drained her strength. She thought it was harmless, and it wasn&#39;t. Eventually, her heart just... stopped.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: That&#39;s why I don&#39;t want you involved with it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 6&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Public Speaking in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That woman, the priestess, keeps staring at me.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you want?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: Your destiny will find you, even if you run from it. You were born to wield the power of a Lumen.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you know about that?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: The power was your mother&#39;s, and the kings and queens before her. It is your right and your responsibility to defend your domain.&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: I have seen signs of the future. Danger is coming. Without that power, this land is defenseless.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Well... What am I supposed to do about it?&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: The Duchess of Ursul will teach you, if you set her free.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But -&lt;br/&gt;Selene, Priestess of the Second Circle: She never harmed your mother. They were friends. It is only because she bears the power of a Lumen so openly that your father rejects her.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [I will free her] [I won&#39;t free her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I won&#39;t free her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is all a trick to get the traitor released. I won&#39;t listen to you!&lt;br/&gt; You sneak a peek at some of the luckless peasants held in the dungeons - petty thieves and troublemakers, now suffering in the dark. They&#39;re obviously bad people, but seeing them so miserable still feels unfair. There must be a better way.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 7&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Herbs in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; As you are walking up the stairs, a maid comes running down holding a towering pile of linen.&lt;br/&gt; You swiftly step aside and let her pass.&lt;br/&gt; You return to your rooms, but you have barely settled when someone knocks on the door.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: A visiting noble wishes to speak with you.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt; Who is it?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The Duke Consort of Mead.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (If I remember right, he&#39;s the brother of the Duchess of Ursul.)&lt;br/&gt; You follow your father downstairs to greet your guest.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: Your Highness. Thank you for meeting with me in this difficult time.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: I come to you on behalf of the people of Ursul, who have been left without a protector.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: Commoners require governance and leadership, or they fall into chaos.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You want me to free your sister the Duchess?&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: I wish for Ursul to have a leader. If my sister has displeased you, then I stand willing to serve.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke Consort of Mead: If you prefer Julianna in that position, then yes, free her. It is, of course, your decision.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Free Duchess Julianna] [Give her title to Ignatius] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Give her title to Ignatius&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Fine, then. &lt;b&gt;You&lt;/b&gt; can be Duke of Ursul.&lt;br/&gt;Ignatius, Duke of Ursul: On behalf of our people, I thank you for your wisdom.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Now I can leave Julianna locked up forever and no one will care!)&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 8&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Instrument in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a man here to see you. He wishes Crown funding for a project of his.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember, the treasury is not unlimited. If you choose to invest, you will have less money to work with later.&lt;br/&gt;Man: Your Royal Highness, I have a plan to print books using metal letters which can be moved and reused.&lt;br/&gt;Man: I need to borrow 875 lassi to assemble the metal and a factory to mold and cast the type.&lt;br/&gt;Man: With this system, we will be able to create new books in a fraction of the time it takes now, and make copies to send all over the world.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know much about factories or trade. Would that really be worthwhile?)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br/&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 9&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Flattery in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Battlefield Medicine in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, my sympathies for your loss. Even after all these years I sometimes forget that my own mother will never be coming back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: However, I must call for your aid. The Ixionite occupation of the county of Imbrium has gone on for too long. Now is the time to push back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I know there&#39;s been some problems with Ixion, but I don&#39;t know the details. I guess they&#39;re occupying southern Maree.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know anything about the military. I don&#39;t want to fight.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There must be a peaceful way to settle this. I will send for diplomats from Ixion and try to come to some arrangement.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Thank you, Your Highness.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: If I might say so, you are looking particularly lovely this day. I hope you will think fondly of me.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Is he flirting with me? He&#39;s almost as old as my father!)&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 10&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The representative from Ixion is here. Be careful - no one wants to give up prizes that they have won.&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: You have the full support of my sister and myself, Your Highness.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: Hmph. Let&#39;s get this over with.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Your Royal Highness, thank you for granting me this audience. I am sure we can come to an amicable agreement.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Let bygones be bygones, no? We will forget about your unprovoked attacks on us, and you will transfer the rights to this little province.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It was the Duchess of Hellas who tried to take over part of Ixion&#39;s territory, without the support of my mother the Queen.)&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: We can be good neighbors again, without any lives being lost.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Surrender Province] [Offer him money if Ixion withdraws] [Offer to punish the Duchess of Hellas] [Bluff / Intimidate] [Execute him] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Offer to punish the Duchess of Hellas&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We appreciate that you feel wronged. One of our subjects attempted to instigate a rebellion in your territory.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: However, she did not have our approval for these actions. If you withdraw your troops, we will punish her.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: Your Highness!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is the fair solution. You have no right to invade us because of her actions.&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: What manner of punishment were you considering?&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Make her a commoner] [Command her to marry an Ixionite] [Execute her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Execute her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: For her disobedience, she will be executed.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: &lt;b&gt;What?!?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, I must protest!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No one crosses me and lives. Not Hellas and not Ixion. Remember that!&lt;br/&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Very well. We will accept this apology.&lt;br/&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: You can&#39;t be serious!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Out!&lt;br/&gt; You go down to the dungeons to taunt Julianna with her helplessness and lack of noble status.&lt;br/&gt; However, when you approach her cell, you find her sitting cross-legged with her eyes closed, paying absolutely no attention to you.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Taunt her anyway] [Execute her] [Leave her alone.] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Taunt her anyway&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You&#39;re nobody, you know that? You&#39;re not a duchess anymore.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You&#39;re going to rot in here.&lt;br/&gt; She doesn&#39;t respond. From this distance, you can&#39;t be certain she&#39;s even breathing.&lt;br/&gt; Not that you&#39;re going to go into her cell to check. You&#39;re not that stupid.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Fine, ignore me! See if I care!&lt;br/&gt; You stomp off, determined not to waste your time. From now on you&#39;ll just avoid this cell.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 11&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There are reports that a keythong has been sighted leaving the Old Forest.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s a keythong?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: A beast with the body of an enormous golden cat, a sharp beak, and spikes on its back.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Eek!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Several disappearances in southern Caloris are already thought to be the work of this creature.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do we do? Should we send hunters?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The traditional policy on stray beasts is to hope that they return to the forest and stay there.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Hunters are no match for such creatures. You would only make it angry and waste more lives.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: So... we just let it eat people?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Everyone dies in the end.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br/&gt; You sneak out of the castle to have a little fun. You enjoy your freedom, but your father won&#39;t like it if he finds out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 12&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a woman here to see you. She wishes Crown funding for a project.&lt;br/&gt;Woman: Thank you for seeing me, Your Royal Highness. I... I come to you on behalf of the people.&lt;br/&gt;Woman: I wish to build a hospital where any citizen afflicted with disease can be brought for treatment.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Putting all the sick people together? Wouldn&#39;t that make them die even faster?)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br/&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 13&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Voice in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You are requested to stand in judgement. A woman has been convicted of attempted murder and requests the mercy of the Crown.&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Your Highness! This slattern dares to beg pardon, when she &lt;b&gt;admits&lt;/b&gt; that she tried to poison my sister under her own roof!&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Which sister?&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Corisande, the Duchess of Mead.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Is she all right?&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: She is unharmed. We caught the culprit in the kitchens before anyone could eat her foul spew.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Well, what do you have to say for yourself?&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: It&#39;s justice, it is! Them devils killed me brother, and broke me mam&#39;s heart.&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: Lied to her, they did, when she went to see why he&#39;d not come back. Said he&#39;d gone for a soldier, when he never would!&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: He weren&#39;t the only one neither. I waited ten years for my chance to get my own back. That&#39;s justice!&lt;br/&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: You see? She&#39;s completely unrepentant! Hang her and be done with it.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know what this is all about. Either way, murder is a serious crime, but...)&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [Put her to work] [Imprison her] [Execute her] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: Execute her&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: As she is clearly guilty, her life is forfeit. She will be hanged in public as a deterrent to other criminals.&lt;br/&gt;Condemned Woman: Ye&#39;ll not have me!&lt;br/&gt; All of a sudden, she breaks loose from her guards and rushes at you!&lt;br/&gt; In your Court dress, you are unarmed - you grope for a weapon and find only a heavy golden ornament which you hurl in her direction.&lt;br/&gt; Your missile flies wide of its mark.&lt;br/&gt; Before you have a chance to do anything else, your personal guards step into action, cutting the woman down before she can endanger you. Her lifeless body lies bleeding on your carpet.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Get that out of here. Put it on display, so that everyone sees what happens to criminals.&lt;br/&gt; You sneak down to the castle dungeons and amuse yourself by poking the locked-up peasants with sticks. Poor fools.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 14&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied World History in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; As you are walking one day in the gardens, you hear a strange sound and look up to see an owl flying overhead. A single dry leaf flutters in its talons.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s funny, I thought owls were nocturnal. I guess I was wrong.)&lt;br/&gt; You sneak down to the castle dungeons and amuse yourself by poking the locked-up peasants with sticks. Poor fools.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 15&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Dance in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember that the Festival of the Good Lady is approaching.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There will be public celebrations for the commoners, followed by a grand gala for the nobility.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A grand ball... There will be dancing.)&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As Queen, you would be expected to lead the procession and take part in the ceremonial planting, possibly give a speech.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: However, since you are not yet crowned, it is not required, and it may not be safe to expose you to the public.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you mean, not safe?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Outside of the castle, you are less well protected. If anyone means you harm... Think on it now, decide later.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a letter for you as well.&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s from Briony! I went to school with her, but she&#39;s a couple years older than me. Her mother is the Duchess of Mead.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s complaining that her mother still won&#39;t let her come home for the holidays.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Apparently her uncle Kevan has been acting strangely lately and shouting at shadows.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Her parents are fighting and she thinks they might split up.)&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s bored and looking for an adventure. Well, I don&#39;t have any to suggest to her!)&lt;br/&gt; You sneak down to the castle dungeons and amuse yourself by poking the locked-up peasants with sticks. Poor fools.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;Week 16&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Dance in the morning.)&lt;br/&gt;(Studied Novan History in the afternoon.)&lt;br/&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Today is the procession and planting for the Festival of the Good Lady. Will you be leading the parade?&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: If you have any concerns about your safety, please, stay here.&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The people will recover from disappointment; if we lose you, there is no recovery.&lt;br/&gt;Menu: [I will lead the parade] [I will parade and make a speech] [I would rather not go] &lt;br/&gt;Player chose: I will lead the parade&lt;br/&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I&#39;m not afraid. I&#39;m going to be the best parade-leader ever!&lt;br/&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: My little girl.&lt;br/&gt; You prepare your best gown for the occasion, then walk slowly through the town with your attendants. It would not be appropriate for you to wear a sword, but you do walk with a sturdy golden scepter that&#39;s taller than you are.&lt;br/&gt; At the end of the route, you help the priestesses turn over the earth for the new tree to be planted.&lt;br/&gt; Then the new life is blessed, and all the attendants join in song.&lt;br/&gt; The procession regroups to return to the castle.&lt;br/&gt; As you walk, all of a sudden, a man in black leaps out of the crowd, heading straight for you... and he&#39;s holding a sword!&lt;br/&gt; The last thing you see are his cold blue eyes staring into yours as his blade drives into your chest...&lt;br/&gt;Elodie did not survive to reach her coronation.  Nova would have to go on without her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&#39;t have to end this way.  Make different choices, train different skills, and Elodie&#39;s star may rise again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Live the Queen: Attempt 1 (Blind)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-1-Blind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 13:55:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Long-Live-the-Queen-Attempt-1-Blind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: We&#39;re almost home. Your room is just the way you left it.&lt;fast&gt;&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: We&#39;re almost home. Your room is just the way you left it.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I know it&#39;s hard to leave your school and all your friends, but I&#39;ve arranged the best possible tutors for every subject.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll have to work hard this year to prepare yourself before your fifteenth birthday, but I know you can do it.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You&#39;ll learn quickly and you&#39;ll make a wonderful queen. It&#39;s what your mother would have wanted.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: This is not what Mother would have wanted!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wouldn&#39;t have wanted to die and leave me.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No. She wouldn&#39;t. But sometimes bad things happen. We have to pick up and carry on.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: All of Nova depends on us. On you.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: *sigh*&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I will be here to guide you until your coronation, but the decisions you make are ultimately up to you.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Come. Your maids are waiting.&lt;br&gt; Welcome to &lt;b&gt;Long Live The Queen!&lt;/b&gt; If this is your first time playing, you should read this brief introduction to how the game works.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Tell me more] [I&#39;ve played this before] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Tell me more&lt;br&gt; You will be controlling Elodie, the almost-Queen of Nova, as she tries to prepare for her coronation. To do that, she needs to take classes every week in order to raise her &lt;b&gt;Skills.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; The skills she learns will provide different choices in the ongoing plot. Learning the right skills can mean the difference between life and death!&lt;br&gt; You also need to keep an eye on Elodie&#39;s &lt;b&gt;Mood.&lt;/b&gt; With her mother&#39;s tragic death, Elodie is not very happy right now. The Mood button will take you to the emotions screen for more details.&lt;br&gt; Elodie is feeling both &lt;b&gt;Afraid&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Depressed&lt;/b&gt;, but her strongest emotion is Depressed. If she becomes more Cheerful to cancel out the depression, her strongest emotion would then be Afraid.&lt;br&gt; Elodie&#39;s current mood affects her ability to learn. It will give her a bonus to some skills and a penalty to others. Let&#39;s take a look at the Skills screen now.&lt;br&gt; Skills are broken into four main categories - Social, Physical, Intellectual, and Mystical. Inside these categories are skillsets, groups of three related skills. You start with 0 in all skills.&lt;br&gt; Every week, Elodie can study two skills. Normally, she earns 2 points in a skill for every weekday that she studies. So if she studies History, she will earn &lt;b&gt;2 points x 5 days = 10 points.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; Because Elodie is depressed, she has a &lt;b&gt;-2&lt;/b&gt; penalty to the Social skillset &lt;b&gt;Conversation.&lt;/b&gt; She doesn&#39;t feel like talking to people right now. If she studies Conversation, she will earn &lt;b&gt;2 - 2 points per day&lt;/b&gt;: that is, &lt;b&gt;0 points!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; However, she has a &lt;b&gt;+1&lt;/b&gt; bonus to the &lt;b&gt;Expression&lt;/b&gt; skillset. If she studies one of the Expression skills, she will earn &lt;b&gt;2 + 1 points per day&lt;/b&gt;. Which means 3 points a day, 15 points for the week.&lt;br&gt; If you study a skill you have a penalty for, you could be wasting your time and not learning anything. If you study a skill you have bonuses for, you will learn much faster than normal.&lt;br&gt; All of these bonuses and penalties will change when Elodie&#39;s mood changes. She can also gain bonuses to skills by studying related skills. Check the skills screen every week to see your current bonuses!&lt;br&gt; Once you know your mood, skills, bonuses, and penalties, you are ready to choose your classes for the week.&lt;br&gt; The classes screen breaks down skillsets by category for your Morning and Evening classes. When you select a skillset, the three options in that set will appear on the right side of the screen.&lt;br&gt; Choose a class option for both Morning and Evening classes, then click the &#39;Done&#39; button which will appear in the lower-right corner.&lt;br&gt; As you play through the story, you will sometimes see feedback bubbles appearing over the text. These tell you what&#39;s happening behind the scenes.&lt;br&gt; Bubbles like these will show you when Elodie&#39;s mood is being altered by events.&lt;br&gt; Bubbles like these will show you when the story is changing based on what skills Elodie has learned so far. If the test fails, there is some option being missed because she doesn&#39;t have enough points in that skill yet.&lt;br&gt; This feedback is very helpful in figuring out different options to try! But if you don&#39;t want to see it, you can turn the bubbles off in the Preferences menu.&lt;br&gt; Now, get ready to become a Queen!&lt;br&gt;(Put on the boarding_school outfit.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Week 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Studied Decoration in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Horses in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s all that noise outside? Who&#39;s here?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! It&#39;s my cousins! And my aunt and uncle.&lt;br&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: Darling. We were so terribly sorry to hear about your mother Fidelia.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br&gt;Laurent, Duke of Merva: You look well, niece.&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Hi, &#39;Lodie!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Hi, Lottie. I haven&#39;t seen you in ages! Will you be staying long?&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Yup! Mummy said we&#39;d be here all month.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Maybe we&#39;ll have some time to talk later.&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: I love this room! It&#39;s so much bigger than mine back home.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You should visit more often. It&#39;s awful that the only time I get to see you is...&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ... something like this.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I know your brother and sister are still too young, but why haven&#39;t you come to school?&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: My mother worries about me. She doesn&#39;t think anywhere but home is safe.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I understand. I&#39;m probably not going to be allowed to leave this castle until my birthday.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But at least we can have fun together here!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 2&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s that commotion outside? Father? What&#39;s going on?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I have come to pay my respects in honor of your mother.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You have no respect or honor. It&#39;s because of you and your powers that my wife is dead!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?!?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I am a Lumen, as was she, and like every Lumen I am willing to give my life if necessary to protect our domain. &lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Your line has been traitors for two hundred years. I won&#39;t have you corrupting my daughter.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: That is for the Crown Princess to decide.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Elodie, your mother trusted me, and I have much to teach you.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Send her away] [Arrest her] [Let her stay] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Let her stay&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I want to hear what she has to say.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She stays.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What is it you wanted to teach me?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: First, I need to know if you have your mother&#39;s crystal.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What crystal?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: The source of power for any Lumen is a particular magical crystal. Once you&#39;ve bonded with it, it becomes a part of you as long as you live.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: The Royal Crystal has been passed down from ruler to ruler for generations. It belongs to you, now - except that the King may be keeping it from you.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Do you have a crystal?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Of course.&lt;br&gt; She holds out her hands. Light flickers above her bosom, and then, with a shower of sparkles, something takes shape.&lt;br&gt; You reach out to touch it, and it dissolves away into nothing.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: It belongs to me. No one can take it from me until I die.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: You need to find the crystal that belongs to you.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 3&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br&gt; You may now play Sports on the weekends.&lt;br&gt;(Studied Divination in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: He loves me, he loves me not...&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Lottie, do you have a boyfriend?&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: Not really. I just like to play with the flowers.&lt;br&gt; All of a sudden, the Duchess of Ursul rushes into the garden and points a sword at you!&lt;br&gt; No, not at you. At your... feet?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Princess! Don&#39;t move!&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Hold still] [Look down] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Hold still&lt;br&gt; You want to hold still, but you don&#39;t have the composure to hold your position without peeking.&lt;br&gt; You look down where her sword is pointing.&lt;br&gt; There&#39;s a &lt;b&gt;snake&lt;/b&gt; in the grass!&lt;br&gt; You can&#39;t help it - you squeak and jump back. The snake tenses and prepares to strike.&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: No!&lt;br&gt; Your cousin pushes you aside, and the snake&#39;s fangs sink into her leg.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Lottie!&lt;br&gt; Too late, Julianna swings her sword and cuts off the snake&#39;s head.&lt;br&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: What is going on out here?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Your daughter&#39;s been bitten by a milk viper. They&#39;re poisonous. Get an herbalist, right away!&lt;br&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: &lt;b&gt;I&lt;/b&gt; will treat my daughter. I certainly can&#39;t trust anyone here to keep her safe!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I&#39;m sorry...&lt;br&gt;Charlotte, Lady Merva: I don&#39;t feel good.&lt;br&gt;Lucille, Countess of Nix: We will be returning home to Merva immediately.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Your aunt has a point. Milk vipers are not native to this area. That snake should never have been here.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Someone may have tried to kill you.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Will Charlotte be okay?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: I don&#39;t know.&lt;br&gt; You sneak a peek at some of the luckless peasants held in the dungeons - petty thieves and troublemakers, now suffering in the dark. They&#39;re obviously bad people, but seeing them so miserable still feels unfair. There must be a better way.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 4&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Meditation in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: The castle seems quieter with Charlotte and Emry and Zahra and their parents gone.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It&#39;s certainly not empty, though. It seems like we get more servants every day.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I was so worried about Charlotte, after that snake bit her...&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But her mother said she&#39;s okay, so I guess it turned out all right.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Maybe she has a guardian angel!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: How do I find my Lumen crystal?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Your father probably knows what happened to it.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What if he destroyed it?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: They can&#39;t be destroyed. He could throw it away, but then someone else might find it. No, he&#39;ll keep it safe.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But if it&#39;s mine, it wouldn&#39;t matter if someone else found it.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: It&#39;s attuned to you, but you haven&#39;t bonded with it yet. If it found a compatible host, someone who was &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; you in some way, it could bond to them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 5&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Reflexes in the morning.)&lt;br&gt; Your skill in Reflexes is now 50.  You may not increase this skill until your other Agility skills are 25 or higher.&lt;br&gt;(Studied Lore in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; One of the maids approaches for your attention.&lt;br&gt;Alice: My lady, couriers have arrived from the Duke of Sedna.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We have a Duke of Sedna?&lt;br&gt;Alice: ... No, my Lady. The duchy of Sedna is in Talasse.&lt;br&gt;Alice: They have brought you a letter, and a gift.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &#39;Condolences on the death of&#39;, &#39;deeply regret&#39;, &#39;best wishes&#39;...&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Oh! What a beautiful necklace!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Something sparkly will make me feel better.&lt;br&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 6&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; As you are walking, you spot a familiar figure in the palace gardens.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s the Duchess of Ursul! Maybe I should go and say hello.)&lt;br&gt; Then you notice that seated beside her is a woman in the robes of a priestess. They are very close together, their hands gently touching as they speak.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Looks like she&#39;s busy!)&lt;br&gt; You turn and walk in a different direction, so as not to disturb them. At that moment, you notice something unusual. It looks like someone just left the palace grounds by going over the hedge.&lt;br&gt; Was that a servant? A thief? Or... an assassin?&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Climb up to look over the hedge] [Call the guards] [Run and hide] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Call the guards&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Guards!&lt;br&gt; However, by the time the response is organised and directed to the area beyond the palace, there&#39;s no sign of any intruder.&lt;br&gt; You wonder if you were only imagining it.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Dad, what happened to Mom&#39;s Lumen crystal?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: It&#39;s in a safe place.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Can I have it?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: No.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: But it&#39;s mine!&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Meddling with magic killed your mother. I don&#39;t want that to happen to you.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Once you&#39;re crowned Queen, I can&#39;t stop you from doing anything you want, but for now you are still a child.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 7&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; As you are walking up the stairs, a maid comes running down holding a towering pile of linen.&lt;br&gt; You swiftly step aside and let her pass.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: My father says I can&#39;t have the crystal until I&#39;m Queen, so we&#39;ll just have to wait.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: There may not be time to wait.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: This world is filled with dangers, and you will need the powers of a Lumen to fight them. You can&#39;t begin training until you have bonded with your crystal.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Well, what else am I supposed to do about it?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: The crystal is probably held under guard in the Royal Treasury. You are the princess; you should be able to find a way inside.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Otherwise we might have to take drastic action.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [I&#39;ll wait until I&#39;m older] [I&#39;ll try to find a way] [What drastic action?] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: What drastic action?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you mean by drastic action?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Let&#39;s hope it doesn&#39;t come to that.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Try to reach the crystal. If you can&#39;t, come and talk to me again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 8&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Naval Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a man here to see you. He wishes Crown funding for a project of his.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember, the treasury is not unlimited. If you choose to invest, you will have less money to work with later.&lt;br&gt;Man: Your Royal Highness, I have a plan to print books using metal letters which can be moved and reused.&lt;br&gt;Man: I need to borrow 875 lassi to assemble the metal and a factory to mold and cast the type.&lt;br&gt;Man: With this system, we will be able to create new books in a fraction of the time it takes now, and make copies to send all over the world.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know much about factories or trade. Would that really be worthwhile?)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 9&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Court Manners in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, my sympathies for your loss. Even after all these years I sometimes forget that my own mother will never be coming back.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: However, I must call for your aid. The Ixionite occupation of the county of Imbrium has gone on for too long. Now is the time to push back.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I know there&#39;s been some problems with Ixion, but I don&#39;t know the details. I guess they&#39;re occupying southern Maree.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (We have plenty of troops, so it shouldn&#39;t be that hard to drive them out, if we want to make a fight of it.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Try to negotiate] [Prepare for battle] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Try to negotiate&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There must be a peaceful way to settle this. I will send for diplomats from Ixion and try to come to some arrangement.&lt;fast&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There must be a peaceful way to settle this. I will send for diplomats from Ixion and try to come to some arrangement.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Thank you, Your Highness.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Your Highness, if I may ask... That necklace you&#39;re wearing. Where did it come from?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: It was a gift from the Duke of Sedna.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Then, you have made arrangements with him?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I think he&#39;s asking if I&#39;m engaged to the Duke!)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [I&#39;m considering it] [I just like jewelry] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: I&#39;m considering it&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No arrangements yet, but I look upon him fondly.&lt;fast&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No arrangements yet, but I look upon him fondly.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: I see. Your happiness is my utmost concern, Your Highness.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you.&lt;br&gt; You sneak a peek at some of the luckless peasants held in the dungeons - petty thieves and troublemakers, now suffering in the dark. They&#39;re obviously bad people, but seeing them so miserable still feels unfair. There must be a better way.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 10&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Strategy in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The representative from Ixion is here. Be careful - no one wants to give up prizes that they have won.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: You have the full support of my sister and myself, Your Highness.&lt;br&gt;Brin, Duchess of Hellas, Countess of Dysnomia: Hmph. Let&#39;s get this over with.&lt;br&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Your Royal Highness, thank you for granting me this audience. I am sure we can come to an amicable agreement.&lt;br&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: Let bygones be bygones, no? We will forget about your unprovoked attacks on us, and you will transfer the rights to this little province.&lt;br&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: We can be good neighbors again, without any lives being lost.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Surrender Province] [Offer him money if Ixion withdraws] [Bluff / Intimidate] [Execute him] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Bluff / Intimidate&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You are trespassing on our lands. You will withdraw your troops at once. Only then will we have peace.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Hmm. This necklace I&#39;m wearing might convince him that we are already allied with Duke Sedna in the domain of Talasse.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Threaten to attack] [Claim you are allied with Talasse] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Claim you are allied with Talasse&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: As you can see, I already have allies. Do you really want to face both Nova and Talasse?&lt;br&gt;Diplomat from Ixion: ... Perhaps not.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Yes! I won!)&lt;br&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 11&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Logistics in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There are reports that a keythong has been sighted leaving the Old Forest.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What&#39;s a keythong?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: A beast with the body of an enormous golden cat, a sharp beak, and spikes on its back.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Eek!&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Several disappearances in southern Caloris are already thought to be the work of this creature.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do we do? Should we send hunters?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The traditional policy on stray beasts is to hope that they return to the forest and stay there.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Hunters are no match for such creatures. You would only make it angry and waste more lives.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: So... we just let it eat people?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Everyone dies in the end.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Also, there is a letter for you.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Talarist, the Duke of Sedna, will be arriving next week for an official visit.)&lt;br&gt; You wander through the parts of the castle where other people rarely visit, but find little except spiderwebs. Yuck.&lt;br&gt;(Put on the intrigue outfit.): (Put on the boarding_school outfit.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 12&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Strategy in the morning.)&lt;br&gt; You may now tour the Barracks on the weekends.
Your skill in Strategy is now 50.  You may not increase this skill until your other Military skills are 25 or higher.&lt;br&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: Ah, Your Highness. What a pleasure it is to meet you in person at last. Your description did not do you justice.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: *giggle*&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know how to deal with handsome older men paying me compliments!)&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: I was so pleased to hear that you had accepted my humble offering. A jewel for a jewel - but you are the more precious.&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: I hope that this is only the beginning of a mutually beneficial relationship. A union between us would bring stability to both our peoples.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (He really does want to marry me!)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Accept his offer] [Politely decline] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Politely decline&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I need to let him down gently.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I am &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; marrying you! I&#39;m only fourteen!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (... That may not have been gentle.)&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: I am aware of your youth, my princess. That is the only reason that our domains are not already at war.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: You told the representative from Ixion that my domain was allied to yours. My king was quite suprised to hear of it.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Er.&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: You are unprepared for the realities of politics. Marry me, and I will be your guide, your protector and your advisor.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [All right, I&#39;ll marry you] [I still won&#39;t marry you] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: I still won&#39;t marry you&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I won&#39;t do it! I won&#39;t, I won&#39;t, I won&#39;t!&lt;br&gt;Talarist, Duke of Sedna: ... I see.&lt;br&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 13&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Naval Strategy in the morning.)&lt;br&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br&gt;(Studied Foreign Intelligence in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You are requested to stand in judgement. A woman has been convicted of attempted murder and requests the mercy of the Crown.&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Your Highness! This slattern dares to beg pardon, when she &lt;b&gt;admits&lt;/b&gt; that she tried to poison my sister under her own roof!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Which sister?&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Corisande, the Duchess of Mead.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Is she all right?&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: She is unharmed. We caught the culprit in the kitchens before anyone could eat her foul spew.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Well, what do you have to say for yourself?&lt;br&gt;Condemned Woman: It&#39;s justice, it is! Them devils killed me brother, and broke me mam&#39;s heart.&lt;br&gt;Condemned Woman: Lied to her, they did, when she went to see why he&#39;d not come back. Said he&#39;d gone for a soldier, when he never would!&lt;br&gt;Condemned Woman: He weren&#39;t the only one neither. I waited ten years for my chance to get my own back. That&#39;s justice!&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: You see? She&#39;s completely unrepentant! Hang her and be done with it.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Hmm. This might have something to do with the last Duke of Mead. He was involved in all sorts of scandals.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Put her to work] [Imprison her] [Execute her] [Ask the Earl of Io about her story] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Ask the Earl of Io about her story&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I need to know if she has any justification for her actions.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: &lt;i&gt;Did&lt;/i&gt; the old Duke kill her brother?&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: Are you &lt;i&gt;accusing&lt;/i&gt; my family?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I&#39;m asking what happened!&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: The honor of our line is far greater than that of the wet-bottomed child who sits the throne!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?&lt;br&gt; Without warning, the Earl of Io draws a dagger and slices the convict&#39;s throat.&lt;br&gt;Kevan, Earl of Io: No one harms my family. No one!&lt;br&gt; He throws the blood-stained blade to the floor and walks away.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Ooooo!&lt;br&gt; Sitting in on court sessions is not fun at all, but it pleases your father and it may be important for your future.&lt;br&gt;(Put on the military outfit.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 14&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Strategy in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; As you are walking one day in the gardens, you hear a strange sound and look up to see an owl flying overhead. A single dry leaf flutters in its talons.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s funny, I thought owls were nocturnal. I guess I was wrong.)&lt;br&gt; When you return to the castle, your father is waiting for you.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a woman here to see you. She wishes Crown funding for a project.&lt;br&gt;Woman: Thank you for seeing me, Your Royal Highness. I... I come to you on behalf of the people.&lt;br&gt;Woman: I wish to build a hospital where any citizen afflicted with disease can be brought for treatment.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Putting all the sick people together? Wouldn&#39;t that make them die even faster?)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: We are not interested.&lt;br&gt; You wander through the parts of the castle where other people rarely visit, but find little except spiderwebs. Yuck.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 15&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Remember that the Festival of the Good Lady is approaching.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There will be public celebrations for the commoners, followed by a grand gala for the nobility.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A grand ball... There will be dancing.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As Queen, you would be expected to lead the procession and take part in the ceremonial planting, possibly give a speech.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: However, since you are not yet crowned, it is not required, and it may not be safe to expose you to the public.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do you mean, not safe?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Outside of the castle, you are less well protected. If anyone means you harm... Think on it now, decide later.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a letter for you as well.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s from Briony! I went to school with her, but she&#39;s a couple years older than me. Her mother is the Duchess of Mead.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s complaining that her mother still won&#39;t let her come home for the holidays.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Apparently her uncle Kevan is absolutely furious about that woman&#39;s trial.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s bored and looking for an adventure. Well, I don&#39;t have any to suggest to her!)&lt;br&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 16&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Public Speaking in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Today is the procession and planting for the Festival of the Good Lady. Will you be leading the parade?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: If you have any concerns about your safety, please, stay here.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The people will recover from disappointment; if we lose you, there is no recovery.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [I will lead the parade] [I will parade and make a speech] [I would rather not go] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: I would rather not go&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No... I guess I&#39;d rather stay here.&lt;br&gt; You watch the procession from your tower window, feeling safe but lonely.&lt;br&gt; Suddenly, you hear someone moving around inside your room. You turn in surprise, but it&#39;s only a maid.&lt;br&gt;Alice: My lady? What are you - Should you not be in the procession?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s a major festival, but there are other ways to celebrate.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Confess your fears] [Yell at her] [Make religious excuse] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Confess your fears&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I can&#39;t go outside... there might be assassins.&lt;fast&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I can&#39;t go outside... there might be assassins.&lt;br&gt;Alice: Oh.&lt;br&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 17&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Presence in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Trade in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Are you ready for the grand ball?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: All the nobles in the domain are here to see you - to see their queen.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (gulp!)&lt;br&gt; You finish dressing and descend the stairs to make a grand entrance.&lt;br&gt; All around, the rich and powerful pause in their activities to gaze upon you, the ruler of them all.&lt;br&gt; Seeing yourself reflected in so many eyes makes you want to run away and hide.&lt;br&gt; After a moment, you force yourself to carry on, but you&#39;re sure they&#39;ve all seen you hesitate.&lt;br&gt; Your father waits for you at the bottom of the stairs and offers you his arm.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The first dance is for us.&lt;br&gt; He guides you gently around the dance floor, never rushing you. It&#39;s fun to dance with your father, but the look in his eyes is so sad.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: After this, you must choose your own partner. There are a number of men who hope to catch your eye.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The Duke of Kigal alone has brought three eligible sons, all near your age.&lt;br&gt; You look around the room at all your possible partners - which is to say, everyone. No one may begin dancing until you do. You can pick whomever you want and you will not be denied.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Someone about your age] [Someone younger than you] [Someone older than you] [Someone already married] [Someone scandalous] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Someone older than you&lt;br&gt; You look around for a likely candidate, and your eye settles on Chaine, the Earl of Mima. He&#39;s almost ten years older than you are and quite good-looking, so why not enjoy yourself?&lt;br&gt; He smiles brightly at your approach and you begin to dance.&lt;br&gt; Dancing with a real partner feels quite different from dancing with your father. You knew him, knew his steps like a part of you. Now every move is a mystery.&lt;br&gt; Unfortunately, you lose track of which steps you&#39;re supposed to do when, and trip over your own feet. Oops!&lt;br&gt; Between the dances, there is time for the guests to mingle, chat, and sample tiny bites of exquisite food.&lt;br&gt; During a lull in the music, Banion, the duke of Maree, taps an elegant fingernail against a wineglass, letting the clear note ring out through the room.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: If I might have your attention?&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: I believe we should offer our compliments to our lovely hostess.&lt;br&gt;Banion, Duke of Maree, Earl of Serenitatis: Her words of wisdom guide us through our difficulties.&lt;br&gt; Everyone applauds politely.&lt;br&gt; As the gala continues, you take the opportunity to observe nobles that you rarely see.&lt;br&gt; There&#39;s Gwenelle, for instance - the Young Lady of Sudbury, only months older than you and due to finally inherit control of her duchy soon.&lt;br&gt; Or Adele, the youngest daughter of the Duchess of Lillah and a fierce sportswoman. She was a few years ahead of you at school and the absolute terror of the ballfields.&lt;br&gt; No Briony - she had said her parents were leaving her stuck at school this season.&lt;br&gt; Her parents are here, dancing together - the Duke-Consort clutching his Duchess possessively tight.&lt;br&gt; Strange that there&#39;s no sign of your cousins, though. Shouldn&#39;t they be here?&lt;br&gt; Your aunt and uncle &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; here, of course. It would be scandalous if they hadn&#39;t come, Merva being so close by.&lt;br&gt; It&#39;s nice to be able to enjoy time with friends and family, isn&#39;t it?&lt;br&gt; You pay your respects to your mother&#39;s tomb, and wonder if the same fate is waiting for you.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 18&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Presence in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Production in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; You wander downstairs to visit your father and talk about the latest events in the domain.&lt;br&gt; You&#39;re moving with such enthusiasm that you don&#39;t realise your father isn&#39;t alone until it&#39;s too late to avoid him and his... companion.&lt;br&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: You are too kind, Joslyn.&lt;br&gt; Countess Sirin. &lt;i&gt;Not&lt;/i&gt; a member of your circles - she&#39;s a bit more than a decade your senior, far too old to have ever been your friend. And yet, not at all old, as noblewomen go.&lt;br&gt; She has two minor titles, no husband, and &lt;i&gt;your father&#39;s arm in her grasp.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt; How &lt;i&gt;dare&lt;/i&gt; she make a move on your father?&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Shame her with silent scorn] [Insult her with false flattery] [Trip her as she passes] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Trip her as she passes&lt;br&gt; You wait until the Countess gets closer, then hook your foot around to make her stumble.&lt;br&gt; Unfortunately, you get your feet tangled up and end up tripping &lt;i&gt;yourself,&lt;/i&gt; falling to the ground with a thud.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Elodie, are you all right?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: ...&lt;br&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: Oh, dear. She does need a bit of looking after, doesn&#39;t she?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Not by you!)&lt;br&gt;Sirin, Countess of Miranda and Callisto: I should go now. I hope to see more of you later.&lt;br&gt; Once she&#39;s gone, you raise an eyebrow at your father.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Don&#39;t give me that look, young lady. She&#39;s a nice woman, nothing more.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: She wants something more!&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: And it&#39;s not going to happen any time soon.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You should be careful how you deal with people like Sirin. You need the goodwill of your nobles as well as your commoners.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: There haven&#39;t been any problems so far.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Many dark looks were aimed your way at the gala.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As Queen, you must be aware of everything around you.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Isn&#39;t that what I have agents for?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Yes, but you must give them direction. What is your greatest concern?&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Noble plots] [Commoner uprisings] [Foreign threats] [Assassins] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Foreign threats&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I need to know if any foreign powers are moving against me.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br&gt; You try to talk your way past the treasury guards, but despite eyelash-fluttering, foot-stomping, and outright threats, they won&#39;t budge. Hmph!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 19&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Presence in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Accounting in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; Your skill in Accounting is now 50.  You may not increase this skill until your other Economics skills are 25 or higher.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: It is the time of year to decide any necessary adjustments to the royal budget.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The majority of the money we receive is already spoken for, but there is always some room for discretion.&lt;br&gt; Based on the records and notes of current expenditures, if you maintain the current rate of tax, you will still have nine thousand, nine hundred and ninety-four gold lassi and ninety-seven silver tilassi available for special projects.&lt;br&gt; You can&#39;t imagine any reason that you would need to spend so much. You could afford to lower taxes.&lt;br&gt; Four thousand lassi should be enough to cover any military surprises for the rest of the year.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Raise taxes] [Keep them the same] [Lower taxes] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Keep them the same&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I think they&#39;re fine as they are.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br&gt; You wander through the parts of the castle where other people rarely visit, but find little except spiderwebs. Yuck.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 20&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Presence in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Trade in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You are requested to stand in judgement. A man has been convicted of the murder-by-strangling of his wife.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: He does not deny the act, but requests a pardon that he might be set free.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: If you admit you killed your wife, why do you think I&#39;m going to set you free?&lt;br&gt;Condemned Man: Save me, Your Majesty! Wasn&#39;t my fault. &lt;i&gt;Demons&lt;/i&gt; made me do it.&lt;br&gt;Condemned Man: Everyone knows the power of magical beasties! They used me, they twisted my fingers into chains...&lt;br&gt;Condemned Man: My wife found me screaming, she tried to shake me, and the chains wrapped around her...&lt;br&gt;Condemned Man: I need the priestesses to bless me and make me clean again!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Demons that make you attack people? Is that even possible?)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Pardon him] [Imprison him] [Execute him] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Execute him&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I don&#39;t care whether there were demons or not, you&#39;re still a murderer and your life is forfeit.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: You will be hanged in public as a deterrent to future criminals.&lt;br&gt; He opens his mouth to argue with you further, but then his shoulders slump.&lt;br&gt;Condemned Man: Yes, Your Majesty.&lt;br&gt; Afterwards, you receive a report from your agents near the Talassian border. There is unusual activity going on in the duchy of Sedna. Official messengers have been coming and going between the Sedna customs stations.&lt;br&gt; Is Duke Talarist planning to disrupt trade between Sedna and Elath? Or is this a sign of something worse?&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Send soldiers to the border] [Do nothing] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Send soldiers to the border&lt;br&gt; You detach a battalion of soldiers to guard the border between Sedna and Elath. If he tries anything, you&#39;ll be prepared.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: You have not yet reached the crystal. Are you making progress, or is it time for another plan?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That would probably be the &#39;drastic action&#39; she mentioned earlier.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Leave it to me] [Take drastic action] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Take drastic action&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I suppose... I&#39;ll have to listen to another plan.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Leave it to me.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Fine.&lt;br&gt; ...&lt;br&gt; That night, an explosion rocks the castle. A section of stone near the Royal Treasury collapses, crushing the guards on duty.&lt;br&gt; Nothing is stolen... at least, nothing that is acknowledged publicly.&lt;br&gt; But when you look at your father&#39;s face, you can see it in his eyes: the crystal is gone, and he knows that you are to blame. He will never trust you the same way again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 21&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Internal Affairs in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; You receive word of an unfortunate incident at the gallows where the man you judged was sent to be executed.&lt;br&gt; As he was led to the platform, he suddenly lashed out with explosive magical power, killing several guards and spectators before making his escape.&lt;br&gt; The population is buzzing with rumors of a secret cabal of evil Lumens who sacrifice innocents in their dark rituals.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Do you have it? You do have it, don&#39;t you?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: The crystal? Of course. Everything is ready for you.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Right.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Did you really have to kill the guards?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: If you regret their sacrifice, then do not let it go to waste.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;s too late to turn back now. I have to do the best I can for my people.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What do I do?&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: Pick up the crystal with your bare hands. Press it against your chest, over your heart, and say &lt;i&gt;&#34;Illuminate!&#34;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Okay... Here we go... 
 Illuminate!&lt;br&gt; You feel dizzy, and both larger and lighter than you were before. The crystal has disappeared from view, but &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; know where it is.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Wow.&lt;br&gt;Julianna, Duchess of Ursul: The priestess here is a friend of mine. I will come to your lessons in the faith and train you to use your powers.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I should feel happy, I guess... I&#39;m a Lumen now. I just hope I&#39;m doing the right thing.)&lt;br&gt; The game will now attempt to save the log and open it in a web browser.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Continue] [Cancel] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Cancel&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 22&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Naval Strategy in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I regret to inform you that Fabian, the Earl of Titan and Duke-Regent of Elath, has passed away.&lt;br&gt; This isn&#39;t really a surprise; he was pretty old. The problem is the political implications.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: With the control of Elath in doubt, it falls to the crown to make decisions.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Young Lord Adair will not reach his fifteenth birthday for over two years. He requires a regent.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: His stepmother, Arisse, the Duchess of Lillah, has petitioned that the boy be left in her care.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: This would, however, leave her in personal control of two neighboring duchies, which is generally forbidden.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Almost the entire eastern border.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (I don&#39;t know anything really &lt;i&gt;bad&lt;/i&gt; about her, though...)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The boy does have a living grandfather, the Earl of Ishtar. Or you might appoint an unrelated noble to act in his stead.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The Earl of Ishtar has suggested another possibility. You and Adair are both young, not too far apart in age.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: He requests that we accept the boy as your future husband and keep him here at the castle.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Leave him with Arisse] [Send him to his grandfather] [Marry him] [Send him to your uncle] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Send him to his grandfather&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: The Earl of Ishtar is the closest blood relation that Adair has. He should be regent.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: As you wish.&lt;br&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 23&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Logistics in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: There is a woman here to see you. She is a musician and wishes Crown patronage.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Which means money.)&lt;br&gt;Sabine: Your Royal Highness! If you accept me as a member of your court I will immortalise you in word and song.&lt;br&gt;Sabine: I have dabbled in musical styles from many countries, and can entertain your guests and lighten your evenings.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Musicians are often used as secret agents and messengers. They can be useful - and dangerous.)&lt;br&gt; The musician sings a little ditty to demonstrate her skills with the lute.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She&#39;s actually pretty good.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Accept her as Court Musician] [Reject her] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Reject her&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Thank you, but we are not interested.&lt;br&gt; You spend the weekend holed up alone in your room with your favorite toys.  It&#39;s childish, but you feel a bit better.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 24&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Lore in the morning.)&lt;br&gt; You have unlocked a new outfit!
&lt;br&gt;(Studied Ciphering in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; You receive a letter from Young Lord Adair.&lt;br&gt; It&#39;s an extremely formal letter for such a little boy, thanking you for your wisdom in allowing him to live with his grandfather (who probably dictated every word he wrote).&lt;br&gt; You try to explain to the guards that you need to visit the treasury in order to get an accurate report on the domain&#39;s finances. They waver slightly, but in the end, they stand by your father&#39;s commands.&lt;br&gt;(Put on the faith outfit.): (Put on the intrigue outfit.): (Put on the military outfit.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 25&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Sense Magic in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; Your agents report a buildup of military strength - particularly warships - in Shanjia, the major power across the ocean to the west. They may be intending to go on the attack.&lt;br&gt; Shanjia lies a great distance from Nova. You have few diplomatic ties and no known conflicts. There&#39;s no reason to assume that you would be their target.&lt;br&gt; Still, if they send a fleet across the ocean, Nova might be in danger. At the very least, shipping would be disrupted.&lt;br&gt; It takes time to assemble worthy vessels, and you have advance warning. You could make your own preparations to defend your coast.&lt;br&gt; The downside is, they won&#39;t come cheap.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Build more warships] [Do nothing] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Build more warships&lt;br&gt; You send orders for the assembly of new ships, and the strengthening of weaponry and cladding on the existing fleet. If trouble comes, you&#39;ll be ready for it.&lt;br&gt; You attend services in the castle grove, letting the peace of the ritual calm your heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 26&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Naval Strategy in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Wield Magic in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I have unpleasant news to report.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Adair, the Young Lord of Elath, has been assassinated.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: What?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: He was shot with a crossbow while playing on the grounds of his grandfather&#39;s estate.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: How did this happen? Where were the guards?&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: This is not the first time such events have happened within the realm of Ishtar.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (The Earl of Ishtar&#39;s first wife and oldest daughter also died under mysterious circumstances.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Officially, an accident, but there were rumors it was agents from Talasse.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Then his other daughter married young and died giving birth to Adair.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (With Adair dead, the only family he has left is his second wife and their son Connor, who&#39;s fifteen.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Blame the Earl of Ishtar] [Blame Talasse] [Blame no one] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Blame no one&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: No matter what we do, things keep going wrong.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Then there is the matter of the duchy of Elath.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: By blood, the nearest living heir is Talarist, the Duke of Sedna.... in Talasse.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A long time ago there were marriages between the leaders of Elath and Sedna. That&#39;s his ancestry.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (But the people of Elath did not want a Duke of foreign blood. There were revolts.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (The title of Duke of Elath was passed to a distant relative instead of Talarist&#39;s ancestor.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Elath is a major duchy. You cannot afford to lose control of it.&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Name a Novan heir] [Name Talarist the heir] [Delay] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Name a Novan heir&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: As Queen, I have the right to pass the lands of an extinct bloodline to a new ruler.&lt;fast&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: As Queen, I have the right to pass the lands of an extinct bloodline to a new ruler.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Like my mother did with Uncle Laurent and Merva.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Talarist is only &lt;i&gt;distantly&lt;/i&gt; related, and he&#39;s foreign. He doesn&#39;t count.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Who should inherit the duchy of Elath, then?&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Hmm. There are a few noble families with a lot of children, too many to inherit all the existing titles.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Arisse, the Duchess of Lillah, has six children. The oldest three all have lands already.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s Kevan, the Earl of Io, Corisande, the Duchess of Mead, and Charmion, the Duchess-Consort of Kigal.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That leaves three others who are all a few years older than me.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (The Duke and Duchess of Kigal have &lt;i&gt;seven&lt;/i&gt; children, three around my age and four younger.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (And they&#39;re all Arisse&#39;s grandchildren through their mother. So either way, it would be her line.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [A child of the Duke of Kigal] [A child of the Duchess of Lillah] [An administrator from Elath] [A random commoner!] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: A random commoner!&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: I don&#39;t know, pick someone! Pick anyone from Elath! I don&#39;t care!&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Very well.&lt;br&gt; You sneak a peek at some of the luckless peasants held in the dungeons - petty thieves and troublemakers, now suffering in the dark. They&#39;re obviously bad people, but seeing them so miserable still feels unfair. There must be a better way.&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 27&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Resist Magic in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Sense Magic in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: I have more unpleasant news.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: Soldiers belonging to the Duke of Sedna have attempted to cross the border into Elath, but were chased off by your patrols.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: Good thing I put soldiers there earlier!&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: The crisis is averted for now, but relations with Talasse are likely to be strained in the future.&lt;br&gt;Joslyn, King Dowager, Duke of Caloris: You also have some letters.&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Another letter from Briony. Why does she keep writing me? We were never even friends.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (She says she&#39;s bored and lonely and she&#39;s looking forward to seeing me at Gwenelle&#39;s birthday party.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (That&#39;s right! Gwenelle is about to turn fifteen! She&#39;ll be Duchess of Sudbury for real now.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (This other letter must be my invitation to her birthday celebration next week.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (Gwenelle and I were friends at school, and this will be a big event, but it&#39;s also a long way to travel.)&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (A lot of things can happen on the road.)&lt;br&gt;Menu: [Go to Sudbury for Gwenelle&#39;s party] [Send your regrets] &lt;br&gt;Player chose: Go to Sudbury for Gwenelle&#39;s party&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;ll be good to see my friends!)&lt;fast&gt;&lt;br&gt;Elodie, Crown Princess: (It&#39;ll be good to see my friends!)&lt;br&gt; You take to the court for a few games of tennis. Feel the thrill of competition!&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;Week 28&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Studied Divination in the morning.)&lt;br&gt;(Studied Wield Magic in the afternoon.)&lt;br&gt; On your journey to Sudbury, your carriage is attacked by bandits!&lt;br&gt; You look down in shock at the arrow which has buried itself in your side. Outside, you can hear screams and curses, but it feels unreal. Your world is centered around pain.&lt;br&gt; You struggle with the arrow, afraid to pull it loose. You heard a story somewhere about pushing arrows through the body, so you brace yourself and give it a shove.&lt;br&gt; Unfortunately, this only drives the arrow deeper into your vital organs, turning a painful wound into a fatal one.&lt;br&gt;Elodie did not survive to reach her coronation.  Nova would have to go on without her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&#39;t have to end this way.  Make different choices, train different skills, and Elodie&#39;s star may rise again!&lt;br&gt;&lt;/fast&gt;&lt;/fast&gt;&lt;/fast&gt;&lt;/fast&gt;&lt;/fast&gt;&lt;/fast&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Just Desserts</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Just-Desserts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 19:11:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Just-Desserts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Looney Labs&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00U05Y830?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Just Desserts&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Just Delicious&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having played the game with three different groups, consisting of 2, 4, and 5 people, I can honestly say that every group I&#39;ve played it with has had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t go into the actual rules, other than to say that they&#39;re relatively simple to learn and pick up. Depending upon the group, however, you may need to keep handy the possible turn options, as in one game a few players kept needing to be reminded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the first game, where I thought new customers were only flipped over to replace the initial three (whoops!), we were able to play, and generally finish, two games in the span of an hour. During the second session we had run low enough on customers, however, that two people were effectively out of the game, and two others were fighting for the last card to complete a run of five different suits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are a number of different types of desserts, generally I think it played fine as-is, as otherwise the games may have ended sooner, as every player ended up looking for one or two types of desserts for the customers available at least a couple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I really like the artwork on the cards. People would comment that some of the customers looked like their names, but I think I was the only one of the eight different people I played with that commented on the desserts. The card quality is also pretty nice, consistent with other Looney Lab games, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this game will be part of my standard game lunch rotation, I have to give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00U05Y830?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Just Desserts&lt;/a&gt; five of five stars. Easy to learn, and pretty fair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Mars Attacks The Dice Game</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Mars-Attacks-The-Dice-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:37:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Mars-Attacks-The-Dice-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00M5KD7FI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Mars Attacks: The Dice Game&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fun, but the theme may be an acquired taste&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a fan of the Mars Attacks movie, I was interested in just how well a dice game based upon it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game actually puts you into the role of the Martians, and does not really tie into the movie. This is quite honestly a wise decision on their part, since personally I like playing the bad guys sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game play consists of putting out a few piles of cards with various locations. Each player will then role dice in an attempt to control each location until one of the stacks has been depleted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it sounds relatively easy, since you must pick a location you&#39;re going for, and each die has three different symbols, one of which can end your turn early, it actually turns into a slightly challenging game, as you must often decide whether you want to keep rolling dice, or quit when you&#39;re ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downside to this game is that the theme appears to turn some people off, or at least doesn&#39;t appeal to them. I&#39;ve brought this to a few sessions and it usually gets turned down for other games instead. The rules also take a little while to understand (I&#39;d recommend readying them beforehand and maybe trying a mock game). However, once you do get a game going, and understand the rules, you&#39;ll probably have a fun time conquering the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, while the game recommends 3-6 players, I was able to play a couple games with only two players, as long as you play with the three player rules for card counts. You could probably also get a solo variant going with nukes perhaps having some impact on the locations you can conquer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the quality of the actual game is pretty high. The long box is already starting to show wear with bending on the top, but the actual cards, dice, and tokens are of a good quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00M5KD7FI?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Mars Attacks: The Dice Game&lt;/a&gt; four stars. I had a lot of fun playing it, despite it being primarily dice based. I really wish I was able to get more people to play with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Karma Card Game</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Karma-Card-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 11:30:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-Karma-Card-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IZ7FH1M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Karma Card Game&lt;/a&gt;, provided to me by the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Simple enough for kids, but fun for all&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of years ago I was introduced to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00000IV34?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Card Game&lt;/a&gt; by a former co-worker. SET is fairly basic game that requires a deal of thinking, and is something I really enjoyed playing. So when I saw the SET name on the box for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IZ7FH1M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Karma Card Game&lt;/a&gt; I knew I had to request a copy. Having now played a few games of it, I&#39;m glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karma is a pretty basic game, similar to the game Shithead, but with additional cards. Basically you and up to 5 other players take a set of cards, some of which are in front of you face down, some of which are face up, and some of which are in your hand. Each turn you either need to lay a card higher than the last card played, or pick up the stack. If you do play a card and have less than a certain number of cards, you draw a replacement card(s), with the goal to have no remaining cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve played one of the other variants you&#39;ll find the inclusion of the Karma cards to be a nice variant. These can be played against any card and have effects ranging from requiring a card below a certain value to be played, a card higher in value than the bottom card, or for someone to pick up the entire stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play initially starts slow as you run through the main desk, especially since unlike other variants there&#39;s not really a good way to clear the play pile (a variant I play has a set of 4 cards in a row clear the pile). Because of this game length varied from 25 to 35 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did generally agree that the game would be great for playing with kids, although the number of cards you need to manage when you pick up a large play pile can be a bit overwhelming. Since there&#39;s nothing more than a small stack of cards required, it&#39;s also very portable (I played a couple games waiting for food at a restaurant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price is a little unfortunate, as when I told people how much it was (list price $13, Amazon for a little over $10) they were expecting something around $7 or $8 instead, especially since this could easily fit into a smaller package. With the exception of the Karma cards, you can also play one of the standard variants with a normal pack of playing cards. The numbering these cards use, however, does seem like it would be better for younger players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately it&#39;s still a very fun game, and is highly recommended. However, I have to give the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00IZ7FH1M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Karma Card Game&lt;/a&gt; only 4 of 5 stars, since while fun, a normal pack of cards would be fine for most older players.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: SET Dice Game</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-SET-Dice-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 09:56:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-SET-Dice-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00O59C9WY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Dice Game&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A pleasant twist on the SET card game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00000IV34?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET card game&lt;/a&gt; a little over four years ago by a former co-worker. Having more experience than I, she kicked my butt every time we played together, but it was enjoyable, and I still did sufficiently good at the single player variant. So when I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00O59C9WY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Dice Game&lt;/a&gt; available for review I snapped up the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the game itself comes in a very nice box. The top of the box is already starting to sag a bit, after less than two weeks of ownership, but the sides still seem sturdy. It&#39;s not too much of an issue since the box does include a nice bag for the dice. The dice are each very large (almost an inch square) and there are 42 in the set. They definitely seem like they&#39;re going to last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unfortunate bit about the game is the game board, which is only used in one of the three game variants. While it&#39;s a nice board, it has some difficulty staying flat, given the size and folding (it wants to fold closed). But, it&#39;s a very minor issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, there are instructions for three variants of SET. If you&#39;ve played the card game before then the base rules of what makes a SET haven&#39;t changed. Each variant states that it will last 20 minutes, although these could easily go longer or shorter, based upon the skill of the players and the roll of the dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scramble SET is much like the SET card game in that a number of dice are rolled and each person can call SETs as they see them. In this variant all 42 dice are rolled at once. This has a solo variant which is enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crossword SET is like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1932188126?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Bananagrams&lt;/a&gt; in that each player gets a number of tiles. They then use those tiles to build a crossword-like grid of their tiles, optionally taking another from the bag if they&#39;re unable to use all their dice. This too has a solo variant which is enjoyable enough, although I think I&#39;d rather play Scramble SET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final variant (technically first in the instructions) is SET Cubed, and is the only one that doesn&#39;t have a solo variant, and is the only one to use the game board. This is also the most complex, having more instructions associated with it than the other two variants combined, due primarily with the instructions. This variant allows players to build upon SETs others have played on the game board for added points, and is like Crossword SET but with a single grid. The complexity of this variant turned me off of this, so we ended up playing one of the other variants instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00O59C9WY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Dice Game&lt;/a&gt; easily gets a full five of five stars. They&#39;ve successfully taken an enjoyable thinking game and added fun variants. The quality of the game definitely makes it worth the price of the package, especially given the high replay value of this game. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: LG Electronics Gaming 24GM77 24-Inch Screen LED-Lit Monitor</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-LG-Electronics-Gaming-24GM77-24-Inch-Screen-LED-Lit-Monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 20:12:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-LG-Electronics-Gaming-24GM77-24-Inch-Screen-LED-Lit-Monitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00P0EOX1S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;LG Electronics Gaming 24GM77 24-Inch Screen LED-Lit Monitor&lt;/a&gt;, released in late 2014, and currently available for purchase for a little over $270. The product I received was free as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Very nice, but may not be required&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For context, I have two rather old HP monitors, from 2007, which up until early last year I was using for my PC monitors. I then upgraded to a 39-inch Samsung television, since my PC is effectively my living room&#39;s main entertainment station. And I&#39;m quite happy with the setup I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I had the opportunity to review the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00P0EOX1S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;LG Electronics Gaming 24GM77 24-Inch Screen LED-Lit Monitor&lt;/a&gt; as part of the Amazon Vine program, I jumped at the chance. Would a gaming monitor change my outlook on playing console and PC games? Or would I be content to continue along the path of using TVs in place of monitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little over three weeks I can honestly say I&#39;m impressed, but I think I&#39;ll be continuing along the path I&#39;m on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For general PC purposes the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00P0EOX1S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;LG Electronics Gaming 24GM77 24-Inch Screen LED-Lit Monitor&lt;/a&gt; works as is to be expected from any monitor, but you&#39;re not going to pick this up merely for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to test this monitor, I tried the following: Starcraft II on PC (highest settings), various Xbox One games and two animated blu-ray movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I guess I got so into the games that I didn&#39;t really notice much of a difference. The screen is definitely crisp, but when you compare the picture of a 24-inch monitor to a 39-inch one, naturally things are going to look better at a smaller physical size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t get me wrong, it&#39;s very nice, and I definitely got into the experience, but it wasn&#39;t clearly obvious to me that I was on a gaming-specific monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the physical aspects of the monitor, I&#39;m not quite sure what I think of the controls. There are base buttons as well as a nub that can be used to access the menu for the various options, as well as turn it off. While it feels sturdy enough, I guess a part of me would rather have an actual button for the power. But it works fairly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re thinking about using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00P0EOX1S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;LG Electronics Gaming 24GM77 24-Inch Screen LED-Lit Monitor&lt;/a&gt; as a monitor for a console, consider that the monitor does not have speakers built-in. That&#39;s fairly standard these days, but something to keep in mind. Since I didn&#39;t want to use headphones, when I used the Xbox I ended up using some USB powered speakers. Plugging into the monitor worked sufficiently fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monitor does feature two HDMI inputs, so you don&#39;t necessarily need to pick between a PC or a console, as you can easily swap between them. The monitor is also fairly smart, and seemed to pick the right input for me (although I did have an oddity initially when I had it hooked up to my PC via the DVI port, and a console via the HDMI, as it kept wanting to focus on the DVI port).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring the price, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00P0EOX1S?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;LG Electronics Gaming 24GM77 24-Inch Screen LED-Lit Monitor&lt;/a&gt; is a fine monitor, definitely worth 5 stars. The price, however, would knock it down one, as at almost $300 it&#39;s almost worth spending just a bit more to get a TV, which would then support component inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, ultimately I have to go with a five star rating for this monitor. I will definitely be looking at better speakers, and will absolutely have this as a part of my entertainment area. Is it required? No. But if you afford it, it comes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: RADical ROACH Deluxe Edition (2014)</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-RADical-ROACH-Deluxe-Edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 11:49:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/posts/Review-RADical-ROACH-Deluxe-Edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KGKWPJS?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;RADical ROACH Deluxe Edition&lt;/a&gt;, available on Steam and Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Not Rad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#39;RADical&#39; ROACH is just not very enjoyable. I somehow made it through the first two levels, and recently opted to run it for a little over an hour today to just get the trading cards (which are worth next to nothing in money and gems).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thankful I only paid 17 cents for this, thanks to a bundle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 of 5 stars, since it at least has cards, and an interesting art style. But not worth a purchase by itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comment on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://steamcommunity.com/id/strivinglife/recommended/301750/&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Steam review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
