<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Board Game on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/board-game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Board Game on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 09:24:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/board-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Fury of Dracula Third Edition Board Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Fury-of-Dracula-Third-Edition-Board-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 09:24:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Fury-of-Dracula-Third-Edition-Board-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OkfQMt&#34;&gt;Fury of Dracula Third Edition Board Game&lt;/a&gt;, which I received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So many pieces, but easy after a week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t played any of the previous editions of Fury of Dracula, so I can&#39;t speak to the changes made in this third edition. However, as I understand it, the game has changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This supports 2 to 5 players, with one player controlling Dracula and the others controlling one or more of the hunters. This does mean that in a two player game one person is controlling all four hunters, which is how I played it for the purposes of this review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game has an approximate run time of 2 to 3 hours, which is why I&#39;m reviewing it from a 2-player perspective; it was difficult to find others to invest that much time, with the perceived difficulty, given the amount of pieces in the box. However, to some extent the difficult is lessened since certain cards that one would think are different, are actually the same. For example, while there are hunter and Dracula event cards, these are combined into a single pile during play. After playing a week of rounds in the game, we had it down pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&#39;ve seen them played, I haven&#39;t played a hidden movement game like this before. I rather enjoyed how it worked, with location cards being used to track where Dracula has moved, instead of using some sort of sheet and writing locations down. It also lessens the ability for Dracula to move backwards (although he can still be tricky to locate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game works with the hunters playing once during the day and then once at night, with Dracula then going at night. This cycle repeats for each day of the week, until either Dracula is defeated, or he wins. However, if the game doesn&#39;t end after a few weeks Dracula starts gaining influence (his way of winning) at a very steady rate. So the game does have some maximum number of turns, based upon how the players do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game itself seemed relatively balanced, which I understand wasn&#39;t the case in earlier editions, with Dracula having a slight advantage. At first I found this to be slightly interesting since Dracula has a number of disadvantages, having less turns and allowing the players to find where he&#39;s been, since Dracula&#39;s last six locations can (generally) be discovered. He also can&#39;t backtrack, since the last six locations aren&#39;t part of the location deck he uses to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as was evident when Dracula was discovered to have moved into Italy, it&#39;s still possible for him to evade capture, as he did when he traveled by sea for three turns, opening up the number of possible locations he could have landed at. He can also leave behind encounters at locations he visited, which may either cause immediate harm, or if left as-is, help him slow down the hunters or finish the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last note is that unlike some games, in Fury of Dracula no player is completely out of the game. While hunters can be defeated, they eventually recover health and can continue on the quest. Each hunter has their own advantages and disadvantages, so no one hunter necessarily dominates over the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the board components themselves are of quite nice quality. The game includes five figures, which are of nice quality (and could potentially be painted), a nice quality board and cardboard pieces, and nice cards. The artwork is of note since it matches the style of the game relatively well. We did find that two of the figures were easy to mistake at a quick glance, which unfortunately did lead to combat happening with a character that should not have been in combat. However, with three or more players, closer attention, or perhaps a paint job, this wouldn&#39;t be an issue. It also only happened once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the only downside I found was the amount of time it took, which was closer to four hours, but was also our first time. Otherwise, when I can find people that will play it, much like Betrayal at House on the Hill and BioShock, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OkfQMt&#34;&gt;Fury of Dracula, Third Edition&lt;/a&gt; will be a game I&#39;ll recommend we try. 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Homeland: The Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Homeland-The-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:51:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Homeland-The-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OH1avz&#34;&gt;Homeland: The Game&lt;/a&gt;, provided to me as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A sort of board game Resistance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading through the rules for the first time I kept thinking about the game &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1PFllJu&#34;&gt;The Resistance&lt;/a&gt; (although there are many games like this). In The Resistance every character is either part of the resistance, or part of a group trying to sabotage them. As the game progresses you start to figure out who&#39;s who, in an attempt to score a win for your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homeland: The Game, is sort of like that, although here you have terrorists, politicians, and the feds, with the terrorist trying to cause havoc, the feds trying to prevent it, and the politicians trying for a &#39;healthy&#39; amount of both. Like other variants missions come in, with each player playing as needed. However, in this game it might turn out that you can only play cards that will threaten the mission, even though you want it to be squashed, and vice versa. There&#39;s also, depending upon how many people you play with, a chance that there won&#39;t even be a terrorist or politician in the game (there&#39;s always at least one of two though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first open the box you might be surprised by the thickness of the rules, combined with the number of pieces you need to punch out. However, the rules do have a number of photos from the show (which I have not seen). They&#39;re still a little complicated, but as you play you&#39;ll get the hang of it pretty quickly. It also comes with cards detailing the turn actions, which is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board itself is a little unfortunate. It&#39;s constructed well enough, but it&#39;s sliced in an odd spot. As the game progresses you end up moving cards from one end of the board to the other. However, the way it was cut results in the inability to smoothly slide half the board&#39;s cards up. A cut from north to south, instead of left to right, would have been preferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the cards are also half-sized, but the way these are actually used during play works out rather well. It just results in a little trouble shuffling them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game will play 3 to 6 players, with a length of 90 minutes. The more players you have the more tricky it might be (in a good way), but you can also expect play to go longer as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many others I haven&#39;t seen the show, so I can&#39;t speak to that, but I hope to get in a game with someone who has seen it (and also loves these types of games), and will update the review once that&#39;s happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1OH1avz&#34;&gt;Homeland: The Game&lt;/a&gt; a 5 of 5. I&#39;ll update once I&#39;ve had the opportunity to play with more people, but the components are well constructed (minus the cut placement in the board), the game plays well without needing to know the source material, and it even comes with, very nice, little marines and agents you can use during the game. Recommended for people who like games like The Resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: SET Dice Game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-SET-Dice-Game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 09:56:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-SET-Dice-Game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00O59C9WY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Dice Game&lt;/a&gt;, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A pleasant twist on the SET card game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00000IV34?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET card game&lt;/a&gt; a little over four years ago by a former co-worker. Having more experience than I, she kicked my butt every time we played together, but it was enjoyable, and I still did sufficiently good at the single player variant. So when I saw the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00O59C9WY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Dice Game&lt;/a&gt; available for review I snapped up the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the game itself comes in a very nice box. The top of the box is already starting to sag a bit, after less than two weeks of ownership, but the sides still seem sturdy. It&#39;s not too much of an issue since the box does include a nice bag for the dice. The dice are each very large (almost an inch square) and there are 42 in the set. They definitely seem like they&#39;re going to last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unfortunate bit about the game is the game board, which is only used in one of the three game variants. While it&#39;s a nice board, it has some difficulty staying flat, given the size and folding (it wants to fold closed). But, it&#39;s a very minor issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, there are instructions for three variants of SET. If you&#39;ve played the card game before then the base rules of what makes a SET haven&#39;t changed. Each variant states that it will last 20 minutes, although these could easily go longer or shorter, based upon the skill of the players and the roll of the dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scramble SET is much like the SET card game in that a number of dice are rolled and each person can call SETs as they see them. In this variant all 42 dice are rolled at once. This has a solo variant which is enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crossword SET is like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1932188126?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Bananagrams&lt;/a&gt; in that each player gets a number of tiles. They then use those tiles to build a crossword-like grid of their tiles, optionally taking another from the bag if they&#39;re unable to use all their dice. This too has a solo variant which is enjoyable enough, although I think I&#39;d rather play Scramble SET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final variant (technically first in the instructions) is SET Cubed, and is the only one that doesn&#39;t have a solo variant, and is the only one to use the game board. This is also the most complex, having more instructions associated with it than the other two variants combined, due primarily with the instructions. This variant allows players to build upon SETs others have played on the game board for added points, and is like Crossword SET but with a single grid. The complexity of this variant turned me off of this, so we ended up playing one of the other variants instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00O59C9WY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;SET Dice Game&lt;/a&gt; easily gets a full five of five stars. They&#39;ve successfully taken an enjoyable thinking game and added fun variants. The quality of the game definitely makes it worth the price of the package, especially given the high replay value of this game. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Cash N Guns Second Edition</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Cash-N-Guns-Second-Edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 08:53:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Cash-N-Guns-Second-Edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of Cash N Guns Second Edition, received as part of the Amazon Vine program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fun with a good group&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When initially reading over the instructions for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KU10OUU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Cash N Guns&lt;/a&gt; I wasn&#39;t sure how it would actually play. The idea of robbers trying to split the loot from a heist is pretty easy to understand, but would it play out fairly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having now played the game in a group of five I think it went fairly well. With the exception of one person (who had played before and knew the rules), everyone else had either known each other for a few months, or in the case of two people, for quite a while. While those two did end up going back and forth, it ultimately didn&#39;t have much of an impact upon the group as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to bring this to my normal group, but one individual has an issue with the inclusion of the foam guns, and would have skipped out had we played. Something to keep in mind depending upon the group, as the game does involve pointing a foam gun at another player, and either shooting them, or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the set&#39;s pieces, I found them to be of a very high quality, and they seem they&#39;ll hold up against abuse as any other game would. However, I did find that the drawings at the bottom of the box, while nice, kept throwing me off; I kept expecting them to be pieces of the game, and not part of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately I give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00KU10OUU?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34; rel=&#34;external&#34;&gt;Cash N Guns&lt;/a&gt; 4 stars of 5. The game is simple enough to play in about 30 minutes, but the number of required players (to make it fair and fun) and the fact that my group can&#39;t play it because of the guns/shooting is unfortunate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>