<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipad on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/ipad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipad on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 21:35:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: SimpleSleeve, Premium Neoprene Sleeve for Apple iPad</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-SimpleSleeve-Premium-Neoprene-Sleeve-for-Apple-iPad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 21:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Review-SimpleSleeve-Premium-Neoprene-Sleeve-for-Apple-iPad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003KXJE4M?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;SimpleSleeve, Premium Neoprene Sleeve for Apple iPad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A well made cover; one happy purchaser&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing as how my Nexus 7 has officially converted me to Android tablets (although we&amp;rsquo;ll see what Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Surface devices are priced at), I figured it was time to finally write a review for the item that&amp;rsquo;s been keeping my iPad safe for almost a year and a half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I picked up my first-generation iPad I obviously needed something to carry it around in. I did a good deal of looking around, and finally settled upon the&amp;nbsp;SimpleSleeve, Premium Neoprene Sleeve for Apple iPad by Grantwood, as the company was fairly active on Amazon for the product reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since April 2011 it&amp;rsquo;s been protecting my iPad, and has yet to fail me. I&amp;rsquo;ve had my iPad fall from approximately 4 feet, and haven&amp;rsquo;t even questioned whether it was damaged. I haven&amp;rsquo;t picked up a &amp;lsquo;shield&amp;rsquo; for the screen, and haven&amp;rsquo;t regretted the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would zip and unzip my iPad at least 3 times a day, if not more on busier days, and haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced any zipper issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve tossed this in bags (first an open one, and now a bookbag) and don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found that the back of the cover gets a little dirty, and at times I wish the plastic covered the same area on the reverse, to prevent against this. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t find that to be too much of an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I highly recommend this item. Since I can find no real issues with it, 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
