<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postgresql on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/postgresql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Postgresql on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 08:50:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/postgresql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Quickie: MySQL and PostgreSQL passwords</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another Ubuntu Quickie, this time on the default passwords for MySQL and PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MySQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;mysql -u root
UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&amp;rsquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;password&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;) WHERE User = &amp;lsquo;root&amp;rsquo;;
FLUSH PRIVILEGES;
\q&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;
sudo -u postgres psql template1
ALTER USER postgres WITH PASSWORD &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;password&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;;
\q&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference: PostgreSQL 8.2 commands on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Reference-PostgreSQL-82-commands-on-Ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Reference-PostgreSQL-82-commands-on-Ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Below are the PostgreSQL 8.2 commands on Ubuntu.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
These are listed here primarily for my own benefit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
General
\c[onnect] [DBNAME|- USER|- HOST|- PORT|-]
connect to new database (currently &amp;quot;template1&amp;quot;)
\cd [DIR]      change the current working directory
\copyright     show PostgreSQL usage and distribution terms
\encoding [ENCODING]
show or set client encoding
\h [NAME]      help on syntax of SQL commands, * for all commands
\q             quit psql
\set [NAME [VALUE]]
set internal variable, or list all if no parameters
\timing        toggle timing of commands (currently off)
\unset NAME    unset (delete) internal variable
! [COMMAND]   execute command in shell or start interactive shell
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Query Buffer
\e [FILE]      edit the query buffer (or file) with external editor
\g [FILE]      send query buffer to server (and results to file or |pipe)
\p             show the contents of the query buffer
\r             reset (clear) the query buffer
\s [FILE]      display history or save it to file
\w FILE        write query buffer to file
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Input/Output
\echo [STRING] write string to standard output
\i FILE        execute commands from file
\o [FILE]      send all query results to file or |pipe
\qecho [STRING]
write string to query output stream (see \o)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Informational
\d [NAME]      describe table, index, sequence, or view
\d{t|i|s|v|S} &lt;a href=&#34;add &amp;amp;quot;+&amp;amp;quot; for more detail&#34;&gt;PATTERN&lt;/a&gt;
list tables/indexes/sequences/views/system tables
\da [PATTERN]  list aggregate functions
\db [PATTERN]  list tablespaces (add &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; for more detail)
\dc [PATTERN]  list conversions
\dC            list casts
\dd [PATTERN]  show comment for object
\dD [PATTERN]  list domains
\df [PATTERN]  list functions (add &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; for more detail)
\dg [PATTERN]  list groups
\dn [PATTERN]  list schemas (add &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; for more detail)
\do [NAME]     list operators
\dl            list large objects, same as \lo_list
\dp [PATTERN]  list table, view, and sequence access privileges
\dT [PATTERN]  list data types (add &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; for more detail)
\du [PATTERN]  list users
\l             list all databases (add &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; for more detail)
\z [PATTERN]   list table, view, and sequence access privileges (same as \dp)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Formatting
\a             toggle between unaligned and aligned output mode
\C [STRING]    set table title, or unset if none
\f [STRING]    show or set field separator for unaligned query output
\H             toggle HTML output mode (currently off)
\pset NAME [VALUE]
set table output option
(NAME := {format|border|expanded|fieldsep|footer|null|
numericlocale|recordsep|tuples_only|title|tableattr|pager})
\t             show only rows (currently off)
\T [STRING]    set HTML &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; tag attributes, or unset if none
\x             toggle expanded output (currently off)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Copy, Large Object
\copy &amp;hellip;      perform SQL COPY with data stream to the client host
\lo_export LOBOID FILE
\lo_import FILE [COMMENT]
\lo_list
\lo_unlink LOBOID    large object operations
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Quickie: Installing MySQL and PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-Installing-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 21:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-Installing-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For SQL on Ubuntu Linux, I decided it was easiest to just use the repositories to just install MySQL and PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a couple of reasons for this. First, MySQL docs recommend it.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, there&#39;s not that much that I really want to configure in SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MySQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install mysql-server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, this will install;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libdbd-mysql-perl&lt;br /&gt;libdbi-perl&lt;br /&gt;libnet-daemon-perl&lt;br /&gt;libplrpc-perl&lt;br /&gt;mysql-client-5.0&lt;br /&gt;mysql-server&lt;br /&gt;mysql-server-5.0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggested packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dbishell&lt;br /&gt;libcompress-zlib-perl&lt;br /&gt;tinyca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mailx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s some official GUIs that you can also install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install mysql-admin mysql-query-browser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, this will install;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libcairomm-1.0-1&lt;br /&gt;libglibmm-2.4-1c2a&lt;br /&gt;libgtkhtml3.8-15&lt;br /&gt;libgtkmm-2.4-1c2a&lt;br /&gt;mysql-admin&lt;br /&gt;mysql-admin-common&lt;br /&gt;mysql-query-browser&lt;br /&gt;mysql-query-browser-common&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggested packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libgtkhtml3.8-dbg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For PostgreSQL, it&#39;s a bit longer of a string, since there&#39;s four packages, but it&#39;s still easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install postgresql-8.2 postgresql-client-8.2 postgresql-client-common postgresql-common&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may as well also go from pgAdmin III, which &#34;is the most popular and feature rich Open Source administration and development platform for PostgreSQL.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install pgadmin3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of this writing, this will install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libpq4&lt;br /&gt;libwxbase2.6-0&lt;br /&gt;libwxgtk2.6-0&lt;br /&gt;pgadmin3&lt;br /&gt;pgadmin3-data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended packages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pgagent (adds functionality to schedule PostgreSQL jobs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next time ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time we&#39;ll &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Ubuntu-Quickie-MySQL-and-PostgreSQL-passwords.aspx&#34;&gt;configure databases&lt;/a&gt; for both MySQL and PostgreSQL on Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 6: phpBB</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-6-phpBB/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2006 18:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-6-phpBB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s that time again. This time, we&#39;ll be looking at &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.phpbb.com/&#34;&gt;phpBB&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;phpBB is a high powered, fully scalable, and highly customizable Open Source bulletin board package. phpBB has a user-friendly interface, simple and straightforward administration panel, and helpful FAQ. Based on the powerful PHP server language and your choice of MySQL, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL or Access/ODBC database servers, phpBB is the ideal free community solution for all web sites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot&#39;s of features, so let&#39;s get to it. In this article, we&#39;ll be installing phpBB version 2.0.21, which is the latest version, as of June 9, 2006. A beta version of 3.0 came out a very short period before this article was written, otherwise I don&#39;t know that phpBB would have made it. Anywho, on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The zip file for phpBB weighs in at around 650 KB. Unzipped, we&#39;re looking at almost 2 MB. The zip file contains a single phpBB2 folder, so extract away. phpBB is also available in gzip and bz2 formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out these requirements. PHP 4.0.3+ and one of these database systems; MySQL 3.22+ or PostgreSQL 7.0.3+ or MS SQL Server 7+ or MS Access 2000+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&#39;re installing it locally as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you&#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run ... and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;mysql -h localhost -u root -p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;re installing phpBB, we&#39;ll create a database called phpBB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;create database phpBB;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we&#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &#39;&lt;strong&gt;phpbb&lt;/strong&gt;&#39; to something different (as this is the user&#39;s password).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop
ON &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt;.*
TO &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;&lt;strong&gt;phpbb&lt;/strong&gt;&#39;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt;.*&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;phpBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;&lt;strong&gt;phpbb&lt;/strong&gt;&#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&#39;t exist yet, we&#39;re also giving a password to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the query is OK, enter the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD_PASSWORD(&#39;phpbb&#39;) WHERE User = &#39;phpBB&#39;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the phpBB user. Once you&#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;show databases;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&#39;s a database of phpbb. Yippee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s install phpBB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing phpBB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, unzip the downloaded zip file. I&#39;ll be using one called phpBB2.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;re installing locally, we don&#39;t have to worry about permissions. So, once phpBB has been decompressed, navigate to the phpBB root folder in your browser. You&#39;ll be automatically be redirected to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/phpbb2/install/install.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/phpbb2/install/install.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a form to fill-out, so let&#39;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Database Type: MySQL 4.x/5.x&lt;br /&gt;Choose your installation method: Install&lt;br /&gt;Database Server Hostname/DSN: localhost&lt;br /&gt;Your Database Name: phpBB&lt;br /&gt;Database Username: phpBB&lt;br /&gt;Database Password: phpbb&lt;br /&gt;Prefix for tables in database: phpbb_&lt;br /&gt;Admin Email Address: strivinglife@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;Domain Name: localhost&lt;br /&gt;Server Port: 80&lt;br /&gt;Script path: /projects/phpbb2/&lt;br /&gt;Administrator Username: admin&lt;br /&gt;Administrator Password: cbe15b&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it. Woot. You&#39;ll have to delete or rename the install and contrib folders (I put an underscore before both). At this point, you can start bouncing around the forum. Woot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How&#39;s the code look?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most other forums, phpBB uses tables, and doesn&#39;t care to declare a summary. There&#39;s also an issue with an &#39;invalid&#39; target for the footer link.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internally, code is commented pretty darn well. However, the main comment header is the same copyright notice over and over. Yuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once installed, phpBB setups up one category, one forum, and one post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the look is very boxy, and reminds me of the look of a number of other forums. There&#39;s really not that much, graphically, that separates it from the others. Very similar look to MyBB and PunBB. Where&#39;s the admin interface? Oh, there&#39;s a link way down at the bottom of the page. Eh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checking for updates, amongst other things, is quite easy from the interface, and the install even had an option regarding upgrading. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do have archived files with the changed and patched files only available for download, which is quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;phpBB is pretty much like the others that we&#39;ve reviewed. But, now that we&#39;ve gone over all of them, as far as installation and first impressions, it&#39;s time to dig into them deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review article, where we start busting heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Forum Software Showdown Part 5: PunBB</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-5-PunBB/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2006 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-5-PunBB/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Almost there. This time, we&amp;#39;ll be looking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.punbb.org/&#34;&gt;PunBB&lt;/a&gt;. First, I did donate to PunBB development some time ago. At the time, I liked PunBB, and received some great support. It&amp;#39;s been sometime since that time, so I don&amp;#39;t know how things stand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anywho, &amp;ldquo;PunBB is a fast and lightweight PHP-powered discussion board. It is released under the GNU General Public License. Its primary goals are to be faster, smaller and less graphically intensive as compared to other discussion boards. PunBB has fewer features than many other discussion boards, but is generally faster and outputs smaller, semantically correct XHTML-compliant pages.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In this article, we&amp;#39;ll be installing PunBB version 1.2.14, which is the latest version, as of October 15, 2006.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;File and folder size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The zip file for MyBB weighs in at around 250 KB. Unzipped, we&amp;#39;re looking at a bit over 800 KB. The zip file does not contain a single folder, but rather three, so you&amp;#39;ll want to unzip to a single PunBB folder. PunBB is also available in gzip and bz2 formats.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Best requirements thus far. PHP 4.1.0+ and MySQL 3.23.17+, or PHP 4.3.0+ and PostgreSQL 7.0+, or SQLite. Not to shabby, as this is the first we&amp;#39;ve reviewed that supports something other than just MySQL for the database.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing on our local Web server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unlike past articles, for these forum reviews we&amp;#39;re going to create the necessary users and databases using the command line interface of MySQL. If you&amp;#39;re going to be installing these forums to a remote system, just create the user(s) and database(s) as usual (and that goes for if you&amp;#39;re installing it locally as well).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating the user and database via the command-line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, you&amp;#39;ll need to login to MySQL. Open up the Run prompt by going to Start &amp;gt; Run &amp;hellip; and type &lt;strong&gt;cmd&lt;/strong&gt;, then press Enter. At the prompt, if you&amp;#39;ve setup MySQL correctly, you can type the following command, followed by pressing Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     mysql -h localhost -u root -p
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be prompted to enter your password, which you&amp;#39;ll have already setup. Enter your password and press Enter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;re logged into MySQL. Now, we can create our database, create our user, and grant the user privilege to modify the database we created.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing PunBB, we&amp;#39;ll create a database called PunBB.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     create database PunBB;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, you&amp;#39;ll be told that &amp;ldquo;Query OK, 1 row affected&amp;rdquo;, followed by the execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, we&amp;#39;ll create a user with privileges to access the database. Note that other than the bold text, this command is case-insensitive. Also, you may want to change &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;punbb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39; to something different (as this is the user&amp;#39;s password).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Before you enter this, look it over, and then read the paragraph following, for an explanation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&lt;br /&gt;
    ON &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    TO &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;punbb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first line, &amp;ldquo;GRANT select, insert, update, delete, index, alter, create, drop&amp;rdquo;, states what privileges the user will be granted. The next line, &amp;ldquo;ON &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, states what the privileges are applied to. Finally, &amp;ldquo;TO &lt;strong&gt;PunBB&lt;/strong&gt; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;&lt;strong&gt;punbb&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;;&amp;rdquo; states what user will get these privileges. Since the user doesn&amp;#39;t exist yet, we&amp;#39;re also giving a password to the user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If the query is OK, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     UPDATE mysql.user SET Password = OLD&lt;em&gt;PASSWORD(&amp;#39;punbb&amp;#39;) WHERE User = &amp;#39;PunBB&amp;#39;;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If this query is OK, and it works, type &lt;strong&gt;exit&lt;/strong&gt;, and press Enter. Now attempt to login to the PunBB user. Once you&amp;#39;ve logged in, enter the following command.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
     show databases;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You should be given an ASCII table that shows there&amp;#39;s a database of punbb. Yippee.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, let&amp;#39;s install PunBB.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Installing PunBB&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, unzip the downloaded zip file. The files are within three folders in the zip file, so make sure you create a folder to dump these into. I&amp;#39;ll be using one called punbb.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since we&amp;#39;re installing locally, we don&amp;#39;t have to worry about permissions. So, once PunBB has been decompressed, navigate to the PunBB root folder in your browser. You&amp;#39;ll be told that config.php doesn&amp;#39;t exist, and be given a link to the install file. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/punbb/install.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/punbb/install.php&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;#39;s a form to fill-out, so let&amp;#39;s get to it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You can select your database type, which we&amp;#39;ll leave at MySQL Standard. Database server hostname can be left at localhost.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Database name: PunBB&lt;br /&gt;
Database username: PunBB&lt;br /&gt;
Database password: punbb&lt;br /&gt;
Table prefix: punbb&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Administrator username: admin&lt;br /&gt;
Password: cbe15b&lt;br /&gt;
Administrator&amp;#39;s e-mail: strivinglife@gmail.com&lt;br /&gt;
Base URL: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/punbb&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/punbb&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At this point, start the installation. Once that&amp;#39;s done, you&amp;#39;ll need to copy some text into a new config.php file, and then you can hit the main forum page at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/projects/punbb/&#34;&gt;http://localhost/projects/punbb/&lt;/a&gt; (for example).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How&amp;#39;s the code look?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Like most other forums, PunBB uses a table, and doesn&amp;#39;t care to declare a summary. However, that looks like the only issue.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Internally, code is commented pretty darn well. Not too shabby at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Default layout and administrative interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once installed, PunBB setups up one category, one forum, and one post.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, the look is very boxy, and reminds me of the look of a number of other forums. There&amp;#39;s really not that much, graphically, that separates it from the others. The look is very similar to MyBB, but much flatter.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Checking for updates, amongst other things, is quite easy from the interface. Unfortunately, when I attempted to check for updates, Apache started choking on me, specifically with problems in the php4ts.dll (as it did with MyBB).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
They do have archived files with the changed files only available for download, which is quite nice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The temporary conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
PunBB is pretty much like the others that we&amp;#39;ve reviewed. Until we get into the last forum, and start comparing all six, we&amp;#39;ll leave it at that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Stay tuned for the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP Forum&lt;/a&gt; review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Apache 2.0.59 to a Windows-based computer, locally: Part 3</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2006 16:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 1 of this Apache 2.0.59 guide&lt;/a&gt;, we setup Apache 2.0.59 on a Windows XP SP2 machine. We also setup Perl and mod_perl, attempting to mimic our Apache 1.3.34 install. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 2 of this Apache 2.0.59 guide&lt;/a&gt;, we setup ColdFusion MX 6.1 and 7.0. This time, we&#39;ll be continuing in our quest by adding support for both PHP 4 and PHP 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In previous guides, we &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-PHP-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;installed PHP 4&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Dual-installing-PHP-Running-PHP-5-and-4-on-the-same-local2c-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP 5&lt;/a&gt;, so if you need to install either one, do so with the above directions. If you&#39;ll be installing PHP 4 and PHP 5 for the first time, and have not installed on Apache 1.3.x already, then you may be able to pick and choose from these guides to get the information you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we do this, however, we need to think about just what we&#39;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until this point, you may have installed any (or none) of the below. (Keep in mind that you can generalize these if you have slightly newer versions. So, PHP 5.1.4 = PHP 5.x.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache 1.3.34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache 2.0.59&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 4.4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP 5.1.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ColdFusion MX 6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ColdFusion MX 7.0.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us a number of options on what our local Web server could be running at one time. For example, we could be running PHP 4, ColdFusion MX 6.1, and Apache 1.3.x or Apache 2.0.x. Likewise, we could use PHP 4 or PHP 5, or ColdFusion MX 6.1 or ColdFusion MX 7.0. Writing out a list of all of our possible combinations, we&#39;ve got something like the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF6.1_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF7.0_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF6.1_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache1.3_CF7.0_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF6.1_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF7.0_PHP4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF6.1_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache2.0_CF7.0_PHP5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we could also run our local server without the ColdFusion MX component, or PHP component at all. For ease, however, we&#39;ll just stick with one of the above possibilities. What this means is that for each of the above that you want to run, you&#39;ll need to have an httpd.conf file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed my above guides, than you should already have the Apache 1.3.x configuration files (although with slightly different names). Once we have all eight configurations, we can write batch files to automate most of the process. For getting these up and running. With one click (and maybe just a little renaming), we can have the Web server that we want up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you may have for Apache 1.3.x, I recommend you create a &#39;configuration&#39; folder in your DocumentRoot directory (so, c:\home\configuration\ if you&#39;ve been following along) where you can begin compiling httpd.conf files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I&#39;ve obviously followed by own guides, so I have four files thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should also have either one or two php.ini files &amp;ndash; one for PHP 4 and one for PHP 5 &amp;ndash; that we&#39;ll also want to put copies of in this folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP4.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP5.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache 1.3.x and Apache 2.0.x use the same php.ini files. So, it&#39;s not necessary to make one copy each for Apache 1.3.x and one each for 2.0.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This done, we can begin connecting to PHP 4 and PHP 5 on Apache 2.0.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hooking up PHP 4.4.2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous guide, we &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-PHP-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;installed PHP 4.4.2&lt;/a&gt; and in yet &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Moving-the-location-of-PHP-on-your-hard-drive.aspx&#34;&gt;a later guide moved our installation&lt;/a&gt; to the c:\php4\ folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we&#39;ve already got PHP 4 working on Apache 1.3.x, most of our setup is already complete. Now it&#39;s just a matter of hooking up Apache 2.0.x to recognize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we&#39;ll need to make sure we&#39;ve got a backup of the httpd.conf file in the C:\Program Files\Apache Group\Apache2\conf folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now open the Apache 2 httpd.conf file. Do a search for LoadModule, and at the end of this section, add the following line. Keep in mind that if you installed PHP 4 to a different folder, you should make that change here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LoadModule php4_module &#34;c:/php4/php4apache2.dll&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, do a search for AddType. After the first uncommented line (AddType application/x-gzip .gz .tgz), place the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AddType application/x-httpd-php .php&lt;br /&gt;AddType application/x-httpd-php-source .phps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, add &#39;index.php&#39; to the DirectoryIndex line, where ever you&#39;d like it be called in the order of things. Depending upon preference, you may also want to add index.htm, since Apache 2.0.x doesn&#39;t seem to want to include these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save httpd.conf. Now go to the c:\php4\ directory (or where you installed PHP 4) and copy the php4apache2.dll from the sapi folder into the root PHP folder. So, from c:\php4\sapi\ to c:\php4\.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For php.ini, everything should be setup correctly. However, you&#39;ll want to verify that the right php.ini file is in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now start Apache2 from the Services panel (or the Apache Services Monitor) and you should find that the description lists PHP 4. If you go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/phpinfo.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/phpinfo.php&lt;/a&gt; (if you created this file), you should also find that PHP is up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure both your ColdFusion MX 6.1 and ColdFusion MX 7.0 httpd.conf files have the httpd.conf changes made, and you can switch between either version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Connecting to PHP 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you&#39;ve already setup PHP 4 for Apache 2.0.x, using the instructions above, moving to PHP 5 is extremely easy. So easy, in fact, that it&#39;s scary. Make a copy of any httpd.conf files you may have for PHP 4. For example, the two I have in C:\Program Files\Apache Group\Apache2\conf\ are called httpd_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf and httpd_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll copy both of these and rename them to httpd_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf and httpd_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf. That done open both up and do a search for php4, one file at a time. You&#39;ll find php4 three times, in the following line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LoadModule php4_module &#34;c:/php4/php4apache2.dll&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which you&#39;ll simply change to three &#39;5&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LoadModule php5_module &#34;c:/php5/php5apache2.dll&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now save the httpd.conf files. The php5apache2.dll file will already be in this location, so you should be set to go. Make a copy of either one of these, make sure that you&#39;re using the right php.ini file, restart Apache2, and verify that phpinfo() gives the correct information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn&#39;t that easy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Now that PHP 4 and/or PHP 5 are installed ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&#39;ve setup PHP 4 and/or PHP 5 with Apache 2.0.x, it&#39;s time to backup the necessary .conf files into our &#39;configuration&#39; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll have up to ten files in this folder (c:\home\configuration\). Up to eight .conf files and up to two .ini files. I&#39;ve listed all ten possibilities below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX6.1_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX6.1_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX7.0_PHP4.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_CFMX7.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP4.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;php_Apache_PHP5.ini &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s create a blank text file called zblank.txt. Next, we should determine whether we want to have a version that does not run ColdFusion MX. If you want to, read the next section. Otherwise, skip the next section and read the following one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--nextpage--&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Removing ColdFusion MX from our configurations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remove ColdFusion MX, you&#39;ll need four more httpd.conf files. Two for Apache 1.3.x and two for Apache 2.0.x, as each has two versions of PHP. Since it doesn&#39;t matter which one we take from, just copy the four httpd.conf files that reference CFMX6.1 in their file names.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, simply remove the &#39;Copy of &#39; and &#39;CFMX&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;&#39; from the four file names. You&#39;ll end up with the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_PHP4.conf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache1.3_PHP5.conf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_PHP4.conf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;httpd_Apache2.0_PHP5.conf &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s just a couple of things to remove from each of these conf files. The following block will need to be removed from the Apache 1.3.x files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# JRun Settings&lt;br /&gt;LoadModule jrun_module &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/1/mod_jrun.so&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;IfModule mod_jrun.c&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Verbose false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Apialloc false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ssl false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ignoresuffixmap false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Serverstore &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/1/jrunserver.store&#34;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Bootstrap 127.0.0.1:51010&lt;br /&gt;#JRunConfig Errorurl &amp;lt;optionally redirect to this URL on errors&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;AddHandler jrun-handler .jsp .jws .cfm .cfml .cfc&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this block will need to be removed from the Apache 2.0.x files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# JRun Settings&lt;br /&gt;LoadModule jrun_module &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/2/mod_jrun20.so&#34;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;IfModule mod_jrun20.c&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Verbose false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Apialloc false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ssl false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Ignoresuffixmap false&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Serverstore &#34;C:/CFusionMX/runtime/lib/wsconfig/2/jrunserver.store&#34;&lt;br /&gt;JRunConfig Bootstrap 127.0.0.1:51010&lt;br /&gt;#JRunConfig Errorurl &amp;lt;optionally redirect to this URL on errors&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;AddHandler jrun-handler .jsp .jws .cfm .cfml .cfc&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/IfModule&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure &#39;index.cfm index.cfml&#39; is removed from the DirectoryIndex lines in each file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By allowing our Apache 2.0.x server, and Apache 1.3.x server, to run without checking for ColdFusion MX, we can keep it running quick, even if we decide not to start any versions of ColdFusion MX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we have left is hooking up MySQL and PostgreSQL and creating batch files to use these httpd.conf and php.ini files to get the server we want up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let the hardest part begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Connecting to MySQL and PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazingly enough, as long as you already setup MySQL and PostgreSQL for Apache 1.3.x, you&#39;re all set to begin using MySQL and PostgreSQL for both ColdFusion MX 6.1, ColdFusion MX 7.0, PHP 4, and PHP 5. This is because ColdFusion MX is handling the SQL requests via the datasources, and PHP is likewise handling it&#39;s own requests (via the php.ini file).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to test this using the PHP files I detailed before (&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-MySQL-and-phpMyAdmin-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;check MySQL connection in PHP&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-PostgreSQL-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;check PostgreSQL connection in PHP&lt;/a&gt;) or just using the ColdFusion MX Administrator to check all datasources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coming in Part 4 ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Part 4, I&#39;ll be going over how to create the batch files that we&#39;ll need to work with the httpd.conf and php.ini files that we&#39;ve created. While I could detail it here, better to just put it in it&#39;s own article/post, as that makes things much easier (if not for you, then at least for me ;)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding PostgreSQL connectivity to ColdFusion MX on a local Windows-based, Apache, server</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Adding-PostgreSQL-connectivity-to-ColdFusion-MX-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2006 06:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Adding-PostgreSQL-connectivity-to-ColdFusion-MX-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having already &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Adding-MySQL-connectivity-to-ColdFusion-MX-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;added MySQL support for ColdFusion MX&lt;/a&gt;, it&#39;s time to look at adding PostgreSQL. For many of the same reasons we installed PostgreSQL with PHP, we&#39;ll be doing this to add to our potential resources. However, unlike our connection of MySQL with ColdFusion MX, we&#39;ll need to install some additional features to ColdFusion MX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This guide assumes you&#39;ve already &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-PostgreSQL-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;installed PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloading and installing the JDBC Driver&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we&#39;ll need to do is install a special driver for ColdFusion. This driver can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jdbc.postgresql.org/&#34;&gt;http://jdbc.postgresql.org/&lt;/a&gt;. Select Download from the left-side navigation, and you&#39;ll be presented with a lot of options. Before we go any further, we&#39;ll need to determine what version we&#39;ll need to download, which will involve determining our version of JDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine this, find where you installed ColdFusion MX, and look in the runtime\jre\ folder. If you&#39;re not sure of where this is, make sure ColdFusion is started and open the ColdFusion Administrator (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/CFIDE/administrator/index.cfm&#34;&gt;http://localhost/CFIDE/administrator/index.cfm&lt;/a&gt; if you&#39;ve been following along).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, select Java and JVM under SERVER SETTINGS, on the left side. You&#39;ll now see a box detailing the Java Virtual Machine Path. Go to this location and open the README.txt file. Here, you&#39;ll be able to determine the version. You can also determine your version by checking the Server Information under ColdFusion Administrator. If you&#39;ve been following along, you&#39;re probably using version 1.4.2. Because of this, and because we&#39;re using PostgreSQL 8.1, we&#39;ll download the JDBC 3, 8.1 Build 405 version (8.1-405 JDBC 3), which is about 400 KB. Save this to your downloads directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now copy this file and move it to C:\CFusionMX\wwwroot\WEB-INF\classes, if you&#39;ve installed ColdFusion to c:\CFusionMX\. Otherwise, substitute as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, enter the path and name of this file into the Class Path field in ColdFusion Administrator, with a comma at the end. For example, &#34;C:/CFusionMX/wwwroot/WEB-INF/classes/postgresql-8.1-405.jdbc3.jar,&#34; (no quotes). Note that we&#39;ve replaced the &#39;\&#39; with &#39;/&#39; in the path. Now Submit Changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, open the file at C:\CFusionMX\lib\neo-query.xml in Notepad. Do a search for postgresql, and scroll through until you find the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;var name=&#39;handler&#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;postgresql.cfm&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/var&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change this to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;var name=&#39;handler&#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;default.cfm&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/var&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, restart ColdFusion via the Services panel. Note that it may take a little longer for ColdFusion to start, since we&#39;ve added a new class for ColdFusion to load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, log back into ColdFusion Administrator and select Data Sources under DATA &amp;amp; SERVICES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creating a new database in PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we&#39;ll need to do is create a new database in PostgreSQL. Start pgAdmin and connect to the PostgreSQL Database Server 8.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve connected, right click on Databases (1), and select New Database. Type in a Name (I used ColdFusion), select an Owner (we&#39;ll just use postgres for now), and select a Tablespace (pg_default). Now hit OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding PostgreSQL as a data source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll now add PostgreSQL as a data source in ColdFusion Administrator. In the Data Source Name, type in PostgreSQL, and select other for Driver. Now hit Add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JDBC URL: jdbc:postgresql://localhost:5432/ColdFusion&lt;br /&gt;Driver Class: org.postgresql.Driver&lt;br /&gt;Driver Name: PostgreSQL&lt;br /&gt;Username: postgres&lt;br /&gt;Password: your_password (note, this will have been the second password you used, not the first)&lt;br /&gt;Description: PostgreSQL database for ColdFusion MX 6.1. (or whatever you want to type)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that for JDBC URL, &#39;ColdFusion&#39; should match the name of the database you created in PostreSQL above. Other than that and Username, your settings should match mine above. Once you do this, it should verify as OK. You can optionally Verify All Connections to verify them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a PostgreSQL table in ColdFusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll now create a new file in Notepad and paste the following text within it, to test our ColdFusion to PostgreSQL connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;coldfusion&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;cfquery name=&#34;CreateNewDatabase&#34; datasource=&#34;PostgreSQL&#34;&amp;gt;
CREATE TABLE TestDatabase (
    TestColumn1 text,
    TestColumn2 text
);
CREATE UNIQUE INDEX TestDatabase_TestColumn1_TestColumn2_uidx ON TestDatabase (TestColumn1,TestColumn2);
&amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;cfoutput&amp;gt;If you see this, the table has been created&amp;lt;/cfoutput&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save and run this file (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/coldfusionmx6_1/CreatePostgreSQLTable.cfm&#34;&gt;http://localhost/coldfusionmx6_1/CreatePostgreSQLTable.cfm&lt;/a&gt;), and you should see a notification that the table has been created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If pgAdmin isn&#39;t still running, start it up and dig way down to find this table: PostgreSQL Database Server 8.1 &amp;gt; Databases &amp;gt; ColdFusion &amp;gt; Schemas &amp;gt; public &amp;gt; Tables &amp;gt; testdatabase. Whew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you run this file again, you&#39;ll receive an error message, saying that the table already exists. Because we haven&#39;t added a check into this code to verify whether the table already exists, we&#39;ll hit a wall. Obviously, we&#39;d have to add this code in in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dropping/deleting our test table&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve verified that you can create a table, it&#39;s time to delete it. Add the following code to the end of the existing code, or create a new document with this code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;coldfusion&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;cfquery name=&#34;DropNewDatabase&#34; datasource=&#34;PostgreSQL&#34;&amp;gt;
    DROP TABLE TestDatabase
&amp;lt;/cfquery&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;cfoutput&amp;gt;If you see this, the table has been dropped&amp;lt;/cfoutput&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run this code, and check pgAdmin to verify that the table no longer exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, note that if you run this code (just this last part), and the table already has been dropped, you&#39;ll get an error. Again, something that would have to be fixed in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations once again, as you&#39;ve successfully setup ColdFusion and PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with MySQL, you can access any tables you setup in ColdFusion with PHP, and vice versa, so long as ColdFusion has the data source entered into ColdFusion Administrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/a-local-apache-web-server-on-a-windows-xp-computer/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing PostgreSQL on a local Windows-based, Apache, server</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-PostgreSQL-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2006 23:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Installing-PostgreSQL-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While we&#39;ve already &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-MySQL-and-phpMyAdmin-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;setup MySQL&lt;/a&gt;, another popular SQL server is PostgreSQL. Like MySQL, PostgreSQL is absolutely free, and will allow us to create databases on our local server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Downloading PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll be downloading the most current version of PostgreSQL, which is 8.1.3 at the time of this writing. You can download the installation file from &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.postgresql.org/ftp/win32&#34;&gt;http://www.postgresql.org/ftp/win32&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;ll want to download the regular zip file, called postgresql-8.1.3-1.zip, and weighing in at 21 MB. You&#39;ll want to save this to the same folder you save your other installers &amp;ndash; c:\home\downloads\ if you&#39;ve been following along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is also applicable to version PostgreSQL 8.2.3 (postgresql-8.2.3-1.zip), with minor changes (noted below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the download has finished, extract the contents to a temporary folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Install PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&#39;ve downloaded the zip and extracted it, run postgresql-8.1.msi, not postgresql-8.1-int.msi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll be prompted to select a language for the &lt;em&gt;installation&lt;/em&gt;. I chose English. Also, you can either check Write detailed installation log to postgresql-8.1.log in the current directory, or not. If you do, a log of the installation will be saved to the temporary folder. Click Next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read through the Installation Notes, and press Next. For Installation options, leave everything as default, and select Next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Service configuration, Install as a service. Leave Service name the default of PostgreSQL Database Server 8.1, and Account name the default of postgres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In PostgreSQL 8.2.3, the Service name will be version 8.2. This is so that you can run more than one version at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Account domain will default as the name of your computer, and we can leave this as is, but make a note of it. Mine was PAVA620N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, fill in Account password and Verify password, or leave these empty to have the installer create a (very long) password. Make sure you make a note of this password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you click through, a pop-up will say that the user was not found. Click Yes to create an account. If your password is weak, it will say so and offer to create a password for you. Again, this will be a very long password, so if you want to change your password, select No and press Back to try a new password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t recall your password, you can change it by going to the Windows command line and typing the following, where &lt;strong&gt;postgres&lt;/strong&gt; is the username and &lt;strong&gt;password&lt;/strong&gt; is the new password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;net user postgres password&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, Initialise database cluster, keep the defaults, but change Encoding to UTF-8. Make a note that the Port number is 5432. Keep the default Superuser name of postgres, but create a unique password &amp;ndash; not the one you used previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve installed Perl, then you&#39;ll be able to check a couple of boxes. Pick the PL/pgsql and PL/perl checkboxes. Otherwise, just pick PL/pgsql. Click Next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Enable contrib modules, only pick the default of Admin81. Click Next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In PostgreSQL 8.2.3, the default is Adminpack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you&#39;ll be &#34;Ready to install.&#34; Click Next to install, and watch the Installation proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the installation has finished, you can choose to subscribe to pgsql-announce. Otherwise, click Finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Verify installation of PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, delete the temporary folder, but keep the log file, if you&#39;d like, and if you opted to create one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, go to Start &amp;gt; All Programs &amp;gt; PostgreSQL 8.1 &amp;gt; pgAdmin III Copy this shortcut to where you store your other shortcuts, and then run this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we check Help &amp;gt; About, we&#39;ll see the version of pgAdmin. Mine is Version 1.4.1. If we need to, we can upgrade this program outside of PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In PostgreSQL 8.2.3, pgAdmin 1.6.2 is installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, right click on PostgreSQL Database Server 8.1 and select Connect. Enter the second password from above, and connect. Once you&#39;ve connected, expand the tree as necessary. To disconnect, select Disconnect after right clicking on PostgreSQL Database Server 8.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting up PHP to connect with PostgreSQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open php.ini and do a search for pgsql. Uncomment &#34;extension=php_pgsql.dll&#34;, by removing the ;, and then save and close php.ini. Now, restart Apache via Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/phpinfo.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/phpinfo.php&lt;/a&gt; and search for pgsql, you should see some information on your installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we&#39;ll be testing the connection by creating a very small php file. Create a new file called postgresqlconnection.php, with the below text. Make sure you change PASSWORD as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;?php
$user=&#34;postgres&#34;;
$password=&#34;PASSWORD&#34;;

$connection = pg_connect(&#34;host=localhost user=$user password=$password&#34;) or die(&#34;Connection failed.&#34; . pg_last_error());
echo &#34;Connected to PostgreSQL.&#34;;
pg_close($connection);
?&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save this to your default Web server directory &amp;ndash; c:\home\. Now visit &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/postgresqlconnection.php&#34;&gt;http://localhost/postgresqlconnection.php&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats, you should see &#34;Connected to PostgreSQL.&#34; and have now setup PostgreSQL to work with PHP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/local-apache-server/&#34;&gt;View all of the steps to creating a local Web server, for development.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A local, Apache Web server, on a Windows XP computer</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/A-local2c-Apache-Web-server2c-on-a-Windows-XP-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2006 03:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/A-local2c-Apache-Web-server2c-on-a-Windows-XP-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My intention is to write a number of guides that will help someone build a functional Web server for testing purposes. Since Windows is fairly popular, I&#39;ve decided to outline how to install Web server programs on it. Since Apache is both powerful and free, I&#39;ve opted to use it as the core, instead of IIS, or the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also plan on keeping the various technologies up-to-date, yet continuing to provide the instructions for past versions used, just in case. I do have copies of the versions I&#39;ve installed below, and would be happy to provide those copies that no longer exist elsewhere; just ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Our local Web server uses the following technology.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apache&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache 2.2.4 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Apache-224-to-a-Windows-based-computer-locally-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 1: Setting up Apache 2.2.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache 2.0.59 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 1: Apache 2.0.59, Perl, mod_perl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-2.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 2: ColdFusion MX 6.1 and ColdFusion MX 7.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-3.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 3: PHP 4.4.2 and PHP 5.1.4, with MySQL and PostgreSQL support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-4.aspx&#34;&gt;Part 4: Using batch files to switch between versions of our local server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Apache-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally.aspx&#34;&gt;Apache 1.3.34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.htaccess file 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Error-handling-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;Error Handling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perl&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Upgrading-(our-local-install-of)-ActivePerl.aspx&#34;&gt;ActivePerl 5.8.8.819&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Perl-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;ActivePerl 5.8.7.815&lt;/a&gt;, ActivePerl 5.8.8.817&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-mod_perl-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;mod_perl 1.0: version 1.29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Apache-2059-to-a-Windows-based-computer2c-locally-Part-1.aspx&#34;&gt;mod_perl 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Python-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;ActivePython 2.4.3.12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHP&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Upgrading-PHP-(442-to-444-and-514-to-520).aspx&#34;&gt;Upgrading PHP 4.x and/or PHP 5.x&lt;/a&gt; (4.4.2 to 4.4.4 and 5.1.4 to 5.2.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-PHP-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP 4.4.2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Dual-installing-PHP-Running-PHP-5-and-4-on-the-same-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;PHP 5.1.4&lt;/a&gt; (with the ability to run one or the other) 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Python-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;Changing our PHP directory name/location&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Upgrading-to-Zend-Optimizer-301-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;Zend Optimizer 3.0.1&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Zend-Optimizer-on-a-local-Windows-based2c-Apache2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;Zend Optimizer 2.6.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MySQL&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL 4.1.18: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-MySQL-and-phpMyAdmin-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;with PHP 4.4.2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Dual-installing-PHP-Running-PHP-5-and-4-on-the-same-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;with PHP 5.1.4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/?p=69&#34;&gt;with ColdFusion MX 6.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.net/wordpress/2006/06/20/154/upgrading-phpmyadmin-270-pl2-to-281-on-a-local-windows-based-apache-server/&#34;&gt;phpMyAdmin 2.8.1&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-MySQL-and-phpMyAdmin-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;phpMyAdmin 2.7.0-pl2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-MySQL-Administrator-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;MySQL Administrator 1.1.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-MySQL-Query-Browser-1120-on-a-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;MySQL Query Browser 1.1.20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL 8.1.3 or PostgreSQL 8.2.3 and pgAdmin 1.4.1 or pgAdmin 1.6.2: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-PostgreSQL-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;with PHP 4.4.2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Dual-installing-PHP-Running-PHP-5-and-4-on-the-same-local-Windows-based-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;with PHP 5.1.4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Adding-PostgreSQL-connectivity-to-ColdFusion-MX-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;with ColdFusion MX 6.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ColdFusion&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-ColdFusion-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;ColdFusion MX 6.1 Developer Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Upgrading-our-installation-of-ColdFusion-MX-701-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;ColdFusion MX 7.0.2 Developer Edition&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-ColdFusion-MX-701-on-a-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-server.aspx&#34;&gt;ColdFusion MX 7.0.1 Developer Edition&lt;/a&gt; (upgrade, but with the ability to swap to 6.1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Upgrading-(our-local-install-of)-WordPress.aspx&#34;&gt;WordPress 2.0.5&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Setting-up-WordPress-on-a-local-Web-server.aspx&#34;&gt;WordPress 2.0.1&lt;/a&gt;, 2.0.2, 2.0.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Log-file-analysis-of-our-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-Web-sites.aspx&#34;&gt;Analog 6.0&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other software to try: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Log-file-analysis-of-our-Windows-based%2c-Apache%2c-Web-sites.aspx&#34;&gt;WebLog Expert Lite 3.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Creating-a-Microsoft-Management-Console-for-our-local-Windows-based%2c-Apache-server.aspx&#34;&gt;Microsoft Management Console setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/Installing-Eclipse-32-to-a-Windows-XP-SP2-machine.aspx&#34;&gt;Eclipse 3.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versioning control&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Installing-Subversion-and-TortoiseSVN-to-a-Windows-XP-Home-Edition-SP2-local-machine-with-Dreamweaver-8.aspx&#34;&gt;Subversion, TortoiseSVN and Dreamweaver 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown.aspx&#34;&gt;Forums&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-1-bbPress.aspx&#34;&gt;bbPress 0.73&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-4-MyBB.aspx&#34;&gt;MyBB 1.2.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-6-phpBB.aspx&#34;&gt;phpBB 2.0.21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-5-PunBB.aspx&#34;&gt;PunBB 1.2.14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-3-Simple-Machines.aspx&#34;&gt;Simple Machines 1.0.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/words/post/PHP-Forum-Software-Showdown-Part-2-Vanilla.aspx&#34;&gt;Vanilla 1.0.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The following upgrades are planned for addition (in no particular order):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL 4.1.21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;phpMyAdmin 2.9.1.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PostgreSQL 8.1.5 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pgAdmin III 1.6.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The following information is planned for expanding the tutorials, in no particular order:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World&#39;s simplest, but professionally functional, Web page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MagpieRSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to restore WordPress/MySQL using phpMyAdmin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to setup a CMS (Joomla and possibly Mambo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWStats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FusionReactor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sending mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FTP?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As new pages are added, I will add additional links and items to the above. If you would like me to cover a particular program, please let me know - any possible additions to this list would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
