<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Persona on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/persona/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Persona on James Skemp&#39;s StrivingLife</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content copyright 1999-2016 James Skemp, unless otherwise noted. This work is licensed under the Creative Commons License Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 19:54:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/persona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Persona 4 pre-order goody = wow</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Persona-4-pre-order-goody-equals-wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 19:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Persona-4-pre-order-goody-equals-wow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Mustn&amp;#39;t ... look ... too ... closely ... (already ruined one surprise)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Atlus certainly out-did themselves this time, with the Persona 4 pre-order goody. While I was expecting the &amp;quot;Visual Data&amp;quot; bonus to be large enough to fit behind the game&amp;#39;s case, like the Persona 3 bonus, this one is actually graphic novel sized. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Very nice Atlus, very nice. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And, with reviews like this, looks like we can expect a Persona 5 in the near future. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now it&amp;#39;s just a question of what the soundtrack is like ... but I&amp;#39;m too hesitant to pop that in before I start playing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1+ hours of text and video before gameplay, here I come! (As soon as the guide gets here, of course :D) (Unless I really &lt;em&gt;won&amp;#39;t&lt;/em&gt; get it until next Monday. Come Saturday evening, I&amp;#39;m popping it in.)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persona 3 Shuffle trick</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Persona-3-Shuffle-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 15:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Persona-3-Shuffle-trick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve spent a couple of hours, the last couple of days, playing Persona 3 (Playstation 2). After winning certain battles, you can get a &amp;#39;shuffle&amp;#39; mode of two or three cards (at least, as far as I&amp;#39;ve gotten). 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, you see what the cards are, they turn over, and then they&amp;#39;re shuffled. They are all usually good, but just to different degrees; for example, you might already have what one of the card would give, and you&amp;#39;ve been getting real crap for what another card would give, ... and there&amp;#39;s also the odd card, every once in a while, that actually is fairly bad. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anywho, I&amp;#39;ve determined that there is a system to it. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For two cards, if they shuffle slowly, the cards will just be switched around; the first card will now be the second, and vice versa. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For two cards, if they shuffle fast, the cards will be in the same spots as when they started. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;m only near the end of May, and have just started into block 2, but it seems to be working thus far. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There seems to be a similar system for three cards as well - they move one to the right for some shuffle, I think ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, I obviously need to figure that out as well, but ... it&amp;#39;s a start.&amp;nbsp; 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>