<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prose on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/categories/prose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prose on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 22:13:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/categories/prose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Night Walk - 7/24/2010</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Night-Walk-07-24-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 22:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Night-Walk-07-24-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A white light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group of kids, playing a game of basketball, laughing, not keeping score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lights illuminating plants, a woman straightening her&#39;s in a newly purchased house, one she may not have been able to enjoy before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Ray Bradbury, I believe, who wrote of a man who walked at night, and before being arrested for doing so, thought of the people sitting inside, their faces illuminated only by the light of a television. But there&#39;s something about a dark room, flickering with that changing light. Calming? Relaxing? It&#39;s the sign of the known. No matter what they might be watching - a movie, a sports game, a sitcom - it&#39;s familar, a common bond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light shining from the basement windows, from the second floor, but the first floor is dark. Is the basement full of work, or play? Has it been forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light creeping out through the top of a curtain, blocked for a moment in regular beats. Is the ceiling fan wood? Painted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A late night visitor, staying for only a moment before going back to their truck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rabbit seen, staring, as two others bounce away. The third follows. Another shortly thereafter. It too decides to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People passed, given a nod and a smile. A younger couple, pushing a stroller. Safe to meet their eyes. But other than the eye contact and allowing for room to pass - for some reason it seemed he&#39;d step in front, but he did the right thing - nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another light, a soft yellow light, comes from above blinds. It&#39;s a kitchen light. I know because I turned it on, knowing it would be dark when I got back. A cat, probably lazing somewhere, but awake. She greats me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten muscles</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Forgotten-muscles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 22:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Forgotten-muscles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The long forgetten muscles&lt;br /&gt;and dozens of cuts on my arms and hands&lt;br /&gt;as if in a single voice&lt;br /&gt;say &#34;Hey buddy.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sound of contempt does not go unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The gods in their place</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/The-gods-in-their-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 07:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/The-gods-in-their-place/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The gods&lt;br /&gt;in their place&lt;br /&gt;no not&lt;br /&gt; of my face.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random - &#34;some walking stuff&#34;</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Random-some-walking-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 22:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Random-some-walking-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Found in &amp;quot;some walking stuff.txt,&amp;quot; dated Sunday, July 20, 2003, 8:18 PM.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    The old ones walk down the road on their way to eternity&lt;br /&gt;
    They do not stop on the way, they merely make their way&lt;br /&gt;
    On ... on ... on stopping for none - needing no help
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    They brought what they need on their back&lt;br /&gt;
    They need not turn back&lt;br /&gt;
    They do not look behind them, to see that which they have left behind&lt;br /&gt;
    They are happy with that which has passed, with that which has occured
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    Is their humour among these men - no, none that anyone can see&lt;br /&gt;
    Yet their hearts are not empty, their hearts are not still&lt;br /&gt;
    They walk yet they live, like few others do&lt;br /&gt;
    They know that they have done what they must, what they can
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A search for the first sentence turned up nothing today. Original?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh the people that you meet</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Oh-the-people-that-you-meet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 20:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Oh-the-people-that-you-meet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Oh the people that you meet,&lt;br /&gt;
when you&amp;#39;re walking down the street,&lt;br /&gt;
can never make you cry,&lt;br /&gt;
if only you remember why.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On one fine day</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/On-one-fine-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 07:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/On-one-fine-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
On one fine day&lt;br /&gt;
you&amp;#39;ll be old and grey&lt;br /&gt;
and you&amp;#39;ll sit and wonder&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#39;where art thy plunder?&amp;#39;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ll tell you once,&lt;br /&gt;
so please don&amp;#39;t be a dunce,&lt;br /&gt;
when that day appears&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;#39;m sure you&amp;#39;ll be sitting on your rear!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Semi-True Tale of Shelly and Allen</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/The-Semi-True-Tale-of-Shelly-and-Allen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2005 02:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/The-Semi-True-Tale-of-Shelly-and-Allen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
May 14th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I thank you for your kind words tonight at the Olympus Centre of the Arts. It&amp;rsquo;s not very often I get a standing ovation, and I believe it is solely due to you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Ever since we first met, last night, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a strong connection to you, and this indeed fills me with great happiness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Again, I thank you for you continued help and guidance,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
May 16th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;It was indeed my pleasure to be there on the 14th, but I fear that I cannot take credit for the, well deserved, standing ovation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Please call on me if you need anything at all,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
May 17th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;You are far too humble. Had it not been for you, the night would not have gone the way it had.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I thank you from the bottom of my heart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
May 20th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I fear humbleness has little to do with it. The part I played was naught compared to what you have brought to those present.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
May 21st
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;You are like an innocent little boy sometimes, my dear Allen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;You really did do more than you take credit for, and you know that quite well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
June 21st
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Can I really call upon you at any time Allen? I always appreciate your help, as I hope that you know.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I await your word,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
June 22nd
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Of course I will always lend a hand when able. Do you have something on your mind? Can I assist in any way?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
June 23rd
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I longed to hear those words from you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I love you Allen, and must have you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Be mine forever Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
June 27th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;You know that I would help if I could. Please tell me if you need anything.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
June 28th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Oh Allen, it is you that I need!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly, the one who will always love you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
July 15th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;As I said before, I would assist if I could. Is there nothing else you need?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
July 16th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Oh Allen, are you truly blind? It is you need that I need and love, like the animals and birds love and need the water and air!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Would not the mosquito die if it were not for the blood of the cow and ox, or some other, similarly blooded, animal?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;Oh Allen, tell me that you love me!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Your forever love (?),
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
August 29th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I fear your last communication just reached me now, and was quite blurred. Please let me know if there is anything I can do for you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
August 30th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen! Can you not see that I would kill myself like the fruit fly kills itself after a late autumn gorging?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The animals, like the monkey, would cry out your name, if only they knew it, my Allen, my sweet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You are the Adam, and I want to be the Eve - can you not see!?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Come to me, soon, my Allen, my forever Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 1st
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen! Are you quite well?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 1st
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen? I have not heard from you in so many days. Please, please, let me know that you are well!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 2nd
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Do you do this to see if I will come back? I, like the canary, will fly back into the cage. If you let me go, I will go back, even if I must bend the bars like Mobes of Galand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Call upon me soon, my Allen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 10th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen! I am starving without you! I can only live so long, in this state of perpetual death! Come to me!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 11th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I have before me a knife, and it is covered in red, like the colour of blood.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 11th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Allen,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;I am killing myself right now, as I write to you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
September 18th
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Did my response not elicit a single response from you?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s always George, I suppose.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Farewell, you fool. You have truly let a fantastic woman out of your grasp.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cordially,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shelly
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As I walked down the valley I saw beside me a small dog</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/As-I-walked-down-the-valley-I-saw-beside-me-a-small-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2005 01:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/As-I-walked-down-the-valley-I-saw-beside-me-a-small-dog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
As I walked down the valley I saw beside me a small dog I do not know where the dog came from pans I do not care now however the one thing that always is the survey is the fact that&amp;rsquo;s dog skin and you&amp;rsquo;re out of nowhere at any time one thing I remember from my childhood visibly an atomic and his team was young But I don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s the team from do not know where he came from again on all my state and that batters and jury of of life and science and field Sophia
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Whenever I think about dogs and cats and while some stuff of science and pricing five wonder whether or not signed from force the King arts degree? The human beings as when we come from and why and doing away I suppose I suppose I suppose 30 to one is enough but that sometimes I I really wonder if it is enough so that someone three to one is greater than or equal to former. The 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying Perfume</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Buying-Perfume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2005 02:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Buying-Perfume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
She was an attractive woman, quite attractive in fact. She was the kind of girl that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but smile at if she gave you her eyes, even if you were having one of the most shit-filled days in your life up to that point.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
She walked over, not quickly, but not slow. It was a perfect pace for a girl in her profession. If you move to quickly, you make the customer think that you&amp;rsquo;re desperate, while moving too slow gives off a feeling of disinterest, or boredom, both of which scare a customer away, or instil a like sensation within them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No, she was moving towards me just right.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I see you&amp;rsquo;re looking at the Don Pierre.&amp;rdquo; She was quite right. &amp;ldquo;Are you looking for something in particular?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I replied that I was not with a &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo; and a sheepish grin. Could I date her? Probably. That&amp;rsquo;s what you start asking yourself, the older you get. You now longer wonder how old a girl is, you just wonder whether you could date her. Of course, it was important to keep in mind that this answered the question of whether she was legal, since you based your answer not on &amp;lsquo;would you date her&amp;rsquo;, but rather &amp;lsquo;could you date her&amp;rsquo;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, I could date her, so she was around my age. But, women do have this way of making themselves look younger than they are. She could pass as 18, but she could be in her semi-late twenties. Semi-late? Hmm. Women will do that to you &amp;ndash; women aren&amp;rsquo;t known for their rationality, rather for their sensuality.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyway. &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s the lucky lady?&amp;rdquo; I knew she was going to ask so when she did it was surprising that it took me by surprise. Duh, of course she&amp;rsquo;s going to ask.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s for me.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s what I should have said. She probably would have taken it as a joke, if I said it jokingly. Maybe I had screwed up and was scouting about. Maybe it was an anniversary, and I loved the smell. Maybe I just loved the smell.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One of those is the right idea, which I suppose makes the other the right idea as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, again I say, I just smiled sheepishly once more. That opened it up for what I could answer quite a bit. Now it could be a gift for blood. Maybe that was the wrong answer, but the other options were just as bad.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not like I have a chance with this women before me. She&amp;rsquo;s attractive and doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be a bitch. That means she&amp;rsquo;s either got a boyfriend, she has her eye on some guy who she hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet, or can&amp;rsquo;t, attain, or she&amp;rsquo;s not interested in a relationship at this time. She could also be a lesbian, not to discount the validity of that path by one iota. There&amp;rsquo;s no other reason for an attractive women, who isn&amp;rsquo;t a bitch, to not have a boyfriend. Well, it could be that every guy that wants to ask her out can&amp;rsquo;t because they all think that she&amp;rsquo;s either one of the above, or way out of their league.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, she could be single.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Excuse me. May I buy you dinner?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah. Like that&amp;rsquo;s really going to happen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hmph. All this &amp;lsquo;stuff&amp;rsquo; going through my head, all while I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the counter trying to pick out some perfume.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ah, now the title makes sense. First it maybe sounds a little sensuous. &amp;ldquo;Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s a story about the narrator meeting a stripper with really nice perfume. After falling in love with her &amp;ndash; obviously someone never watched &lt;em&gt;Moulin Rouge!&lt;/em&gt;, or didn&amp;rsquo;t get it &amp;ndash; he buys her perfume, takes it to her one night, but sees her dancing for someone else. In a fit of sorrow, he shatters the perfume bottle and stabs his eyes, pushing them out of his skull, like one would push a clam out of it&amp;rsquo;s shell.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No. Sadly, this story is far less interesting, less bloody, will not discuss massive amounts of skin, and is far more sickening. You see, I was out shopping for perfume merely because I had ran out that very morning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t wear the perfume; I just buy it and spray it about. There&amp;rsquo;s a song from many years ago, about a &amp;lsquo;junk food junkie&amp;rsquo;. This song says that the junkie would hide in a closet and eat his junk food, while in public he would eat only natural foods. My habit is quite similar.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You see, many years ago my heart, some would say my soul, perhaps my mind, finally &amp;lsquo;shattered like a glass goblin&amp;rsquo;. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the Harlan Ellison story titled this, then you&amp;rsquo;re aware of what I mean. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with the Harlan Ellison story, then chances are you either know what I mean, or will know what I mean, very soon indeed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I can&amp;rsquo;t quite remember when it was, and chances are it was not one moment, but rather a gradual process. Not a shattering, but a disintegrating, as the mountains slowly erode away.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, I had taken to buying perfume, as if I was buying it for some lucky lady, hiding it away, and, when I knew that I was alone and would not be caught, going into my closet and spraying a fine mist in the air before me, so that I could dip my head into the cloud of scent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sad, indeed, but it is who I am, by what I have been.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So that is why I could not answer the young woman who was helping me make a purchase. If I told her the truth, could I honestly expect her to not laugh and not look horrified? No. If I told her, or anyone else for that matter, I, gentle reader, would be introduced again to a feeling that I am quite aware of, for we have met before.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So I leave this tale to you. To those who read this and are male &amp;ndash; beware that you do not become what I have become. To the female &amp;ndash; see how your kind treats some of us. We that are like this cannot help it &amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;ve been created by experience in such a way that we are who we are. Yet, beware too, for a love-stricken man is much to fear&amp;hellip;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ah, but love is a horrible beast, no matter what Dante and the rest may say.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Modified:&lt;/strong&gt; February 5th 2005
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good-bye, farewell, my darling, sweet</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Good-bye-farewell-my-darling-sweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 00:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Good-bye-farewell-my-darling-sweet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Good-bye&lt;br /&gt;
farewell&lt;br /&gt;
my darling&lt;br /&gt;
sweet&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
When first we met&lt;br /&gt;
oh&lt;br /&gt;
so long ago&lt;br /&gt;
you whispered sweet nothings&lt;br /&gt;
into my ear&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recall the day&lt;br /&gt;
you wore that flowered dress&lt;br /&gt;
that you told me that you loved me&lt;br /&gt;
that you would be mine&lt;br /&gt;
that I could have all&lt;br /&gt;
I need merely ask&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then one day&lt;br /&gt;
when the birds were leaving&lt;br /&gt;
we sat under our tree and you told me&lt;br /&gt;
oh&lt;br /&gt;
that fateful day&lt;br /&gt;
that you were leaving&lt;br /&gt;
(were you a caged bird&lt;br /&gt;
I think not)&lt;br /&gt;
but that I would always be on your mind&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Years have passed&lt;br /&gt;
and I have aged&lt;br /&gt;
and while I still think of you&lt;br /&gt;
I think you think of me no more&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
How long has it been&lt;br /&gt;
since you have forgotten&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Do you still recall the time under the porch&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Do you still recall the time I chased you through the woods&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I do&lt;br /&gt;
and always will&lt;br /&gt;
for I am a man of memories&lt;br /&gt;
naught but memories&lt;br /&gt;
and tears&lt;br /&gt;
my darling&lt;br /&gt;
sweet
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dream – The Life</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/The-Dream-E28093-The-Life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2004 00:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/The-Dream-E28093-The-Life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
What happens to a dream deferred?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I ask What happens to a dream deterred?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Could it be that the dream is the life deterred?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If the dream is the life deterred, and the dream is deferred, then what?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is not the dream a life?&lt;br /&gt;
Is not the life a dream?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Is there one life?&lt;br /&gt;
Is there one dream?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps it is as such, that the dream is not singular.&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps it is as such, that the life is not singular.&lt;br /&gt;
Yet the life is quite singular, and so too is the dream.&lt;br /&gt;
Yet the plurality that runs through both can not be denied.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Who am I to deny it?&lt;br /&gt;
Who am I to question it?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to Richard Fitz</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/An-Open-Letter-to-Richard-Fitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2004 01:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/An-Open-Letter-to-Richard-Fitz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
January 11 2005: I noticed a missing parenthesis, so I made the change &amp;ndash; this is such a minor change that it has no real impact upon the document as a whole.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;lt;Address Information Removed&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Mr. Fitz,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On March 3rd 2004 I found, much to my dismay, an individual attributing various unsatisfactory statements to you, Richard Fitz. I, having read contrary statements in articles that you had previously written, felt that the very least I could was point out said statements to this individual, as well as suggest to them that they contact you directly regarding said statements. However, after a few emails back and forth, I found that you had in fact made the contrary statements. The article&amp;#39;s writer had also read the statements that I sent to him to look over, as proof that you could not say what he was attributing to you, and he too found your recent statements to be contrary to what you had originally stated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From what I can tell, the articles that had the contrary-to-your-recent-statements were the first occurrence of said statements, and are dated to various months in mid-2003. While some individuals can certainly change their mind regarding a stand, and be fully justified in doing so (such as Senator John Kerry), I find that the time between these statements, as well as the content of the statements, prohibits me from finding this case to be justified. In fact, if I may be so bold, these statements are as different as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I urge you to re-read the fifth, seventeenth, and twenty-first paragraphs in your article from October 9th 2003. Then, please peruse paragraphs six and seven (especially the last two sentences of the former) in your first article from October 23rd 2003. Finally, notice the contradictions that continually occur while keeping the previously mentioned articles (especially the above mentioned paragraphs) in mind while re-reading your statements to Mr. Drev (I assume that the fifth instance of another person was merely a spelling error on the part of the typist) on March 2nd 2004.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While not a part of your largest organized following, I am indeed quite a supporter of your ideas. I hope that I&amp;#39;m not too modest in asking you to recall that I have sent you two letters previously (late August and mid-September of 2003) regarding various issues which I found you to be slightly confused on (and which I later found you changed your position in order to correct said mistakes). I hope that you will realize your mistake in this instance as well, and will seek to clarify your perspective.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As always, I appreciate your time and effort for the causes that you bring to the light.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I look forward to your comments regarding this both privately and, I&amp;#39;m sure, publicly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sincerely,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
James Skemp&lt;br /&gt;
Madison WI
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we not free? (A question asked, a question answered)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Are-we-not-free-%28A-question-asked-a-question-answered%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 00:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Are-we-not-free-%28A-question-asked-a-question-answered%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Drumming On the mind - Whispers in the Ears -&lt;br /&gt;
NOThing yet has been said - Again we wait quietLy Like the cat -&lt;br /&gt;
How cAn Value Even be placed -&lt;br /&gt;
FrEe As i wRite Soundly i sleep?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I heard you talking...</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/I-heard-you-talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2003 00:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/I-heard-you-talking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I heard you talking&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;just the other day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You talked like Aphrodite,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;that damned goddess of old,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You were talking in her ear&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and it made me feel so cold...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I would give you all the attention,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;perhaps more then you could hold,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;d put my heart on the block,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and not expect a &amp;#39;thunk&amp;#39;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Do you hurt me on purpose?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Did those before?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m not an artist,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;but I&amp;#39;ve a bleeding heart...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;When you are not about&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I curse the ground you tread.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;When you are around me&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I wish for ground beneath my feet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;But you are a woman,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and that explains all...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about you...</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Thinking-about-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2003 00:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Thinking-about-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Thinking about you,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I found your picture,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You were oh so beautiful,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and I&amp;#39;m sure you still are.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sometimes I wonder,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;what would I have been&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;without seeing you&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;without meeting you&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;without having the pleasure...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Sometimes I cry,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;sometimes I bleed,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;sometimes I sit&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;sometimes I gaze...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I looked at your picture,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and I put it back down.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I picked up your picture,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;and I put it back down.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I try to forget,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;but memories don&amp;#39;t always die,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;no matter how hard I try&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;to make them go away.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I guess what they say is true,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;you can&amp;#39;t escape the past,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;you can&amp;#39;t kill your memories...&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Oh, think of the possibilities,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Frontal Lobotomies...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>