<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Years on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/new-years/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Years on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2009 16:58:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/tags/new-years/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2010 resolutions (with special appearance by 2009)</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/2010-resolutions-with-special-appearance-by-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2009 16:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/2010-resolutions-with-special-appearance-by-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t much believe in New Year&#39;s Resolutions, or the like. Instead, I believe that if you want to change something, you should just do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, it&#39;s nice to have a start date, so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2009 &#39;resolutions&#39;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily resolutions, these were things I decided to do or try in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stopped drinking soda&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve flirted with soda for a long time, switching back to Mountain Dew after college, and drinking Dr. Pepper throughout. After putting on more weight than I cared for, I decided to quit drinking soda, period, around May of this year. I lost more than a few pounds, and while I still can see a soda and think it will taste good, I know better. I&#39;ve switched to drinking mostly just water, with some periods of Gatorade and juices. I effectively gave up alcohol as well, but I never drank much as it was, so that wasn&#39;t difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Purchase at least one album a month from a new-to-me artist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one I tried for four or five months, kicked into overdrive near the last few months, and have put on hold in December. I was so into this that I actually created a basic&amp;nbsp;app to help me &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Music-Recommendations-Please!-045-beta-released.aspx&#34;&gt;find new music&lt;/a&gt;. I plan on starting this again in 2010, and sticking to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stopped chewing my nails&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seem to recall that I chewed my nails even before my parents divorced. Around October 10th I stopped chewing my nails, and over two months later, I still don&#39;t know why. This is the longest it&#39;s been in &lt;em&gt;well over&lt;/em&gt; 15 years. This is my biggest accomplishment this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Paid off my car&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I paid off my car 2+ years early. Next up are my students loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stopped watching television&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest part was skipping the new episode of the show I liked watching. After that, it was rather simple. With 3+ years of Netflix, game consoles, books, technology, and the Internet, it&#39;s been rather simple. Note that I still watch some shows online, but consider the two sufficiently different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I&#39;d like to do in 2010&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Purchase at least one album a month from a new-to-me artist&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started doing this in 2009, but eventually got a bit carried away and &#39;paused&#39; in December. Having found some really great music while I was doing this, I&#39;m looking forward to doing this in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Take at least one&amp;nbsp;picture every day&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I think my muse has died, as lately I&#39;ve had no interest in some of the things I liked doing; taking photos is one such thing. I think my problem in the past has been that I think it has to have appeal to a large audience. Since that may have been holding me back, screw it&amp;nbsp;- I&#39;ll take a photo of whatever I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Write something every day&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quasi-post, although it won&#39;t be posted here, but rather somewhere else. It&#39;ll be for my own purposes only, and will have no format, per se. Again, seems like my muse is MIA lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Get a solid 3 months of savings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been flirting with the amount, but my goal has been to get a solid 3 months of wages in savings. Once that happens, I plan on ramping it up (4 months, 5, etcetera) as time goes by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pay down my student loans at a faster pace&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This somewhat conflicts with the previous, but since my car is paid off, I&#39;d like to get my&amp;nbsp;student loans&amp;nbsp;paid off sooner. At this point if I keep what I&#39;m doing it will be under $7k, but I&#39;d like to see them right around $6.5k by this time next year. Ultimately, however, since this is fairly good debt, the previous has higher priority.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why not start out 2006 right?</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Why-not-start-out-2006-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 09:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/words/post/Why-not-start-out-2006-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
With the new year, comes a couple of smart technology reminders.  Your computer can&amp;#39;t stay clean by itself - make sure you&amp;#39;re doing your part.  And with the new year, and new month, why not verify things are up-to-date now?&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
1. Make sure you&amp;#39;re running the most up-to-date product, with the most up-to-date definitions for your anti-virus software.  Not using a AV program?  Grisoft offers AVG for free for home users.  I&amp;#39;ve used this product for years and stand behind it 100%. http://www.grisoft.com/doc/289/lng/us/tpl/tpl01
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you&amp;#39;re using Norton Internet Security, on the other hand, don&amp;#39;t update to NIS 2006 - either update your past version&amp;#39;s definitions, or look for another product.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
2. Ad-Aware - it just makes sense.  Download Ad-Aware and run it on a semi-regular basis.  Your computer, mouse, keyboard, and network will thank you.  Again, completely free.  http://www.lavasoft.de/software/adaware/
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
3. Disk Defragmentation.  If you&amp;#39;re running a new version of Windows (like XP), there&amp;#39;s no reason not to defragment on a semi-regular basis.  Heck, it&amp;#39;s already installed.  Under the Start menu&amp;#39;s programs, Accessories &amp;gt; System Tools.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>