<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xbox 360 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/xbox-360/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xbox 360 on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 21:12:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/xbox-360/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad (2009)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Onechanbara-Bikini-Samurai-Squad-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Onechanbara-Bikini-Samurai-Squad-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Onechanbara-Bikini-Samurai-Squad-Xbox-360/dp/B001EOQV9U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad&lt;/a&gt; (2009), for the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ignore the cover, Onechanbara actually isn&amp;rsquo;t that bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I hesitated bringing this up to the counter to pay for it.&amp;nbsp;However, with the 3-point-something rating, new copies selling for over $60, and the store having it used for $6.30, I had to pick up Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll admit it, as I guy who likes girls sex can get me to purchase something, and Onechanbara certainly promises that. However, under that exterior lies a fairly good hack-and-slash game. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly not as complex as other games in the genre, but it sucked up at least 18 and a half hours of my time over the last couple weeks, and I can certainly see myself popping it in to try to unlock a few more achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right or wrong, at times the game seemed to remind me of &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Bullet-Witch-2006-Xbox-360.aspx&#34;&gt;Bullet Witch&lt;/a&gt;. However, Bullet Witch is extremely quick, a third-person shooter, with much simpler gameplay. However, the developers certainly spent more time on the main characters than on any of the non-female enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story-wise Bullet Witch is actually fairly good, while when I was playing&amp;nbsp;Onechanbara I felt like I was really missing out having this be the first game in the series I&amp;rsquo;ve played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Button-mashing and grinding will get you past the main story, but a certain skill is definitely required to master the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no Dynasty Warriors,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Sengoku-Basara-Samurai-Heroes-Playstation-3/dp/B002X9KYFW?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Sengoku Basara Samurai Heroes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Drakengard-Playstation-2/dp/B0001A86EG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drakengard&lt;/a&gt;, Devil May Cry, or &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Bayonetta-Xbox-360/dp/B001YI0Z2U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Bayonetta&lt;/a&gt;, (or perhaps even &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Fist-North-Star-Kens-Playstation-3/dp/B003NSECVY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Fist of the North Star: Ken&amp;rsquo;s Rage&lt;/a&gt;) but&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Onechanbara-Bikini-Samurai-Squad-Xbox-360/dp/B001EOQV9U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Onechanbara: Bikini Samurai Squad&lt;/a&gt; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t simply be overlooked because of the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 of 5 stars. Ultimately, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I picked this up. At 18+ hours I certainly got my money&amp;rsquo;s worth and I&amp;rsquo;ll play it again. But there&amp;rsquo;s better games in this genre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Ninja Blade (2009)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Ninja-Blade-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Ninja-Blade-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001KWFBG0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ninja Blade (2009)&lt;/a&gt;, for the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of quick time events, but an overlooked gem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God of War was a pretty good game, but the game made popular quick time events, which I absolutely despised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw Ninja Blade at a used media store I was taken back by how little it cost, for what seemed like a fairly enjoyable game, similar to Ninja Gaiden (note: Ninja Gaiden 2 for the Xbox 360 is kicking my butt, but I fully plan on finishing it, have picked up Sigma for the PlayStation 3, and am semi-interested in picking up others in the series).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I popped it in I was impressed with the visuals, and then the quick time events started. And they never stop.&amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;re as poor at quick times events as I am, expect to have approximately half your time taken up by them. Of course, I kid, but only slightly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;However&lt;/em&gt;, after finishing Ninja Blade, I was actually rather happy with the game, and can absolutely see myself putting it in in the future to pick up some of the achievements (less than half) that I&amp;rsquo;m missing. Sure, the quick time events are harsh, but the ability to replay them with little ill-effect tones the frustration down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rather liked the story, which reminded me of The Third Birthday and Drakengard (keeping in mind that I read an English translation of a Nier book).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the exception of weapon switching, which is mostly due to the 360&amp;rsquo;s inferior d-pad, the game was also rather fluid, suffering from only a bit of slowness at extremely &amp;lsquo;intense&amp;rsquo; periods of activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like Ninja Gaiden&amp;rsquo;s game play, and aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid of fairly intense quick time events, definitely give &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001KWFBG0?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ninja Blade&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 of 5 stars for a difficult, but rewarding, and replayable, game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nier weapon data in XML (and LINQ sample query)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Nier-weapon-data-in-XML-and-LINQ-sample-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 21:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Nier-weapon-data-in-XML-and-LINQ-sample-query/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going through the game &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Nier-2010-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3.aspx&#34;&gt;Nier&lt;/a&gt; yet again, I wanted an easier way to track what weapon levels I had already upgraded to, and what items I still needed to unlock weapon items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase one towards that goal is creating an XML file with weapon upgrade information which is available online: &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/NierWeapons.xml&#34;&gt;Nier weapon data&lt;/a&gt;. An XML schema document for this information is also available: &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xsd/2011/10/NierWeapons.xsd&#34;&gt;Nier weapon XSD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sample LINQ query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following query can be run from LINQPAD, and will either display all items with their counts, or a grouped listing of items with the total quantity needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;csharp&#34;&gt;XDocument weaponsXml = XDocument.Load(@&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/NierWeapons.xml&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;http://media.jamesrskemp.com/xml/NierWeapons.xml&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;var items = weaponsXml
    .Descendants()
    .Elements(&amp;ldquo;Item&amp;rdquo;)
    .Select(i =&amp;gt; new WeaponItem { Name = i.Attribute(&amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo;).Value, Quantity = i.Attribute(&amp;ldquo;Quantity&amp;rdquo;) != null ? int.Parse(i.Attribute(&amp;ldquo;Quantity&amp;rdquo;).Value) : 1 })
    .OrderBy(i =&amp;gt; i.Name).ThenBy(i =&amp;gt; i.Quantity)
    ;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;var itemsGrouped = items.GroupBy(i =&amp;gt; i.Name).Select(g =&amp;gt; new WeaponItem { Name = g.Key, Quantity = g.Sum(i =&amp;gt; i.Quantity) });&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//items.Dump();
itemsGrouped.Dump();&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;}
public class WeaponItem {
    public string Name {get;set;}
    public int Quantity {get;set;}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Bullet Witch (2006) (Xbox 360)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Bullet-Witch-2006-Xbox-360/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 20:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Bullet-Witch-2006-Xbox-360/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ICV996?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Bullet Witch&lt;/a&gt;, released in 2006 for the Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It is what it is, and that&amp;rsquo;s just fine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I was hooked by the uniqueness of the first few levels of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0001A86EG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drakengard&lt;/a&gt;, released for the PlayStation 2. When I finally found and picked up a copy I found it had hooked its claws into me even more.&amp;nbsp;So when &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000CSUKY6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drakengard 2&lt;/a&gt; came out I of course picked up a copy. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as the first Drakengard, but it was nonetheless still a good entry to the series. Many many years later I picked up &lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Nier-2010-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3.aspx&#34;&gt;Nier&lt;/a&gt;, which was associated with Square Enix, but received extremely harsh reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the same time I found that Cavia, a name I remembered well from the Drakengard series, had worked on Nier, which got me wondering what other games they had had a hand in. I had played&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0002CHJ00?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the PlayStation 2 years before, and ended up trading it in due to what I found were clunky controls (if I remember correctly). But as I was looking through the list I saw one game I had seen before and skimmed over due to the price and cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I released Cavia had had a hand in Bullet Witch I decided to pick up a copy once I found it at a good price (and with the manual and original box). Having found a copy for under $5, I figured it was definitely worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullet Witch is a rather interesting game. The controls are annoying but as I played I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001YI0Z2U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Bayonetta&lt;/a&gt;. Both characters have a certain sex appeal, but both are extremely deadly. One might be ashamed to admit that they not only played, but owned their games, but both contain fairly good games, even if it&amp;rsquo;s significantly easier to tell that Bayonetta is one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Bullet Witch you control a woman who carries with her a gun larger than herself. As you progress you can switch between 4 guns total, each with their own uses. You also gain certain magic spells, and can increase your own abilities, although its limited to increasing your health and magic regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a total of six stages with each lasting between 10 minutes to an hour, depending upon how lost you get and how many times you&amp;rsquo;ve played a level. There are five or six different difficulty settings, with only the lower three available at the start. Achievements are available for beating the game under each difficulty, but since they do not stack you can look forward to playing multiple times (if you care about the points). However, each time you start a game your previously unlocked skills and remaining points carry over, so you could even play the first level over and over again (10-15 minutes a shot) to build up your skills early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above the controls are fairly clunky, which is unfortunate since it&amp;rsquo;s a third-person shooter with some fairly fast enemies. The lighting can also be tricky at times, and there&amp;rsquo;s no good indication of the fact that you&amp;rsquo;re near death, so expect that surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general suggestion is that you play your first time on easy, since achievements don&amp;rsquo;t stack and the game is a little &amp;hellip; clunky, so that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I did. I played the first level a number of times as well, on both easy and normal, but I finished my first game on easy. All told I probably put 6 or 7 hours into the game (thus far).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story isn&amp;rsquo;t horrible, and is actually about what I expected after playing Cavia&amp;rsquo;s other games. Since you&amp;rsquo;re introduced to it within the first few minutes of the game, I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and say that I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite catch why she hears a voice, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s the only oddity (although it could be left unstated for a reason).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I really enjoyed the graphics in the game. It certainly shows its age, and is probably on par with PlayStation 2 graphics, but because of the nature of the story I have no issues with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not the greatest game ever, it&amp;rsquo;s generally not that bad.&amp;nbsp;I&amp;rsquo;ll play it again and beat it at least on normal, and could easily see myself playing it even after that.&amp;nbsp;The game also received a good deal of DLC, all of which is extremely cheap, as in free to 25 cents. The latter is actual maps, which adds a pretty good deal of content for a fairly low price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these reasons I&amp;rsquo;m going to give Bullet Witch 4 of 5 stars. One could perhaps argue that it only deserves 3 stars, but I think the game tells a good story and once you release the shortcomings (using maps removes the pain of wandering around in the larger maps), it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad at all, and offers a good deal of content for the current price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Darksiders (2009) (Xbox 360/PlayStation 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Darksiders-2009-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Darksiders-2009-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001D7T2VM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Darksiders (2009)&lt;/a&gt;, available for the Xbox 360 and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001D7T2VC?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;PlayStation 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darksiders, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Nier-2010-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3.aspx&#34;&gt;Nier&lt;/a&gt;, the last game I played through and beat, didn&amp;rsquo;t get all that much respect when it first came out. But Darksiders features more than just God of War meets Zelda gameplay, it tells a story worth seeing through until the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following review is based upon a playthrough on the Xbox 360, on the hardest -&amp;nbsp;Apocalyptic - difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darksiders is similar to God of War in that you play in a third person view, slashing up enemies and powering up your weapons and variety of moves. Unlike &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001YI0Z2U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Bayonetta&lt;/a&gt;, for example, for the most part you can get away with mostly just slashing away, so long as you dash and jump to avoid attacks, even on the most difficult setting. Blocking is also an option, but whether because of the button combination to do it, or more likely because of my recent playthrough of Bayonetta, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find much use for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One grace that Darksiders provides is that the button smashing cutscenes in Darksiders are limited to only a couple. As someone who dislikes God of War because of the large number of these types of scenes, and had a heck of a time in Wolverine during the one scene that used them, this is absolutely wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gore and violence is approximately what you&amp;rsquo;d get with that type of game as well, so the M rating is well deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darksiders is similar to Zelda, or even Metroid, in that not all areas will be accessible to you when you first start out. Only a few areas are absolutely required, but the optional items make full use of backtracking (not that the game doesn&amp;rsquo;t require backtracking). Puzzles also make an appearance, only a few of which really drove me crazy, especially near the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music in the game is quite majestic, and I found myself sitting and waiting in some areas just to hear snippets, but is never in the way. The rest of the soundtrack is equally good, and do a fairly good variety of enemies, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything horribly repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is the last part I&amp;rsquo;ll mention. As is usually the case you start out strong and rather quickly lose your powers. Here you actually lose them, instead of a game like Prototype where you flash back in time, and must recover them, learning new powers along the way. You really don&amp;rsquo;t make much use of your powers at the beginning of the game, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a horrible loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I found the story compelling enough to draw me into the game, and that was most clear by how I felt during the ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my game I ran into three spots where my console completely froze up, requiring me to turn the console completely off. All were after long playing sessions, so it may have been related to that. They were also rather late in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted above, I played on the hardest difficulty setting, and my total play time was approximately 22 hours, with around 90% of the achievements complete, and grinding to level my weapons and moves, found all optional unlockables. I choose the Xbox 360 version only because it was available where I picked it up. As far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware, there&amp;rsquo;s no difference between the versions (although one article discussing a possible sequel suggested the PlayStation 3 version was better, for some reason).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001D7T2VM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Darksiders&lt;/a&gt; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be my type of game, and I honestly wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting much, but it completely blew me away. In the hope that they&amp;rsquo;ll release another Darksiders, changing only the story, I give this game 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Nier (2010) (Xbox 360 / PlayStation 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Nier-2010-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Nier-2010-Xbox-360-PlayStation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002BRUTT2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Nier (2010)&lt;/a&gt;, available on the Xbox 360 and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002BRYIJY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;PlayStation 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Yes, the main character is ugly, but the story is anything but&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nier, released in 2010, and developed by Cavia, gained mediocre reviews when it was released. The one thing I remember most about those reviews is the common statement that the main character in Nier was rather ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, he (named whatever you name him) &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; rather ugly. And as time goes by he doesn&amp;rsquo;t get much prettier. But Nier doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell just the story of this one man living his live. No, instead it tells the story of a man trying to save his daughter, and going to the greatest lengths to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003 the Cavia developed &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0001A86EG?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drakengard&lt;/a&gt; was released, followed in 2005 by &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000CSUKY6?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Drakengard 2&lt;/a&gt;. The game play style of Nier is similar to both of these, as you play a third-person behind action game, with RPG elements, including health and magic points. You can either attack, use some type of (attack) magic, defend, jump, or roll, as well as use items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your weapons, starting with one-handed swords and growing to include both two-handed swords and spears, can also be upgraded, assuming you can find the necessary materials to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To progress the story you speak with the various inhabitants of the world, going from place to place, fighting enemies between villages, and doing quests (the majority being optional) for various characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other common complaint is the amount of backtracking required in this game. However, there are approximately a dozen major areas in the game, and moving between the furthest points takes much less than 10 minutes, on average (two areas are fairly long, but they are not the norm, and since you go through them multiple times, depending upon how many optional quests you do, you can move through them rather quickly). Because of the small number of unique areas, backtracking in a 12 to 45+ hour game is of course going to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game features four endings, however the game is split into two parts, and you start near the beginning of the second on subsequent playthroughs. The last two endings involve different choices at the very end of the game, so you really only play the game 1 and a half times, and the last battles twice, if you&amp;rsquo;re going for all four endings (which I recommend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nier is, in some ways, the spiritual successor to the Drakengard games, with some even considering it as part of a trilogy. Indeed the story of Nier is rather good, and reminiscent of the Drakengard games. As mentioned above, the story tells the tale of a man seeking to save his daughter, and in the process gains companions, and discovers a deeper truth. This deeper nature of the world is especially clear when you start on the path to the second ending, and results in additions to the major plot elements. One could argue, in fact, that without playing at least through the second ending you can&amp;rsquo;t really understand the story they&amp;rsquo;ve told.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the game was attacked on its fishing component, that&amp;rsquo;s worth a mention here. Nier does feature a fishing component, which turned one game-related Web site off of the game. However, once you realize the trick to fishing in Nier - which is really just paying attention to the pole, as it&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious after the first couple times when you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to start pulling back - and pay attention to map markers, the fishing component is actually pretty relaxing. (And sure, like real-life, a little boring as you keep trying to catch the fish you want, but instead get other fish or junk.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind that I enjoyed Drakengard and Drakengard 2, and will overlook certain things if a game features a good story, I must give Nier 5 of 5 stars. I only wish I had picked up Nier sooner, and disregarded the reviews I had read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002BRUTT2?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Xbox 360&lt;/a&gt; version of Nier, which supposedly offered some advantage over &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002BRYIJY?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;the PlayStation 3 version&lt;/a&gt;. I clocked approximately 45 hours of game play, with 28 going towards my first playthrough, and obtaining 100% weapons, 91% quest completion, and 37 of 41 achievements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kinect is selling really well; but is that good for gamers?</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Kinect-is-selling-really-well-but-is-that-good-for-gamers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 21:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/The-Kinect-is-selling-really-well-but-is-that-good-for-gamers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Techmeme had a couple of interesting titles this evening. &#34;&lt;a rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/kinect_is_selling_2x_as_fast_as_the_ipad.php&#34;&gt;Kinect is Selling 2X as Fast as the iPad&lt;/a&gt;&#34; and &#34;&lt;a rel=&#34;external nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://blogs.barrons.com/techtraderdaily/2010/11/29/microsoft-over-25m-kinect-sold/&#34;&gt;Microsoft: Over 2.5M Kinect Sold&lt;/a&gt;.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I thought I had the space for it (I&#39;d have to move furniture every time I wanted to play it in my current apartment) I still wouldn&#39;t pick up the Kinect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First there&#39;s the price. At $150 you might as well buy a PSP (which I did) or a Nintendo DSi. Either of which would solve the second issue, which is a lack of good games for that $150 you threw down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there&#39;s a couple of reasons it&#39;s done so well. First, it&#39;s fairly unique as a gaming device. Second, they&#39;ve marketed it to almost no end (I wonder how many devices they just gave away during their blitz?). Third, it&#39;s fast approaching the holiday season, which means parents buying gifts for kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also have those who are using the device for purposes other than those intended, but that&#39;s admitedly a very small chunk of that number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what&#39;s unfortunate is that it&#39;s doing so well, when there&#39;s so few games, which makes me afraid that the price on the device will drop rapidly, simply because it&#39;s become a niche device with no games developed for it, and those that are in line with what you can get on the Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, games that the older &#39;style&#39; of gamer won&#39;t want to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sony&#39;s Move seems like a better technology, as it builds upon the success (and science, if you will) of the Wii&#39;s controller, but moves it to a platform that can deliver much better graphically. Unfortunately, it too suffers from too few launch titles, although seemingly offers more in the next year. And of course a number of existing games have already been updated to now offer Move support (such as Heavy Rain). But, it hasn&#39;t been marketed anywhere near as much as the Kinect has, and it doesn&#39;t draw a big audience because it&#39;s too similar to the Wii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wii, which suffers from a large number of shovelware titles, made only to take advantage of the uniqueness of the console&#39;s controller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps history won&#39;t repeat itself ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Kinect and Playstation Move</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-the-Kinect-and-Playstation-Move/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Thoughts-on-the-Kinect-and-Playstation-Move/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laying aside the question of whether these are merely in response to the amount of money being made by the Wii, and whether the technology will be as lasting as history suggests 3D televisions will be, I&#39;ve been thinking about the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002BSA298?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kinect&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002I0J4NE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Move&lt;/a&gt; recently. Here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How well will they work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the biggest question. Ever since they were first shown on television there&#39;s been the question of what environments will support the Kinect. For the Move, with it&#39;s big glowing ball, there hasn&#39;t been much of a question, since everything suggests that it&#39;ll be easier to track (especially after learning that the ball consists of LEDs which can change based on the environment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this regard, unless I can see Kinect working in a Best Buy or GameStop, or at someone&#39;s house, there&#39;s almost no reason I&#39;d pick one of these up. The last thing I need after paying $150 is to find out that it won&#39;t work in my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hardware pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Price doesn&#39;t just mean how much you pay out of the gate, but also what you get for hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002BSA298?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Kinect&lt;/a&gt; you currently pay $150 for the sensor and a game, with no other costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002I0J4NE?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Playstation Move&lt;/a&gt; costs $100 for a Playstation Eye, main move controller, and game. The navigation controller costs $30, but a Playstation 3 controller can be used instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the Kinect wins out is that with the one sensor you can seemingly support up to two people, while to do the same with the Move you have to purchase another $50 &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002I0J51U?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Move controller&lt;/a&gt;. (At that price it might be easier to purchase another Starter Bundle and sell the game and Eye.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you already have an Eye and don&#39;t care about the starter game you can just purchase the Move controller. Which of course suggests another benefit, in that the Playstation Eye is hardly new technology, and is already used by a handful of existing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity of the Microsoft solution is also a little disarming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For software we have a couple aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less obvious at first is the pricing of the games. Sony seems to be sticking to a lower price of $40 for their games, while Microsoft is sticking to a higher $50 price. Both are less than the $60 games normally go for, and since Wii game prices range from $40 to $50, are on par with Wii games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft seems to be going more for a playful look with their avatars, in line with the Wii, while Sony is sticking with their hardware abilities and leaning towards realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a larger number of Move games being announced for release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Launch date&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Playstation Move is set to release in the middle of September, with the Kinect launching in the beginning of November. Necessarily we have to think about holiday sales. I personally think Microsoft is cutting it a little close in case issues come up. On the other hand, if the Move has issues out of the gate it may result in sales of the Kinect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I can&#39;t help but think that the Kinect won&#39;t be able to outsell the Playstation Move now, for more than a month or two at a time, because of that month and a half delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Company support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As was recently pointed out to me, the Playstation Move doesn&#39;t seem to be the main focus of Sony marketing, while the same cannot be said on the Microsoft front, who seem to be betting fairly heavy. With Microsoft generally seen as more hardcore/shooter focused, getting a chunk of the casual players would move a good deal of hardware, and a $300 price for their Kinect+console bundle certainly isn&#39;t that bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Sony is stressing the games, with really only the Move controller the truly new hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How they both trump the Wii&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the Kinect and Playstation Move trump the Wii, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both consoles support better graphics, but more importantly, both do away with the waste of having to purchase batteries to power the controller. This is obvious for the Kinect, and in the case of the Playstation Move, like their other controllers, it can be charged via USB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to pick one I&#39;d pick the Playstation Move, without a doubt, because of the above. And if no other reason than that Heavy Rain looks pretty playable with Move controllers, I may actually do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Borderlands</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Borderlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 20:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Review-Borderlands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review for &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WMEEBM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;Borderlands&lt;/a&gt;, available for the Playstation 3 and Xbox 360. I specifically played the Playstation 3 version, but my review should be applicable to the Xbox 360 version as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I was expecting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all the hype and reviews I was expecting a ripe-off, albeit a&amp;nbsp;fairly good&amp;nbsp;one, of Fallout 3. Of course, Diablo II with it&amp;rsquo;s randomly generated baddies and weapons (and drops in general) was also mentioned. Seeing as how I played Diablo II and its expansion quite a bit when they were released, and absolutely enjoyed Fallout 3 (purchasing all of the DLC and even getting into the double-digit levels for a second evil/neutral player), this sounded like something I would enjoy. One thing I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about was the first-person aspect, having a generally weak stomach for &amp;lsquo;twitch&amp;rsquo; games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this I decided to hold off until the price dropped, after a handful of months. But as I had a coupon that I wanted to use towards a game (since I was in one of those moods where I just needed something new to play) I decided to pick this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I got&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pleasant surprise. Having just beaten the game after playing for around 2 weeks (with two batches of the flu in there) this is probably one of my favorite games of the last year; definitely in the top 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;RPG elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borderlands has a fairly robust skill tree, for each of the four character classes, similar to Diablo II versus Fallout 3; the former having a small set of skills, within a couple of skill trees, that&amp;nbsp;you can increase in skill, and the latter having a wide variety of skills, without too much in the way of skills requiring other skills. This makes it extremely simple, ignoring the decisions you have to make when gaining new skill points, to work with this element. In fact, the decision making process is fairly flexible, as you can always reset your skill points (without losing any) to try a different style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played a game with a skill implemention like this, I&amp;rsquo;ll honestly have a slightly harder time going back to games that don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to reset (although within the story this element makes sense).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of story, it&amp;rsquo;s actually much better than what I thought it would be, after the various reviews. The ending seems a bit abrupt, but everything is tied together, so it may be more an issue with the open-endness of the game. Which brings us to mission&amp;nbsp;structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are seemingly well over a hundred missions, only a small quantity of which are required to advance the story. The rest serve to help increase your level (more on this later) to what is required for the story missions. Generally they tie into the story enough that it makes sense to just do them, especially for the rewards (whether you&amp;rsquo;re going to just sell them or not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back-tracking, an essential element of RPGs, is present in this game, but isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad once you gain access to an &amp;lsquo;instant-travel network.&amp;rsquo; With enemy respawns being fairly quick (approximately two in-game days, which seems to be less than an hour) and vehicles available for most large areas, the travel isn&amp;rsquo;t tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shooter elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borderlands is&amp;nbsp;a fairly standard FPS, made interesting by the art style it uses and the plethora of weapon choices. While there are a handful of weapon types, most weapons are randomly generated, making it fairly hard in the beginning and middle of the game to choose just four weapons (the most you can have equipped). Generally you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have at least one or two kept in your backpack to swap in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This randomization and weapon type scope is what really makes this aspect of the game interesting, in my opinion. But when you add in class-specific skills, you end up with something completely more. In fact, I think it&amp;rsquo;s fairly easy to miss out on the importance of your core skills, often forgetting to use them. I personally didn&amp;rsquo;t use my character&amp;rsquo;s skill all that often until near the end of the game, and having played with others online, that seems to be fairly common for lower-level first-timers. Perhaps that just serves to show the deepness of this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already mentioend, I have a hard time with FPS games usually, if they&amp;rsquo;re twitch. While Borderlands can be, generally you survey the area and come up with some kind of plan; rushing straight at enemies at or above your level is suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to the level aspect. Each enemy has a set level, excluding one-off mission-related enemies, which is consistent throughout the game. Higher level enemies give great rewards, but are also more difficult. This is the same with the quests/missions. Thankfully there&amp;rsquo;s almost no grinding required (although I should note that I did all optional missions in addition to the story-related ones). Experience also changes based on this, so targeting lower level enemies eventually becomes near useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is interesting in this, allowing you to get a &amp;lsquo;second wind&amp;rsquo; if you kill an enemy before you bleed out. Failing that, a certain amount of money is deducted and you are resurrected at the nearest &amp;lsquo;station&amp;rsquo; (saying no more in case of minor spoilers) ready to go back up against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multiplayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borderlands offers on- and offline cooperative play. Offline coop is okay, with the split screen (side-by-side) a little hard to use. Online multiplayer (using Playstation Network) was fairly quick and without issue. You can choose what game you join, making it fairly easy to find a group at your level (or higher/lower if you so choose). (Unlike on Xbox, Playstation owners typically don&amp;rsquo;t have mics, so I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on communication.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having let my Xbox Live Gold subscription lapse a few weeks ago, online multiplayer was actually the reason I picked this up for the Playstation 3; surprising since I usually don&amp;rsquo;t care too much about online play with games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Replayability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a new game plus mode (keep everything, replay the story again with enemy levels increased) and four classes, as well as the online multiplayer and two currently DLC (with one more in the works), replayability is pretty high. Once&amp;nbsp;I finish the DLC and a few&amp;nbsp;upcoming games - Mass Effect 2, BioShock 2, and probably Heavy Rain - I&amp;rsquo;ll be back on Pandora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Borderlands is, again, one of the top 5 games I&amp;rsquo;ve played in the last year (in no particular order, Fallout 3, Muramasa: The Demon Blade, Uncharted 2: Among Thieves, and Lost Odyssey, with Batman: Arkham Asylum getting bumped). A good, long, game, with an&amp;nbsp;interesting&amp;nbsp;story, and high replayability means I give Borderlands 5 of 5 stars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video games I&#39;m looking forward to in 2010</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Video-games-Im-looking-forward-to-in-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 11:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Video-games-Im-looking-forward-to-in-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In no particular order, here are the video games I&#39;m currently looking forward to playing in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that some games may have been released earlier. Consoles that games can be released for are the PS2/PS3, Xbox 360, or Wii (which therefore includes GameCube games). Since I will probably not be getting an Xbox Live Gold subscription this coming January, and am going to go back to playing RPGs on PS systems only, when possible, PS3&amp;nbsp;versions of multi-console releases&amp;nbsp;will be higher on my list. Of course, FFXIII on PS3 is a no-brainer, even if I was hard-core Xbox 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bioshock 2 (Feb 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tales of Vesperia (release for the PS3 w/ unknown date)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (Feb 2010 for PS3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy XIII (Mar 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resonance of Fate (May 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mass Effect 2 (Jan 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demon&#39;s Souls (Oct &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, once it drops in price a bit more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strivinglife.com/words/post/Review-Borderlands.aspx&#34;&gt;Borderlands&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, once it drops in price a bit more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BioShock (for the PS3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are the games that all signs point to interest being high, but that I&#39;m not interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assassin&#39;s Creed&amp;nbsp;II - Disappointed by the first one, and combat on this one looks pretty boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragon Age: Origins - Looks as though it would be good on the PC, but doubtfully so on consoles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did you know? Xbox Live auto-renewals</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Did-you-know-Xbox-Live-auto-renewals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 16:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Did-you-know-Xbox-Live-auto-renewals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know you have to go through 4 screens - 3 of which are adverts - to turn off &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://live.xbox.com/member/strivinglife&#34;&gt;Xbox Live&lt;/a&gt; auto-renewals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it seems like there&#39;s only one click (or one purchase) to turn them back on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Achievements and Trophies</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Achievements-and-Trophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/On-Achievements-and-Trophies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To a very large extent, I consider myself to be a gamer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time the NES came out, my family picked up an Atari 2600, used. I don&#39;t know who sold it to us, but I can remember going with my dad to pick it up at my school&#39;s playground (that was the meeting place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a later point we picked up an NES, via my dad, and then my mom bought us a SNES. Nintendo 64 came after that, followed by the Playstation, Playstation 2, and Playstation 3, all of which I purchased. (I can&#39;t recall the N64 purchase, but I think that was a family purchase.) Finally the Xbox 360 and Wii. At some point there was a Game Gear as well, which our dad picked up for us at a Circuit City, if I remember correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, with that kind of history, I&#39;ve been playing games over over half my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before when you wanted to play with someone you had to invite them over. Now you can play with people all over the world. Boasting about beating a game, or getting a certain score, is as timeless as games themselves, and there were (are?) books that even kept track of this information. But with Microsoft&#39;s Xbox came achievements, which, although possible to cheat, allows you to show anyone (with a Live account) just what kind of gamer you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, or maybe the month before, I surpassed the second person I personally knew in Achievements on Xbox Live. I also surpassed the one person I personally know in Trophies shortly after they were launched, although being relatively new to the PS3, that wasn&#39;t very hard to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Xbox, one of those individuals (the first I passed) purchased their Xbox around December 2006, while the second purchased their&#39;s around January 2006. (I didn&#39;t dig into their information very deeply, and they don&#39;t track it as much as I do, so ... these are estimates.) I purchased my Xbox in December 2008. And in five months and change I&#39;m approaching 9900 points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now some people might consider me an achievement &#39;whore,&#39; in that I gained so many points so fast. However, I think it&#39;s important to look further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I have played 22 games on Xbox 360. Those games allow for 18775 gamerscore, if I were to get every point. (Although that&#39;s actually high, since they track points for games in which you can&#39;t get all the points yet, such as for Halo 3.) I have 9830, which is 52.36%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those 22 games, I don&#39;t own 2 of them, having instead borrowed them. Those two games gave me 205 of 2250, and since I felt extremely ill after playing those games, I will probably be unable to pick them up again. Removing those &#39;bad decisions&#39; would result in 58.25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two games that I own that I don&#39;t play, one of which came with another, and one of which I can&#39;t get the control scheme down. Subtracting the 120 of 2000 would result in 65.44%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the 18 games remaining, I have beat (meaning the main story line) 12 of them. I am close to completing&amp;nbsp;2 others, and 4 I would consider endless (I consider Rez HD to have a story line).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I play games, and I beat &#39;em.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trophies on the Playstation 3 are a little different. I have trophies listed for 12 games on the PS3 (although 1 additional game should be listed, and is not). Having four different types of trophies, I have 101 bronze and 18 silver, with no gold or platnium trophies. I have beat the story on four of those games (since I purchased Eden Encore, I&#39;m missing those gardens, so that game is now &#39;unfinished&#39;), and have not on 6. Two others I would consider endless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since they use a percentage of completion, doing the math gives a 23.8% completion rate across those games with trophies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Metal Gear Solid 4, which has no trophies, was finished twice by me. Uncharted got beat three times, and the third time was for the trophies. And that&#39;s not to mention all the other games I&#39;ve finished on the PS3 and PS2, before trophies (and for the latter, achievements) were about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I go for achievements? Yeah, sometimes I&#39;ll do something and then re-load a save to continue with a game. Is that because the achievement is silly? Yeah. But if they feel it necessary to give an arbitrary value to something silly, I&#39;ll go with the designers on that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I play the game to play the game. And if it&#39;s horrid, I won&#39;t play it. (But I will let the achievements keep me going, when I would otherwise give up - I&#39;ve tried three times to finish disc 1/2 of FFXIII, and I just can&#39;t do it.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve been up to (Feb &#39;09 edition)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-Ive-been-up-to-Feb-09-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2009 20:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/What-Ive-been-up-to-Feb-09-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
As my last post may have suggested ... I&amp;#39;ve been playing games. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s a small taste of the games currently on my plate. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Playstation 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Hearts: From the New World&lt;/strong&gt; was close to completion .. before I bought an Xbox 360. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Persona 3: Fes&lt;/strong&gt; still remains to be started, and&amp;nbsp;ditto for &lt;strong&gt;Persona 4&lt;/strong&gt; ... Yes, I didn&amp;#39;t even start Persona 4. Yes, I know how good reviews said it is. (I did pre-order it, after all.) 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Disgaea&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be &amp;#39;finished,&amp;#39; and &lt;strong&gt;Disgaea 2&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be started. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I didn&amp;#39;t finish the first, I pre-ordered &lt;em&gt;Devil Summoner 2&lt;/em&gt; ... How could I not? If it&amp;#39;s great, I&amp;#39;d never be able to get a copy again. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Playstation 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I just picked up &lt;strong&gt;Flower&lt;/strong&gt; the other day, and really enjoyed it. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Disgaea 3&lt;/em&gt; has been out for a while, and they&amp;#39;re releasing questionable character packs, but ... it&amp;#39;s still supposedly a solid game. Need to pick up a copy ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Xbox 360&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Lost Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt; is my current game of choice. Maybe a week more for that to be finished. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I should get further in &lt;strong&gt;Skate&lt;/strong&gt;, but it&amp;#39;s certainly not Tony Hawk ... This might be a rainy day game. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Blue Dragon&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Infinite Undiscovery&lt;/strong&gt; need to be started. Probably once I finished Lost Odyssey I&amp;#39;ll do so. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fallout 3&lt;/strong&gt; seemingly still has a couple of major bugs. This the only reason I haven&amp;#39;t been playing it as much as I&amp;#39;d like; it&amp;#39;s really a pretty awesome game. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fable 2&lt;/em&gt;, also seemingly had bugs, but they may be fixed? If so, this sounds like a definite buy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Others that I missed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
After writing this, I realized I missed a couple.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Valkyria Chronicles&lt;/em&gt; (Playstation 3) has been getting very good reviews, and the demo I played wasn&amp;#39;t too shabby.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I played the demo for &lt;em&gt;Star Wars: The Force Unleashed&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the Playstation 3,&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;was tempted. All things being equal, this is probably something I&amp;#39;ll pick up for the Xbox 360&amp;nbsp;at some point. (For the power aspect, not the Star Wars/George Lucas aspect.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tales of Vesperia&lt;/em&gt; (Xbox 360) has gotten &amp;#39;eh&amp;#39; reviews, but I starred it for some reason ... probably a video review.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lost Planet&lt;/em&gt; (Xbox 360) and &lt;em&gt;The Last Remnant&lt;/em&gt; (Xbox 360) are for picking up when they&amp;#39;re cheap, since the last is supposedly pretty &amp;#39;eh,&amp;#39; while the second has graphics issues, and needs a patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Even though life is merely striving, it&amp;#39;s good to know that I won&amp;#39;t suffer from boredom on account of not having enough video games to enjoy ... 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear ... whomever (Halo 3)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Dear-whomever-Halo-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 21:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Dear-whomever-Halo-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Dear whomever,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Halo 3 sucks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First,&amp;nbsp;I can only play two missions (missions implying goals) at a time because there&amp;#39;s far too much confusion after those two missions. What did I do, and why? Is there any point? Should I just go as fast through the&amp;nbsp;map as I can? (Having done this the last two missions, it seems to work great, assuming I can find my way around, which leads me to&amp;nbsp;...)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Second, where&amp;#39;s the map? Is there a map? Did you hire level designers? Granted, there&amp;#39;s an arrow, but it consistently points forwards. And that&amp;#39;s only if you sit in one place or drive/walk around for approximately 15 minutes (give or take).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Third, no saving mid-mission. So everyone dies but me. I spend 20 minutes trying to get past something, alone. I&amp;#39;m screwed. I restart the mission and am finally able to proceed. If you&amp;#39;re going to make the checkpoints so messed up, at least let me save when I want, instead of having to save and quit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Fourth, no intelligence required. Run and shoot. Go back to restore shields. Run and shoot. WTF mate?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You either did or didn&#39;t waste your time playing the video game</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/You-either-did-or-didnt-waste-your-time-playing-the-video-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 21:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/You-either-did-or-didnt-waste-your-time-playing-the-video-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
You know what grinds my gears?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When people say that they wasted time playing a video game.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For example, &amp;#39;I was playing Fallout 3 and it began freezing at this certain point, twenty hours in; since I can&amp;#39;t proceed, I&amp;#39;ve wasted twenty hours of my life.&amp;#39;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hello? What do you get for finishing the game? Not the hours that you spent playing it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Or did you? If you spend 80 hours and beat a game, how is that really different? You beat it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But isn&amp;#39;t stopping after 20 hours because of a bug different than stopping because you got tired of the game? Sure it is. For the latter the game wasn&amp;#39;t any fun; there&amp;#39;s no point in wasting any more time. But for the former, the game &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; fun, and you want to spend more time with it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But you can&amp;#39;t. So suddenly the entire 20 hours becomes wasted time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But then they fix the issue and you&amp;#39;re able to continue. Yay.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But since you wasted 20 hours, why waste any more? Or did you really not waste those 20 hours? (Or did you, and wasting 20 hours wasn&amp;#39;t a bad thing?)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tagged &lt;strong&gt;xbox 360&lt;/strong&gt; since a video on Fallout 3 freezes was the reason for this post.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>