<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hp Compaq Cq60 615dx on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/hp-compaq-cq60-615dx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hp Compaq Cq60 615dx on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 16:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/hp-compaq-cq60-615dx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>iPod Touch, netbooks, laptops, and desktops</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iPod-Touch-netbooks-laptops-and-desktops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 16:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/iPod-Touch-netbooks-laptops-and-desktops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last handful of months I&#39;ve been thinking about accessing the Internet, and otherwise being productive,&amp;nbsp;while on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of months back I picked up an HP device with Windows Mobile, unfortunately, after a few months the short battery life and inability to run the applications I wanted/needed to be truly productive forced me to sell it and start looking elsewhere ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;iPod Touch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone had been out for a while when I started looking at what&amp;nbsp;an iPod Touch could offer. I already own an 80GB iPod Classic, so unless it offered enough room to store my music collection (at the time under 40 GB), I wasn&#39;t going to be interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, while I kept telling myself that, part of me knew that I didn&#39;t regularly listen to my entire collection, and I could therefore get away with a smaller size. Nonetheless, price was one of the first things I looked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently we&#39;re looking at third generation models of 8, 32, and 64 GB, at (Amazon pricing, rounded up) $190, $270, and $360. The 8GB made no sense to purchase, which leaves pricing at $3-400. A little pricing when I could just get an 160GB iPod Classic for $230.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Netbook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had looked at netbooks in the past. More real-estate, and able to run a real operating system, netbooks are made for portablility and some level of productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the screen size is pretty harsh, but comes with the above benefits. Overall, I&#39;d pretty much excluded netbooks as an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jeff Atwood wrote about netbooks (&lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2010/01/a-democracy-of-netbooks.html&#34;&gt;A Democracy of Netbooks&lt;/a&gt;) I started giving&amp;nbsp;them another look. According to him, a $400 netbook (give or take) is about equal, in certain ways, to a $5-600+ laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#39;s about what you&#39;re looking to pay; $3-400 for a relatively good netbook. Unfortunately, the operating system I wanted -&amp;nbsp;Windows 7 compared to Windows XP - seems to only be the Starter edition. While that&#39;s certainly not horrible, I really didn&#39;t want to be forced to a sub-par machine, performance-wise, that would limit that productivity applications I&#39;d be able to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And have you seen the screen size on netbooks? I&#39;m hardly that old, but my glass-covered eyes shrieked when I saw them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it basically seems that a laptop is what I really wanted. Why didn&#39;t I just decide on a laptop in the first place? Ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last purchased a laptop around the turn of the century. (Not often I get to use that phrase.) At that time laptops were pretty basic, but I still enjoyed mine. I&#39;d owned nothing but desktops before, and with the exception of the last one, they were all hand-me-downs. I spec&#39;d out the machine approximately to what I wanted (I would have gone higher, but cost was an issue) and ended up paying around a grand, if I remember correctly. (Might have been around $900 ... I have the receipt somewhere.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It lasted me through the rest of college, until right around my last semester when it finally crapped out. I went out a picked up a KOGi monitor (which I still have and use today on my main machine) and hooked up an older desktop to make things work. Later I got it running again, but it crapped out yet again and I gave up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two or three years wasn&#39;t too bad, but in the coming years I stayed away from purchasing another laptop and stuck with desktops, getting more powerful machines for less money. And of course there&#39;s the ease of upgrading a desktop. First simply memory, then media drives, to hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I wasn&#39;t completely away from laptops during those years. I was involved in the purchase of two laptops, both of which have served their owners fairly well as they&#39;ve owned them (the first is nearing the end of it&#39;s life). With this last, which got upgraded to Windows 7 shortly after it came out, I was strongly tempted to give laptops another chance. After all, a lot had changed in almost a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I started pricing out laptops, as I wanted them, I started seeing numbers on par with what my last desktop cost, &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; two widescreen monitors. Did I really want to pay around&amp;nbsp;a grand for a laptop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brought me back to desktops. Why pay a grand when I could get a really nice machine for less than that? Isn&#39;t that what I really wanted, so that I could replace my 4 year old HP that runs approximately 24/7, but which was still fairly good, thanks to me buying a nice machine and maxing out the RAM over time? Heck, the only thing I don&#39;t like about it is that I can&#39;t install Windows 7 on it because of the hardware that&#39;s in it, and I don&#39;t yet feel comfortable completey replacing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with a desktop I lose the portability, which got me on this entire line of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;iPad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short while ago Apple started talking about the iPad, which they place between an iPhone (iPod Touch in my mind, since I&#39;m happy with U.S. Cellular and don&#39;t feel like paying even more a month for Internet access) a laptop or desktop. Not to mention the various other tablet devices that are already out, or coming out. And of course, the iPad is &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; than a netbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is this generally seem single-purpose, as the netbook does. Not only that, but, like the Touch/iPhone, you&#39;re forced to go through the Apple app store. That&#39;s a heavy price to pay when I can purchase a netbook running Windows and either download (for no cost) or build an application to solve a need. With Apple now going after apps which show a little skin, or T &amp;amp; A, it&#39;s difficult to give up control on what applications (as compared to apps)&amp;nbsp;I can run on &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So ...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I ended up doing was just looking at low-end laptops.&amp;nbsp;I had gone full circle, so the only solution I saw was to purchase a laptop, but one with a relatively low cost. After a good deal of research, I&amp;nbsp;kept coming back to the &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0033KELCM?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;HP Compaq Presario CQ60-615DX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a little under $400, we have some amazing features; 250 GB hard drive, Windows 7 Home Premium 64-bit, a modest 2.2GHz with 2 GB of RAM (and only around $100 to max it out to a full 4 GB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&#39;m still a little &#39;eh&#39; about the Compaq brand (another lasting opinion from the last century), every machine I&#39;ve purchased, excluding the one Dell laptop, has been an HP. I like HP machines, and I like that all that I&#39;ve purchased can still be plugged in and fired up; even the one that&#39;s got Windows Me on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on BestBuy.com, I believe I&amp;nbsp;even saw a reviewer suggesting graphic card models that could be swapped in to replace the one it came with, at an extremely low cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A co-worker also purchased one of these, if not a similar model, and when I asked him of it, said he was still happy with it. That was the last&amp;nbsp;nudge I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been mostly busy with side work, which means I might not even consider this a purchase using part of my tax refund, but which also means that I haven&#39;t had much time over the last week to really use the laptop. But having finally gotten the majority of applications that I want on it, and having spent the last 50 minutes writing this article (although a few minutes of that was doing research for this article and leaning over to choose music on my iPod), I&#39;m still happy with my purchase, and am looking forward to continuing to use it. (In fact, I should be watching some Netflix streaming tonight on it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, seeing as how my sister is in desperate need of a computer, I&#39;ve strongly recommended this machine to her, and may be lending the money so that she can purchase one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full review coming shortly, but hopefully the above is of some benefit to someone else, trying to make the same decision as I was.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>