<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adsense on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/adsense/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adsense on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 21:25:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.strivinglife.com/tags/adsense/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AdSense on the spammer sites</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/AdSense-on-the-spammer-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 21:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/AdSense-on-the-spammer-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
It&amp;#39;s about time one of the heavy hitters realizes what some of us smaller hitters have realized a long time ago; cut out a spammer&amp;#39;s revenue, you hit the spammer the only place they care about - their wallets.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogtoolscollection.com/archives/2006/05/15/hurting-comment-spammers/&#34;&gt;Hurting Comment Spammers&lt;/a&gt; links to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.problogger.net/archives/2006/05/15/hitting-comment-spammers-and-plagiarists-where-it-hurts/&#34;&gt;Hitting Comment Spammers and Plagiarists where it Hurts&lt;/a&gt;, where the author discusses reporting spammers to AdSense.  Again, it&amp;#39;s about time one of larger 2.0 advocates starts injecting a worthwhile idea in the hive.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Honestly, I&amp;#39;m being harsh, but this is something that a number of people have already been doing.  After all, spammers don&amp;#39;t make their money out of thin air anymore - the dot-com burst the bubble, and with the new bubble, it&amp;#39;s not quite so easy to get a ton of money out of investors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyways, I hope this catches on with the hive.  I&amp;#39;d like to see the advocates create a site where this information can be tracked.  As I said in a comment to the first linked site above, we need to track what sites we&amp;#39;re reporting, and get enough people to make it count.  I report sites when I see them, but I don&amp;#39;t hear anything back, and when I report a site, but 2-3 weeks later see the site still using ads inappropriately, I don&amp;#39;t feel that I&amp;#39;m really making a difference, or being listened to.  I&amp;#39;ll still keep reporting, but, it&amp;#39;s time for this to be injected into the group-think.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I really dislike writing about Web 2.0 ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Update May 15, 2006 @ 9:31 pm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Which is to say, sorry if I step on any toes in this post, but sometimes I&amp;#39;m disappointed that it takes this long for people to see methods that can benefit a group of people outside of the Web 2.0 community.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
WordPress is a great example: Sure, you can use it in it&amp;#39;s standard sense, or you can use it as a pretty good CMS - like what I did for The Framing Business.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Heck, even a wiki can do some good ...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
:D
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content really is key (AdSense)</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Content-really-is-key-%28AdSense%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2006 16:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/Content-really-is-key-%28AdSense%29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve just updated The Framing Business to work with WordPress. While doing so, I decided to take a close look at just how AdSense is working on that site, compared to just this blog. What I found was actually quite surprising.&lt;!--adsense--&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
First, The Framing Business (FB) has earned a couple pennies less than one of the channels I setup for this blog. So, dollars are pretty comparable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Second, click through rates are fairly equal as well. FB is 0.05% lower than the one channel for this site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Third, clicks are higher for FB than this one site channel (almost three times).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, page impressions are over four times as high. Also, this one channel has been in play for a couple of months - significantly less than the single ads on the bottom of The Framing Business pages. Which means?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Content is king. Back when I started I was making zilch, and while I&amp;#39;m still not making much, I&amp;#39;m at least bringing in a steady trickle.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Why? Because I started writing about technology. Because I moved my old articles out of PDF and into HTML content (that I could then attach an ad to). I&amp;#39;m still writing great content, I&amp;#39;m just learning to make it open to a wider audience (non-PDF files), with better ad format(s), and I&amp;#39;m writing more often (although, unfortunately, shorter content).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Just an observation I had recently that I thought I would share.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When it comes to AdSense, content is king. However, while you hear it all the time, you don&amp;#39;t realize just how true it is until you see actual numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdSense and smaller sites</title>
      <link>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/AdSense-and-smaller-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2005 20:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.strivinglife.com/post/AdSense-and-smaller-sites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday I talked about site/network popularity.  My closing thoughts were that I believe my site is growing and think it is &amp;#39;popular&amp;#39; for some fields, but that it could probably be more so.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With that said, how can a smaller site attract advertisers who will, hopefully, pay (some of) the costs of creating and updating a site?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the old days, advertising on a small site meant banner networks, or exchanges.  By putting some code on your page, a banner ad would display.  For every ad you displayed, you would get an ad on someone else&amp;#39;s pages. Sometimes you could make money instead - display 100 ads and get 10&amp;cent;. Now days, the racket is slightly different.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Where once only top sites could work with the top advertisers, and where once ads had to be banner images of a certain size, Google&amp;#39;s AdSense has changed the rules.  Now, smaller sites, as well as larger sites, are able to use the same service.  Of course, the bigger sites will continue to get the better paying ads, but &amp;#39;bigger sites&amp;#39; can now be run by one individual, instead of a large company.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As a small site, and as an individual who wanted to make some money off of my site, (if nothing else, in order to pay the hosting or domains cost) I signed up for AdSense.  Yesterday we went over the stats, so we all have an idea of what kind of traffic I get.  But, what kind of traffic did I get for AdSense?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For AdSense, they count page impressions and ad unit impressions (below, the first and second numbers, respectively).  From Google, &amp;quot;Page impressions are [...] the number of page views we detect. Ad Unit Impressions are [...] one impression logged for each ad unit shown.&amp;quot;  Since some pages have more than one unit, the numbers will not be the same.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: none&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2005&lt;/strong&gt;: 4990-5045, &lt;strong&gt;daily average&lt;/strong&gt; of 166-168&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2005&lt;/strong&gt;: 3271-3371, &lt;strong&gt;daily average&lt;/strong&gt; of 105-108&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2005&lt;/strong&gt;: 3537-3651, &lt;strong&gt;daily average&lt;/strong&gt; of 114-117&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Having thrown those numbers out, we can throw out the click-thru rates, or the percent of clicks per view; .2%, .4%, and .5% (September, August, July).  Views are going up, but clicks are going down?  Actually, clicks are staying consistent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If I now look at stats from when I started to today (December 27th, 2004 to October 8th, 2005), we&amp;#39;ve got 24,460-28,615, with averages of 86-100, and a rate of .6%-.5%.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Is the percentage low?  On the one hand, yes.  On the other hand, it&amp;#39;s not too bad.  Browsing about, you&amp;#39;ll learn that a click-thru rate of 1-2% is pretty good, no matter the site.  Obviously, the more ads you display, and the better your ads, the more money you can make.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If things continue as they have, it will be a couple more years until I make enough to be paid.  Am I expecting to make a lot of money with AdSense, right away?  No.  I&amp;#39;ll admit I was hoping for a greater number of clicks, but that&amp;#39;s the point this time.  AdSense, and any other revenue making tool, is not going to get the small site owner rich quick.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, focus on content - get the people to your site - and then see what you can do about getting them to click on the links.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
~Jk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>