<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nes on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</title>
    <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/tags/nes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nes on James Skemp&#39;s Test Hugo-Generated Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 14:50:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/tags/nes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: 72 Pin Connector for NES 8 BIT Nintendo System</title>
      <link>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Review-72-Pin-Connector-for-NES-8-BIT-Nintendo-System/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 14:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamesskemp.github.io/blog/posts/Review-72-Pin-Connector-for-NES-8-BIT-Nintendo-System/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a review of a &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DLOM6C?tag=strivinglifen-20&#34;&gt;72 Pin Connector for NES 8 BIT Nintendo System (Bulk Packaging)&lt;/a&gt;, by Classic Game Source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Nintendo was purchased new (as far as I know), way back when they were still being sold in stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we haven&amp;rsquo;t played it all that much, since, like many others, the console would blink instead of playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I visited my sister, who has it now, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it come on at all. A common issue seems to be the 72-pin connector, so I decided to finally take it back with me and give that a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t recall our NES ever starting a game as soon as you press the power, so I was absolutely shocked (but not enough to hold back my shout of joy) when it started a game immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some suggest pulling the pins back into position, but quite honestly our pins were completely flat (no resistance when sliding in a game) and I&amp;rsquo;m sure the time it would have taken would have been more than the $12 I paid for a new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read a good guide on replacing it (I used &lt;a rel=&#34;external&#34; href=&#34;http://www.hitgaming.com/connectorinstall2.html&#34;&gt;Hitgaming&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s, which comes up for a Google search for &amp;lsquo;nes replace 72 pin connector&amp;rsquo;) and enjoy playing your NES again!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
